<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Smart Digital Agriculture</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2020-06-01T21:24:53+10:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/06/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/06/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-06-02T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-06-02T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-10&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data fusion of vis-NIR and PXRF spectra to predict soil physical and chemical properties&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Boundary line models for soil nutrient concentrations and wheat yield in national-scale datasets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Global patterns of soil heterotrophic respiration - A meta-analysis of available dataset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-fusion-of-vis-nir-and-pxrf-spectra-to-predict-soil-physical-and-chemical-properties&quot;&gt;Data fusion of vis-NIR and PXRF spectra to predict soil physical and chemical properties&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Zhang, Yakun; Hartemink, Alfred E.
EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF SOIL SCIENCE  Volume: 71   Issue: 3   Pages: 316-333   Published: MAY 2020
Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
We tested one front-end data fusion method to combine visible near-infrared (vis-NIR) and portable X-ray fluorescence (PXRF) spectra for predicting different soil properties and investigated the contribution of different sensor data. A total of 197 soil samples were collected from 25 Alfisols and Mollisols in south-central Wisconsin, USA. Soils were analysed in the laboratory for clay, sand, silt content, total carbon (TC), total nitrogen (TN) and pH. Air-dried soil samples were scanned with vis-NIR and PXRF spectrometers. A principal component analysis (PCA) was applied to each of the vis-NIR and PXRF spectra to extract the first 10 principal components (PCs), which were used in the Cubist model. Five types of input data were compared for constructing the models using a front-end data fusion approach, including: (a) 10 PCs from vis-NIR spectra, (b) 10 PCs from spectra of PXRF beam 1 (XRF40), (c) 10 PCs from spectra of PXRF beam 2 (XRF10), (d) concatenating 20 PCs from two PXRF spectra (XRF40 + 10), and (e) concatenating 30 PCs from two PXRF spectra and vis-NIR spectra (XRF40 + 10 + NIR). In addition, the performances of the preprocessing methods (four smoothing methods with or without background removal) of PXRF spectra were compared. Multiple linear regression was also used to predict soil properties directly from 11 PXRF-estimated elements. Our results suggest that smoothing should be applied to the PXRF spectra prior to developing predictive models. PXRF spectra and elemental data can predict soil texture with validation R-2 &amp;gt; 0.85, better than using solely vis-NIR spectra, and combining vis-NIR and PXRF spectra improved the prediction. Combining PXRF and vis-NIR can also predict TC and TN moderately well. Soil pH cannot be predicted from vis-NIR or PXRF spectra in this dataset due to its weak correlations with other soil properties and elements. It is concluded that PXRF spectra can be solely used to estimate soil texture, whereas combining vis-NIR and PXRF spectra via PCA should be used to estimate TC and TN. Highlights
The use of front-end data fusion method to combine vis-NIR and PXRF spectra for predicting soil properties. Different preprocessing algorithms were compared systematically for PXRF spectra. Spectral smoothing should be applied to the PXRF spectra prior to developing predictive models. PXRF spectra can be used solely to estimate soil texture, whereas combining vis-NIR and PXRF spectra via PCA should be used to estimate TC and TN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;boundary-line-models-for-soil-nutrient-concentrations-and-wheat-yield-in-national-scale-datasets&quot;&gt;Boundary line models for soil nutrient concentrations and wheat yield in national-scale datasets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Lark, Richard M.; Gillingham, Vincent; Langton, David; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF SOIL SCIENCE  Volume: 71   Issue: 3   Pages: 334-351   Published: MAY 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In boundary line analysis a biological response (e.g., crop yield) is assumed to be a function of a variable (e.g., soil nutrient concentration), which limits the response in only some subset of observations because other limiting factors also apply. The response function is therefore expressed by an upper boundary of the plot of the response against the variable. This model has been used in various branches of soil science. In this paper we apply it to the analysis of some large datasets, originating from commercial farms in England and Wales, on the recorded yield of wheat and measured concentrations of soil nutrients in within-field soil management zones. We considered boundary line models for the effects of potassium (K), phosphorus (P) and magnesium (Mg) on yield, comparing the model with a simple bivariate normal distribution or a bivariate normal censored at a constant maximum yield. We were able to show, using likelihood-based methods, that the boundary line model was preferable in most cases. The boundary line model suggested that the standard RB209 soil nutrient index values (Agriculture and Horticulture Development Board, nutrient management guide (RB209), 2017) are robust and apply at the within-field scale. However, there was evidence that wheat yield could respond to additional Mg at concentrations above index 0, contrary to RB209 guidelines. Furthermore, there was evidence that the boundary line model for yield and P differs between soils at different pH and depth intervals, suggesting that shallow soils with larger pH require a larger target P index than others. Highlights
Boundary line analysis is one way to examine how soil variables influence crop yield in large datasets. We showed that boundary line models could be applied to large datasets on soil nutrients and crop yield. The resulting models are consistent with current practice for P and K, but not for Mg. Models suggest that more refined recommendations for P requirement could be based on soil pH and depth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;global-patterns-of-soil-heterotrophic-respiration---a-meta-analysis-of-available-dataset&quot;&gt;Global patterns of soil heterotrophic respiration - A meta-analysis of available dataset&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Tang, Xiaolu; Du, Jie; Shi, Yuehong; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CATENA  Volume: 191   Pages: 4574-4574   Published: AUG 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil heterotrophic respiration (RH) represents the carbon losses from the decomposition of litter detritus and soil organic matter by microorganisms. Despite conflicting findings on the dominant climatic, soil and vegetation controls on RH from local studies, little is known on the global patterns of RH and the potential drivers behind these patterns. Based on the updated Global Soil Respiration Database, we conducted a meta-analysis to evaluate the direct and indirect effects of climatic, soil and vegetation controls on RH across the globe using structure equation model (SEM). Our results showed that the global weighted mean RH was 457 +/- 139 g C m(-2) a(-1) (mean +/- standard deviation), but RH differed significantly among ecosystem types and positively correlated with gross primary production, highlighting the importance of the vegetation control on RH. Climate was the most important environmental control on RH indicated by SEM. Soil organic carbon (SOC) content had a negative influence on RH at the global scale, challenging the current understanding that SOC leads to a positive effect on RH at site or ecosystem scale, further indicating that SOC quantity may dominate RH at local scales, while SOC quality and availability may dominate RH at regional or global scales. Great differences were found not only between observed and dymanic global vegetation model (DGVM)-based RH, but also among different DGVMs, highlighting a better parameterizing of DGVMs, particularly the model output not validated by field observations, to better understand RH and belowground carbon dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/06/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on June 02, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/06/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/06/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-06-01T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-06-01T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-9&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sub-pixel mapping with point constraints&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An integrated methodology using open soil spectral libraries and Earth Observation data for soil organic carbon estimations in support of soil-related SDGs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Earth observation-based ecosystem services indicators for national and subnational reporting of the sustainable development goals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Validation practices for satellite soil moisture retrievals: What are (the) errors?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agricultural drought mitigating indices derived from the changes in drought characteristics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An optimal design for hierarchical generalized group testing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“sen2r”: An R toolbox for automatically downloading and preprocessing Sentinel-2 satellite data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;atakrig: An R package for multivariate area-to-area and area-to-point kriging predictions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Content search within large environmental datasets using a convolution neural network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sub-pixel-mapping-with-point-constraints&quot;&gt;Sub-pixel mapping with point constraints&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Wang, Qunming; Zhang, Chengyuan; Atkinson, Peter M.
REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT  Volume: 244   Pages: 11817-11817   Published: JUL 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Remote sensing images contain abundant land cover information. Due to the complex nature of land cover, however, mixed pixels exist widely in remote sensing images. Sub-pixel mapping (SPM) is a technique for predicting the spatial distribution of land cover classes within mixed pixels. As an ill-posed inverse problem, the uncertainty of prediction cannot be eliminated and hinders the production of accurate sub-pixel maps. In contrast to conventional methods that use continuous geospatial information (e.g., images) to enhance SPM, in this paper, a SPM method with point constraints into SPM is proposed. The method of fusing point constraints is implemented based on the pixel swapping algorithm (PSA) and utilizes the auxiliary point information to reduce the uncertainty in the SPM process and increase map accuracy. The point data are incorporated into both the initialization and optimization processes of PSA. Experiments were performed on three images to validate the proposed method. The influences of the performances were also investigated under different numbers of point data, different spatial characters of land cover and different zoom factors. The results show that by using the point data, the proposed SPM method can separate more small-sized targets from aggregated artifacts and the accuracies are increased obviously. The proposed method is also more accurate than the advanced radial basis function interpolation-based method. The advantage of using point data is more evident when the point data size and scale factor are large and the spatial autocorrelation of the land cover is small. As the amount of point data increases, however, the increase in accuracy becomes less noticeable. Furthermore, the SPM accuracy can still be increased even if the point data and coarse proportions contain errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-integrated-methodology-using-open-soil-spectral-libraries-and-earth-observation-data-for-soil-organic-carbon-estimations-in-support-of-soil-related-sdgs&quot;&gt;An integrated methodology using open soil spectral libraries and Earth Observation data for soil organic carbon estimations in support of soil-related SDGs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Tziolas, Nikolaos; Tsakiridis, Nikolaos; Ogen, Yaron; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT  Volume: 244   Pages: 11793-11793   Published: JUL 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
There is a growing realization amongst policy-makers that reliable and accurate soil monitoring information is required at scales ranging from regional to global to support ecosystem functions and services in a sustainable manner under the amplifying climate change enabling countries in target setting of the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). In this line, the need of access to and integration of existing regional in situ Earth Observation (EO) data and different sources such as contemporary and forthcoming satellite imagery is highlighted. The current study puts major emphasis on leveraging existing open soil spectral libraries and EO systems and bridging them with memory-based learning algorithms that create more cost-efficient and targeted large scale mapping of soil properties. Relying mostly on contemporary capacities and open resources it can be readily applied to countries with differing capacities and levels of development. To test our methodology, the GEOCRADLE SSL developed in the Balkans, Middle East, and North Africa region and a hyperspectral airborne image were utilized to provide Soil Organic Carbon (SOC) maps of cropland fields over an agricultural region near the city of Netanya, Israel. Furthermore, simulated data of forthcoming space-borne satellite (EnMAP) and current super-spectral mission (Sentinel 2) were explored. The SOC content of the collected in situ soil samples was predicted using a novel local regression approach that combines spatial proximity and spectral similarities. These predictions were subsequently used to develop models using the airborne and simulated satellite spectra, achieving a fair prediction accuracy of R-2 &amp;gt; 0.8 and RPIQ &amp;gt; 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;earth-observation-based-ecosystem-services-indicators-for-national-and-subnational-reporting-of-the-sustainable-development-goals&quot;&gt;Earth observation-based ecosystem services indicators for national and subnational reporting of the sustainable development goals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Cochran, Ferdouz; Daniel, Jessica; Jackson, Laura; et al.
REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT  Volume: 244   Pages: 11796-11796   Published: JUL 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Decision-making that impacts sustainability occurs at national and subnational levels, highlighting the need for multi-scale Earth observations (EO) and geospatial data for assessing the United Nations’ Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). EnviroAtlas, developed by the United States Environmental Protection Agency and partners, provides a collection of web-based, interactive maps of environmental and socio-economic data relevant to the SDGs. EnviroAtlas maps ecosystem services indicators at national, regional, and local extents that can contribute to targets set forth in numerous goals, such as SDG 6 for clean water, SDG 11 for sustainable cities and communities, and SDG 15 for life on land. Examples of EnviroAtlas indicators that provide a way to view spatial inequalities, help fill gaps in environmental indicators, and integrate socio-economic and environmental data for the SDGs are explored herein. Remotely sensed EO data are essential for producing these indicators and informing planning and decision-making for the SDGs at subnational scales. The National Land Cover Dataset is the basis for many EnviroAtlas maps at the national extent, while National Agriculture Imagery Program and Light Detection and Ranging (LiDAR) data are used to classify Meter-scale Urban Land Cover in select US metro areas. These 30 m and 1 m land cover products are combined with demographic and other geospatial data (remotely sensed and otherwise) to produce integrated indicators that can aid in target setting of the SDGs. Though EnviroAtlas was created for the conterminous US, the methods for indicator creation are transferable, and the open-source code for the EnviroAtlas resource may serve as an example for other nations. Achieving the SDGs means assessing targets and decision-making outcomes at local, regional, and national levels using consistent and accurate data. Geospatial resources like EnviroAtlas that provide open access to indicators based on EO data and allow for assessment at multiple extents and resolutions are critical to broadly addressing national to subnational SDG goals and targets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;validation-practices-for-satellite-soil-moisture-retrievals-what-are-the-errors&quot;&gt;Validation practices for satellite soil moisture retrievals: What are (the) errors?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Gruber, A.; De Lannoy, G.; Albergel, C.; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT  Volume: 244   Pages: 11806-11806   Published: JUL 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract
This paper presents a community effort to develop good practice guidelines for the validation of global coarse-scale satellite soil moisture products. We provide theoretical background, a review of state-of-the-art methodologies for estimating errors in soil moisture data sets, practical recommendations on data pre-processing and presentation of statistical results, and a recommended validation protocol that is supplemented with an example validation exercise focused on microwave-based surface soil moisture products. We conclude by identifying research gaps that should be addressed in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;agricultural-drought-mitigating-indices-derived-from-the-changes-in-drought-characteristics&quot;&gt;Agricultural drought mitigating indices derived from the changes in drought characteristics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Wu, Bingfang; Ma, Zonghan; Yan, Nana&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT  Volume: 244   Pages: 11813-11813   Published: JUL 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Droughts can cause tremendous losses to agricultural and economic development; humans have explored many anti-drought measures to mitigate the influence of drought and accordingly altering the characteristics of actual agricultural drought. In this study, a method is proposed to detect the spatiotemporal changes in drought characteristics, which show the effects of anti-drought measures on drought mitigation. Two agricultural drought mitigation evaluation indices are proposed, the agricultural drought frequency change (ADFC) and agricultural drought area change (ADAC), which are calculated by combining the Palmer drought severity index (PDSI) and vegetation health index (VHI), two widely used drought monitoring indices. The PDSI and VHI represent the natural and actual agricultural drought severity under natural and actual conditions respectively, and their differences in drought frequency and affected area reflect the level of anti-drought measures in mitigating agricultural drought. The feasibility of using ADFC and ADAC to quantify the effects of anti-drought measures for agriculture is explored using data from six typical agricultural provinces in the North China Plain and Northeast China. The results show that ADFC and ADAC could reflect both the spatiotemporal changes in agricultural drought characteristics and the influence of anti-drought measures on agricultural drought. The trend of the drought mitigation index is consistent with agricultural activity statistics. These two indices could be further used to evaluate the effects of different anti-drought methods and aid in defeating agricultural drought across many countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-optimal-design-for-hierarchical-generalized-group-testing&quot;&gt;An optimal design for hierarchical generalized group testing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Malinovsky, Yaakov; Haber, Gregory; Albert, Paul S.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JOURNAL OF THE ROYAL STATISTICAL SOCIETY SERIES C-APPLIED STATISTICS  Volume: 69   Issue: 3   Pages: 607-621   Published: JUN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Choosing an optimal strategy for hierarchical group testing is an important problem for practitioners who are interested in disease screening with limited resources. For example, when screening for infectious diseases in large populations, it is important to use algorithms that minimize the cost of potentially expensive assays. Black and co-workers described this as an intractable problem unless the number of individuals to screen is small. They proposed an approximation to an optimal strategy that is difficult to implement for large population sizes. We develop an optimal design with respect to the expected total number of tests that can be obtained by using a novel dynamic programming algorithm. We show that this algorithm is substantially more efficient than the approach that was proposed by Black and co-workers. In addition, we compare the two designs for imperfect tests. R code is provided for practitioners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sen2r-an-r-toolbox-for-automatically-downloading-and-preprocessing-sentinel-2-satellite-data&quot;&gt;“sen2r”: An R toolbox for automatically downloading and preprocessing Sentinel-2 satellite data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Ranghetti, Luigi; Boschetti, Mirco; Nutini, Francesco; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COMPUTERS &amp;amp; GEOSCIENCES  Volume: 139   Pages: 4473-4473   Published: JUN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
sen2r is a scalable and flexible R package to enable downloading and preprocessing of Sentinel-2 satellite imagery via an accessible and easy to install interface. It allows the execution of several preprocessing steps which are commonly performed by Sentinel-2 users: searching the Sentinel-2 archive for datasets available over a spatial area of interest and in a defined time window, downloading them, applying the Sen2Cor atmospheric correction algorithm to compute surface reflectances, merging adjacent files, performing geometric transformations, applying a cloud mask, computing spectral indices and colour images. The package is designed to be accessible to a range of users, from beginners to skilled R users. It comes with a Graphical User Interface, which can be used to set the processing parameters and launch processing operations: this feature makes sen2r accessible also for novices with limited programming experience. High-level R functions, which enable customised image processing workflows and control over intermediate steps, can be useful to experienced remote sensing researchers. Thanks to those functions it is possible to easily schedule automatic processing chains, so to manage massive processing operations. This paper describes the main characteristics, functionalities and performance of the package and highlights its usefulness as the operational back-end of service-oriented architectures, as illustrated by the SATURNO project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;atakrig-an-r-package-for-multivariate-area-to-area-and-area-to-point-kriging-predictions&quot;&gt;atakrig: An R package for multivariate area-to-area and area-to-point kriging predictions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Hu, Maogui; Huang, Yanwei&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COMPUTERS &amp;amp; GEOSCIENCES  Volume: 139   Pages: 4471-4471   Published: JUN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Geostatistical interpolation methods are used in diverse disciplines, such as environmental science, ecology, and hydrology. With the increasing availability of areal spatial data, area-to-area and area-to-point interpolations have great application potential. In this study, based on the variogram deconvolution algorithm proposed by Goovaerts (2008), an open-source area-to-area kriging package atakrig is developed in the R environment. In atakrig, point-scale variogram and cross-variogram can be automatically deconvoluted from spatial areal samples. It provides a general framework for area-to-area and area-to-point ordinary kriging and cokriging. Two applications show that the package works well in river runoff prediction and missing data interpolation for remote sensing aerosol optical depth. The package can be deployed on different operating systems and computer hardware platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;content-search-within-large-environmental-datasets-using-a-convolution-neural-network&quot;&gt;Content search within large environmental datasets using a convolution neural network&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Freeman, J.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COMPUTERS &amp;amp; GEOSCIENCES  Volume: 139   Pages: 4479-4479   Published: JUN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Convolution Neural Networks (CNN) have demonstrated a high level of performance in the areas of image recognition and classification. The training of such networks over large corpora of imagery has facilitated additional applications such as content-based image searching and retrieval. Here we investigate the efficacy of applying a pre-trained deep CNN to the task of content searching within large environmental datasets. It is demonstrated that the learned convolution filters from a pre-trained network provide sufficient fidelity and diversity to accurately perform a content search within a dataset that is unrelated to the CNN training data.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/06/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on June 01, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/04/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/04/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-04-14T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-04-14T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-8&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #8&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;VisNIR integrated multi-sensing penetrometer for in situ high-resolution vertical soil sensing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Classification of soil aggregates: A novel approach based on deep learning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applications of SAR Interferometric Coherence Time Series: Spatiotemporal Dynamics of Geomorphic Transitions in the South-Central Andes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clay content and mineralogy, organic carbon and cation exchange capacity affect water vapour sorption hysteresis of soil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simultaneous measurement of net nitrogen mineralization and denitrification rates in soil using nitrification inhibitor 3,5-dimethylpyrazole&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;visnir-integrated-multi-sensing-penetrometer-for-in-situ-high-resolution-vertical-soil-sensing&quot;&gt;VisNIR integrated multi-sensing penetrometer for in situ high-resolution vertical soil sensing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Wijewardane, Nuwan K.; Hetrick, Sarah; Ackerson, Jason; et al.
SOIL &amp;amp; TILLAGE RESEARCH  Volume: 199   Pages: 4604-4604   Published: MAY 2020
Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract
An in situ penetrometer system that can measure profile soil properties rapidly, cost-effectively, and at high vertical resolution would benefit the soil science and agriculture communities. A visible and near infrared (VisNIR) integrated multi-sensing penetrometer system was developed to automatically measure in situ soil VisNIR reflectance spectra, penetration resistance, and insertion depth along a soil profile. The system was tested in 11 agricultural fields in Nebraska, Illinois, Iowa, and South Dakota of the U.S. An independent soil VisNIR spectral library was used to build calibration models for soil property prediction. External Parameter Orthogonalization (EPO) was used to correct for the field intactness of in situ VisNIR spectra. The results showed that EPO was effective in correcting for the spectral disparity between in situ and dry-ground VisNIR spectra. The EPO correction showed an improvement of prediction accuracy of soil total carbon (R-2 and RMSE improved from 0.29 and 3.06 % to 0.5 and 0.79%, respectively) and total nitrogen (R-2 and RMSE improved from 0.51 and 0.36 % to 0.62 and 0.06 %, respectively). The system also predicted soil bulk density with an RMSE of 0.12 g cm(-3) and R-2 of 0.80. It is concluded that the VisNIR multi-sensing penetrometer, along with the use of external soil spectral libraries and the spectral correction algorithm EPO, can lead to a rapid, robust and cost-effective system for in situ high resolution vertical soil sensing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;classification-of-soil-aggregates-a-novel-approach-based-on-deep-learning&quot;&gt;Classification of soil aggregates: A novel approach based on deep learning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Azizi, Afshin; Gilandeh, Yousef Abbaspour; Mesri-Gundoshmian, Tarahom; et al.
SOIL &amp;amp; TILLAGE RESEARCH  Volume: 199   Pages: 4586-4586   Published: MAY 2020
Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Having a powerful tool and the knowledge to classify soil aggregates, one of the most important factors in evaluating the performance of tillage implements, will result in quick and accurate classification of soil aggregates. By considering them as virtual sieve, a large part of the energy and workforce used in this sector can be reduced. In this regard, computational intelligence tools can play an important and optimal role in the evaluation of tillage quality and its real-time employment. The objective of the present study was to introduce a method known as deep learning to classify aggregates of any size in specific classes. Accordingly, stereo-pair images were used to provide multiple images simultaneously and the proper nutrition of the network. Since stereo-pair images are not dependent on changes in ambient light, imaging was done under conditions of the field with no lighting system. To train the deep models, the images of each lens were separated from each other and entered into the network. Without the extraction of the required features that is done manually in most image and vision-processing algorithms, the presented deep model began to learn to observe and could extract the required features from the lowest level to highly complex features automatically. Among the variety of neural network algorithms in deep learning, a convolutional neural network (CNN) was used in this study for its unique properties in working on images. To train the CNN, VggNet16, ResNet50, and Inception-v4 architects were used. Classification accuracy of these networks was above 95 %, but the highest accuracy achieved with ResNet50 (98.72 %). This accuracy, which was significantly different from previous studies, indicated the good performance of the deep learning method in the classification of aggregates. The results of the current study showed that the estimation of mean weight diameter (MWD) of aggregates without limitations in size and with great precision is completely practical and achievable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;applications-of-sar-interferometric-coherence-time-series-spatiotemporal-dynamics-of-geomorphic-transitions-in-the-south-central-andes&quot;&gt;Applications of SAR Interferometric Coherence Time Series: Spatiotemporal Dynamics of Geomorphic Transitions in the South-Central Andes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Olen, Stephanie; Bookhagen, Bodo
JOURNAL OF GEOPHYSICAL RESEARCH-EARTH SURFACE  Volume: 125   Issue: 3   Pages: 5141-5141   Published: MAR 2020
Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Sediment transport domains in mountain landscapes are characterized by fundamentally different processes and rates depending on several factors, including geology, climate, and biota. Accurately identifying where transitions between transport domains occur is an important step to quantify the past, present, and future contribution of varying erosion and sedimentation processes and enhance our predictive capabilities. We propose a new methodology based on time series of synthetic aperture radar (SAR) interferometric coherence images to map sediment transport regimes across arid and semiarid landscapes. Using 4 years of Sentinel-1 data, we analyze sediment transport regimes for the south-central Andes in northwestern Argentina characterized by steep topographic and climatic gradients. We observe seasonally low coherence during the regional wet season, particularly on hillslopes and in alluvial channels. The spatial distribution of coherence is compared to drainage areas extracted from digital topography to identify two distinct transitions within watersheds: (a) a hillslope-to-fluvial and (b) a fluvial-to-alluvial transition. While transitions within a given basin can be well-constrained, the relative role of each sediment transport domain varies widely over the climatic and topographic gradients. In semiarid regions, we observe larger relative contributions from hillslopes compared to arid regions. Across regional gradients, the range of coherence within basins positively correlates to previously published millennial catchment-wide erosion rates and to topographic metrics used to indicate long-term uplift. Our study suggests that a dense time series of interferometric coherence can be used as a proxy for surface sediment movement and landscape stability in vegetation-free settings at event to decadal timescales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;clay-content-and-mineralogy-organic-carbon-and-cation-exchange-capacity-affect-water-vapour-sorption-hysteresis-of-soil&quot;&gt;Clay content and mineralogy, organic carbon and cation exchange capacity affect water vapour sorption hysteresis of soil&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Arthur, Emmanuel; Tuller, Markus; Moldrup, Per; et al.
EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF SOIL SCIENCE  Volume: 71   Issue: 2   Pages: 204-214   Published: MAR 2020
Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract
The hysteretic behaviour of the dry region (&amp;lt;-1.5 MPa) of the soil water characteristic, which is of the essence for accurate characterization and modelling of bio-physicochemical soil processes under dry conditions, is well documented. However, knowledge about how to best quantify water vapour sorption hysteresis and about the effects of soil properties on dry-region hysteretic behaviour is limited. To overcome this knowledge gap, we proposed a new method for quantifying sorption hysteresis and evaluated its applicability based on measured sorption isotherms of four source clay minerals and 147 soil samples. Furthermore, the effects of clay mineralogy, clay content, soil organic carbon (SOC) and cation exchange capacity (CEC) on the magnitude of sorption hysteresis were investigated. For the clay minerals, kaolinite did not exhibit hysteretic behaviour, illite showed some hysteresis, whereas Na- and Ca-smectite exhibited strong hysteretic behaviour. The average hysteresis, corrected for clay and SOC contents, was strongly reflective of the dominant clay mineralogy of the soil samples. For the soil samples with low SOC content, the average hysteresis significantly increased with increasing clay content (R-2 = 0.92), except for the kaolinite-rich samples (R-2 = 0.35). The SOC-rich samples that exhibited illitic clay mineralogy and similar soil texture showed a significant increase in average hysteresis with increasing organic carbon content (R-2 = 0.93). For all soil samples combined, the CEC was the strongest indicator for the magnitude of water vapour sorption hysteresis.
Highlights
A new index for quantification of soil vapour sorption hysteresis was proposed
Large SOC and clay content increased sorption hysteresis
For soil samples, dominant clay mineralogy controlled the magnitude of hysteresis
Cation exchange capacity was the best predictor of hysteresis for all soil types&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;simultaneous-measurement-of-net-nitrogen-mineralization-and-denitrification-rates-in-soil-using-nitrification-inhibitor-35-dimethylpyrazole&quot;&gt;Simultaneous measurement of net nitrogen mineralization and denitrification rates in soil using nitrification inhibitor 3,5-dimethylpyrazole&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Zebarth, B. J.; Burton, D. L.; Spence, J.; et al.
CANADIAN JOURNAL OF SOIL SCIENCE  Volume: 100   Issue: 1   Pages: 1-10   Published: MAR 2020
Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract
A practical means to quantify the response of the rates of net N mineralization and denitrification over a wide range of soil water contents is generally lacking. This study examined the potential to use a nitrification inhibitor (NI) assay system to simultaneously estimate the rates of net N mineralization and denitrification, and applied the NI assay to assess the effect of water content on net N mineralization and denitrification rates in two soils with contrasting soil texture. The compound 3,5-dimethylpyrazole (DMP) applied at a rate of 200 mg kg(-1) was found to provide essentially complete inhibition of nitrification over the duration of the soil incubation for two soils with contrasting soil texture (clay loam vs. sandy loam) and over a range of soil water contents (35%, 55%, and 85% water-filled pore space). This allowed net N mineralization to be estimated as the accumulation of soil ammonium (NHthorn 4) and of denitrification as the disappearance of added nitrate (NO3-). Addition of DMP resulted in a small increase in soil respiration rate but did not appear to influence the rate of net soil N mineralization. The NI assay provides a practical means to quantify the rates of net N mineralization and denitrification simultaneously over a wide range of soil water contents. The assay can be readily scaled up to routinely test multiple soils in an efficient manner, has limited material costs, and is also relatively simple to perform.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/04/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on April 14, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/04/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/04/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-04-07T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-04-07T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-7&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mapping nature’s contribution to SDG 6 and implications for other SDGs at policy relevant scales&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Comprehensive analysis of alternative downscaled soil moisture products&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The impact of sensitivity and uncertainty of soil physical parameters on the terms of the water balance: Some case studies with default R packages. Part I: Theory, methods and case descriptions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The impact of sensitivity and uncertainty of soil physical parameters on the terms of the water balance: Some case studies with default R packages. Part II: Results and discussion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improving the Predictive Skill of a Distributed Hydrological Model by Calibration on Spatial Patterns With Multiple Satellite Data Sets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The role of climate variability in Australian drought&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mapping-natures-contribution-to-sdg-6-and-implications-for-other-sdgs-at-policy-relevant-scales&quot;&gt;Mapping nature’s contribution to SDG 6 and implications for other SDGs at policy relevant scales&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Mulligan, Mark; van Soesbergen, Arnout; Hole, David G.; et al.
REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT  Volume: 239   Pages: 11671-11671   Published: MAR 15 2020
Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
The natural world has multiple, sometimes conflicting, sometimes synergistic, values to society when viewed through the lens of the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), Spatial mapping of nature’s contributions to the SDGs has the potential to support the implementation of SDG strategies through sustainable land management and conservation of ecosystem services. Such mapping requires a range of spatial data. This paper examines the use of remote sensing and spatial ecosystem service modelling to examine nature’s contribution to targets under SDG 6, also highlighting synergies with other key SDGs and trade-offs with agriculture.
We use a wide range of remotely sensed and globally available datasets (for land cover, climate, soil, population, agriculture) alongside the existing and widely used spatial ecosystem services assessment tool, Co$tingNature. With these we identify priority areas for sustainable management to realise targets under SDG 6 (water) at the country scale for Madagascar and at the basin scale for the Volta basin, though the application developed can be applied to any country or major basin in the world. Within this SDG 6 priority areas footprint, we assess the synergies and trade-offs provided by this land for SDG 15 (biodiversity) and SDG 13 (climate action) as well as SDG 2 (zero hunger).
Results highlight the co-benefits of sustainably managing nature’s contribution to SDG 6, such as the protection of forest cover (for SDG target 15.2), carbon storage as a contribution to the Paris climate agreement and nationally determined contributions (SDG 13) and biodiversity (for SDG target 15.5) but also trade-offs with the zero hunger goal (for SDG 2). Such analyses allow for better understanding of land management requirements for realising multiple SDGs through protection and restoration of green infrastructure. We provide a freely available tool, within the Co$tingNature platform, based on a variety of remotely sensed products, that can be used by SDG practitioners to carry out similar analyses and inform decision-making at national or sub-national levels globally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comprehensive-analysis-of-alternative-downscaled-soil-moisture-products&quot;&gt;Comprehensive analysis of alternative downscaled soil moisture products&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Sabaghy, Sabah; Walker, Jeffrey P.; Renzullo, Luigi J.; et al.
REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT  Volume: 239   Pages: 11586-11586   Published: MAR 15 2020
Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Recent advances in L-band passive microwave remote sensing provide an unprecedented opportunity to monitor soil moisture at similar to 40 km spatial resolution around the globe. Nevertheless, retrieval of the accurate high spatial resolution soil moisture maps that are required to satisfy hydro-meteorological and agricultural applications remains a challenge. Currently, a variety of downscaling, otherwise known as disaggregation techniques have been proposed as the solution to disaggregate the coarse passive microwave soil moisture into high-to-medium resolutions. These techniques take advantage of the strengths of both the passive microwave observations of soil moisture having low spatial resolution and the spatially detailed information on land surface features that either influence or represent soil moisture variability. However, such techniques have typically been developed and tested individually under differing weather and climate conditions, meaning that there is no clear guidance on which technique performs the best. Consequently, this paper presents a quantitative assessment of the existing radar-, optical-, radiometer-, and oversampling-based downscaling techniques using a singular extensive data set collected specifically for that purpose, being the Soil Moisture Active Passive Experiment (SMAPEx)-4 and -5 airborne field campaigns, and the OzNet in situ stations, to determine the relative strengths and weaknesses of their performances. The oversampling-based soil moisture product best captured the temporal and spatial variability of the reference soil moisture overall, though the radar-based products had a better temporal agreement with airborne soil moisture during the short SMAPEx-4 period. Moreover, the difference between temporal analysis of products against in situ and airborne soil moisture reference data sets pointed to the fact that relying on in situ measurements alone is not appropriate for validation of spatially enhanced soil moisture maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-impact-of-sensitivity-and-uncertainty-of-soil-physical-parameters-on-the-terms-of-the-water-balance-some-case-studies-with-default-r-packages-part-i-theory-methods-and-case-descriptions&quot;&gt;The impact of sensitivity and uncertainty of soil physical parameters on the terms of the water balance: Some case studies with default R packages. Part I: Theory, methods and case descriptions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Wesseling, Jan; Kroes, Joop; Oliveira, Thalita Campos; et al.
COMPUTERS AND ELECTRONICS IN AGRICULTURE  Volume: 170   Pages: 5054-5054   Published: MAR 2020
Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract
These papers (part I and part II) emphasize the need for sensitivity and uncertainty analyses. A number of techniques are applied, e.g. latin hypercube sampling, impact response surfaces and Sobol-analyses. Five examples are presented, four of them concerning the numerical model SWAP. The data generation and analysis is performed with standard R packages. Although the computations can be made on any computer, the most time-consuming examples in this paper have been run on a High Performance Computer Cluster. With the relatively simple Impact Response Surface technique it is shown that variation of the saturated hydraulic conductivity has far less impact than changing the moisture content at saturation. Analyses according to the Sobol-Jansen method show that when the soil physical relationships are described according to Damiano, then the parameter b has a very large influence on the results. If the well-known Mualem - Van Genuchten equations are applied, most variation can be explained by the parameter n.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;improving-the-predictive-skill-of-a-distributed-hydrological-model-by-calibration-on-spatial-patterns-with-multiple-satellite-data-sets&quot;&gt;Improving the Predictive Skill of a Distributed Hydrological Model by Calibration on Spatial Patterns With Multiple Satellite Data Sets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Dembele, Moctar; Hrachowitz, Markus; Savenije, Hubert H. G.; et al.
WATER RESOURCES RESEARCH  Volume: 56   Issue: 1   Pages: 26085-26085   Published: JAN 2020
Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Hydrological model calibration combining Earth observations and in situ measurements is a promising solution to overcome the limitations of the traditional streamflow-only calibration. However, combining multiple data sources in model calibration requires a meaningful integration of the data sets, which should harness their most reliable contents to avoid accumulation of their uncertainties and mislead the parameter estimation procedure. This study analyzes the improvement of model parameter selection by using only the spatial patterns of satellite remote sensing data, thereby ignoring their absolute values. Although satellite products are characterized by uncertainties, their most reliable key feature is the representation of spatial patterns, which is a unique and relevant source of information for distributed hydrological models. We propose a novel multivariate calibration framework exploiting spatial patterns and simultaneously incorporating streamflow and three satellite products (i.e., Global Land Evaporation Amsterdam Model [GLEAM] evaporation, European Space Agency Climate Change Initiative [ESA CCI] soil moisture, and Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment [GRACE] terrestrial water storage). The Moderate Resolution Imaging Spectroradiometer (MODIS) land surface temperature data set is used for model evaluation. A bias-insensitive and multicomponent spatial pattern matching metric is developed to formulate a multiobjective function. The proposed multivariate calibration framework is tested with the mesoscale Hydrologic Model (mHM) and applied to the poorly gauged Volta River basin located in a predominantly semiarid climate in West Africa. Results of the multivariate calibration show that the decrease in performance for streamflow (-7%) and terrestrial water storage (-6%) is counterbalanced with an increase in performance for soil moisture (+105%) and evaporation (+26%). These results demonstrate that there are benefits in using satellite data sets, when suitably integrated in a robust model parametrization scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-role-of-climate-variability-in-australian-drought&quot;&gt;The role of climate variability in Australian drought&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: King, Andrew D.; Pitman, Andy J.; Henley, Benjamin J.; et al.
NATURE CLIMATE CHANGE  Volume: 10   Issue: 3   Pages: 177-179   Published: MAR 2020
Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Much of Australia has been in severe drought since at least 2017. Here we link Australian droughts to the absence of Pacific and Indian Ocean mode states that act as key drivers of drought-breaking rains. Predicting the impact of climate change on drought requires accurate modelling of these modes of variability.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/04/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on April 07, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/03/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/03/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-03-29T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-03-29T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-6&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Which practices co-deliver food security, climate change mitigation and adaptation, and combat land degradation and desertification?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Global patterns of terrestrial nitrogen and phosphorus limitation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mapping soil organic carbon and clay using remote sensing to predict soil workability for enhanced climate change adaptation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modelling the spatial extent and severity of extreme European windstorms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;which-practices-co-deliver-food-security-climate-change-mitigation-and-adaptation-and-combat-land-degradation-and-desertification&quot;&gt;Which practices co-deliver food security, climate change mitigation and adaptation, and combat land degradation and desertification?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Smith, P (Smith, Pete)[ 1 ] ; Calvin, K (Calvin, Katherine)[ 2 ] ; Nkem, J (Nkem, Johnson)[ 3 ] ; Campbell, D (Campbell, Donovan)[ 4 ] ; Cherubini, F (Cherubini, Francesco)[ 5 ] ; Grassi, G (Grassi, Giacomo)[ 6 ] ; Korotkov, V (Korotkov, Vladimir)[ 7 ] ; Hoang, AL (Anh Le Hoang)[ 8 ] ; Lwasa, S (Lwasa, Shuaib)[ 9 ] ; McElwee, P (McElwee, Pamela)[ 10 ] …More&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View Web of Science ResearcherID and ORCID
GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pages: NIL_1-NIL_44
Published: DEC 14 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
There is a clear need for transformative change in the land management and food production sectors to address the global land challenges of climate change mitigation, climate change adaptation, combatting land degradation and desertification, and delivering food security (referred to hereafter as “land challenges”). We assess the potential for 40 practices to address these land challenges and find that: Nine options deliver medium to large benefits for all four land challenges. A further two options have no global estimates for adaptation, but have medium to large benefits for all other land challenges. Five options have large mitigation potential (&amp;gt;3 Gt CO(2)eq/year) without adverse impacts on the other land challenges. Five options have moderate mitigation potential, with no adverse impacts on the other land challenges. Sixteen practices have large adaptation potential (&amp;gt;25 million people benefit), without adverse side effects on other land challenges. Most practices can be applied without competing for available land. However, seven options could result in competition for land. A large number of practices do not require dedicated land, including several land management options, all value chain options, and all risk management options. Four options could greatly increase competition for land if applied at a large scale, though the impact is scale and context specific, highlighting the need for safeguards to ensure that expansion of land for mitigation does not impact natural systems and food security. A number of practices, such as increased food productivity, dietary change and reduced food loss and waste, can reduce demand for land conversion, thereby potentially freeing-up land and creating opportunities for enhanced implementation of other practices, making them important components of portfolios of practices to address the combined land challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;global-patterns-of-terrestrial-nitrogen-and-phosphorus-limitation&quot;&gt;Global patterns of terrestrial nitrogen and phosphorus limitation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By:Du, EZ (Du, Enzai)[ 1,2,3 ] ; Terrer, C (Terrer, Cesar)[ 3,4 ] ; Pellegrini, AFA (Pellegrini, Adam F. A.)[ 3 ] ; Ahlstrom, A (Ahlstrom, Anders)[ 3,5,6 ] ; van Lissa, CJ (van Lissa, Caspar J.)[ 7 ] ; Zhao, X (Zhao, Xia)[ 8 ] ; Xia, N (Xia, Nan)[ 2 ] ; Wu, XH (Wu, Xinhui)[ 2 ] ; Jackson, RB (Jackson, Robert B.)[ 3,9,10 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View Web of Science ResearcherID and ORCID
NATURE GEOSCIENCE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 13 Issue: 3 Pages: 221-+
Published: MAR 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Spatial patterns in the phosphorus and nitrogen limitation in natural terrestrial ecosystems are reported from analysis of a global database of the resorption efficiency of nutrients by leaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nitrogen (N) and phosphorus (P) limitation constrains the magnitude of terrestrial carbon uptake in response to elevated carbon dioxide and climate change. However, global maps of nutrient limitation are still lacking. Here we examined global N and P limitation using the ratio of site-averaged leaf N and P resorption efficiencies of the dominant species across 171 sites. We evaluated our predictions using a global database of N- and P-limitation experiments based on nutrient additions at 106 and 53 sites, respectively. Globally, we found a shift from relative P to N limitation for both higher latitudes and precipitation seasonality and lower mean annual temperature, temperature seasonality, mean annual precipitation and soil clay fraction. Excluding cropland, urban and glacial areas, we estimate that 18% of the natural terrestrial land area is significantly limited by N, whereas 43% is relatively P limited. The remaining 39% of the natural terrestrial land area could be co-limited by N and P or weakly limited by either nutrient alone. This work provides both a new framework for testing nutrient limitation and a benchmark of N and P limitation for models to constrain predictions of the terrestrial carbon sink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mapping-soil-organic-carbon-and-clay-using-remote-sensing-to-predict-soil-workability-for-enhanced-climate-change-adaptation&quot;&gt;Mapping soil organic carbon and clay using remote sensing to predict soil workability for enhanced climate change adaptation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Paul, SS (Paul, S. S.)[ 1 ] ; Coops, NC (Coops, N. C.)[ 2 ] ; Johnson, MS (Johnson, M. S.)[ 3 ] ; Krzic, M (Krzic, M.)[ 1,4 ] ; Chandna, A (Chandna, A.)[ 1 ] ; Smukler, SM (Smukler, S. M.)[ 1 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GEODERMA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 363 Pages: 14177-14177
Published: APR 1 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Climate change is presenting sizeable challenges for agricultural production around the world. In some regions, shifting precipitation patterns in the spring and fall are negatively impacting farm operation by reducing the number of “workable days” or the days fields can be worked with heavy equipment without damaging soil structure. This can be particularly problematic for farms on clay soils and/or poor drainage. Approximating a water content threshold at which a soil is not workable due to soil structure destruction can be helpful for planning effective farm operations. In this study, we applied advanced remote sensing and machine learning tools to produce digital maps of soil organic carbon (SOC) and clay (CL) content and used them in existing pedotransfer functions (PTFs) to predict a workability threshold (WT) across a study area in Delta, British Columbia, Canada. We combined field data, soil and vegetation indices derived from multiple Landsat satellite images, topographic indices, and soil survey information to digitally map SOC and CL of the agricultural lands in Delta using random forest (RF) and generalized boosted regression model (GBM). When validated against an independent field dataset, the RF model outperformed GBM for all accuracy measures (coefficient of determination - R-2, concordance correlation coefficient - CCC, and normalized root mean square error - nRMSE). We then spatially applied several PTFs using our digital maps to estimate the plasticity limits of the soil and produce WT map. The WT map was then tested against independent field samples of the soil water content at - 10 kPa and we achieved R-2 of 0.59, CCC of 0.70, and nRMSE of 0.15. Our analysis showed that 40% of the fields in the study area had WT &amp;lt; 30%, a threshold that is already being impacted by reduced workable days. This WT map could be used to improve spatial prioritizations of investments for climate change adaptation at farm to regional scales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;modelling-the-spatial-extent-and-severity-of-extreme-european-windstorms&quot;&gt;Modelling the spatial extent and severity of extreme European windstorms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Sharkey, P (Sharkey, Paul)[ 1 ] ; Tawn, JA (Tawn, Jonathan A.)[ 2 ] ; Brown, SJ (Brown, Simon J.)[ 3 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JOURNAL OF THE ROYAL STATISTICAL SOCIETY SERIES C-APPLIED STATISTICS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 69 Issue: 2 Pages: 223-250
Published: APR 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Windstorms are a primary natural hazard affecting Europe that are commonly linked to substantial property and infrastructural damage and are responsible for the largest spatially aggregated financial losses. Such extreme winds are typically generated by extratropical cyclone systems originating in the North Atlantic and passing over Europe. Previous statistical studies tend to model extreme winds at a given set of sites, corresponding to inference in an Eulerian framework. Such inference cannot incorporate knowledge of the life cycle and progression of extratropical cyclones across the region and is forced to make restrictive assumptions about the extremal dependence structure. We take an entirely different approach which overcomes these limitations by working in a Lagrangian framework. Specifically, we model the development of windstorms over time, preserving the physical characteristics linking the windstorm and the cyclone track, the path of local vorticity maxima, and make a key finding that the spatial extent of extratropical windstorms becomes more localized as its magnitude increases irrespective of the location of the storm track. Our model allows simulation of synthetic windstorm events to derive the joint distributional features over any set of sites giving physically consistent extrapolations to rarer events. From such simulations improved estimates of this hazard can be achieved in terms of both intensity and area affected.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/03/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on March 29, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/03/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/03/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-03-02T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-03-02T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-5&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Model parameterization to represent processes at unresolved scales and changing properties of evolving systems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;R software packages as a tool for evaluating soil physical and hydraulic properties&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrating satellite soil-moisture estimates and hydrological model products over Australia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Process-Guided Deep Learning Predictions of Lake Water Temperature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;model-parameterization-to-represent-processes-at-unresolved-scales-and-changing-properties-of-evolving-systems&quot;&gt;Model parameterization to represent processes at unresolved scales and changing properties of evolving systems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Luo, Yiqi; Schuur, Edward A. G.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY  Pages: NIL_1-NIL_9   Published: JAN 12 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modeling has become an indispensable tool for scientific research. However, models generate great uncertainty when they are used to predict or forecast ecosystem responses to global change. This uncertainty is partly due to parameterization, which is an essential procedure for model specification via defining parameter values for a model. The classic doctrine of parameterization is that a parameter is constant. However, it is commonly known from modeling practice that a model that is well calibrated for its parameters at one site may not simulate well at another site unless its parameters are tuned again. This common practice implies that parameter values have to vary with sites. Indeed, parameter values that are estimated using a statistically rigorous approach, that is, data assimilation, vary with time, space, and treatments in global change experiments. This paper illustrates that varying parameters is to account for both processes at unresolved scales and changing properties of evolving systems. A model, no matter how complex it is, could not represent all the processes of one system at resolved scales. Interactions of processes at unresolved scales with those at resolved scales should be reflected in model parameters. Meanwhile, it is pervasively observed that properties of ecosystems change over time, space, and environmental conditions. Parameters, which represent properties of a system under study, should change as well. Tuning has been practiced for many decades to change parameter values. Yet this activity, unfortunately, did not contribute to our knowledge on model parameterization at all. Data assimilation makes it possible to rigorously estimate parameter values and, consequently, offers an approach to understand which, how, how much, and why parameters vary. To fully understand those issues, extensive research is required. Nonetheless, it is clear that changes in parameter values lead to different model predictions even if the model structure is the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;r-software-packages-as-a-tool-for-evaluating-soil-physical-and-hydraulic-properties&quot;&gt;R software packages as a tool for evaluating soil physical and hydraulic properties&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: de Sousa, Dedola Fernandes; Rodrigues, Sueli; de Lima, Herdjania Veras; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COMPUTERS AND ELECTRONICS IN AGRICULTURE  Volume: 168   Pages: 5077-5077   Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The determination of soil physical properties requires complex analyzes performed by software, which are mostly paid access programs. The advantage of using R software is that it is open access and offers several packages for the analysis of soil physic-hydrical properties data. The objective of this review is to present and to disseminate the tools available in R for studies in soil physics. We briefly describe some packages of the R software for soil physics and analyze their ease of reproduction. From the examples given in the manuals of each package we observed that their reproducibility was not always self-explanatory, as verified for the packages soilwater and SoilHyP. The HydroMe and soilphysics packages were the most comprehensible to be reproduced. The most common determination offered by these packages is related to soil water retention curve models. We hope this will guide the soil science researchers to employ, more often, R codes to analyze their data. The R scripts that were used to exemplify the packages reported in this paper are available at https://github.com/sousaetal/COMPAG_2019_600.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;integrating-satellite-soil-moisture-estimates-and-hydrological-model-products-over-australia&quot;&gt;Integrating satellite soil-moisture estimates and hydrological model products over Australia&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Khaki, M.; Zerihun, A.; Awange, J. L.; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AUSTRALIAN JOURNAL OF EARTH SCIENCES  Volume: 67   Issue: 2   Pages: 265-277   Published: FEB 17 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accurate soil-moisture monitoring is essential for water-resource management and agricultural applications, and is now widely undertaken using satellite remote sensing or terrestrial hydrological models’ products. While both methods have limitations, e.g. the limited soil depth resolution of space-borne data and data deficiencies in models, data-assimilation techniques can provide an alternative approach. Here, we use the recently developed data-driven Kalman-Takens approach to integrate satellite soil-moisture products with those of the Australian Water Resources Assessment system Landscape (AWRA-L) model. This is done to constrain the model’s soil-moisture simulations over Australia with those observed from the Advanced Microwave Scanning Radiometer-Earth Observing System and Soil-Moisture and Ocean Salinity between 2002 and 2017. The main objective is to investigate the ability of the integration framework to improve AWRA-L simulations of soil moisture. The improved estimates are then used to investigate spatiotemporal soil-moisture variations. The results show that the proposed model-satellite data integration approach improves the continental soil-moisture estimates by increasing their correlation to independent in situ measurements (similar to 10% relative to the non-assimilation estimates).
HIGHLIGHTS
Satellite soil-moisture measurements are used to improve model simulation.
A data-driven approach based on Kalman-Takens is applied.
The applied data-integration approach improves soil-moisture estimates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;process-guided-deep-learning-predictions-of-lake-water-temperature&quot;&gt;Process-Guided Deep Learning Predictions of Lake Water Temperature&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Read, Jordan S.; Jia, Xiaowei; Willard, Jared; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WATER RESOURCES RESEARCH  Pages: NIL_1-NIL_18   Published: NOV 16 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rapid growth of data in water resources has created new opportunities to accelerate knowledge discovery with the use of advanced deep learning tools. Hybrid models that integrate theory with state-of-the art empirical techniques have the potential to improve predictions while remaining true to physical laws. This paper evaluates the Process-Guided Deep Learning (PGDL) hybrid modeling framework with a use-case of predicting depth-specific lake water temperatures. The PGDL model has three primary components: a deep learning model with temporal awareness (long short-term memory recurrence), theory-based feedback (model penalties for violating conversation of energy), and model pretraining to initialize the network with synthetic data (water temperature predictions from a process-based model). In situ water temperatures were used to train the PGDL model, a deep learning (DL) model, and a process-based (PB) model. Model performance was evaluated in various conditions, including when training data were sparse and when predictions were made outside of the range in the training data set. The PGDL model performance (as measured by root-mean-square error (RMSE)) was superior to DL and PB for two detailed study lakes, but only when pretraining data included greater variability than the training period. The PGDL model also performed well when extended to 68 lakes, with a median RMSE of 1.65 degrees C during the test period (DL: 1.78 degrees C, PB: 2.03 degrees C; in a small number of lakes PB or DL models were more accurate). This case-study demonstrates that integrating scientific knowledge into deep learning tools shows promise for improving predictions of many important environmental variables.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/03/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on March 02, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/02/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/02/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-02-26T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-02-26T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-4&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quantification of Peat Thickness and Stored Carbon at the Landscape Scale in Tropical Peatlands: A Comparison of Airborne Geophysics and an Empirical Topographic Method&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hydrogeological Modeling and Water Resources Management: Improving the Link Between Data, Prediction, and Decision Making&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quantification-of-peat-thickness-and-stored-carbon-at-the-landscape-scale-in-tropical-peatlands-a-comparison-of-airborne-geophysics-and-an-empirical-topographic-method&quot;&gt;Quantification of Peat Thickness and Stored Carbon at the Landscape Scale in Tropical Peatlands: A Comparison of Airborne Geophysics and an Empirical Topographic Method&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Silvestri, S (Silvestri, Sonia)[ 1,2 ] ; Knight, R (Knight, Rosemary)[ 3 ] ; Viezzoli, A (Viezzoli, Andrea)[ 4 ] ; Richardson, CJ (Richardson, Curtis J.)[ 2 ] ; Anshari, GZ (Anshari, Gusti Z.)[ 5 ] ; Dewar, N (Dewar, Noah)[ 3 ] ; Flanagan, N (Flanagan, Neal)[ 2 ] ; Comas, X (Comas, Xavier)[ 6 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JOURNAL OF GEOPHYSICAL RESEARCH-EARTH SURFACE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 124 Issue: 12 Pages: 3107-3123
Published: DEC 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Peatlands play a key role in the global carbon cycle, sequestering and releasing large amounts of carbon. Despite their importance, a reliable method for the quantification of peatland thickness and volume is still missing, particularly for peat deposits located in the tropics given their limited accessibility, and for scales of measurement representative of peatland environments (i.e., of hundreds of km(2)). This limitation also prevents the accurate quantification of the stored carbon as well as future greenhouse gas emissions due to ongoing peat degradation. Here we present the results obtained using the airborne electromagnetic (AEM) method, a geophysical surveying tool, for peat thickness detection at the landscape scale. Based on a large amount of data collected on an Indonesian peatland, our results show that the AEM method provides a reliable and accurate 3-D model of peatlands, allowing the quantification of their volume and carbon storage. A comparison with the often used empirical topographic approach, which is based on an assumed correlation between peat thickness and surface topography, revealed larger errors across the landscape associated with the empirical approach than the AEM method when predicting the peat thickness. As a result, the AEM method provides higher estimates (22%) of organic carbon pools than the empirical method. We show how in our case study the empirical method tends to underestimate the peat thickness due to its inability to accurately detect the large variability in the elevation of the peat/mineral substrate interface, which is better quantified by the AEM method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hydrogeological-modeling-and-water-resources-management-improving-the-link-between-data-prediction-and-decision-making&quot;&gt;Hydrogeological Modeling and Water Resources Management: Improving the Link Between Data, Prediction, and Decision Making&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Harken, Bradley; Chang, Ching-Fu; Dietrich, Peter; et al.
WATER RESOURCES RESEARCH  Volume: 55   Issue: 12   Pages: 10340-10357   Published: DEC 2019
Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A risk-based decision-making mechanism capable of accounting for uncertainty regarding local conditions is crucial to water resources management, regulation, and policy making. Despite the great potential of hydrogeological models in supporting water resources decisions, challenges remain due to the many sources of uncertainty as well as making and communicating decisions mindful of this uncertainty. This paper presents a framework that utilizes statistical hypothesis testing and an integrated approach to the planning of site characterization, modeling prediction, and decision making. Benefits of this framework include aggregated uncertainty quantification and risk evaluation, simplified communication of risk between stakeholders, and improved defensibility of decisions. The framework acknowledges that obtaining absolute certainty in decision making is impossible; rather, the framework provides a systematic way to make decisions in light of uncertainty and determine the amount of information required. In this manner, quantitative evaluation of a field campaign design is possible before data are collected, beginning from any knowledge state, which can be updated as more information becomes available. We discuss the limitations of this approach by the types of uncertainty that can be recognized and make suggestions for addressing the rest. This paper presents the framework in general and then demonstrates its application in a synthetic case study. Results indicate that the effectiveness of field campaigns depends not only on the environmental performance metric being predicted but also on the threshold value in decision-making processes. The findings also demonstrate that improved parameter estimation does not necessarily lead to better decision making, thus reemphasizing the need for goal-oriented characterization.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/02/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on February 26, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/02/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/02/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-02-12T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-02-12T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-3&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Human fingerprint in global weather&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Changing risks of simultaneous global breadbasket failure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;human-fingerprint-in-global-weather&quot;&gt;Human fingerprint in global weather&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Min, Seung-Ki&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NATURE CLIMATE CHANGE  Volume: 10   Issue: 1   Pages: 15-16   Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An anthropogenic fingerprint has been detected in long-term climate trends, but distinguishing human-induced change from natural variability in day-to-day weather remains a challenge. Research now finds that a human influence is discernible in global patterns of daily temperature and moisture.
&lt;em&gt;Climate change now detectable from any single day of weather at global scale&lt;/em&gt;
Sebastian Sippel, Nicolai Meinshausen, Erich M. Fischer, Enikő Székely &amp;amp; Reto Knutti&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;changing-risks-of-simultaneous-global-breadbasket-failure&quot;&gt;Changing risks of simultaneous global breadbasket failure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Gaupp, Franziska; Hall, Jim; Hochrainer-Stigler, Stefan; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NATURE CLIMATE CHANGE  Volume: 10   Issue: 1   Pages: 54-+   Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The risk of extreme climatic conditions leading to unusually low global agricultural production is exacerbated if more than one global ‘breadbasket’ is exposed at the same time. Such shocks can pose a risk to the global food system, amplifying threats to food security, and could potentially trigger other systemic risks(1,2). While the possibility of climatic extremes hitting more than one breadbasket has been postulated(3,4,) little is known about the actual risk. Here we combine region-specific data on agricultural production with spatial statistics of climatic extremes to quantify the changing risk of low production for the major food-producing regions (breadbaskets) over time. We show an increasing risk of simultaneous failure of wheat, maize and soybean crops across the breadbaskets analysed. For rice, risks of simultaneous adverse climate conditions have decreased in the recent past, mostly owing to solar radiation changes favouring rice growth. Depending on the correlation structure between the breadbaskets, spatial dependence between climatic extremes globally can mitigate or aggravate the risks for the global food production. Our analysis can provide the basis for more efficient allocation of resources to contingency plans and/or strategic crop reserves that would enhance the resilience of the global food system.
The risk of concurrent climate extremes affecting breadbasket regions is increasing with climate change, with wheat, maize and soybean crops at risk of simultaneous failure. Correlation between the regions and climate extremes should be considered to ensure food security in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/02/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on February 12, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/02/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/02/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-02-06T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-02-06T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-2&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimating Soil Hydraulic Conductivity at the Field Scale With a State-Space Approach&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil risk maps - Interpreting soils data for policy makers, agencies and industry&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A review of remote laser-induced breakdown spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to measure, report and verify soil carbon change to realize the potential of soil carbon sequestration for atmospheric greenhouse gas removal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How eddy covariance flux measurements have contributed to our understanding of Global Change Biology&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rethinking sources of nitrogen to cereal crops&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conceptualizing soil organic matter into particulate and mineral-associated forms to address global change in the 21st century&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;estimating-soil-hydraulic-conductivity-at-the-field-scale-with-a-state-space-approach&quot;&gt;Estimating Soil Hydraulic Conductivity at the Field Scale With a State-Space Approach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Zhang, Xi; Wendroth, Ole; Matocha, Christopher; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOIL SCIENCE  Volume: 184   Issue: 3   Pages: 101-111   Published: JUN 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A precise description of saturated (K-s) and near-saturated hydraulic conductivity (K-10) and their spatial variability is important for understanding water/solute transport in the vadose zone. However, it is laborious to measure K directly. Alternatively, K could be predicted from easily measurable soil properties using pedotransfer functions (PTFs). Because PTFs ignore the spatial relationships and covariance between soil variables, they often perform unsatisfactorily when field-scale estimations of K are needed. Therefore, the objective of this study was to improve the estimation of K at field scale through consideration of spatial dependences between soil variables. K was measured at 48 locations in a 71 x 71-m grid within a farmland under no-till. An autoregressive state-space approach was used to quantify the spatial relations between K and soil properties and to analyze the spatial variability of K in the field. In comparison, multiple linear regression (MLR) was used to derive PTFs for K estimation. Using various combinations of variables, state-space analysis outperformed PTFs in estimating spatial K distribution across the field. While state-space approach explained 69%, MLR method explained only 6% of the total variation in K-s. For K-10, the best state-space model included silt, clay, and macroporosity and performed almost perfectly (R-2 &amp;gt;95%) in characterizing the spatial variability of K-10. In that case, the best MLR-type PTF explained only 60% of the variation. The results indicate that, by considering the spatial relations between soil variables, state-space approach is an effective tool for analyzing the spatial variability of K at field scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-risk-maps---interpreting-soils-data-for-policy-makers-agencies-and-industry&quot;&gt;Soil risk maps - Interpreting soils data for policy makers, agencies and industry&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Baggaley, Nikki; Lilly, Allan; Blackstock, Kirsty; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOIL USE AND MANAGEMENT  Volume: 36   Issue: 1   Pages: 19-26   Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surface runoff, erosion, compaction and the leaching of potential pollutants from land can degrade the soil resource and damage the water environment, reducing crop yields, causing loss of valuable nutrients and organic matter, together with increasing flood risk. Increasingly, it is recognized that scientific information must be translated into practical tools to change practices and protect the soil and water resource. Working alongside agencies in Scotland, we applied a suite of simple, transparent, rule-based models to identify areas most at risk of exporting sediment and pollutants that may degrade water quality based on field-scale (1:25,000) soil maps. The maps have been used by Scottish Environment Protection Agency, Scottish Water and Scottish Government to assess soil risks to waters from field to regional scale. The work brought scientists together with policy makers, agencies and the water industry to pool their knowledge to apply these practical tools for decision-making. It highlights the need to apply existing knowledge to answer salient questions. All three examples described show that providing the right type of information, which is based on fundamental soils data, can directly influence the implementation of policies, investment and monitoring decisions and provide evidence in support of government. However, this requires both researchers and agency scientists to develop skills as knowledge brokers and to normalize the use of soil data in everyday agency settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-review-of-remote-laser-induced-breakdown-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;A review of remote laser-induced breakdown spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Li, WT (Li, Wanting)[ 1 ] ; Li, XY (Li, Xiangyou)[ 1 ] ; Li, X (Li, Xin)[ 1 ] ; Hao, ZQ (Hao, Zhongqi)[ 1,2 ] ; Lu, YF (Lu, Yongfeng)[ 1 ] ; Zeng, XY (Zeng, Xiaoyan)[ 1 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;APPLIED SPECTROSCOPY REVIEWS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 55 Issue: 1 Pages: 1-25
Published: JAN 2 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Review&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Laser-induced breakdown spectroscopy (LIBS) is well known for its feature of remote detection. In this review, the development of remote detection based on LIBS is presented. Three kinds of remote LIBS configurations and their characteristics have been illustrated. Owing to an inferior efficiency and intensity of spectral signals collected in a remote distance, different methods have been studied to enhance signals. This review briefly summarized the advanced enhancement approaches for remote LIBS, which further improves the capabilities of LIBS for real-time and in situ measurement. Furthermore, the recent development and application of remote LIBS in a variety of fields have been presented. The potential of LIBS in remote detection and its existing problems have also been discussed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-measure-report-and-verify-soil-carbon-change-to-realize-the-potential-of-soil-carbon-sequestration-for-atmospheric-greenhouse-gas-removal&quot;&gt;How to measure, report and verify soil carbon change to realize the potential of soil carbon sequestration for atmospheric greenhouse gas removal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Smith, Pete; Soussana, Jean-Francois; Angers, Denis; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY  Volume: 26   Issue: 1   Pages: 219-241   Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is growing international interest in better managing soils to increase soil organic carbon (SOC) content to contribute to climate change mitigation, to enhance resilience to climate change and to underpin food security, through initiatives such as international ‘4p1000’ initiative and the FAO’s Global assessment of SOC sequestration potential (GSOCseq) programme. Since SOC content of soils cannot be easily measured, a key barrier to implementing programmes to increase SOC at large scale, is the need for credible and reliable measurement/monitoring, reporting and verification (MRV) platforms, both for national reporting and for emissions trading. Without such platforms, investments could be considered risky. In this paper, we review methods and challenges of measuring SOC change directly in soils, before examining some recent novel developments that show promise for quantifying SOC. We describe how repeat soil surveys are used to estimate changes in SOC over time, and how long-term experiments and space-for-time substitution sites can serve as sources of knowledge and can be used to test models, and as potential benchmark sites in global frameworks to estimate SOC change. We briefly consider models that can be used to simulate and project change in SOC and examine the MRV platforms for SOC change already in use in various countries/regions. In the final section, we bring together the various components described in this review, to describe a new vision for a global framework for MRV of SOC change, to support national and international initiatives seeking to effect change in the way we manage our soils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-eddy-covariance-flux-measurements-have-contributed-to-our-understanding-of-global-change-biology&quot;&gt;How eddy covariance flux measurements have contributed to our understanding of Global Change Biology&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Baldocchi, Dennis D.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY  Volume: 26   Issue: 1   Pages: 242-260   Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A global network of long-term carbon and water flux measurements has existed since the late 1990s. With its representative sampling of the terrestrial biosphere’s climate and ecological spaces, this network is providing background information and direct measurements on how ecosystem metabolism responds to environmental and biological forcings and how they may be changing in a warmer world with more carbon dioxide. In this review, I explore how carbon and water fluxes of the world’s ecosystem are responding to a suite of covarying environmental factors, like sunlight, temperature, soil moisture, and carbon dioxide. I also report on how coupled carbon and water fluxes are modulated by biological and ecological factors such as phenology and a suite of structural and functional properties. And, I investigate whether long-term trends in carbon and water fluxes are emerging in various ecological and climate spaces and the degree to which they may be driven by physical and biological forcings. As a growing number of time series extend up to 20 years in duration, we are at the verge of capturing ecosystem scale trends in the breathing of a changing biosphere. Consequently, flux measurements need to continue to report on future conditions and responses and assess the efficacy of natural climate solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rethinking-sources-of-nitrogen-to-cereal-crops&quot;&gt;Rethinking sources of nitrogen to cereal crops&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Yan, Ming; Pan, Genxing; Lavallee, Jocelyn M.; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY  Volume: 26   Issue: 1   Pages: 191-199   Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding how to manage N inputs to identify the practices that maximize N recovery has been an organizing principle of agronomic research. Because growth in N fertilizer inputs is expected to continue in an ongoing effort to boost crop production over coming decades, understanding how to efficiently manage recovery of fertilizer N will be important going forward. Yet synthesis of published data that has traced the fate of N-15-labeled fertilizer shows that less than half of the N taken up by crops is derived from current-year N fertilizer. The source of the majority of N in crops is something other than current-year fertilizer and the sources are not really known. This is true for maize (only 41% of N in crops was from current-year N fertilizer), rice (32%), and small grains (37%). Recovery of organic fertilizer N (manure, green manure, compost, etc.) in crops is low (27%), though N recovery in subsequent years (10%) was greater than that for mineral fertilizers. Thus, while research on efficiency of N fertilizer use through improved rate, type, location, and timing is important, this research fails to directly address management of the majority of the N supplied to crops. It seems likely that the majority of non-fertilizer N found in crops comes from turnover of soil and crop residue N. We encourage the research community to revisit the mental model that fertilizer is a replacement for N supply from turnover of soil organic N (SON) and consider a model in which N fertilizer augments ongoing SON turnover and makes an important longer term contribution to SON maintenance and turnover. Research focused on the efficient recovery of N current-year fertilizer inputs neglects this potential role for building soil N and managing soil N turnover, which seems likely to be the most important source of crop N.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conceptualizing-soil-organic-matter-into-particulate-and-mineral-associated-forms-to-address-global-change-in-the-21st-century&quot;&gt;Conceptualizing soil organic matter into particulate and mineral-associated forms to address global change in the 21st century&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Lavallee, Jocelyn M.; Soong, Jennifer L.; Cotrufo, M. Francesca&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY  Volume: 26   Issue: 1   Pages: 261-273   Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Managing soil organic matter (SOM) stocks to address global change challenges requires well-substantiated knowledge of SOM behavior that can be clearly communicated between scientists, management practitioners, and policy makers. However, SOM is incredibly complex and requires separation into multiple components with contrasting behavior in order to study and predict its dynamics. Numerous diverse SOM separation schemes are currently used, making cross-study comparisons difficult and hindering broad-scale generalizations. Here, we recommend separating SOM into particulate (POM) and mineral-associated (MAOM) forms, two SOM components that are fundamentally different in terms of their formation, persistence, and functioning. We provide evidence of their highly contrasting physical and chemical properties, mean residence times in soil, and responses to land use change, plant litter inputs, warming, CO2 enrichment, and N fertilization. Conceptualizing SOM into POM versus MAOM is a feasible, well-supported, and useful framework that will allow scientists to move beyond studies of bulk SOM, but also use a consistent separation scheme across studies. Ultimately, we propose the POM versus MAOM framework as the best way forward to understand and predict broad-scale SOM dynamics in the context of global change challenges and provide necessary recommendations to managers and policy makers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;interannual-variation-of-terrestrial-carbon-cycle-issues-and-perspectives&quot;&gt;Interannual variation of terrestrial carbon cycle: Issues and perspectives&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Piao, Shilong; Wang, Xuhui; Wang, Kai; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY  Volume: 26   Issue: 1   Pages: 300-318   Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With accumulation of carbon cycle observations and model developments over the past decades, exploring interannual variation (IAV) of terrestrial carbon cycle offers the opportunity to better understand climate-carbon cycle relationships. However, despite growing research interest, uncertainties remain on some fundamental issues, such as the contributions of different regions, constituent fluxes and climatic factors to carbon cycle IAV. Here we overviewed the literature on carbon cycle IAV about current understanding of these issues. Observations and models of the carbon cycle unanimously show the dominance of tropical land ecosystems to the signal of global carbon cycle IAV, where tropical semiarid ecosystems contribute as much as the combination of all other tropical ecosystems. Vegetation photosynthesis contributes more than ecosystem respiration to IAV of the global net land carbon flux, but large uncertainties remain on the contribution of fires and other disturbance fluxes. Climatic variations are the major drivers to the IAV of net land carbon flux. Although debate remains on whether the dominant driver is temperature or moisture variability, their interaction,that is, the dependence of carbon cycle sensitivity to temperature on moisture conditions, is emerging as key regulators of the carbon cycle IAV. On timescales from the interannual to the centennial, global carbon cycle variability will be increasingly contributed by northern land ecosystems and oceans. Therefore, both improving Earth system models (ESMs) with the progressive understanding on the fast processes manifested at interannual timescale and expanding carbon cycle observations at broader spatial and longer temporal scales are critical to better prediction on evolution of the carbon-climate system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;managing-soils-for-resolving-the-conflict-between-agriculture-and-nature-the-hard-talk&quot;&gt;Managing soils for resolving the conflict between agriculture and nature: The hard talk&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Lal, Rattan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF SOIL SCIENCE  Volume: 71   Issue: 1   Pages: 1-9   Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among soil-centric options for addressing global issues being intensely debated by soil scientists, ecologists and earth scientists regarding their effectiveness and applicability are: (a) harnessing soil carbon (C) sink capacity for adaptation and mitigation of climate change; (b) reducing soil erosion as a source of greenhouse gases and the need to include it in the global C budget; (c) enhancing use efficiency of inputs to agroecosystems and returning land, water and other resources back to nature; (d) using global drylands, saline culture, halomorphic plants and brackish water for provisioning of ecosystem services; and (e) adopting a system-based conservation agriculture for eco-intensification of agroecosystems as a strategy of “producing more from less”. Not only should agriculture be made a solution for addressing global issues, but it is also essential to reconciling the need for advancing food and nutritional security with the absolute necessity of enhancing the environment, restoring degraded soils and desertified ecosystems, and advancing Sustainable Development Goals or the Agenda 2030. Highlights
Sustainable soil management, degraded soil restoration abridging agronomic yield gap and improving the environment are important to achieve world peace. Sustainable eco-intensification of agro-ecosystems reduces inputs and enhances use efficiency by restoring soil health. Harnessing soil carbon sink capacity includes reducing accelerated soil erosion for adaptation and mitigation of climate change. System-based conservation agriculture sustains agronomic productivity and minimizes soil degradation and environmental pollution.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/02/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on February 06, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/01/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/01/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-01-28T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-01-28T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-1-part-3&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #1 (part 3)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil health assessment: Past accomplishments, current activities, and future opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Development of soil spectral allocation models considering the effect of soil moisture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evolutionary Pathways in Soil-Geomorphic Systems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Australian hot and dry extremes induced by weakenings of the stratospheric polar vortex&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exogenous and endogenous controls on the development of soil structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-health-assessment-past-accomplishments-current-activities-and-future-opportunities&quot;&gt;Soil health assessment: Past accomplishments, current activities, and future opportunities&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Karlen, Douglas; Veum, Kristen S.; Sudduth, Kenneth A.; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOIL &amp;amp; TILLAGE RESEARCH  Volume: 195   Pages: 4365-4365   Published: DEC 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Global interest in soil health has increased exponentially during the past decade, with many different government, non-government, and private sector groups striving to develop monitoring and assessment protocols. This brief review focuses on developments in the United States (U.S.) with some references to activities in other countries. It also documents how the soil health concept evolved and projects what is needed to scientifically advance monitoring and assessment with a particular focus on activities in the U.S. Recommendations emphasize improving the Soil Management Assessment Framework (SMAF) and/or Comprehensive Assessment of Soil Health (CASH) assessment tools, developing protocols for national soil health monitoring, identifying and calibrating better indicators of soil biological, chemical, and physical health, and developing sensors and other tools for more rapid and in-situ assessments. Collectively, these and other research and technology transfer activities will help achieve what we suggest should be a universal goal - striving for healthy soils, healthy landscapes, and vibrant economies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;development-of-soil-spectral-allocation-models-considering-the-effect-of-soil-moisture&quot;&gt;Development of soil spectral allocation models considering the effect of soil moisture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Wang, Xiang; Dou, Xin; Zhang, Xinle; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOIL &amp;amp; TILLAGE RESEARCH  Volume: 195   Pages: 4374-4374   Published: DEC 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil spectral allocation or classification is usually conducted on air-dried soils. However, the field soils are not all air-dried, and the change of soil moisture will affect soil reflectance. We introduce a soil allocation model that considers the effect of soil moisture for the purpose of eliminating the effect of soil moisture. The topsoil spectral curves of four typical soils from the Songnen Plain in Northeast China were re-sampled to 10-nm intervals and converted to first-derivative spectral curves and continuum removal curves. The spectral feature parameters were extracted from continuum removal curves in the visible-near infrared (VNIR) range (350-2500 nm), and the range of 430-2400 nm was used to build soil allocation models for reducing the effect of noise. Samples with different soil moisture were mixed into air-dried soils and we calculated the coefficient of variation (CV) of different inputs to assess the effect of soil moisture and to find allocation indices that were not affected by soil moisture. We used allocation indices of Zhang et al. (2018) because of the high accuracy of their DT (Decision Tree) model to allocate mixed-soil samples. We also used allocation indices that were not affected by soil moisture to allocate mixed-soil samples with decision tree (DT), multinomial logistic regression (MLR) and multi-layer perception neural network (MLPNN), and compared the results of the two methods. The results show the following: 1) As SFPs were built with shorter bands, SFP was less sensitive to soil moisture than PCR and PCFD and thus SFP is more suitable to build soil allocation models that consider the effect of soil moisture as input than PCR and PCFD. 2) Differences in soil moisture had little effect on absorption valley shoulders, symmetry and absorption positions, moderate effect on absorption area and depth, and a major effect on the slope of different bands. 3) The effect of soil moisture on continuum removal curves of different soil classes was variable. There was little effect on Arenosols, a moderate effect on Chernozems and Cambisols, and a large effect on Phaeozems. 4) The accuracy of the DT model using allocation indices that were not affected by soil moisture was 91.892% with a Kappa coefficient of 0.888. Our results suggest that it is feasible to build soil spectral allocation models that are not affected by soil moisture, and this improves the universality of soil spectral allocation, especially to field soils, which can be of considerable help in soil classification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evolutionary-pathways-in-soil-geomorphic-systems&quot;&gt;Evolutionary Pathways in Soil-Geomorphic Systems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Phillips, Jonathan D.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOIL SCIENCE  Volume: 184   Issue: 1   Pages: 1-12   Published: FEB 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding evolution of soils and landforms (and other Earth surface systems) has itself evolved from concepts of single-path, single-outcome development to those that recognize multiple possible developmental trajectories and different maturely developed stales. Soil geomorphology and pedology should now move beyond showing that multiple trajectories are possible to investigating why some evolutionary pathways (EPs) are common and persistent, whereas others are rare and transient. A typology of EPs is developed and applied to soil formation in the North Carolina coastal plain. Some EN are impossible because of violation of generally applicable laws or absence of necessary conditions; others are currently impossible, having occurred in the past but requiring conditions that no longer exist. Improbable paths are possible but rare, because necessary circumstances involve rare events or boundary conditions. Inhibited EPs are also possible but rare because of resistance factors or feedbacks that prevent or inhibit them. Transient paths may be common but are not long-lived or well preserved and are thus rarely observed. Recurring but nonrepeating EPs occur in different locations but are irreversible in any given location and cannot recur except in the case of system-resetting disturbance or new inputs. Recurring EPs are riot inhibited or self-limited, occur in different locations, and may be repeated because of ongoing or recurrent processes or conditions. Selected path types occur in multiple situations, but with increased probability due to feedbacks or responses that encourage or enhance recurrence and/or persistence. The case study shows examples of all possible EP types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;australian-hot-and-dry-extremes-induced-by-weakenings-of-the-stratospheric-polar-vortex&quot;&gt;Australian hot and dry extremes induced by weakenings of the stratospheric polar vortex&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Lim, Eun-Pa; Hendon, Harry H.; Boschat, Ghyslaine; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NATURE GEOSCIENCE  Volume: 12   Issue: 11   Pages: 896-+   Published: NOV 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The occurrence of extreme hot and dry conditions in warm seasons can have large impacts on human health, energy and water supplies, agriculture and wildfires. Australian hot and dry extremes have been known to be associated with the occurrence of El Nino and other variations of tropospheric circulation. Here we identify an additional driver: variability of the stratospheric Antarctic polar vortex. On the basis of statistical analyses using observational data covering the past 40 yr, we show that weakenings and warmings of the stratospheric polar vortex, which episodically occur during austral spring, substantially increase the chances of hot and dry extremes and of associated fire-conducive weather across subtropical eastern Australia from austral spring to early summer. The promotion of these Australian climate extremes results from the downward coupling of the weakened polar vortex to tropospheric levels, where it is linked to the low-index polarity of the Southern Annular Mode, an equatorward shift of the mid-latitude westerly jet stream and subsidence and warming in the subtropics. Because of the long timescale of the polar vortex variations, the enhanced likelihood of early-summertime hot and dry extremes and wildfire risks across eastern Australia may be predictable a season in advance during years of vortex weakenings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;boundary-line-models-for-soil-nutrient-concentrations-and-wheat-yield-in-national-scale-datasets&quot;&gt;Boundary line models for soil nutrient concentrations and wheat yield in national-scale datasets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Lark, Richard M.; Gillingham, Vincent; Langton, David; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF SOIL SCIENCE  Pages: NIL_1-NIL_18   Published: NOV 15 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In boundary line analysis a biological response (e.g., crop yield) is assumed to be a function of a variable (e.g., soil nutrient concentration), which limits the response in only some subset of observations because other limiting factors also apply. The response function is therefore expressed by an upper boundary of the plot of the response against the variable. This model has been used in various branches of soil science. In this paper we apply it to the analysis of some large datasets, originating from commercial farms in England and Wales, on the recorded yield of wheat and measured concentrations of soil nutrients in within-field soil management zones. We considered boundary line models for the effects of potassium (K), phosphorus (P) and magnesium (Mg) on yield, comparing the model with a simple bivariate normal distribution or a bivariate normal censored at a constant maximum yield. We were able to show, using likelihood-based methods, that the boundary line model was preferable in most cases. The boundary line model suggested that the standard RB209 soil nutrient index values (Agriculture and Horticulture Development Board, nutrient management guide (RB209), 2017) are robust and apply at the within-field scale. However, there was evidence that wheat yield could respond to additional Mg at concentrations above index 0, contrary to RB209 guidelines. Furthermore, there was evidence that the boundary line model for yield and P differs between soils at different pH and depth intervals, suggesting that shallow soils with larger pH require a larger target P index than others. Highlights
Boundary line analysis is one way to examine how soil variables influence crop yield in large datasets. We showed that boundary line models could be applied to large datasets on soil nutrients and crop yield. The resulting models are consistent with current practice for P and K, but not for Mg. Models suggest that more refined recommendations for P requirement could be based on soil pH and depth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exogenous-and-endogenous-controls-on-the-development-of-soil-structure&quot;&gt;Exogenous and endogenous controls on the development of soil structure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Mohammed, Aoesta K.; Hirmas, Daniel R.; Nemes, Attila; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GEODERMA  Volume: 357   Pages: 13945-13945   Published: JAN 1 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The categorical and qualitative nature of currently available soil structural data along with the lack of a geographically broad dataset have impeded progress in understanding the development of soil structure. In this study, we assembled a soil, climate, and ecological dataset for the USA, and used it to analyze relationships between soil structure (ped type, shape, size, and grade) and exogenous and endogenous variables influencing the development of soil structure. We analyzed a subset of the National Cooperative Soil Survey (NCSS) Soil Characterization database after merging this information with climatological and ecological data. The merged and cleaned dataset contains &amp;gt; 4400 observations from approximately 1600 pedons. We found that climate, as an exogenous factor was the most important predictor of ped shape and size. Cold and/or dry climates promoted the development of larger anisotropic peds with rougher surfaces whereas warmer and more humid climates promoted the development of finer equidimensional peds with smoother surfaces. Based on these findings, we argue that climate promotes the development of soil structure along either fragmentation or aggregation pathways. The former pathway is characterized by largely mechanical processes in cold and dry environments, whereas aggregation is promoted by predominately biological and chemical mechanisms found in warmer and wet environments. This connection between climate and the development of soil structure represents a potentially important effect of climate on a morphological property strongly linked to soil hydrology that warrants further investigation with continental-scale soil data.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/01/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on January 28, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/01/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/01/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-01-27T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-01-27T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-1-part-2&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #1 (part 2)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Primitives as building blocks for constructing land cover maps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The East African contribution to the formalisation of the soil catena concept&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A note on knowledge discovery and machine learning in digital soil mapping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nitrogen mineralisation in sugarcane soils in Queensland, Australia: I. evaluation of soil tests for predicting nitrogen mineralisation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Predicting soil carbon saturation deficit and related properties of New Zealand soils using infrared spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mapping change in key soil properties due to climate change over south-eastern Australia (vol 57, pg 467, 2019)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modeling the co-evolution of natural, economic and governance subsystems in integrated agri-ecological systems: Perspectives and challenges&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Utilising geochemical data for the identification and characterisation of mineral exploration sample media within cover sequence materials&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimating Atterberg Limits of Fine-Grained Soils by Visible-Near-Infrared Spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;primitives-as-building-blocks-for-constructing-land-cover-maps&quot;&gt;Primitives as building blocks for constructing land cover maps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Saah, David; Tennesona, Karis; Poortinga, Ate; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF APPLIED EARTH OBSERVATION AND GEOINFORMATION  Volume: 85   Pages: 1979-1979   Published: MAR 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Land cover maps play an integral role in environmental management. However, countries and institutes encounter many challenges with producing timely, efficient, and temporally harmonized updates to their land cover maps. To address these issues we present a modular Regional Land Cover Monitoring System (RLCMS) architecture that is easily customized to create land cover products using primitive map layers. Primitive map layers are a suite of biophysical and end member maps, with land cover primitives representing the raw information needed to make decisions in a dichotomous key for land cover classification. We present best practices to create and assemble primitives from optical satellite using computing technologies, decision tree logic and Monte Carlo simulations to integrate their uncertainties. The concept is presented in the context of a regional land cover map based on a shared regional typology with 18 land cover classes agreed on by stakeholders from Cambodia, Laos PDR, Myanmar, Thailand, and Vietnam. We created annual map and uncertainty layers for the period 2000-2017. We found an overall accuracy of 94% when taking uncertainties into account. RLCMS produces consistent time series products using free long term historical Landsat and MODIS data. The customizable architecture can include a variety of sensors and machine learning algorithms to create primitives and the best suited smoothing can be applied on a primitive level. The system is transferable to all regions around the globe because of its use of publicly available global data (Landsat and MODIS) and easily adaptable architecture that allows for the incorporation of a customizable assembly logic to map different land cover typologies based on the user’s landscape monitoring objectives&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-east-african-contribution-to-the-formalisation-of-the-soil-catena-concept&quot;&gt;The East African contribution to the formalisation of the soil catena concept&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Borden, R. Wayne; Baillie, Ian C.; Hallett, Stephen H.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CATENA  Volume: 185   Pages: 4291-4291   Published: FEB 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of the soil catena was first explicitly formalised by Geoffrey Milne and his colleagues in East Africa in the 1930s. It has been widely adopted and applied in soil survey and continues to be of great value in soil and other field sciences The concept characterises widespread patterns in which distinctive associations of soils and vegetation are consistently located in specific slope positions. The formalisation of the concept in an area well outside the mainstream of soil research appears to have been due to the combination of highly visible recurrent patterns of red slope soils overlooking dark valley clays in East Africa’s extensive savannahs, together with a group of receptive and collaborative soil scientists working in a supportive institutional environment. The concept is often attributed to Geoffrey Milne, the group’s coordinator, but we show that several colleagues and friends also contributed. We summarise some of the early soil catenas characterised by Milne and his colleagues in Uganda, Kenya and Tanganyika Territory (now Tanzania). Even at the beginning, it was appreciated that the catena was not universally applicable and that heterogeneity of parent materials can override catenary patterns. The catena was quickly and widely adopted in soil science, and this diffusion has led to some broadening of the definition, and several types of soil pattern are now designated as catenas. The concept has also spread beyond soil science and is used by ecologists, geomorphologists and hydrologists amongst others. It continues to be a paradigm of great explicative and educational power in soil science and ecology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-note-on-knowledge-discovery-and-machine-learning-in-digital-soil-mapping&quot;&gt;A note on knowledge discovery and machine learning in digital soil mapping&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Wadoux, Alexandre M. J-C; Samuel-Rosa, Alessandro; Poggio, Laura; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF SOIL SCIENCE  Pages: NIL_1-NIL_4   Published: DEC 19 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In digital soil mapping, machine learning (ML) techniques are being used to infer a relationship between a soil property and the covariates. The information derived from this process is often translated into pedological knowledge. This mechanism is referred to as knowledge discovery. This study shows that knowledge discovery based on ML must be treated with caution. We show how pseudo-covariates can be used to accurately predict soil organic carbon in a hypothetical case study. We demonstrate that ML methods can find relevant patterns even when the covariates are meaningless and not related to soil-forming factors and processes. We argue that pattern recognition for prediction should not be equated with knowledge discovery. Knowledge discovery requires more than the recognition of patterns and successful prediction. It requires the pre-selection and preprocessing of pedologically relevant environmental covariates and the posterior interpretation and evaluation of the recognized patterns. We argue that important ML covariates could serve the purpose of providing elements to postulate hypotheses about soil processes that, once validated through experiments, could result in new pedological knowledge. Highlights
We discuss the rationale of knowledge discovery based on the most important machine learning covariates We use pseudo-covariates to predict topsoil organic carbon with random forest Soil organic carbon was accurately predicted in a hypothetical case study Pattern recognition by random forest should not be equated to knowledge discovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nitrogen-mineralisation-in-sugarcane-soils-in-queensland-australia-i-evaluation-of-soil-tests-for-predicting-nitrogen-mineralisation&quot;&gt;Nitrogen mineralisation in sugarcane soils in Queensland, Australia: I. evaluation of soil tests for predicting nitrogen mineralisation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Allen, D. E.; Bloesch, P. M.; Orton, T. G.; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOIL RESEARCH  Volume: 57   Issue: 7   Pages: 738-754   Published: 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We explored soil properties as indices of mineralisable nitrogen (N) in sugarcane soils and whether we could increase the accuracy of predicting N mineralisation during laboratory incubations. Utilising historical data in combination with samples collected during 2016, we: (i) measured mineralised N over the course of short-term (14 days) and long-term (301 days) laboratory incubations; (ii) compared models representing mineralisation; then (iii) related model parameters to measured soil properties. We found measures representing the labile organic N pool (Hydrolysable NaOH organic N; amino sugar Illinois soil N test) best related to short-term mineralised N (R-2 of 0.50-0.57, P &amp;lt; 0.001), while measures of CO2 production (3, 7, 10 and 14 days) best related to longer-term mineralised N (R-2 of 0.75-0.84, P &amp;lt; 0.001). Indices were brought together to model the active and slow pools of a two-pool mineralisation model in the statistical framework of a mixed-effects model. Of the models that relied on measurement of one soil property, cumulative CO2 production (7 days) performed the best when considering all soil types; in a cross-validation test, this model gave an external R-2 of 0.77 for prediction of the 301-day mineralised N. Since the mixed-effects model accounts for the various sources of uncertainty, we suggest this approach as a framework for prediction of in-field available N, with further measurement of long-term mineralised N in other soils to strengthen predictive certainty of these soil indices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;predicting-soil-carbon-saturation-deficit-and-related-properties-of-new-zealand-soils-using-infrared-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Predicting soil carbon saturation deficit and related properties of New Zealand soils using infrared spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Baldock, J. A.; McNally, S. R.; Beare, M. H.; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOIL RESEARCH  Volume: 57   Issue: 8   Pages: 835-844   Published: 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversion of soils supporting native vegetation to agricultural production has led to a loss of soil carbon stocks. Replacing a portion of the lost stocks will sequester atmospheric carbon with the concurrent benefit of enhancing soil sustainability. The ability of the fine fraction of soils (&amp;lt;= 50-mu m fraction) to adsorb organic carbon (OC) is considered a key mechanism capable of stabilising soil OC against loss. The difference between the current and maximum concentrations of OC in the soil fine fraction (FFC) has been termed the ‘saturation deficit’ (SatDef) and used to define the potential for a soil to sequester carbon. For New Zealand surface 0-15 cm soil layers, pedotransfer functions have been derived to quantify the soil carbon SatDef. The ability of combining infrared spectroscopy (IR) with partial least squares regression (PLSR) to derive predictive algorithms for soil properties included in these pedotransfer functions, the capacity of the soil fine fraction to stabilise carbon and the SatDef of the soil fine fraction were assessed in this study. A total of 168 air-dried and finely ground New Zealand surface soils representative of the major soil orders used for agricultural production were included. Principal components analysis of IR spectra showed a grouping by soil order that was related to mineralogy. Predictive IR/PLSR algorithms were derived for specific surface area, pyrophosphate-extractable aluminium, the FFC content, the 90th quantile regression of FFC and the SatDef of the fine fraction (R-2 values &amp;gt;= 0.85; ratio of performance to interquartile range values &amp;gt;= 2.9). The results indicate that IR/PLSR provides a rapid and cost-effective mechanism for deriving information related to the amount of FFC in soils and the SatDef of the fine fraction. The IR/PLSR approach could be used to define the potential of soils to sequester carbon and identify the soil types to target for carbon sequestration technologies. The approach would also generate valuable data for soil carbon in national inventories or national soil condition monitoring programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mapping-change-in-key-soil-properties-due-to-climate-change-over-south-eastern-australia-vol-57-pg-467-2019&quot;&gt;Mapping change in key soil properties due to climate change over south-eastern Australia (vol 57, pg 467, 2019)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Gray, Jonathan M.; Bishop, Thomas F. A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOIL RESEARCH  Volume: 57   Issue: 7   Pages: 805-+   Published: 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Climate change will lead to altered soil conditions that will impact on plant growth in both agricultural and native ecosystems. Additionally, changes in soil carbon storage will influence carbon accounting schemes that may play a role in climate change mitigation programs. We applied a digital soil mapping approach to examine and map (at 100-m resolution) potential changes in three important soil properties - soil organic carbon (SOC), pH and sum-of-bases (common macro-nutrients) - resulting from projected climate change over south-eastern Australia until similar to 2070. Four global climate models were downscaled with three regional models to give 12 climate models, which were used to derive changes for the three properties across the province, at 0-30 and 30-100 cm depth intervals. The SOC stocks were projected to decline over the province, while pH and sum-of-bases were projected to increase; however, the extent of change varied throughout the province and with different climate models. The average changes primarily reflected the complex interplay of changing temperatures and rainfall throughout the province. The changes were also influenced by the operating environmental conditions, with a uniform pattern of change particularly demonstrated for SOC over 36 combinations of current climate, parent material and land use. For example, the mean decline of SOC predicted for the upper depth interval was 15.6 Mg ha(-1) for wet-mafic-native vegetation regimes but only 3.1 Mg ha(-1) for dry-highly siliceous-cropping regimes. The predicted changes reflected only those attributable to the projected climate change and did not consider the influence of ongoing and changing land management practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;modeling-the-co-evolution-of-natural-economic-and-governance-subsystems-in-integrated-agri-ecological-systems-perspectives-and-challenges&quot;&gt;Modeling the co-evolution of natural, economic and governance subsystems in integrated agri-ecological systems: Perspectives and challenges&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Gerling, C.; Waetzold, F.; Theesfeld, I; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ECOLOGICAL COMPLEXITY  Volume: 40   Pages: 792-792   Part: A   Published: DEC 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current agri-ecological systems face the twin challenge of providing sufficient food for a growing global population and of mitigating severe negative environmental impacts from agricultural land-use in terms of biodiversity loss, greenhouse gas emissions, nutrient run-off, soil degradation, and water pollution. Disciplinary research provides detailed answers to specific questions related to the challenges faced by agri-ecological systems. However, it fails to consider the complex interrelationships and dynamics of the different economic, natural and governance subsystems of which agri-ecological systems consist and that need to be considered to address these challenges. In principle, it is possible to develop models that integrate knowledge from the fields of ecology, economics and governance, and consider dynamic system features such as feedbacks between subsystems as well as tipping points. In this viewpoint article, we scrutinize selected integrated agri-ecological system models and find that only very few models address the challenges mentioned above. We suggest further research in three areas: (I) in-depth integration of the governance subsystem in integrated models, (II) more comprehensive inclusion of tipping points in integrated models, and (III) integration of cascading effects where one system change stimulates another system change. Finally, we briefly discuss the challenges of complex integrated modeling in relation to computational power and the necessity to gather expertise from different disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;utilising-geochemical-data-for-the-identification-and-characterisation-of-mineral-exploration-sample-media-within-cover-sequence-materials&quot;&gt;Utilising geochemical data for the identification and characterisation of mineral exploration sample media within cover sequence materials&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Tiddy, C. J.; Hill, S. M.; Giles, D.; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AUSTRALIAN JOURNAL OF EARTH SCIENCES  Pages: NIL_1-NIL_29   Published: NOV 18 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A first pass workflow for placing cover sequence materials into four broad lithological groups using A-CNK-FM (Al2O3-CaO + Na2O + K2O-Fe2O3+MgO) and A-CN-K (Al2O3-CaO + Na2O-K2O) ternary diagrams in conjunction with the SiO2 vs Al2O3, Fe2O3 and CaO plus the Ca versus Sr XY diagrams has been derived from lithological logging and laboratory whole-rock geochemistry of 2346 samples. These lithological groups include siliciclastics (quartz sands and clays), weathered material, carbonate lithologies (marine limestone, pedogenic carbonate and compositions intermediate between the two end members) and ferruginous lithologies (including ferricrete and ferruginous sediments). Depositional, weathering and groundwater processes influence sample geochemistry during or after the formation of the material and will influence where the sample will plot on the geochemical diagrams used in this study. Geochemical data for discrete lithologies targeted during sampling (e.g. carbonate lithologies) clusters on diagrams used in the geochemical workflow, whereas data from targeted stratigraphic horizons (e.g. basement-cover interface) are more variable. The ability to characterise rock types that are texturally defined using the geochemical workflow is limited. For instance, the geochemistry of diamictite/conglomerate samples is dependent on the matrix versus clast content and composition as well as the source rock and catchment area. This workflow has the potential to be applied in a mineral exploration environment for rapid interpretation of real-time geochemical (e.g. portable XRF) data to gain an understanding of background geochemistry and geochemical signatures that may be related to underlying mineralisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;estimating-atterberg-limits-of-fine-grained-soils-by-visible-near-infrared-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Estimating Atterberg Limits of Fine-Grained Soils by Visible-Near-Infrared Spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Rehman, Hafeez Ur; Knadel, Maria; Kayabali, Kamil; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VADOSE ZONE JOURNAL  Volume: 18   Issue: 1   Pages: 90039-90039   Published: NOV 7 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Atterberg limits (shrinkage limit [SL], plastic limit [PL], and liquid limit [LL]) describe the physico-mechanical behavior of soils and thus are crucial for civil and agricultural applications. Conventional laboratory methods for measurement of these limits are tedious and costly for a large number of samples. Our objective was to develop visible-near-infrared spectroscopy (Vis-NIRS, from 400-2500 nm) based reliable models to estimate the Atterberg limits. Two conventional methods for each Atterberg limit were used to generate the reference data: paraffin wax and Hg methods for SL; rolling and motorized devices for PL; and Casagrande cup and drop-cone penetrometer methods for LL. Calibration models were built on 80% of the data using partial least squares regression and validated with the remaining 20% of the dataset. The Vis-NIRS independent validation of LL showed very good estimation with standardized RMSE (SRMSE = RMSE/Range) of 0.16 and 0.15, respectively, for LLdrop-cone and LLCasagrande methods. Similarly for PL, the Vis-NIRS estimation accuracy was quite good with SRMSE values of 0.18 and 0.22, respectively, for PLmotorized and PLrolling. Reasonably good estimation was obtained for the SLparaffin and SLHg with SRMSE of 0.25 for both methods. The results suggest that the Vis-NIRS calibration models and the accuracy following validation were similar for the pair of methods used for the SL, PL, and LL. Finally, analyses of the model regression coefficients revealed that the important wavelengths to estimate the SL, PL, and LL in the Vis-NIR regions were present across the entire Vis-NIR spectrum and were strongly related to clay type and content.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/01/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on January 27, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/01/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/01/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-01-26T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-01-26T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-1&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Global fire season severity analysis and forecasting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A generalizable index of soil development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A method for estimating soil water characteristic curve with limited experimental data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monitoring agricultural drought in Australia using MTSAT-2 land surface temperature retrievals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No pixel left behind: Toward integrating Earth Observations for agriculture into the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals framework&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remote sensing for agricultural applications: A meta-review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new drone-borne GPR for soil moisture mapping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil alters seedling establishment responses to climate (no abstract)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multiscale Data Fusion for Surface Soil Moisture Estimation: A Spatial Hierarchical Approach&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil carbon storage informed by particulate and mineral-associated organic matter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Which practices co-deliver food security, climate change mitigation and adaptation, and combat land degradation and desertification?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rethinking sources of nitrogen to cereal crops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;global-fire-season-severity-analysis-and-forecasting&quot;&gt;Global fire season severity analysis and forecasting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Ferreira, LN (Ferreira, Leonardo N.)[ 1 ] ; Vega-Oliveros, DA (Vega-Oliveros, Didier A.)[ 2,3 ] ; Zhao, L (Zhao, Liang)[ 3 ] ; Cardoso, MF (Cardoso, Manoel F.)[ 4 ] ; Macau, EEN (Macau, Elbert E. N.)[ 1,5 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COMPUTERS &amp;amp; GEOSCIENCES&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 134 Pages: 4339-4339
Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Fire activity has a huge impact on human lives. Different models have been proposed to predict fire activity, which can be classified into global and regional ones. Global fire models focus on longer timescale simulations and can be very complex. Regional fire models concentrate on seasonal forecasting but usually require inputs that are not available in many places. Motivated by the possibility of having a simple, fast, and general model, we propose a seasonal fire prediction methodology based on time series forecasting methods. It consists of dividing the studied area into grid cells and extracting time series of fire counts to fit the forecasting models. We apply these models to estimate the fire season severity (FSS) from each cell, here defined as the sum of the fire counts detected in a season. Experimental results using a global fire detection data set show that the proposed approach can predict FSS with a relatively low error in many regions. The proposed approach is reasonably fast and can be applied on a global scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-generalizable-index-of-soil-development&quot;&gt;A generalizable index of soil development&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Koop, Aaron N.; Hirmas, Daniel R.; Sullivan, Pamela L.; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GEODERMA  Volume: 360   Pages: 13898-13898   Published: FEB 15 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The growing influence of climatic and land-use pressures on soils across broad geographic extents have revealed a need for generalizable indices of soil development applicable at continental scales. In this study, we present generalizable horizon and profile development indices (HDIs and PDIs, respectively) based primarily on relative horizon properties instead of parent material information and provide an evaluation of these indices at a continental scale. The indices developed in this work combine knowledge of pedogenic processes with selected properties from a large database of predominantly US soils to yield relevant soil morphological, physical, and chemical information on 57,171 horizons arising from 8980 pedons. We selected four properties from which the generalizable HDI and PDI calculations were based: particle size, calcium carbonate equivalent (CCE), color, and clay films. Modified z-scores were used to assess relative changes between either eluvial and illuvial horizons for particle size and CCE or surface and subsurface horizons for color. These values were then normalized using maximum and minimum values observed in the dataset. Normalized clay film scores were calculated using percent cover along with ordinal values assigned to distinctness categories described in the field. The index values from HDI compared well to both diagnostic horizon designations and chemical index of alteration and PDI values matched the sequence of taxonomic soil orders that represent a development gradient. In addition, we observed a correspondence between calculated PDIs and a clay mineralogy index representing weathering intensity. Relationships between these generalizable indices, evaluation metrics, and climate (i.e., MAP) explored in this work opens the door to numerous broad-scale applications in the future such as pedogenic modeling, identification of soil anomalies, and estimation of surface soil ages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-method-for-estimating-soil-water-characteristic-curve-with-limited-experimental-data&quot;&gt;A method for estimating soil water characteristic curve with limited experimental data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Ren, Xingwei; Kang, Jianyu; Ren, Junjie; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GEODERMA  Volume: 360   Pages: 14013-14013   Published: FEB 15 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the difficulty to reach high suction at the residual state of unsaturated soils, the saturation-suction experimental data for soil water characteristic curve (SWCC) is often limited and incomplete, which will lead to unreliable estimation of mechanical and hydraulic conductivity of unsaturated soils. However, no study has been published on how to obtain a reliable SWCC for unsaturated soils with limited experimental data. In response to this situation, an innovative method was proposed based on the analysis of shape characteristics of SWCC with three identified critical points in it. 78 experimental datasets from existing literature were compiled to identify the mathematical relationship among three critical points in the SWCC. The proposed method was evaluated by experimental datasets from this study and existing literature and proved to have a satisfying performance in predicting a complete SWCC for a wide range of soils, from the coarse-grained to the fine-grained. Overall, the research results present an effective and capable method for estimating a more reliable SWCC when experimental data is limited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;monitoring-agricultural-drought-in-australia-using-mtsat-2-land-surface-temperature-retrievals&quot;&gt;Monitoring agricultural drought in Australia using MTSAT-2 land surface temperature retrievals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Hu, Tian; Renzullo, Luigi J.; van Dijk, Albert I. J. M.; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT  Volume: 236   Pages: 11419-11419   Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drought indices based on thermal remote sensing have been developed and have merit for effective early warning of agricultural droughts, but approaches so far are relatively complex or sensitive to land surface temperature (LST) estimation uncertainties. Here, we propose the temperature rise index (TRI), a drought index that is comparatively robust and easy to calculate, as the anomaly of the intrinsic morning rise of LST. The underlying principle is that the rate of LST rise between 1.5 and 3.5 h after the sunrise is approximately linear and occurs more rapidly under dry conditions than under wet conditions over vegetated surfaces as a consequence of stomatal control. TRI during the growing seasons of 2010-2014 was calculated over the Australian wheatbelt from LST retrievals from the geostationary Multifunction Transport Satellite-2 (MTSAT-2) instrument. The calculated TRI was compared with indices based on precipitation integrated over 1-, 3- and 6-month time scales, on Soil Moisture and Ocean Salinity (SMOS) soil moisture derived from passive microwave remote sensing, and on vegetation condition (normalized difference vegetation index, NDVI) derived from optical remote sensing. The various indices were also compared to annual wheat yield over large areas. The correlation coefficient between TRI and precipitation anomaly that serves as an operational drought index in Australia was above 0.6 in general with 3-month integrative time scale for precipitation. TRI produced spatiotemporal dryness patterns that were very similar to those in soil moisture, but with more detail due to its finer resolution. A time lag of &amp;gt; 1 month was found between TRI and observed vegetation condition, supporting the use of TRI in early warning. Among the compared drought indices, TRI explained the largest fraction (35%) of wheat yield variations. TRI correlations with wheat yields peaked higher and earlier by almost one month in comparison to other indices. We conclude that the thermal drought index proposed here shows considerable potential for use in drought early warning as an effective complement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;no-pixel-left-behind-toward-integrating-earth-observations-for-agriculture-into-the-united-nations-sustainable-development-goals-framework&quot;&gt;No pixel left behind: Toward integrating Earth Observations for agriculture into the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals framework&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Whitcraft, Alyssa K.; Becker-Reshef, Inbal; Justice, Christopher O.; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT  Volume: 235   Pages: 11470-11470   Published: DEC 15 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remotely sensed Earth observations (EO) have their history firmly rooted in agricultural monitoring, and more recently with applications in food production, food security, and sustainable agriculture. Still, after more than 45 years of observing the Earth’s land surface, usage of EO data by operational monitoring entities concerned with global agriculture is uneven. One reason for this is a gap in continuous communication and collaboration between those who undertake research and development of methods for cropland assessment and monitoring, and those who have the mandate to report on agricultural indicators at a national, regional, and global scales. The recent international policy focus on the United Nations 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development via its Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) is giving increased attention to measurements and indicators for monitoring and measuring progress for meeting these goals. Satellite EO provide a source of measurements beyond traditional census data collection and statistical reporting. In this vein, this overview paper describes the current and potential uses of EO data and tools that can support the SDGs, particularly highlighting the activities of the Group on Earth Observations Global Agricultural Monitoring (GEOGLAM) Initiative. GEOGLAM is composed of agricultural ministries, intergovernmental organizations, research entities, universities, space agencies, and members of industry concerned with agricultural monitoring. This GEOGLAM community has a broad portfolio of activities which provide information on the state and changes in agricultural production and land use that can be considered as contributions to both supporting the attainment of several of the 17 SDGs and many of their 169 Targets, as well as monitoring their achievement via the Global Indicator Framework. GEOGLAM contributes in particular to Goal 2: Zero Hunger, but also has less immediately apparent contributions in the realms of water (Goal 6), responsible consumption and production (Goal 12), climate action (Goal 13), life on land (Goal 15), and global partnerships for sustainable development (Goal 17). We further characterize the applicability and use of EO data products and tools as they correspond with the United Nations Interagency Expert Group on Sustainable Development Goals (IAEG-SDGs) Global Indicator Framework. This inventory will be complemented by a discussion of the intersection of other policy mandates with the SDGs in the agriculture and food security contexts, and will conclude with a discussion of approaches to improving awareness of EO value and bridging the gap between policy and EO communities, to the societal benefit of all with no one left behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;remote-sensing-for-agricultural-applications-a-meta-review&quot;&gt;Remote sensing for agricultural applications: A meta-review&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Weiss, M.; Jacob, F.; Duveiller, G.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT  Volume: 236   Pages: 11402-11402   Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agriculture provides humanity with food, fibers, fuel, and raw materials that are paramount for human livelihood. Today, this role must be satisfied within a context of environmental sustainability and climate change, combined with an unprecedented and still-expanding human population size, while maintaining the viability of agricultural activities to ensure both subsistence and livelihoods. Remote sensing has the capacity to assist the adaptive evolution of agricultural practices in order to face this major challenge, by providing repetitive information on crop status throughout the season at different scales and for different actors. We start this review by making an overview of the current remote sensing techniques relevant for the agricultural context. We present the agronomical variables and plant traits that can be estimated by remote sensing, and we describe the empirical and deterministic approaches to retrieve them. A second part of this review illustrates recent research developments that permit to strengthen applicative capabilities in remote sensing according to specific requirements for different types of stakeholders. Such agricultural applications include crop breeding, agricultural land use monitoring, crop yield forecasting, as well as ecosystem services in relation to soil and water resources or biodiversity loss. Finally, we provide a synthesis of the emerging opportunities that should strengthen the role of remote sensing in providing operational, efficient and long-term services for agricultural applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-new-drone-borne-gpr-for-soil-moisture-mapping&quot;&gt;A new drone-borne GPR for soil moisture mapping&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Wu, Kaijun; Rodriguez, Gabriela Arambulo; Zajc, Marjana; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT  Volume: 235   Pages: 11456-11456   Published: DEC 15 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this study, we set up a new drone-borne ground-penetrating radar (GPR) for soil moisture mapping. The whole radar system weighs 1.5 kg and consists of a handheld vector network analyzer (VNA) working as frequency domain radar, a lightweight hybrid horn-dipole antenna covering a wide frequency range (250-2800 MHz), a GPS for positioning, a microcomputer with the controlling application, and a smartphone for remote control. Soil moisture is derived from the radar data using full-wave inverse modeling based on the radar equation of Lambot et al. and multilayered media Green’s functions. The inversion is performed in the time domain and focuses on the surface reflection. The antenna-drone system is characterized by global reflection and transmission functions which are determined through a calibration procedure. We performed drone-GPR measurements over three different agricultural fields in the loess belt region of Belgium. In this study, we used the 500-700 MHz range to avoid soil surface roughness effects and to focus on the top 10-20 cm of the soil. These fields present a range of landform conditions leading to specific soil moisture distributions. The soil moisture maps were constructed from the local measurements using kriging. The obtained soil moisture maps are in good agreement with the topographical conditions of the fields and aerial orthophotography observations. These results demonstrated the potential and benefits of drone-GPR for fast, high-resolution mapping of soil moisture at the field scale, and to support, e.g., precision agriculture and environmental monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;multiscale-data-fusion-for-surface-soil-moisture-estimation-a-spatial-hierarchical-approach&quot;&gt;Multiscale Data Fusion for Surface Soil Moisture Estimation: A Spatial Hierarchical Approach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Kathuria, Dhruva; Mohanty, Binayak P.; Katzfuss, Matthias&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WATER RESOURCES RESEARCH  Pages: NIL_1-NIL_23   Published: DEC 10 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surface soil moisture (SSM) has been identified as a key climate variable governing hydrologic and atmospheric processes across multiple spatial scales at local, regional, and global levels. The global burgeoning of SSM datasets in the past decade holds a significant potential in improving our understanding of multiscale SSM dynamics. The primary issues that hinder the fusion of SSM data from disparate instruments are (1) different spatial resolutions of the data instruments, (2) inherent spatial variability in SSM caused due to atmospheric and land surface controls, and (3) measurement errors caused due to imperfect retrievals of instruments. We present a data fusion scheme which takes all the above three factors into account using a Bayesian spatial hierarchical model (SHM), combining a geostatistical approach with a hierarchical model. The applicability of the fusion scheme is demonstrated by fusing point, airborne, and satellite data for a watershed exhibiting high spatial variability in Manitoba, Canada. We demonstrate that the proposed data fusion scheme is adept at assimilating and predicting SSM distribution across all three scales while accounting for potential measurement errors caused due to imperfect retrievals. Further validation of the algorithm is required in different hydroclimates and surface heterogeneity as well as for other data platforms for wider applicability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-carbon-storage-informed-by-particulate-and-mineral-associated-organic-matter&quot;&gt;Soil carbon storage informed by particulate and mineral-associated organic matter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Cotrufo, M. Francesca; Ranalli, Maria Giovanna; Haddix, Michelle L.; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NATURE GEOSCIENCE  Volume: 12   Issue: 12   Pages: 989-+   Published: DEC 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Effective land-based solutions to climate change mitigation require actions that maximize soil carbon storage without generating surplus nitrogen. Land management for carbon sequestration is most often informed by bulk soil carbon inventories, without considering the form in which carbon is stored, its capacity, persistency and nitrogen demand. Here, we present coupling of European-wide databases with soil organic matter physical fractionation to determine continental-scale forest and grassland topsoil carbon and nitrogen stocks and their distribution between mineral-associated and particulate organic matter pools. Grasslands and arbuscular mycorrhizal forests store more soil carbon in mineral-associated organic carbon, which is more persistent but has a higher nitrogen demand and saturates. Ectomycorrhizal forests store more carbon in particulate organic matter, which is more vulnerable to disturbance but has a lower nitrogen demand and can potentially accumulate indefinitely. The share of carbon between mineral-associated and particulate organic matter and the ratio between carbon and nitrogen affect soil carbon stocks and mediate the effects of other variables on soil carbon stocks. Understanding the physical distribution of organic matter in pools of mineral-associated versus particulate organic matter can inform land management for nitrogen-efficient carbon sequestration, which should be driven by the inherent soil carbon capacity and nitrogen availability in ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;which-practices-co-deliver-food-security-climate-change-mitigation-and-adaptation-and-combat-land-degradation-and-desertification&quot;&gt;Which practices co-deliver food security, climate change mitigation and adaptation, and combat land degradation and desertification?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Smith, Pete; Calvin, Katherine; Nkem, Johnson; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY  Pages: NIL_1-NIL_44   Published: DEC 14 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a clear need for transformative change in the land management and food production sectors to address the global land challenges of climate change mitigation, climate change adaptation, combatting land degradation and desertification, and delivering food security (referred to hereafter as “land challenges”). We assess the potential for 40 practices to address these land challenges and find that: Nine options deliver medium to large benefits for all four land challenges. A further two options have no global estimates for adaptation, but have medium to large benefits for all other land challenges. Five options have large mitigation potential (&amp;gt;3 Gt CO(2)eq/year) without adverse impacts on the other land challenges. Five options have moderate mitigation potential, with no adverse impacts on the other land challenges. Sixteen practices have large adaptation potential (&amp;gt;25 million people benefit), without adverse side effects on other land challenges. Most practices can be applied without competing for available land. However, seven options could result in competition for land. A large number of practices do not require dedicated land, including several land management options, all value chain options, and all risk management options. Four options could greatly increase competition for land if applied at a large scale, though the impact is scale and context specific, highlighting the need for safeguards to ensure that expansion of land for mitigation does not impact natural systems and food security. A number of practices, such as increased food productivity, dietary change and reduced food loss and waste, can reduce demand for land conversion, thereby potentially freeing-up land and creating opportunities for enhanced implementation of other practices, making them important components of portfolios of practices to address the combined land challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rethinking-sources-of-nitrogen-to-cereal-crops&quot;&gt;Rethinking sources of nitrogen to cereal crops&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Yan, Ming; Pan, Genxing; Lavallee, Jocelyn M.; et al.
GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY  Pages: NIL_1-NIL_9   Published: DEC 2 2019
Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Understanding how to manage N inputs to identify the practices that maximize N recovery has been an organizing principle of agronomic research. Because growth in N fertilizer inputs is expected to continue in an ongoing effort to boost crop production over coming decades, understanding how to efficiently manage recovery of fertilizer N will be important going forward. Yet synthesis of published data that has traced the fate of N-15-labeled fertilizer shows that less than half of the N taken up by crops is derived from current-year N fertilizer. The source of the majority of N in crops is something other than current-year fertilizer and the sources are not really known. This is true for maize (only 41% of N in crops was from current-year N fertilizer), rice (32%), and small grains (37%). Recovery of organic fertilizer N (manure, green manure, compost, etc.) in crops is low (27%), though N recovery in subsequent years (10%) was greater than that for mineral fertilizers. Thus, while research on efficiency of N fertilizer use through improved rate, type, location, and timing is important, this research fails to directly address management of the majority of the N supplied to crops. It seems likely that the majority of non-fertilizer N found in crops comes from turnover of soil and crop residue N. We encourage the research community to revisit the mental model that fertilizer is a replacement for N supply from turnover of soil organic N (SON) and consider a model in which N fertilizer augments ongoing SON turnover and makes an important longer term contribution to SON maintenance and turnover. Research focused on the efficient recovery of N current-year fertilizer inputs neglects this potential role for building soil N and managing soil N turnover, which seems likely to be the most important source of crop N.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/01/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on January 26, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2019/12/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2019/12/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2019-12-11T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2019-12-11T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2019-20&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2019 #20&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Needle in a haystack: Mapping rare and infrequent crops using satellite imagery and data balancing methods&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Generation of spatially complete and daily continuous surface soil moisture Chock forof high spatial resolution&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The SMAP and Copernicus Sentinel 1A/B microwave active-passive high resolution surface soil moisture product&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remote sensing of the terrestrial carbon cycle: A review of advances over 50 years&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interannual variation of terrestrial carbon cycle: Issues and perspectives&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;External shocks, agent interactions, and endogenous feedbacks - Investigating system resilience with a stylized land use model&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exploring resilience with agent-based models: State of the art, knowledge gaps and recommendations for coping with multidimensionality&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;State factor network analysis of ecosystem response to climate change&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil organic matter is stabilized by organo-mineral associations through two key processes: The role of the carbon to nitrogen ratio&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prediction of phosphorus sorption indices and isotherm parameters in agricultural soils using mid-infrared spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;needle-in-a-haystack-mapping-rare-and-infrequent-crops-using-satellite-imagery-and-data-balancing-methods&quot;&gt;Needle in a haystack: Mapping rare and infrequent crops using satellite imagery and data balancing methods&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Waldner, F (Waldner, Francois)[ 1 ] ; Chen, Y (Chen, Yang)[ 2 ] ; Lawes, R (Lawes, Roger)[ 3 ] ; Hochman, Z (Hochman, Zvi)[ 1 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 233 Pages: 11375-11375
Published: NOV 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Most cropping systems around the world are organised around few dominant crops and a larger number of less frequent crops. While rare and infrequent crops occupy a small share of the cropped area, they produce ecological benefits on farmland, contribute to sustainability and help provide food and nutritional security. However, data about their location and extent derived from satellite imagery generally lack accuracy, largely owing to the class imbalance problem. Class imbalance occurs when only few instances of some classes are available for training classifiers, and leads to large error rates of the infrequent classes. In this study, we assessed the magnitude of the class imbalance problem in crop classification and evaluated balancing methods to combat it by creating synthetic minority observations or by removing majority observations. To that aim, we generated 18 unbalanced data sets from Sentinel-2 time series and crop type observations in Victoria, Australia. These data sets covered a wide range of complexity, number of classes, number of samples per class and spectral separability which enabled us to gather evidence about the benefits and drawbacks of balancing methods in various settings. Classification accuracy was assessed with two metrics: the Overall Accuracy (OA), which gives more weight to majority classes, and the G-Mean accuracy (GM), which is more sensitive to minority classes. Results showed that class imbalance explained near 40% of the accuracy variability. We found that balancing methods boosted GM by 0.01-0.54 but no single best solution emerged. The price for increasing the accuracy of minority classes was a drop in OA of a magnitude that was problem- and method-specific. We thus applied an algorithm selection method called the F-race to identify optimal balancing methods in a computationally economic fashion. Optimal balancing methods lead to maximum gain in GM and minimum loss in OA. We demonstrated that this approach either successfully identified optimal balancing methods or ones that were not significantly sub-optimal, while reducing the computational cost by up to 60%. It can readily be incorporated to operational crop classification systems with little disruption to the existing processing chains. This contribution paves the way for achieving a more comprehensive and detailed view of crop distribution and cropping sequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;generation-of-spatially-complete-and-daily-continuous-surface-soil-moisture-chock-forof-high-spatial-resolution&quot;&gt;Generation of spatially complete and daily continuous surface soil moisture Chock forof high spatial resolution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Long, D (Long, Di)[ 1 ] ; Bai, LL (Bai, Liangliang)[ 1 ] ; Yan, L (Yan, La)[ 1 ] ; Zhang, CJ (Zhang, Caijin)[ 1 ] ; Yang, WT (Yang, Wenting)[ 1 ] ; Lei, HM (Lei, Huimin)[ 1 ] ; Quan, JL (Quan, Jinling)[ 2 ] ; Meng, XY (Meng, Xianyong)[ 3 ] ; Shi, CX (Shi, Chunxiang)[ 4 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View Web of Science ResearcherID and ORCID
REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 233 Pages: 11364-11364
Published: NOV 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Surface soil moisture (SSM), as a vital variable for water and heat exchanges between the land surface and the atmosphere, is essential for agricultural production and drought monitoring, and serves as an important boundary condition for atmospheric models. The spatial resolution of soil moisture products from microwave remote sensing is relatively coarse (e.g., similar to 40 km x 40 km), whereas SSM of higher spatiotemporal resolutions (e.g., 1 km x 1 km and daily continuous) is more useful in water resources management. In this study, first, to improve the spatiotemporal completeness of SSM estimates, we downscaled land surface temperature (LST) output from the China Meteorological Administration Land Data Assimilation System (CLDAS, 0.0625 degrees x 0.0625 degrees) using a data fusion approach and MODIS LST acquired on clear-sky days to generate spatially complete and temporally continuous LST maps across the North China Plain. Second, spatially complete and daily continuous 1 km x 1 km SSM was generated based on random forest models combined with quality LST maps, normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI), surface albedo, precipitation, soil texture, SSM background fields from the European Space Agency Soil Moisture Climate Change Initiative (CCI, 0.25 degrees x 0.25 degrees) and CLDAS land surface model (LSM) SSM output (0.0625 degrees x 0.0625 degrees) to be downscaled, and in situ SSM measurements. Third, the importance of different input variables to the downscaled SSM was quantified. Compared with the original CCI and CLDAS SSM, both the accuracy and spatial resolution of the downscaled SSM were largely improved, in terms of a bias (root mean square error) of -0.001 cm(3)/cm(3) (0.041 cm(3)/cm(3)) and a correlation coefficient of 0.72. These results are generally comparable and even better than those in published studies, with our SSM maps featuring spatiotemporal completeness and relatively high spatial resolution. The downscaled SSM maps are valuable for monitoring agricultural drought and optimizing irrigation scheduling, bridging the gaps between microwave-based and LSM-based SSM estimates of coarse spatial resolution and thermal infrared-based LST at a 1 km x 1 km resolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-smap-and-copernicus-sentinel-1ab-microwave-active-passive-high-resolution-surface-soil-moisture-product&quot;&gt;The SMAP and Copernicus Sentinel 1A/B microwave active-passive high resolution surface soil moisture product&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Das, NN (Das, Narendra N.)[ 1 ] ; Entekhabi, D (Entekhabi, Dara)[ 2 ] ; Dunbar, RS (Dunbar, R. Scott)[ 1 ] ; Chaubell, MJ (Chaubell, Mario J.)[ 1 ] ; Colliander, A (Colliander, Andreas)[ 1 ] ; Yueh, S (Yueh, Simon)[ 1 ] ; Jagdhuber, T (Jagdhuber, Thomas)[ 3 ] ; Chen, F (Chen, Fan)[ 4 ] ; Crow, W (Crow, Wade)[ 5 ] ; O’Neill, PE (O’Neill, Peggy E.)[ 6 ] …More&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 233 Pages: 11380-11380
Published: NOV 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Soil Moisture Active Passive (SMAP) mission of NASA was launched in January 2015. Currently, SMAP has an L-band radiometer and a defunct L-band radar with a rotating 6-m mesh reflector antenna. On July 7th, 2015, the SMAP radar malfunctioned and became inoperable. Consequently, the production of high-resolution active-passive soil moisture product got hampered, and only similar to 2.5 months (April 15th, 2015 to July 7th, 2015) of data remain available. Therefore, during the SMAP post-radar phase, many ways were examined to restart the high-resolution soil moisture product generation of the SMAP mission. One of the feasible approaches was to substitute the SMAP radar with other available SAR data. Sentinel-1A/Sentinel-1B SAR data was found most suitable for combining with the SMAP radiometer data because of its nearly similar orbit configuration that allows overlapping of their swaths with a minimal time difference, a key feature/requirement for the SMAP active-passive algorithm. The Sentinel interferometric wide swath (IW) mode acquisition also provides the co-polarized and cross-polarized observations required for the SMAP active-passive algorithm. However, some differences do exist between the SMAP and Sentinel SAR data. They are mainly: 1) Sentinel has a C-band SAR whereas SMAP operates at L-band; 2) Sentinel has multiple incidence angles within its swath, and SMAP has one single incidence angle; and 3) Sentinel 1A/B Interferometric Wide (IW) swath width is similar to 250 km as compared to SMAP with 1000 km swath width. On any given day, the narrow swath width of the Sentinel observations significantly reduces the overlap spatial coverage between SMAP and Sentinel as compared to the original SMAP radar and radiometer swath coverage. Hence, the temporal resolution (revisit interval) suffers due to narrow overlapped swath width and degrades from 3 days to 12 days. One advantage of using very high-resolution resolution Sentinel-1A/Sentinel-1B data in the SMAP active-passive algorithm is the potential of obtaining the disaggregated brightness temperature and thus soil moisture at a much finer spatial resolution of 3 km and 1 km at global extent. The assessment of high-resolution product at 3 km and 1 km using the soil moisture calibration and validations sites shows reasonable accuracy of similar to 0.05 m(3)/m(3). The SMAP-Sentinel1 active-passive high-resolution product is now available to the public (new version released in October 2018) through NSIDC (NASA DAAC). The duration of this product is from April 2015 to current date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;remote-sensing-of-the-terrestrial-carbon-cycle-a-review-of-advances-over-50-years&quot;&gt;Remote sensing of the terrestrial carbon cycle: A review of advances over 50 years&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Xiao, JF (Xiao, Jingfeng)[ 1 ] ; Chevallier, F (Chevallier, Frederic)[ 2 ] ; Gomez, C (Gomez, Cecile)[ 3 ] ; Guanter, L (Guanter, Luis)[ 4 ] ; Hicke, JA (Hicke, Jeffrey A.)[ 5 ] ; Huete, AR (Huete, Alfredo R.)[ 6 ] ; Ichii, K (Ichii, Kazuhito)[ 7 ] ; Ni, WJ (Ni, Wenjian)[ 8 ] ; Pang, Y (Pang, Yong)[ 9 ] ; Rahman, AF (Rahman, Abdullah F.)[ 10 ] …More&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 233 Pages: 11383-11383
Published: NOV 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Review&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Quantifying ecosystem carbon fluxes and stocks is essential for better understanding the global carbon cycle and improving projections of the carbon-climate feedbacks. Remote sensing has played a vital role in this endeavor during the last five decades by quantifying carbon fluxes and stocks. The availability of satellite observations of the land surface since the 1970s, particularly the early 1980s, has made it feasible to quantify ecosystem carbon fluxes and stocks at regional to global scales. Here we provide a review of the advances in remote sensing of the terrestrial carbon cycle from the early 1970s to present. First, we present an overview of the terrestrial carbon cycle and remote sensing of carbon fluxes and stocks. Remote sensing data acquired in a broad wavelength range (visible, infrared, and microwave) of the electromagnetic spectrum have been used to estimate carbon fluxes and/or stocks. Second, we provide a historical overview of the key milestones in remote sensing of the terrestrial carbon cycle. Third, we review the platforms/sensors, methods, findings, and challenges in remote sensing of carbon fluxes. The remote sensing data and techniques used to quantify carbon fluxes include vegetation indices, light use efficiency models, terrestrial biosphere models, data-driven (or machine learning) approaches, solar-induced chlorophyll fluorescence (SIF), land surface temperature, and atmospheric inversions. Fourth, we review the platforms/sensors, methods, findings, and challenges in passive optical, microwave, and lidar remote sensing of biomass carbon stocks as well as remote sensing of soil organic carbon. Fifth, we review the progresses in remote sensing of disturbance impacts on the carbon cycle. Sixth, we also discuss the uncertainty and validation of the resulting carbon flux and stock estimates. Finally, we offer a forward-looking perspective and insights for future research and directions in remote sensing of the terrestrial carbon cycle. Remote sensing is anticipated to play an increasingly important role in carbon cycling studies in the future. This comprehensive and insightful review on 50?years of remote sensing of the terrestrial carbon cycle is timely and valuable and can benefit scientists in various research communities (e.g., carbon cycle, remote sensing, climate change, ecology) and inform ecosystem and carbon management, carbon-climate projections, and climate policymaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;interannual-variation-of-terrestrial-carbon-cycle-issues-and-perspectives&quot;&gt;Interannual variation of terrestrial carbon cycle: Issues and perspectives&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Piao, SL (Piao, Shilong)[ 1,2,3 ] ; Wang, XH (Wang, Xuhui)[ 1 ] ; Wang, K (Wang, Kai)[ 1 ] ; Li, XY (Li, Xiangyi)[ 1 ] ; Bastos, A (Bastos, Ana)[ 4 ] ; Canadell, JG (Canadell, Josep G.)[ 5 ] ; Ciais, P (Ciais, Philippe)[ 1,6 ] ; Friedlingstein, P (Friedlingstein, Pierre)[ 7 ] ; Sitch, S (Sitch, Stephen)[ 8 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View Web of Science ResearcherID and ORCID
GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pages: NIL_1-NIL_19
Published: NOV 29 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
With accumulation of carbon cycle observations and model developments over the past decades, exploring interannual variation (IAV) of terrestrial carbon cycle offers the opportunity to better understand climate-carbon cycle relationships. However, despite growing research interest, uncertainties remain on some fundamental issues, such as the contributions of different regions, constituent fluxes and climatic factors to carbon cycle IAV. Here we overviewed the literature on carbon cycle IAV about current understanding of these issues. Observations and models of the carbon cycle unanimously show the dominance of tropical land ecosystems to the signal of global carbon cycle IAV, where tropical semiarid ecosystems contribute as much as the combination of all other tropical ecosystems. Vegetation photosynthesis contributes more than ecosystem respiration to IAV of the global net land carbon flux, but large uncertainties remain on the contribution of fires and other disturbance fluxes. Climatic variations are the major drivers to the IAV of net land carbon flux. Although debate remains on whether the dominant driver is temperature or moisture variability, their interaction,that is, the dependence of carbon cycle sensitivity to temperature on moisture conditions, is emerging as key regulators of the carbon cycle IAV. On timescales from the interannual to the centennial, global carbon cycle variability will be increasingly contributed by northern land ecosystems and oceans. Therefore, both improving Earth system models (ESMs) with the progressive understanding on the fast processes manifested at interannual timescale and expanding carbon cycle observations at broader spatial and longer temporal scales are critical to better prediction on evolution of the carbon-climate system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;external-shocks-agent-interactions-and-endogenous-feedbacks---investigating-system-resilience-with-a-stylized-land-use-model&quot;&gt;External shocks, agent interactions, and endogenous feedbacks - Investigating system resilience with a stylized land use model&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Chen, Y (Chen, Yang)[ 1,2 ] ; Bakker, MM (Bakker, Martha M.)[ 2 ] ; Ligtenberg, A (Ligtenberg, Arend)[ 1 ] ; Bregt, AK (Bregt, Arnold K.)[ 1 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ECOLOGICAL COMPLEXITY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 40 Pages: 765-765 Part: B Special Issue: SI
Published: DEC 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Dynamics of coupled Social-Ecological Systems (SES) result from the interplay of society and ecology. To assess SES resilience, we constructed an Agent-Based Model (ABM) of a land use system as a stereotypical example of SES and investigated how resilience of the represented system is affected by both external disturbances and internal dynamics. The model explicitly considered different aspects of resilience in a framework derived from literature, which includes “resilience to”, “resilience of”, “resilience at”, “resilience due to”, and “indicators of resilience”. External disturbances were implemented as shocks in crop yields. Internal dynamics comprised of two types of social interaction between agents (learning and cooperation), an ecological feedback of soil depletion and an economic feedback of agglomeration benefits. We systematically varied these mechanisms and measured indicators that reflected spatial, social, and economic resilience. Results showed that (1) internal mechanisms increased the ability of the system to recover from external shocks, (2) feedbacks resulted in different regimes of crop cultivation, each with a distinctive set of functions, and (3) resilience is not a generic system property, but strongly depends on what system function is considered. We recommend future studies to include internal dynamics, especially feedbacks, and to systematically assess them across different aspects of resilience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exploring-resilience-with-agent-based-models-state-of-the-art-knowledge-gaps-and-recommendations-for-coping-with-multidimensionality&quot;&gt;Exploring resilience with agent-based models: State of the art, knowledge gaps and recommendations for coping with multidimensionality&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Egli, L (Egli, Lukas)[ 1 ] ; Weise, H (Weise, Hanna)[ 2 ] ; Radchuk, V (Radchuk, Viktoriia)[ 3 ] ; Seppelt, R (Seppelt, Ralf)[ 4 ] ; Grimm, V (Grimm, Volker)[ 1,5,6 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View Web of Science ResearcherID and ORCID
ECOLOGICAL COMPLEXITY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 40 Pages: 718-718 Part: B Special Issue: SI
Published: DEC 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Anthropogenic pressures increasingly alter natural systems. Therefore, understanding the resilience of agent-based complex systems such as ecosystems, i.e. their ability to absorb these pressures and sustain their functioning and services, is a major challenge. However, the mechanisms underlying resilience are still poorly understood. A main reason for this is the multidimensionality of both resilience, embracing the three fundamental stability properties recovery, resistance and persistence, and of the specific situations for which stability properties can be assessed. Agent-based models (ABM) complement empirical research which is, for logistic reasons, limited in coping with these multiple dimensions. Besides their ability to integrate multidimensionality through extensive manipulation in a fully controlled system, ABMs can capture the emergence of system resilience from individual interactions and feedbacks across different levels of organization. To assess the extent to which this potential of ABMs has already been exploited, we reviewed the state of the art in exploring resilience and its multidimensionality in ecological and socio-ecological systems with ABMs. We found that the potential of ABMs is not utilized in most models, as they typically focus on a single dimension of resilience by using variability as a proxy for persistence, and are limited to one reference state, disturbance type and scale. Moreover, only few studies explicitly test the ability of different mechanisms to support resilience. To overcome these limitations, we recommend to simultaneously assess multiple stability properties for different situations and under consideration of the mechanisms that are hypothesised to render a system resilient. This will help us to better exploit the potential of ABMs to understand and quantify resilience mechanisms, and hence support solving real-world problems related to the resilience of agent-based complex systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;state-factor-network-analysis-of-ecosystem-response-to-climate-change&quot;&gt;State factor network analysis of ecosystem response to climate change&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Phillips, JD (Phillips, Jonathan D.)[ 1 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ECOLOGICAL COMPLEXITY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 40 Pages: 789-789 Part: A
Published: DEC 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Case studies of ecosystem responses to changing climates are necessary in understanding and adapting to these changes. However, more general conceptual frameworks are also needed to contextualize and synthesize case studies, and to provide guidelines for assessment and prediction. This study analyzes a network model of ecological and soil state factor interrelationships to address issues such as sensitivity, resilience, and complexity of climate-driven terrestrial ecosystem changes. A factorial ecosystem model is analyzed using techniques from algebraic graph theory. Results show high values for spectral radius, graph energy, and algebraic connectivity. These indicate complexity, dynamical instability, active reverberating feedbacks, and high synchronization. Implications are that climate effects on ecosystems will be complicated, complex, and difficult to predict. We should be prepared for surprises in the form of unanticipated pathways and outcomes. The inherent nature of ecosystem interconnectivity indicated by the state factor model also suggests that when simulation models and change assessments do turn out to be wrong, it does not necessarily mean the underlying scientific understandings, data, or assumptions are wrong, as sensitivity to relatively minor variations and disturbances is high, and complexity and low predictability are inherent. Ecosystem reactions to climate (and other, often contemporaneous) changes will reverberate through the ecosystem. Both filtering and amplification may occur, but net amplification is indicated by the graph analysis. Ecosystem responses are integrated system responses-state factors will respond as a single integrated unit, not as a collection or sequence of individual responses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-organic-matter-is-stabilized-by-organo-mineral-associations-through-two-key-processes-the-role-of-the-carbon-to-nitrogen-ratio&quot;&gt;Soil organic matter is stabilized by organo-mineral associations through two key processes: The role of the carbon to nitrogen ratio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Kopittke, PM (Kopittke, Peter M.)[ 1 ] ; Dalal, RC (Dalal, Ram C.)[ 1 ] ; Hoeschen, C (Hoeschen, Carmen)[ 2 ] ; Li, C (Li, Cui)[ 1,3 ] ; Menzies, NW (Menzies, Neal W.)[ 1 ] ; Mueller, CW (Mueller, Carsten W.)[ 1,2 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View Web of Science ResearcherID and ORCID
GEODERMA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 357 Pages: 13974-13974
Published: JAN 1 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
The loss of organic matter (OM) from soil during long-term agricultural cropping results in a decrease in the inherent fertility of the soil as well as releasing greenhouse gases. Despite the importance of organo-mineral associations in the stabilization of OM within soils, much remains unknown about these organo-mineral associations. We used nano-scale secondary ion mass spectrometry (NanoSIMS) to investigate the incorporation and stabilization of C-13 and N-15 labelled residues of lucerne (Medicago sativa) and buffel grass (Cenchrus ciliaris) when incubated in a Vertisol from temperate Australia for up to 365 d. We show that newly-added OM forms organo-mineral associations through two mechanisms. Firstly, it was observed that the newly-added OM forms associations with the existing mineral-bound OM. However, this apparent stabilization of newly-added OM by associating with existing mineral-bound OM was not influenced by the C:N ratio of the plant residues, with the lucerne residues (C:N ratio of 11) being incorporated to a similar extent as the buffel grass (C:N ratio of 35). Secondly, we observed that N-rich microbial metabolites attached directly to mineral particle surfaces that did not contain existing OM patches, thereby creating new organo-mineral associations through which additional stabilization of OM would be possible. The information obtained in this study is valuable in understanding the stabilization of OM through organo-mineral associations, and raises the possibility of using cover crops or catch crops with narrow C:N ratios to allow for formation of new organo-mineral associations for increased stabilization of OM in soil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prediction-of-phosphorus-sorption-indices-and-isotherm-parameters-in-agricultural-soils-using-mid-infrared-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Prediction of phosphorus sorption indices and isotherm parameters in agricultural soils using mid-infrared spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Dunne, KS (Dunne, K. S.)[ 1,2 ] ; Holden, NM (Holden, N. M.)[ 2 ] ; O’Rourk, SM (O’Rourk, S. M.)[ 2 ] ; Fenelon, A (Fenelon, A.)[ 1 ] ; Daly, K (Daly, K.)[ 1 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GEODERMA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 358 Pages: 13981-13981
Published: JAN 15 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Phosphorus is a macro nutrient essential for optimum crop growth and animal health. The soil’s ability to supply P in an available form is influenced by sorption capacity and P binding energies in soil. These properties are usually derived from sorption isotherms that are time consuming and difficult for routine analysis. Mid-infrared diffuse reflectance Fourier transform (MIR DRIFT) spectroscopy is a rapid analysis technique that can potentially replace extractive and digestive techniques traditionally used in soil analysis. This study explored the application of MIR DRIFT in combination with chemometrics, to predict indicators of soil fertility and quality, specifically, P sorption properties. Using an archive of 11 great soil groups a P sorption reference library was generated using five different sorption models; (1) single point sorption index; (2) Langmuir sorption isotherm in the 0-25 mg l(-1) P range; (3) Langmuir sorption isotherm in the 0-50 mg l(-1) P range; (4) Freundlich sorption isotherm in the 0-25 mg l(-1 )P range; and (5) Freundlich sorption isotherm in the 0-50 mg l(-1) P range. Thirteen reference values were generated for each sample for calibration and validation of P sorption models developed from MIR DRIFT spectra. Validation of the single point P sorption index and Langmuir parameters were satisfactory for rough screening with the exception of the Langmuir binding energy in the 0-50 mg l(-1) P range (k(50) [8]). The P sorption capacity remaining was the best predicted parameter and the Freundlich sorption isotherm predictions were poor. The results indicated that there is potential for benchtop MIR to describe P sorption properties in agricultural soil to improve management decisions and that soil specific models could be developed to further enhance prediction performance.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/12/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on December 11, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2019/12/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2019/12/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2019-12-02T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2019-12-02T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2019-19&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2019 #19&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Responses of soil carbon sequestration to climate-smart agriculture practices: A meta-analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Predicting future climate at high spatial and temporal resolution&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Boundary line models for soil nutrient concentrations and wheat yield in national-scale datasets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evolutionary Pathways in Soil-Geomorphic Systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;responses-of-soil-carbon-sequestration-to-climate-smart-agriculture-practices-a-meta-analysis&quot;&gt;Responses of soil carbon sequestration to climate-smart agriculture practices: A meta-analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Bai, XX (Bai, Xiongxiong)[ 1,2 ] ; Huang, YW (Huang, Yawen)[ 1 ] ; Ren, W (Ren, Wei)[ 1 ] ; Coyne, M (Coyne, Mark)[ 1 ] ; Jacinthe, PA (Jacinthe, Pierre-Andre)[ 3 ] ; Tao, B (Tao, Bo)[ 1 ] ; Hui, DF (Hui, Dafeng)[ 4 ] ; Yang, J (Yang, Jian)[ 5 ] ; Matocha, C (Matocha, Chris)[ 1 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View Web of Science ResearcherID and ORCID
GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 25 Issue: 8 Pages: 2591-2606
Published: AUG 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Climate-smart agriculture (CSA) management practices (e.g., conservation tillage, cover crops, and biochar applications) have been widely adopted to enhance soil organic carbon (SOC) sequestration and to reduce greenhouse gas emissions while ensuring crop productivity. However, current measurements regarding the influences of CSA management practices on SOC sequestration diverge widely, making it difficult to derive conclusions about individual and combined CSA management effects and bringing large uncertainties in quantifying the potential of the agricultural sector to mitigate climate change. We conducted a meta-analysis of 3,049 paired measurements from 417 peer-reviewed articles to examine the effects of three common CSA management practices on SOC sequestration as well as the environmental controlling factors. We found that, on average, biochar applications represented the most effective approach for increasing SOC content (39%), followed by cover crops (6%) and conservation tillage (5%). Further analysis suggested that the effects of CSA management practices were more pronounced in areas with relatively warmer climates or lower nitrogen fertilizer inputs. Our meta-analysis demonstrated that, through adopting CSA practices, cropland could be an improved carbon sink. We also highlight the importance of considering local environmental factors (e.g., climate and soil conditions and their combination with other management practices) in identifying appropriate CSA practices for mitigating greenhouse gas emissions while ensuring crop productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;predicting-future-climate-at-high-spatial-and-temporal-resolution&quot;&gt;Predicting future climate at high spatial and temporal resolution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Maclean, IMD (Maclean, Ilya M. D.)[ 1 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View Web of Science ResearcherID and ORCID
GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pages: NIL_1-NIL_9
Published: NOV 16 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Most studies on the biological effects of future climatic changes rely on seasonally aggregated, coarse-resolution data. Such data mask spatial and temporal variability in microclimate driven by terrain, wind and vegetation, and ultimately bear little resemblance to the conditions that organisms experience in the wild. Here, I present the methods for providing fine-grained, hourly and daily estimates of current and future temperature and soil moisture over decadal timescales. Observed climate data and spatially coherent probabilistic projections of daily future weather were disaggregated to hourly and used to drive empirically calibrated physical models of thermal and hydrological microclimates. Mesoclimatic effects (cold-air drainage, coastal exposure and elevation) were determined from the coarse-resolution climate surfaces using thin-plate spline models with coastal exposure and elevation as predictors. Differences between micro and mesoclimate temperatures were determined from terrain, vegetation and ground properties using energy balance equations. Soil moisture was computed in a thin upper layer and an underlying deeper layer, and the exchange of water between these layers was calculated using the van Genuchten equation. Code for processing the data and running the models is provided as a series of R packages. The methods were applied to the Lizard Peninsula, United Kingdom, to provide hourly estimates of temperature (100 m grid resolution over entire area, 1 m for a selected area) for the periods 1983-2017 and 2041-2049. Results indicated that there is a fine-resolution variability in climatic changes, driven primarily by interactions between landscape features and decadal trends in weather conditions. High-temporal resolution extremes in conditions under future climate change were predicted to be considerably less novel than the extremes estimated using seasonally aggregated variables. The study highlights the need to more accurately estimate the future climatic conditions experienced by organisms and equips biologists with the means to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;boundary-line-models-for-soil-nutrient-concentrations-and-wheat-yield-in-national-scale-datasets&quot;&gt;Boundary line models for soil nutrient concentrations and wheat yield in national-scale datasets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Lark, RM (Lark, Richard M.)[ 1 ] ; Gillingham, V (Gillingham, Vincent)[ 2 ] ; Langton, D (Langton, David)[ 3 ] ; Marchant, B (Marchant, Ben P.)[ 4 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF SOIL SCIENCE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pages: NIL_1-NIL_18
Published: NOV 15 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
In boundary line analysis a biological response (e.g., crop yield) is assumed to be a function of a variable (e.g., soil nutrient concentration), which limits the response in only some subset of observations because other limiting factors also apply. The response function is therefore expressed by an upper boundary of the plot of the response against the variable. This model has been used in various branches of soil science. In this paper we apply it to the analysis of some large datasets, originating from commercial farms in England and Wales, on the recorded yield of wheat and measured concentrations of soil nutrients in within-field soil management zones. We considered boundary line models for the effects of potassium (K), phosphorus (P) and magnesium (Mg) on yield, comparing the model with a simple bivariate normal distribution or a bivariate normal censored at a constant maximum yield. We were able to show, using likelihood-based methods, that the boundary line model was preferable in most cases. The boundary line model suggested that the standard RB209 soil nutrient index values (Agriculture and Horticulture Development Board, nutrient management guide (RB209), 2017) are robust and apply at the within-field scale. However, there was evidence that wheat yield could respond to additional Mg at concentrations above index 0, contrary to RB209 guidelines. Furthermore, there was evidence that the boundary line model for yield and P differs between soils at different pH and depth intervals, suggesting that shallow soils with larger pH require a larger target P index than others. Highlights&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boundary line analysis is one way to examine how soil variables influence crop yield in large datasets. We showed that boundary line models could be applied to large datasets on soil nutrients and crop yield. The resulting models are consistent with current practice for P and K, but not for Mg. Models suggest that more refined recommendations for P requirement could be based on soil pH and depth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evolutionary-pathways-in-soil-geomorphic-systems&quot;&gt;Evolutionary Pathways in Soil-Geomorphic Systems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Phillips, JD (Phillips, Jonathan D.)[ 1 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOIL SCIENCE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 184 Issue: 1 Pages: 1-12
Published: FEB 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Understanding evolution of soils and landforms (and other Earth surface systems) has itself evolved from concepts of single-path, single-outcome development to those that recognize multiple possible developmental trajectories and different maturely developed stales. Soil geomorphology and pedology should now move beyond showing that multiple trajectories are possible to investigating why some evolutionary pathways (EPs) are common and persistent, whereas others are rare and transient. A typology of EPs is developed and applied to soil formation in the North Carolina coastal plain. Some EN are impossible because of violation of generally applicable laws or absence of necessary conditions; others are currently impossible, having occurred in the past but requiring conditions that no longer exist. Improbable paths are possible but rare, because necessary circumstances involve rare events or boundary conditions. Inhibited EPs are also possible but rare because of resistance factors or feedbacks that prevent or inhibit them. Transient paths may be common but are not long-lived or well preserved and are thus rarely observed. Recurring but nonrepeating EPs occur in different locations but are irreversible in any given location and cannot recur except in the case of system-resetting disturbance or new inputs. Recurring EPs are riot inhibited or self-limited, occur in different locations, and may be repeated because of ongoing or recurrent processes or conditions. Selected path types occur in multiple situations, but with increased probability due to feedbacks or responses that encourage or enhance recurrence and/or persistence. The case study shows examples of all possible EP types.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/12/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on December 02, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2019/11/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2019/11/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2019-11-26T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2019-11-26T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2019-18&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2019 #18&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Australian hot and dry extremes induced by weakenings of the stratospheric polar vortex&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil health assessment: Past accomplishments, current activities, and future opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Development of soil spectral allocation models considering the effect of soil moisture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Development and Uncertainty Assessment of Pedotransfer Functions for Predicting Water Contents at Specific Pressure Heads&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimating Atterberg Limits of Fine-Grained Soils by Visible-Near-Infrared Spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pH and exchangeable aluminum are major regulators of microbial energy flow and carbon use efficiency in soil microbial communities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;australian-hot-and-dry-extremes-induced-by-weakenings-of-the-stratospheric-polar-vortex&quot;&gt;Australian hot and dry extremes induced by weakenings of the stratospheric polar vortex&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Lim, EP (Lim, Eun-Pa)[ 1 ] ; Hendon, HH (Hendon, Harry H.)[ 1 ] ; Boschat, G (Boschat, Ghyslaine)[ 2,3 ] ; Hudson, D (Hudson, Debra)[ 1 ] ; Thompson, DWJ (Thompson, David W. J.)[ 4 ] ; Dowdy, AJ (Dowdy, Andrew J.)[ 1 ] ; Arblaster, JM (Arblaster, Julie M.)[ 2,3,5 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NATURE GEOSCIENCE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 12 Issue: 11 Pages: 896-+
Published: NOV 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
The occurrence of extreme hot and dry conditions in warm seasons can have large impacts on human health, energy and water supplies, agriculture and wildfires. Australian hot and dry extremes have been known to be associated with the occurrence of El Nino and other variations of tropospheric circulation. Here we identify an additional driver: variability of the stratospheric Antarctic polar vortex. On the basis of statistical analyses using observational data covering the past 40 yr, we show that weakenings and warmings of the stratospheric polar vortex, which episodically occur during austral spring, substantially increase the chances of hot and dry extremes and of associated fire-conducive weather across subtropical eastern Australia from austral spring to early summer. The promotion of these Australian climate extremes results from the downward coupling of the weakened polar vortex to tropospheric levels, where it is linked to the low-index polarity of the Southern Annular Mode, an equatorward shift of the mid-latitude westerly jet stream and subsidence and warming in the subtropics. Because of the long timescale of the polar vortex variations, the enhanced likelihood of early-summertime hot and dry extremes and wildfire risks across eastern Australia may be predictable a season in advance during years of vortex weakenings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-health-assessment-past-accomplishments-current-activities-and-future-opportunities&quot;&gt;Soil health assessment: Past accomplishments, current activities, and future opportunities&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Karlen, D (Karlen, Douglas)[ 1 ] ; Veum, KS (Veum, Kristen S.)[ 2 ] ; Sudduth, KA (Sudduth, Kenneth A.)[ 2 ] ; Obrycki, JF (Obrycki, John F.)[ 3 ] ; Nunes, MR (Nunes, Marcio R.)[ 4 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOIL &amp;amp; TILLAGE RESEARCH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 195 Pages: 4365-4365
Published: DEC 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Review&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Global interest in soil health has increased exponentially during the past decade, with many different government, non-government, and private sector groups striving to develop monitoring and assessment protocols. This brief review focuses on developments in the United States (U.S.) with some references to activities in other countries. It also documents how the soil health concept evolved and projects what is needed to scientifically advance monitoring and assessment with a particular focus on activities in the U.S. Recommendations emphasize improving the Soil Management Assessment Framework (SMAF) and/or Comprehensive Assessment of Soil Health (CASH) assessment tools, developing protocols for national soil health monitoring, identifying and calibrating better indicators of soil biological, chemical, and physical health, and developing sensors and other tools for more rapid and in-situ assessments. Collectively, these and other research and technology transfer activities will help achieve what we suggest should be a universal goal - striving for healthy soils, healthy landscapes, and vibrant economies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;development-of-soil-spectral-allocation-models-considering-the-effect-of-soil-moisture&quot;&gt;Development of soil spectral allocation models considering the effect of soil moisture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Wang, X (Wang, Xiang)[ 1,2 ] ; Dou, X (Dou, Xin)[ 2 ] ; Zhang, XL (Zhang, Xinle)[ 2 ] ; Liu, HJ (Liu, Huanjun)[ 1,2 ] ; Li, HX (Li, Houxuan)[ 2 ] ; Meng, XT (Meng, Xiangtian)[ 2 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOIL &amp;amp; TILLAGE RESEARCH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 195 Pages: 4374-4374
Published: DEC 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Soil spectral allocation or classification is usually conducted on air-dried soils. However, the field soils are not all air-dried, and the change of soil moisture will affect soil reflectance. We introduce a soil allocation model that considers the effect of soil moisture for the purpose of eliminating the effect of soil moisture. The topsoil spectral curves of four typical soils from the Songnen Plain in Northeast China were re-sampled to 10-nm intervals and converted to first-derivative spectral curves and continuum removal curves. The spectral feature parameters were extracted from continuum removal curves in the visible-near infrared (VNIR) range (350-2500 nm), and the range of 430-2400 nm was used to build soil allocation models for reducing the effect of noise. Samples with different soil moisture were mixed into air-dried soils and we calculated the coefficient of variation (CV) of different inputs to assess the effect of soil moisture and to find allocation indices that were not affected by soil moisture. We used allocation indices of Zhang et al. (2018) because of the high accuracy of their DT (Decision Tree) model to allocate mixed-soil samples. We also used allocation indices that were not affected by soil moisture to allocate mixed-soil samples with decision tree (DT), multinomial logistic regression (MLR) and multi-layer perception neural network (MLPNN), and compared the results of the two methods. The results show the following: 1) As SFPs were built with shorter bands, SFP was less sensitive to soil moisture than PCR and PCFD and thus SFP is more suitable to build soil allocation models that consider the effect of soil moisture as input than PCR and PCFD. 2) Differences in soil moisture had little effect on absorption valley shoulders, symmetry and absorption positions, moderate effect on absorption area and depth, and a major effect on the slope of different bands. 3) The effect of soil moisture on continuum removal curves of different soil classes was variable. There was little effect on Arenosols, a moderate effect on Chernozems and Cambisols, and a large effect on Phaeozems. 4) The accuracy of the DT model using allocation indices that were not affected by soil moisture was 91.892% with a Kappa coefficient of 0.888. Our results suggest that it is feasible to build soil spectral allocation models that are not affected by soil moisture, and this improves the universality of soil spectral allocation, especially to field soils, which can be of considerable help in soil classification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;development-and-uncertainty-assessment-of-pedotransfer-functions-for-predicting-water-contents-at-specific-pressure-heads&quot;&gt;Development and Uncertainty Assessment of Pedotransfer Functions for Predicting Water Contents at Specific Pressure Heads&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Kotlar, AM (Kotlar, Ali Mehmandoost)[ 1 ] ; van Uer, QD (van Uer, Quirijn de Jong)[ 1 ] ; Barros, AHC (Barros, Alexandre Hugo C.)[ 2 ] ; Iversen, BV (Iversen, Bo, V)[ 3 ] ; Vereecken, H (Vereecken, Harry)[ 4 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VADOSE ZONE JOURNAL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 18 Issue: 1 Pages: 90063-90063
Published: NOV 7 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
There has been much effort to improve the performance of pedotransfer functions (PTFs) using intelligent algorithms, but the issue of covariate shift, i.e., different probability distributions in training and testing datasets, and its impact on prediction uncertainty of PTFs has been rarely addressed. The common practice in PTF generation is to randomly separate the dataset into training and testing subsets, and the outcomes of this random selection may be different if the process is subject to covariate shift. We evaluated the impact of covariate shift generated by data shuffling and detected by Kolmogorov-Smirnov test for the prediction of water contents using soil databases from Denmark and Brazil. The soil water contents at different pressure heads were predicted by developing linear and stepwise regression besides machine learning based PTFs including Gaussian process regression and ensemble method. Regression based PTFs for the Brazilian dataset resulted in better predictions compared with machine learning methods, which in their turn estimated high water contents in Danish soils more accurately. One hundred PTFs were developed for water content at specific pressure heads by data shuffling. From these, 100 sets of fitted van Genuchten parameters were obtained representing the generated uncertainty. Data shuffling led to covariate shift, resulting in uncertainty in water content prediction by the PTFs. Inherent variability of data may lead to increased prediction uncertainty. For correlated data, simple regression models performed as good as sophisticated machine learning methods. Using PTF-predicted water contents for van Genuchten retention parameter fitting may lead to a high uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;estimating-atterberg-limits-of-fine-grained-soils-by-visible-near-infrared-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Estimating Atterberg Limits of Fine-Grained Soils by Visible-Near-Infrared Spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Rehman, HU (Rehman, Hafeez Ur)[ 1 ] ; Knadel, M (Knadel, Maria)[ 1 ] ; Kayabali, K (Kayabali, Kamil)[ 2 ] ; Arthur, E (Arthur, Emmanuel)[ 1 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VADOSE ZONE JOURNAL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 18 Issue: 1 Pages: 90039-90039
Published: NOV 7 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
The Atterberg limits (shrinkage limit [SL], plastic limit [PL], and liquid limit [LL]) describe the physico-mechanical behavior of soils and thus are crucial for civil and agricultural applications. Conventional laboratory methods for measurement of these limits are tedious and costly for a large number of samples. Our objective was to develop visible-near-infrared spectroscopy (Vis-NIRS, from 400-2500 nm) based reliable models to estimate the Atterberg limits. Two conventional methods for each Atterberg limit were used to generate the reference data: paraffin wax and Hg methods for SL; rolling and motorized devices for PL; and Casagrande cup and drop-cone penetrometer methods for LL. Calibration models were built on 80% of the data using partial least squares regression and validated with the remaining 20% of the dataset. The Vis-NIRS independent validation of LL showed very good estimation with standardized RMSE (SRMSE = RMSE/Range) of 0.16 and 0.15, respectively, for LLdrop-cone and LLCasagrande methods. Similarly for PL, the Vis-NIRS estimation accuracy was quite good with SRMSE values of 0.18 and 0.22, respectively, for PLmotorized and PLrolling. Reasonably good estimation was obtained for the SLparaffin and SLHg with SRMSE of 0.25 for both methods. The results suggest that the Vis-NIRS calibration models and the accuracy following validation were similar for the pair of methods used for the SL, PL, and LL. Finally, analyses of the model regression coefficients revealed that the important wavelengths to estimate the SL, PL, and LL in the Vis-NIR regions were present across the entire Vis-NIR spectrum and were strongly related to clay type and content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ph-and-exchangeable-aluminum-are-major-regulators-of-microbial-energy-flow-and-carbon-use-efficiency-in-soil-microbial-communities&quot;&gt;pH and exchangeable aluminum are major regulators of microbial energy flow and carbon use efficiency in soil microbial communities&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Jones, DL (Jones, Davey L.)[ 1,2 ] ; Cooledge, EC (Cooledge, Emily C.)[ 2 ] ; Hoyle, FC (Hoyle, Frances C.)[ 1 ] ; Griffiths, RI (Griffiths, Robert I.)[ 3 ] ; Murphy, DV (Murphy, Daniel V.)[ 1 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOIL BIOLOGY &amp;amp; BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 138 Pages: 7584-7584
Published: NOV 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
The microbial partitioning of organic carbon (C) into either anabolic (i.e. growth) or catabolic (i.e. respiration) metabolic pathways represents a key process regulating the amount of added C that is retained in soil. The factors regulating C use efficiency (CUE) in agricultural soils, however, remain poorly understood. The aim of this study was to investigate substrate CUE from a wide range of soils (n = 970) and geographical area (200,000 km(2)) to determine which soil properties most influenced C retention within the microbial community. Using a C-14-labeling approach, we showed that the average CUE across all soils was 0.65 +/- 0.003, but that the variation in CUE was relatively high within the sample population (CV 14.9%). Of the major properties measured in our soils, we found that pH and exchangeable aluminum (Al) were highly correlated with CUE. We identified a critical pH transition point at which CUE declined (pH 5.5). This coincided exactly with the point at which Al3+ started to become soluble. In contrast, other soil factors [e.g. total C and nitrogen (N), dissolved organic C (DOC), clay content, available calcium, phosphorus (P) and sulfur (S), total base cations] showed little or no relationship with CUE. We also found no evidence to suggest that nutrient stoichiometry (C:N, C:P and C:S ratios) influenced CUE in these soils. Based on current evidence, we postulate that the decline in microbial CUE at low pH and high Al reflects a greater channeling of C into energy intensive metabolic pathways involved in overcoming H+/Al3+ stress (e.g. cell repair and detoxification). The response may also be associated with shifts in microbial community structure, which are known to be tightly associated with soil pH. We conclude that maintaining agricultural soils above pH 5.5 maximizes microbial energy efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/11/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on November 26, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2019/11/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2019/11/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2019-11-19T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2019-11-19T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2019-17&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2019 #17&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understanding ecosystems of the future will require more than realistic climate change experiments - A response to Korell et al.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A method to assess the impact of soil available water capacity uncertainty on crop models with a tipping-bucket approach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;understanding-ecosystems-of-the-future-will-require-more-than-realistic-climate-change-experiments---a-response-to-korell-et-al&quot;&gt;Understanding ecosystems of the future will require more than realistic climate change experiments - A response to Korell et al.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;De Boeck, Hans J.; Bloor, Juliette M. G.; Aerts, Rien; Bahn, Michael; Beier, Claus; et al.
Global Change Biology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-method-to-assess-the-impact-of-soil-available-water-capacity-uncertainty-on-crop-models-with-a-tipping-bucket-approach&quot;&gt;A method to assess the impact of soil available water capacity uncertainty on crop models with a tipping-bucket approach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Constantin, Julie; Picheny, Victor; Nassar, Lina H.; Bergez, Jacques-Eric
European Journal Of Soil Science&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/11/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on November 19, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2019/11/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2019/11/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2019-11-03T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2019-11-11T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2019-16&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2019 #16&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimation of Field-Scale Variability in Soil Saturated Hydraulic Conductivity From Rainfall-Runoff experiments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mapping forest change using stacked generalization: An ensemble approach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;estimation-of-field-scale-variability-in-soil-saturated-hydraulic-conductivity-from-rainfall-runoff-experiments&quot;&gt;Estimation of Field-Scale Variability in Soil Saturated Hydraulic Conductivity From Rainfall-Runoff experiments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Goyal, A (Goyal, Abhishek)[ 1 ] ; Morbidelli, R (Morbidelli, Renato)[ 2 ] ; Flammini, A (Flammini, Alessia)[ 2 ] ; Corradini, C (Corradini, Corrado)[ 2 ] ; Govindaraju, RS (Govindaraju, Rao S.)[ 1 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View Web of Science ResearcherID and ORCID
WATER RESOURCES RESEARCH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 55 Issue: 9 Pages: 7902-7915
Published: SEP 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Saturated hydraulic conductivity (K-s) is among the important soil properties that influence the partitioning of rainfall into surface and subsurface waters. Point estimates of K-s are difficult to determine and exhibit large spatial variability in fields. Often, data from field-scale rainfall-runoff experiments are utilized to assess the properties of the K-s random field that are required in the use of field-scale infiltration models. Standard methods of calibration are confounded by nonuniqueness and identifiability problems associated with experimental data. In this study, a new method that employed a field-averaged infiltration model and Monte Carlo simulations was used to obtain the possible range of distributions of K-s that would describe experimental observations over a field for a rainfall event. A Shannon information-theoretic approach was subsequently adopted to consolidate the ranges of K-s distributions over multiple rainfall events to yield the best range of K-s distributions. The method was applied to data from several rainfall-runoff events observed under natural conditions over an experimental field characterized by a silty loam soil and a small surface slope. Results suggest the existence of numerous parameter combinations that could satisfy the experimental observations over a single rainfall event, and high variability of these combinations among different events, thereby providing insights regarding the identifiable space of K-s distributions from individual rainfall experiments. Validation results showed that the method provides a realistic estimate of our ability to quantify the spatial variability of K-s in natural fields from rainfall-runoff experiments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mapping-forest-change-using-stacked-generalization-an-ensemble-approach&quot;&gt;Mapping forest change using stacked generalization: An ensemble approach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Healey, SP (Healey, Sean P.)[ 1 ] ; Cohen, WB (Cohen, Warren B.)[ 2 ] ; Yang, ZQ (Yang, Zhiqiang)[ 3 ] ; Brewer, CK (Brewer, C. Kenneth)[ 4 ] ; Brooks, EB (Brooks, Evan B.)[ 5 ] ; Gorelick, N (Gorelick, Noel)[ 6 ] ; Hernandez, AJ (Hernandez, Alexander J.)[ 7 ] ; Huang, CQ (Huang, Chengquan)[ 8 ] ; Hughes, MJ (Hughes, M. Joseph)[ 3 ] ; Kennedy, RE (Kennedy, Robert E.)[ 3 ] …More&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View Web of Science ResearcherID and ORCID
REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 204 Pages: 717-728
Published: JAN 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
The ever-increasing volume and accessibility of remote sensing data has spawned many alternative approaches for mapping important environmental features and processes. For example, there are several viable but highly varied strategies for using time series of Landsat imagery to detect changes in forest cover. Performance among algorithms varies across complex natural systems, and it is reasonable to ask if aggregating the strengths of an ensemble of classifiers might result in increased overall accuracy. Relatively simple rules have been used in the past to aggregate classifications among remotely sensed maps (e.g. using majority predictions), and in other fields, empirical models have been used to create situationally specific algorithm weights. The latter process, called “stacked generalization” (or “stacking”), typically uses a parametric model for the fusion of algorithm outputs. We tested the performance of several leading forest disturbance detection algorithms against ensembles of the outputs of those same algorithms based upon stacking using both parametric and Random Forests-based fusion rules. Stacking using a Random Forests model cut omission and commission error rates in half in many cases in relation to individual change detection algorithms, and cut error rates by one quarter compared to more conventional parametric stacking. Stacking also offers two auxiliary benefits: alignment of outputs to the precise definitions built into a particular set of empirical calibration data; and, outputs which may be adjusted such that map class totals match independent estimates of change in each year. In general, ensemble predictions improve when new inputs are added that are both informative and uncorrelated with existing ensemble components. As increased use of cloud-based computing makes ensemble mapping methods more accessible, the most useful new algorithms may be those that specialize in providing spectral, temporal, or thematic information not already available through members of existing ensembles.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/11/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on November 11, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2019/11/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2019/11/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2019-11-03T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2019-11-03T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2019-15&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2019 #15&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scale-Dependent Patterning of Wetland Depressions in a Low-Relief Karst Landscape&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Functional Diversity: An Epistemic Roadmap&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimation of soil water content at permanent wilting point using hygroscopic water content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;scale-dependent-patterning-of-wetland-depressions-in-a-low-relief-karst-landscape&quot;&gt;Scale-Dependent Patterning of Wetland Depressions in a Low-Relief Karst Landscape&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Quintero, CJ; Cohen, MJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF GEOPHYSICAL RESEARCH-EARTH SURFACE&lt;/em&gt;, 124 (8):2101-2117; AUG 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Thousands of small wetland depression features (cypress domes) dot the low-relief karst of Big Cypress National Preserve (BICY) in South Florida, USA. We hypothesized that these wetland depressions are organized in a regular pattern, which is atypical of wetlandscapes elsewhere. Regular patterning implies the existence of coupled feedbacks operating at different spatial scales, with local wetland depression expansion (facilitation via karst dissolution) limited by competition among adjacent depressions for finite water resources (inhibition). We sought to test the hypothesis that wetlands in BICY exhibit regular patterning, and to quantify pattern properties to evaluate competing genesis mechanisms. We tested four predictions about landscape structure and geometry using high-resolution Light Detection and Ranging elevation data from six 2.25-km(2) domains across BICY. Specifically, we predicted (1) feature overdispersion resulting from competition between adjacent basins; (2)
  truncated wetland area distributions due to growth inhibition feedbacks; (3) periodicity in surface elevation indicating a characteristic pattern wavelength; and (4) elevation bimodality indicating distinct upland and wetland states. All four predictions were strongly supported. Depressions were significantly overdispersed and efficiently fill the landscape, generating hexagonal patterning. Wetland areas followed truncated power law scaling, indicating incremental constraints on basin expansion, in contrast to depression areas elsewhere. Variogram and radial spectrum analyses revealed clear periodicity (similar to 150- to 250-m wavelength) in surface elevations. Finally, surface elevations were consistently bimodal with elevation divergence of 10 to 40 cm. Regular patterning of wetland depressions across BICY is clear, implying long-term biogeomorphic control on landform structure in this karst landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;functional-diversity-an-epistemic-roadmap&quot;&gt;Functional Diversity: An Epistemic Roadmap&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Malaterre, C; Dussault, AC; Rousseau-Mermans, S; Barker, G; Beisner, BE;
Bouchard, F; Desjardins, E; Handa, IT; Kembel, SW; Lajoie, G; Maris, V;
Munson, AD; Odenbaugh, J; Poisot, T; Shapiro, BJ; Suttle, CA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;BIOSCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, 69 (10):800-811; OCT 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Functional diversity holds the promise of understanding ecosystems in ways unattainable by taxonomic diversity studies. Underlying this promise is the intuition that investigating the diversity of what organisms actually do (i.e., their functional traits) within ecosystems will generate more reliable insights into the ways these ecosystems behave, compared to considering only species diversity. But this promise also rests on several conceptual and methodological (i.e., epistemic) assumptions that cut across various theories and domains of ecology. These assumptions should be clearly addressed, notably for the sake of an effective comparison and integration across domains, and for assessing whether or not to use functional diversity approaches for developing ecological management strategies. The objective of this contribution is to identify and critically analyze the most salient of these assumptions. To this aim, we provide an epistemic roadmap that pinpoints these assumption
 s along a set of historical, conceptual, empirical, theoretical, and normative dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;estimation-of-soil-water-content-at-permanent-wilting-point-using-hygroscopic-water-content&quot;&gt;Estimation of soil water content at permanent wilting point using hygroscopic water content&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Chen, C; Zhou, H; Shang, JY; Hu, KL; Ren, TS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF SOIL SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, NIL_1-NIL_7; OCT 21 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Traditional methods for determining soil water content at permanent wilting point (theta(PWP)) are time consuming. The objectives of this study are to develop a model for predicting theta(PWP) based on easily measured hygroscopic water content and to compare the performance of the proposed model with three previous models: the Aina &amp;amp; Periaswamy model (AP model), the van den Berg et al. model (vdB model) and the Seybold &amp;amp; Harms model (SH model), which estimate theta(PWP) from particle size distribution and/or organic matter (OM) content. By assuming that the dry end of the soil water retention curve could be described with the linear Campbell &amp;amp; Shiozawa model, a simple linear model, theta(PWP) = 3 theta(RH50), was developed to predict theta(PWP) using theta(RH50). The theta(RH50) of the soils ranged from 0.002 to 0.157 g g(-1) and the theta(PWP) ranged from 0.014 to 0.279 g g(-1). The validation results on 48 soils showed that the root mean squared error (RMSE) and mean absolu
 te error (MAE) of the proposed model were 0.007 g g(-1) and 0.005 g g(-1), respectively. Model comparison showed that the prediction accuracy of four models for theta(PWP) was in the order of proposed model &amp;gt; AP model &amp;gt; SH model &amp;gt; vdB model. Thus, theta(RH50) is a viable predictor for theta(PWP), which eliminates the need for soil particle size distribution and OM content. HighlightsWater content at permanent wilting point (theta(PWP)) relates to hygroscopic water content. A model was developed to predict theta(PWP) using water content at relative humidity of 50%. The proposed model performed better than existing models.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/11/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on November 03, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2019/10/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2019/10/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2019-10-30T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2019-10-31T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2019-14&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2019 #14&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preparing a soil spectral library using the Internal Soil Standard (ISS) method: Influence of extreme different humidity laboratory conditions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In situ and laboratory soil spectroscopy with portable visible-to-near-infrared and mid-infrared instruments for the assessment of organic carbon in soils&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alternative approach to calculate soil hydraulic-energy-indices and -functions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mapping LUCAS topsoil chemical properties at European scale using Gaussian process regression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;preparing-a-soil-spectral-library-using-the-internal-soil-standard-iss-method-influence-of-extreme-different-humidity-laboratory-conditions&quot;&gt;Preparing a soil spectral library using the Internal Soil Standard (ISS) method: Influence of extreme different humidity laboratory conditions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Chabrillat, S; Gholizadeh, A; Neumann, C; Berger, D; Milewski, R; Ogen,
Y; Ben-Dor, E&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GEODERMA&lt;/em&gt;, 355 13855-13855; DEC 1 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Extensive efforts are currently being devoted to the establishment of soil spectral libraries on regional, national, continent-wide and global domains. In particular, a new development goes in the direction of global harmonized soil spectral databases that shall be acquired following common standards and procedures so that they can be merged with other soil spectral libraries. The choice of standards is important, especially with respect to their behaviors when laboratory conditions, such as humidity, change. In this study, we test the application and robustness of the Internal Soil Standard (ISS) spectral re-alignment procedure on an extended number of soil samples acquired at different laboratories. In particular, a focus is placed on the comparison between two standards Lucky Bay (LB) and Wylie Bay (WB), for their performance with different humidity laboratory conditions. LB and WB are almost pure quartz sands from Australia. For this, 71 soil samples from Israel with diff
 erent mineralogical background and variable soil organic matter contents are scanned at two laboratories. The scanning took place with different spectral measurement protocols and extreme diverse conditions in terms of laboratory humidity and moist. All scans are completed by the repeated scans of the two Australian white sands through all scan batches to harmonize the spectral measurements. Our results show that the ISS minimizes the visual spectral variation, aligns the minor and extreme systematic changes of the protocols, and makes them more stable. Furthermore, the LB and WB standards do not exhibit equal performance regarding to relatively dry and humid conditions. The WB standard provides more stable and satisfactory results in humid condition. However, the high performance of the LB sample in spectral correction is still observed, particularly in laboratories with lower moist. Accordingly, these analyses suggest that in the ISS re-alignment procedure, the WB sample i
 s more reliable to be used in humid laboratory condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-situ-and-laboratory-soil-spectroscopy-with-portable-visible-to-near-infrared-and-mid-infrared-instruments-for-the-assessment-of-organic-carbon-in-soils&quot;&gt;In situ and laboratory soil spectroscopy with portable visible-to-near-infrared and mid-infrared instruments for the assessment of organic carbon in soils&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Hutengs, C; Seidel, M; Oertel, F; Ludwig, B; Vohland, M&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GEODERMA&lt;/em&gt;, 355 13900-13900; DEC 1 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Mid-infrared (MIR) spectroscopy has been established as a rapid and cost-efficient laboratory analysis technique for soil organic carbon (SOC) concentrations. Current portable, high-performance handheld MIR instruments have opened the opportunity to take the technique from the laboratory to the field. We tested the potential of handheld MIR spectroscopy for SOC estimation with field spectral data against parallel VIS-NIR measurements and further evaluated the impact of soil state (in situ, dried, ground) on the accuracy of SOC prediction models. MIR and VIS-NIR data were collected for a set of 90 soils from 90 agricultural loess sites in Central Germany in the field, (i) in situ on the soil surface, and in the laboratory, on (ii) dried and sieved (&amp;lt; 2 mm), and (iii) dried, sieved and ground sample material (similar to 10 mu m). Multivariate calibrations for SOC for each pre-treatment were evaluated with a repeated double cross-validation (rdCV) analysis and the Kennard-Stone 
 (KS) calibration sampling approach. MIR calibrations were more accurate than VIS-NIR calibrations for samples measured under the same conditions in each case with lower RMSE values from 27 to 56% in the rdCV and from 15 to 61% in the KS approach. Sample pre-treatment in the laboratory had a pronounced effect on calibrations in the MIR as models developed on finely ground samples (R-rdCV(2) = 0.86, RMSErdCV = 0.11%) were more accurate than those for dried and sieved samples (R-rdCV(2) = 0.79, RMSErdCV = 0.13%), but differences in the VIS-NIR were negligible. SOC estimates with in situ MIR measurements were less accurate due to spectral variation induced by surface heterogeneity and soil moisture but compared favourably against VIS-NIR data (R-rdCV_MIR(2) = 0.63, RMSErdCV_MIR = 0.17% vs R-rdCV_VIS-NIR(2) = 0.39, RMSErdCV_VIS-NIR = 0.23%). Our findings show that portable MIR spectroscopy can achieve superior SOC calibrations to the VIS-NIR range with in situ data demonstrating 
 its applicability for the on-the-go acquisition of spectral !
 soil information in the field. Handheld MIR instruments thus have the potential to facilitate quantitative applications in proximal soil sensing, although with less accuracy than achievable with pre-treated samples in the laboratory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;alternative-approach-to-calculate-soil-hydraulic-energy-indices-and--functions&quot;&gt;Alternative approach to calculate soil hydraulic-energy-indices and -functions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Armindo, RA; Wendroth, O&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GEODERMA&lt;/em&gt;, 355 13903-13903; DEC 1 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Soil physical quality (SPQ) is related to soil health and many studies have applied these indices manifesting soil structural behavior. A widely used hydraulic function in this analysis is the soil water retention curve (SWRC) and its integration holds important information, which reflects SPQ diversity. Usually, the SWRC is mathematically describing the relationship between volumetric soil water content (theta) and suction head (h) in the functions theta(h) and h(theta), in which h &amp;gt;= 0 and 0 &amp;lt; theta &amp;lt; 1. Geometrically, a logic way to describe the SWRC is applying the logarithm to the values of h to build the function theta(log(10)h) or log(10)h(theta), however, in this case the graph usually begins at h = 1, since log(10)(1) = 0. In several studies, the concept of the integral integral theta(h)dh [or integral h(theta)d theta] has been presented in the literature since 1978. Unfortunately, the integral integral log(10)h(theta)d theta should be used for h &amp;gt;= 1 in order to avo
 id negative results generated from the domain 0 &amp;lt; h &amp;lt; 1, which would be integrated to the final area under the SWRC. Furthermore, since the fitted values of the parameters of the Van Genuchten-Mualem (VGM) equation are different when functions theta(h) and theta(log(10)h) are used, results of water content at saturation (theta(s)), permanent wilting point (theta(pwp)) and field capacity (theta(fc)) are different as well, questioning the applicability of the integral integral log(10)h(theta)d theta. The objective of this study was to develop a novel approach to calculate hydraulic-energy indices and to improve their capacity to reflect SPQ differences. In this approach, the function theta(h) was parameterized in order to find results for theta(s), theta(pwp) and theta(fc). Then, the function theta(log(10)h) was parameterized to obtain results for theta(s-pF), theta(pwp-pF) and theta(fc-pF), which were tested against theta(s), theta(pwp) and theta(fc). A total of 72 SWRCs were
  analysed with both functions theta(h) and (log(10)h). Resul!
 ts showed that the limits of integration theta(s-pF), theta(pwp-pF) and theta(fc-F) remained the same by keeping the same ranges of available water and drainable porosity, as in the case when the function theta(h) was used. This new approach turned out more suitable than the original approach for calculating hydraulic-energy indices, because it was more sensitive to reveal SPQ differences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mapping-lucas-topsoil-chemical-properties-at-european-scale-using-gaussian-process-regression&quot;&gt;Mapping LUCAS topsoil chemical properties at European scale using Gaussian process regression&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Ballabio, C; Lugato, E; Fernandez-Ugalde, O; Orgiazzi, A; Jones, A;
Borrelli, P; Montanarella, L; Panagos, P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GEODERMA&lt;/em&gt;, 355 13912-13912; DEC 1 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
This paper presents the second part of the mapping of topsoil properties based on the Land Use and Cover Area frame Survey (LUCAS). The first part described the physical properties (Ballabio et al., 2016) while this second part includes the following chemical properties: pH, Cation Exchange Capacity (CEC), calcium carbonates (CaCO3), C:N ratio, nitrogen (N), phosphorus (P) and potassium (K). The LUCAS survey collected harmonised data on changes in land cover and the state of land use for the European Union (EU). Among the 270,000 land use and cover observations selected for field visit, approximately 20,000 soil samples were collected in 24 EU Member States in 2009 together with more than 2000 samples from Bulgaria and Romania in 2012. The chemical properties maps for the European Union were produced using Gaussian process regression (GPR) models. GPR was selected for its capacity to assess model uncertainty and the possibility of adding prior knowledge in the form of covaria
 nce functions to the model.The derived maps will establish baselines that will help monitor soil quality and provide guidance to agroenvironmental research and policy developments in the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/10/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on October 31, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2019/10/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2019/10/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2019-10-30T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2019-10-30T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2019-14&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2019 #14&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prediction of soil organic matter using multi-temporal satellite images in the Songnen Plain, China&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Predicting 2,4-dintroanisole (DNAN) sorption on various soil “types” using different compositional datasets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A concept to optimize the accuracy of soil surface area and SOC stock quantification in mountainous landscapes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evaluating sampling efforts of standard laboratory analysis and mid-infrared spectroscopy for cost effective digital soil mapping at field scale&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Texas Soil Observation Network: A Comprehensive Soil Moisture Dataset for Remote Sensing and Land Surface Model Validation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consistency Between NASS Surveyed Soil Moisture Conditions and SMAP Soil Moisture Observations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prediction-of-soil-organic-matter-using-multi-temporal-satellite-images-in-the-songnen-plain-china&quot;&gt;Prediction of soil organic matter using multi-temporal satellite images in the Songnen Plain, China&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Dou, X; Wang, X; Liu, HJ; Zhang, XL; Meng, LH; Pan, Y; Yu, ZY; Cui, Y&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GEODERMA&lt;/em&gt;, 356 13896-13896; DEC 15 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Due to confounding factors such as crop residue and soil moisture, soil organic matter (SOM) is usually estimated from soil samples in a laboratory or in the field at a local scale. In this study, laboratory and field data of crop residue, soil moisture, crop management practices, and SOM content were used in concert with multi-temporal MODIS images captured during bare soil periods over three years to construct spectral indices, which were then used as input variables to build a regional-scale SOM prediction model. Results showed that: (1) multi-temporal satellite images can be used to predict SOM content at a regional scale; (2) crop residue cover and time interval between snow melt, rainfall, and ploughing determined the optimal input variables for SOM prediction; (3) compared to a SOM model based on a single image, a multi-temporal model reduced the influence of soil moisture and improved both the stability and the accuracy of SOM prediction; (4) the best models generally
  used the ratio of MODIS Band 6 and Band 1 (R-61) as an input variable, as R-61 showed good correlation with SOM and less correlation with moisture; and (5) comparing different models in different years showed that models performed better in years with less crop residue. The study results can be used to improve the accuracy of quantitative estimates of the soil organic carbon pool and provide assistance in digital soil mapping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;predicting-24-dintroanisole-dnan-sorption-on-various-soil-types-using-different-compositional-datasets&quot;&gt;Predicting 2,4-dintroanisole (DNAN) sorption on various soil “types” using different compositional datasets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Chappell, MA; Seiter, JM; West, HM; Miller, LF; Negrete, ME; LeMonte,
JJ; Porter, BE; Price, CL; Middleton, MA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GEODERMA&lt;/em&gt;, 356 13916-13916; DEC 15 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Soil heterogeneity is a major contributor to the uncertainty in predicting the environmental fate of data-scare contaminants. For this paper, we focused on research designed to predict the soil environmental fate of the new munition compound, called 2,4-dinitroanisole (DNAN) -a compound increasingly employed by the U.S. and international militaries in the next-generation, insensitive explosive formulations. Here, we employed multi-variate statistical correlation models to predict DNAN sorption among different soil “types” seeking to reduce the uncertainty common in all contaminant sorption models by using soil taxonomic designation as a calibrant. We collected composite soils classified under the Ultisols taxonomic Order in the U.S. National Resource Conservation Service soil classification system and quantified their properties via physical and chemical characterizations. Using multivariate statistical modeling modified for compositional data analysis (CoDa), we developed qu
 antitative analogies of the Ultisols by partitioning the characterization data up into four different compositions: Water-extracted, Mehlich-III (referring to the weak acid) extracted, particle-size distribution, and solid-phase carbon-nitrogen-sulfur compositions. DNAN sorption was measured in batch soil suspensions and distribution coefficients (K-D) were calculated using linear regression modeling. Prediction models testing the correlation of the DNAN K-D values to the centered logratio-transformed compositions were calculated using CoDa-modified multilinear regression. Results showed that DNAN sorption was only predictable by dissolved organic carbon, pH, and the exchangeable cations Ca and K within the water-extracted composition. Analogies for DNAN sorption were the most discriminating at the Suborder level because of the inherent ambiguity in the Hapludults class at the Great Group level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-concept-to-optimize-the-accuracy-of-soil-surface-area-and-soc-stock-quantification-in-mountainous-landscapes&quot;&gt;A concept to optimize the accuracy of soil surface area and SOC stock quantification in mountainous landscapes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Prietzel, J; Wiesmeier, M&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GEODERMA&lt;/em&gt;, 356 13922-13922; DEC 15 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
A correct quantification of soil surface and soil organic carbon (SOC) stocks is crucial for the evaluation of important soil functions, including atmospheric C sequestration. At present, soil science lacks (i) a clear definition of soil depth, (ii) consented procedures for soil sampling, as well as (iii) adequate awareness concerning pitfalls and caveats associated with quantification of soil surface area and large-scale SOC stocks in mountainous, complex landscapes. Traditional SOC stock quantification in these landscapes often did not adequately address site-specific geomorphological conditions and thus yielded incorrect results due to combination of incompatible methods for soil depth assessment, soil profile or core sampling, and soil surface area calculation. In our paper, we suggest unequivocal definitions of soil depth, horizon thickness, and SOC density, which can be applied for soils in sloping as well as flat terrain. Moreover, we quantify and discuss potential SOC
  (and other soil nutrient) stock assessment errors in mountainous regions, using the German Alps as case study. We present a protocol to ensure an unbiased quantification of soil surface area, as well as SOC or nutrient element stocks in mountainous landscapes. Taking into account the considerable area of sloping terrain on the global scale, and particularly in mountainous countries (e.g. Switzerland, Austria, Andes Countries, Nepal, Japan), our publication will contribute to a more accurate quantification of soil stocks of SOC and important nutrients as well as area-based C fluxes (e.g. CO2 sequestration or release) or other surface-related biogeochemical fluxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evaluating-sampling-efforts-of-standard-laboratory-analysis-and-mid-infrared-spectroscopy-for-cost-effective-digital-soil-mapping-at-field-scale&quot;&gt;Evaluating sampling efforts of standard laboratory analysis and mid-infrared spectroscopy for cost effective digital soil mapping at field scale&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Paul, SS; Coops, NC; Johnson, MS; Krzic, M; Smukler, SM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GEODERMA&lt;/em&gt;, 356 13925-13925; DEC 15 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The performance of digital soil mapping (DSM) model is highly reliant on the intensity and spatial distribution of the input soil data points. Increasing the number of soil data points (i.e. samples) improves the accuracy of the prediction, but it also raises the sampling effort, including the time, money and labor required for field and laboratory analysis. Thus, optimizing the production of DSMs requires maximizing accuracy while minimizing cost. In this study, we evaluated a range of strategies for DSM of a farm field using high spatial resolution ancillary environmental data (e.g. unmanned aerial vehicle-UAV imagery) and compared sampling efforts of soil data generated from standard laboratory analysis (SLA) and mid-infrared spectroscopy (MIRS) at equivalent costs. We produced DSMs of a number of soil properties including sand, silt, clay, pH, salinity, organic matter, and total nitrogen. We employed Conditioned Latin Hypercube Sampling (cLHS) to generate a range of sampl
 ing efforts from the full SLA (n = 62) and MIRS (n = 308) datasets and contrasted the DSM outcomes modeled using kriging with external drift (KED). We found that the DSM outputs were most effective, in terms of accuracy and cost, at 50-60% of the full sampling effort. Although MIRS predictions of soil properties introduced a sizable amount of error, DSMs produced using the MIRS dataset were more accurate as compared to the outcomes of SLA datasets at equivalent sampling efforts. The prediction accuracy for DSMs varied across the soil properties with R-2 ranging from 0.82 (for sand) to 0.45 (for total nitrogen) at the optimum sampling effort. The outcomes of the study highlight that spatially optimized sampling efforts and the use of the MIRS technique substantially improve the cost efficiency and accuracy of kriging-based DSM models for predicting a range of field scale soil properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-texas-soil-observation-network-a-comprehensive-soil-moisture-dataset-for-remote-sensing-and-land-surface-model-validation&quot;&gt;The Texas Soil Observation Network: A Comprehensive Soil Moisture Dataset for Remote Sensing and Land Surface Model Validation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Caldwell, TG; Bongiovanni, T; Cosh, MH; Jackson, TJ; Colliander, A;
Abolt, CJ; Casteel, R; Larson, T; Scanlon, BR; Young, MH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;VADOSE ZONE JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, 18 (1):34-34; SEP 26 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The spatiotemporal variability of soil water content (SWC) at the remote sensing scale requires dense monitoring for calibration and validation. Here, we present an overview of the Texas Soil Observation Network (TxSON), an intensively monitored area in the semiarid rangelands of the central Texas Hill Country. TxSON is a dense network consisting of 40 in situ locations nested at 36, 9, and 3 km within the Equal-Area Scalable Earth Grid and serves as a Core Calibration and Validation Site for NASA’s Soil Moisture Active Passive mission. The 4-yr dataset consists of hourly SWC measured at 5, 10, 20, and 50 cm. The SWC data are upscaled using arithmetic, Voronoi, and inverse distance weighting for 36-, (2) 9-, and (5) 3-km grid cells. We present the site selection, environmental characteristics, network design, quality assurance (QA), upscaling algorithms, and data structure. Ancillary data include bulk density, particle size, and carbon content for each site and depth. We also
  provide automated QA for each location and scripts to use our binary flagging in upscaling methods. To summarize, the 36-km grid cell has a mean bulk density of 1.34 +/- 0.18 g cm(-3) and a loam textural class. The in situ SWC has a root mean square error of 0.029 m(3) m(-3) against gravimetric data from 14 field campaigns. TxSON continues to add new locations with additional dense networks planned in other ecotones of the Edwards Plateau. The time series data along with scripts to import, plot, and upscaled SWC are available at https:// doi .org/10.18738/T8/JJ16CF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;consistency-between-nass-surveyed-soil-moisture-conditions-and-smap-soil-moisture-observations&quot;&gt;Consistency Between NASS Surveyed Soil Moisture Conditions and SMAP Soil Moisture Observations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Colliander, A; Yang, ZW; Mueller, R; Sandborn, A; Reichle, R; Crow, W;
Entekhabi, D; Yueh, S&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;WATER RESOURCES RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, NIL_1-NIL_12; SEP 6 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The U.S. Department of Agriculture National Agricultural Statistics Survey (NASS) collects and publishes crop growth status and soil moisture conditions in major U.S. agricultural regions. The operationally produced weekly reports are based on survey information. The surveys are based on visual assessments and-in the case of soil moisture-report soil moisture levels in one of four categories (Very Short, Short, Adequate, and Surplus). In this study, we show that these reports have remarkable correspondence with the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Soil Moisture Active Passive (SMAP) Level-4 Soil Moisture (L4SM) product. This consistency allows for combining the two different types of data to produce a value-added assessment, which enables cropland soil moisture mapping and state-level statistics. Moreover, it enables daily assessment rather than weekly. In this study classification thresholds are derived for L4SM by mapping cumulative distribution functions of L4
 SM surface and root zone SM to the categorical NASS SM conditions. The results show that, year over year, the SMAP cumulative SM distributions are consistent with the NASS SM conditions and, furthermore, that the temporal evolution of the SMAP-derived thresholds is consistent with the seasonal crop growth cycles from year to year. The results signify that the SMAP SM retrievals are relatable to SM estimation conducted in agricultural crop land by land managers and farmers, which underlines the general applicability of the SMAP data.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/10/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on October 30, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>
