<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Smart Digital Agriculture</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2022-11-08T14:10:13+11:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2022/11/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2022/11/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2022-11-08T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2022-11-08T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2022-21&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2022 #21&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Factors controlling SOC stability in colluvial soils under contrasting climate and soil weathering conditions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The dynamic changes of soil air-filled porosity associated with soil shrinkage in a Vertisol&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The probability-based granular field of vegetated soils&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understanding geological reports based on knowledge graphs using a deep learning approach&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feeding existing expertise into a possibly ‘new’ theory for soil health?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remote sensing of land change: A multifaceted perspective&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Dutch soil physical units map: BOFEK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-dutch-soil-physical-units-map-bofek&quot;&gt;The Dutch soil physical units map: BOFEK&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soils and their properties play an important role in land evaluation studies. Often such studies focus on larger scales ranging from watersheds up to the national scale or even larger. Soil properties are often known at smaller scales, sometimes at the level of individual soil samples. The aim of this study is to show how point information on soil hydraulic properties, i.e., water retention and hydraulic conductivity characteristics, can be upscaled via soil textural classes to a soil physical units map of a region or nation. Base information is the Dutch soil map (1:50,000) and the hydraulic properties of individual soil samples. All individual soil samples for which hy-draulic properties were measured were divided based on their texture into eighteen top-soils and eighteen sub-soils. For each of these thirty-six groups geometric average water retention and hydraulic conductivity charac-teristics were derived. In total 368 derived soil profiles are distinguished in the Dutch soil map consisting of soil layers that are linked to the thirty-six texture groups. For each soil profile eight static hydraulic properties were calculated. The soil profiles were then clustered based on these properties into seventy-nine clusters or units, which then make up a soil physical units map for the Netherlands. It has been demonstrated that dynamically simulated transpiration reduction for the clustered situation is similar to obtained for all individual soil profiles. At the Dutch national scale, the difference in simulated transpiration reduction between runs using all 368 soil profiles or the 79 soil physical units was less than 2.5 % percentage-points in 96 % of all plots or less than 5 % percentage-points in 99 % of all plots. Similar good correspondence was obtained for other water balance terms as well, including actual transpiration, actual evaporation at the soil surface, degree of saturation at 15 and 30 cm depth, the integrated water flux at 100 cm depth and surface runoff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;remote-sensing-of-land-change-a-multifaceted-perspective&quot;&gt;Remote sensing of land change: A multifaceted perspective&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The discipline of land change science has been evolving rapidly in the past decades. Remote sensing played a major role in one of the essential components of land change science, which includes observation, monitoring, and characterization of land change. In this paper, we proposed a new framework of the multifaceted view of land change through the lens of remote sensing and recommended five facets of land change including change location, time, target, metric, and agent. We also evaluated the impacts of spatial, spectral, temporal, angular, and data-integration domains of the remotely sensed data on observing, monitoring, and characterization of different facets of land change, as well as discussed some of the current land change products. We recommend clarifying the specific land change facet being studied in remote sensing of land change, reporting multiple or all facets of land change in remote sensing products, shifting the focus from land cover change to specific change metric and agent, integrating social science data and multi-sensor datasets for a deeper and fuller understanding of land change, and recognizing limitations and weaknesses of remote sensing in land change studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;understanding-geological-reports-based-on-knowledge-graphs-using-a-deep-learning-approach&quot;&gt;Understanding geological reports based on knowledge graphs using a deep learning approach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geological reports aid in understanding exploration by providing valuable information on rock formation , evolution and the geological environment in which deposits formed. Querying and extracting the critical information from these enormous historical geological report data helps in understanding the exploration risks in different geological settings. However, large amounts of unstructured text data occur in geological reports; therefore, it is challenging to obtain valuable information from them without performing information extraction and processing. This study proposed an automated method for extracting information from geological reports through triple extraction, then automatically constructs a geological knowledge graph from the extracted entities and relations. Simultaneously, due to the lack of samples, this study used multiple geological reports to construct a corpus of jointly extracted geological entities and relations. The proposed model reached an F1-score of 90.05% in the experimental results on the constructed corpus. Finally, a knowledge graph was constructed based on the extracted results to demonstrate the application value of the proposed method. The results showed that the structured information helps better represent the content of the source report and matches well with the geological domain knowledge. The proposed method can quickly and robustly convert textual data into a structured form that is convenient for reasoning and querying geological entities and relations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-probability-based-granular-field-of-vegetated-soils&quot;&gt;The probability-based granular field of vegetated soils&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soils in vegetation-covered areas are of high variability in space and time, and the variability is crucial for hydro-geophysical processes at small and large scales. Conventionally, the spatial heterogeneity at large scale is visualized as a regional division map of soil properties by extrapolating sample measurements. No formalized method is available for assigning parameters for soils at the resolution of a small grid cell. This study formulates a method of establishing parameter space for vegetated soil by a single index (mu) derived from the unified grain size distribution (GSD). The index mu varies in space as a random variable and defines soil as a granular field. The mu-division represents the concentration of fine grains in response to root-soil interactions. Coupling mu-division with moisture distribution suggests that the gradient of mu plays a potential role in rooted soil hydraulics. It is further found that mu satisfies the Weibull distribution, which makes it possible to establish the mu-field for a soil space at large scale using the random dataset of mu. A case study is conducted in two vegetated slopes based on high-resolution digital elevation models (DEM) derived from unmanned aerial vehicle survey to create the field and illustrate its implications in morphology and hydrology. It is expected that the mu-field may derive parameter fields of various soil properties as functions of the GSD parameters and thus equip DEM with a complete dataset of soil. The paradigm proposed in the study fills the gap of establishing high-resolution data space for soil at large scale for dynamics of surface processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;factors-controlling-soc-stability-in-colluvial-soils-under-contrasting-climate-and-soil-weathering-conditions&quot;&gt;Factors controlling SOC stability in colluvial soils under contrasting climate and soil weathering conditions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although agricultural colluvial soils are important storage for soil organic carbon (SOC), the mechanisms underlying colluvial (cumulative soils) SOC stability have received little attention so far. In this study, we aim to understand to what extent the main controls on colluvial SOC stability differ from those observed in non-colluvial soils. Paired soil profiles (non-colluvial versus colluvial) were collected from five sites which differ in climate, soil geochemical background and cultivation history. Topsoil (0-10 cm) and subsoil (30-50 cm) were analysed for SOC fractions, mineral composition, potential soil respiration and radiocarbon content. Our analysis showed that for non-colluvial soils, climate, cultivation history and weathering degree have significant effects on potential soil respiration. In contrast, for colluvial soils, the most influential factor for potential soil respiration was the rate of accretion and this was independent of climatic and geochemical context. Furthermore, accretion rates indirectly affected potential soil respiration by interacting with the degree of weathering of deposited soil. This changed the mineral matrix of colluvial soil settings and thereby may enhance soil mineral-related SOC stabilisation mechanisms. Together, these results suggest that the dominant controls on SOC stability in colluvial soils differ from those in non-colluvial soils, and the soil accretion rate is the most important control on colluvial SOC stability in agricultural systems. Highlights The dominant controls on SOC stability in colluvial and non-colluvial soils were compared. Climate and mineral weathering predominantly control SOC stability in non-colluvial soils. In contrast, the accretion rate is the key factor controlling colluvial SOC stability. Accretion rate drives the role of mineral weathering in colluvial SOC stability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-dynamic-changes-of-soil-air-filled-porosity-associated-with-soil-shrinkage-in-a-vertisol&quot;&gt;The dynamic changes of soil air-filled porosity associated with soil shrinkage in a Vertisol&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil aeration is critical for crop growth, which is generally assessed by air-filled porosity (AFP). In non-rigid soils with high shrinkage and swelling, the AFP is not only related to the total porosity and soil moisture, but also to the soil shrinkage behaviour. However, the relationship between AFP and soil shrinkage has not been clarified. The objectives of this study were to (1) establish a mathematical equation to describe the behaviours of AFP associated with soil shrinkage (AFP(sh)); and (2) to evaluate the influence of tillage practice on the AFP(sh). Undisturbed soil core samples were collected from the 0-10 cm to 10-20 cm layers in a Vertisol under four tillage treatments (No tillage, NT; Rotary tillage, RT; Subsoiling, SS; Deep ploughing, DP) to measure the changes in the volumes of soil core, soil water and air at different soil matric potentials. Our results showed that an equation of AFP(sh) as a function of moisture ratio (&amp;amp; thetasym;) was well established based on the developed soil shrinkage model (R-2 &amp;gt; 0.990, RMSE &amp;lt;0.012). Compared with the AFP under a constant pore assumption (AFP(c)), the AFP(sh) was significantly decreased by 10.6% to 60.3% as soil water matric potentials were at &amp;lt;-33 kPa in the 0-10 cm layer or at &amp;lt;-10 kPa in the 10-20 cm layer (p &amp;lt; 0.05). According to the AFP(sh) curve of the Vertisol, soil moisture content (theta) was approximately 68%-80% of the field capacity when AFP(sh) reached non-limiting status (0.10 cm(3) cm(-3)), where the soil matric potential was close to the wilting point (-1500 kPa). Deep tillage treatment (SS and DP) increased AFP(sh), showing good performance in decreasing the risk of soil aeration deficit relative to the NT and RT treatment. Our results demonstrate that neglecting the porosity variations during shrinkage may lead to a high bias in the AFP prediction. Highlights An equation of AFP associated with soil shrinkage was established. AFP was significantly decreased when soil shrinkage was considered for a Vertisol. The Vertisol was easily subjected to both water and air stress due to soil shrinkage. Deep tillage practises improved soil aeration in the Vertisol.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/11/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on November 08, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2022/11/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2022/11/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2022-11-07T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2022-11-07T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2022-20&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2022 #20&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visual assessment of soil structural quality across soil textures and compaction levels - Part II: Examination of profile walls vs Intact soil cores.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evaluation of aggregate stability methods for soil health&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From point to field scale-indirect monitoring of soil moisture variations at the DWD test site in Falkenberg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visual assessment of soil structural quality across soil textures and compaction levels - Part I: Examination of intact soil cores&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil organic matter storage in temperate lowland arable, grassland and woodland topsoil and subsoil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remote Sensing of Groundwater: Current Capabilities and Future Directions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Differentiable, Learnable, Regionalized Process-Based Models With Multiphysical Outputs can Approach State-Of-The-Art Hydrologic Prediction Accuracy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;differentiable-learnable-regionalized-process-based-models-with-multiphysical-outputs-can-approach-state-of-the-art-hydrologic-prediction-accuracy&quot;&gt;Differentiable, Learnable, Regionalized Process-Based Models With Multiphysical Outputs can Approach State-Of-The-Art Hydrologic Prediction Accuracy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Predictions of hydrologic variables across the entire water cycle have significant value for water resources management as well as downstream applications such as ecosystem and water quality modeling. Recently, purely data-driven deep learning models like long short-term memory (LSTM) showed seemingly insurmountable performance in modeling rainfall runoff and other geoscientific variables, yet they cannot predict untrained physical variables and remain challenging to interpret. Here, we show that differentiable, learnable, process-based models (called delta models here) can approach the performance level of LSTM for the intensively observed variable (streamflow) with regionalized parameterization. We use a simple hydrologic model HBV as the backbone and use embedded neural networks, which can only be trained in a differentiable programming framework, to parameterize, enhance, or replace the process-based model’s modules. Without using an ensemble or post-processor, delta models can obtain a median Nash-Sutcliffe efficiency of 0.732 for 671 basins across the USA for the Daymet forcing data set, compared to 0.748 from a state-of-the-art LSTM model with the same setup. For another forcing data set, the difference is even smaller: 0.715 versus 0.722. Meanwhile, the resulting learnable process-based models can output a full set of untrained variables, for example, soil and groundwater storage, snowpack, evapotranspiration, and baseflow, and can later be constrained by their observations. Both simulated evapotranspiration and fraction of discharge from baseflow agreed decently with alternative estimates. The general framework can work with models with various process complexity and opens up the path for learning physics from big data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;remote-sensing-of-groundwater-current-capabilities-and-future-directions&quot;&gt;Remote Sensing of Groundwater: Current Capabilities and Future Directions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Globally, groundwater represents a critical natural resource that is affected by changes in natural supply and renewal, as well as by increasing human demand and consumption. However, despite its critical role, groundwater is difficult to accurately quantify as it is beneath the Earth surface. Here, we review several state-of-the-art remote sensing techniques useful for local- to global-scale groundwater monitoring and assessment, including proxies for groundwater extraction. These include inferring changes in subsurface water from mass changes using gravitational measurements, and analyzing changes in the Earth surface height using Interferometric Synthetic Aperture Radar, Light Detection and Ranging, Airborne Electromagnetic Systems, and satellite altimetry. Remote sensing information is often used in tandem with ground-based observations such as hydraulic head in wells, Global Navigational Satellite System monitoring, and numerical modeling to complement the space-based approaches. In the future, fusing different remote sensing techniques capable of operating in various environments will yield additional insight on the state and rate of use for groundwater across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-organic-matter-storage-in-temperate-lowland-arable-grassland-and-woodland-topsoil-and-subsoil&quot;&gt;Soil organic matter storage in temperate lowland arable, grassland and woodland topsoil and subsoil&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soils are the largest terrestrial pool of organic carbon, with up to 50% of soil organic carbon (SOC) stored below 30 cm. Knowledge of the impact of land use on the mechanisms by which SOC is stored in subsoils is critical to developing and delivering strategies to mitigate climate change. We characterized SOC under arable, grassland, and deciduous woodland land uses in lowland England to determine how land use affects the mechanisms by which topsoil and subsoil SOC are protected. Soil organic matter (SOM) physical fractionation and ammonium oxalate extractable Al, Fe and Mn were analysed to elucidate protection mechanisms. Results revealed that the mineral-free particulate organic matter (fPOM) fraction was significantly greater in both the topsoil and subsoil under woodland than under grassland or arable. The mineral-associated organic carbon (MinOC) fraction was proportionally greater in the subsoil compared with topsoil under all land uses, with arable &amp;gt;grassland &amp;gt; woodland. These findings indicate that land use affects the extent to which SOC is protected, with woodlands containing a higher proportion of carbon that has less protection from decomposition. Subsoil SOC is protected from decomposition by organo-mineral interactions with amorphous Al, Fe and Mn, and may be susceptible to future pH shifts as a result of land use change. This study highlights the need to consider the impact of land use change on SOC, given policy and public interest in woodland planting for climate change mitigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;visual-assessment-of-soil-structural-quality-across-soil-textures-and-compaction-levels---part-i-examination-of-intact-soil-cores&quot;&gt;Visual assessment of soil structural quality across soil textures and compaction levels - Part I: Examination of intact soil cores&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil structural degradation has become very common and leads to a serious decline in soil health. Improving or maintaining soil structure is key to build resilience against drought and flooding, and thus contributes to assuring food and water security. Quantification of soil structural quality is usually accomplished by traditional laboratory-based methods, which are time-, labour-and money-consuming. Visual soil evaluation and exami-nation methods comprise rapid and simple tests that offer a numeric semi-quantitative assessment of soil structure. The common criteria are aggregate size and shape, ease of break or rupture resistance, and inter-or intra-aggregate porosity. In this study, the CoreVESS method, a variant of the Visual Evaluation of Soil Structure (VESS) method originally developed for topsoil assessment, was applied on 250 cm(3) undisturbed soil core samples. Resulting soil quality scores (Sq, ranging between 1, good, and 5, poor) were compared with soil quality indicators (SQi) derived from traditional quantitative methods of soil structure analysis. Tested SQi’s included penetration resistance, bulk density, soil hydraulic properties, soil organic carbon and texture (percentage of clay, silt and sand). The objective of the study was to assess and quantify the state of soil structural degradation induced by agricultural operations using a suite of methods of analysis at a regional scale, with a special focus on CoreVESS. Soil core samples were taken in Belgium from 42 cropped fields, at two positions (headland and in-field zone) and from three layers, notably the ploughed topsoil (TOP, 10-20 cm), the compacted subsoil (CSUB, 30-40 cm) and the deeper subsoil (SUB, 60-70 cm), totalling the sample horizons to 252. Test and sampling sites comprised all major soil texture classes within the Belgian soil textural triangle and varied from sand to heavy clay. In-field positions (IN-FIELD) showed significantly better coreVESS-based Sq scores as compared to headland positions (HEAD), with the CSUB layers always exhibiting significantly lower quality than the other two layers. Laboratory-derived soil quality indicator (SQi) values portrayed the same trend, with CSUB layers always indicating the poorest soil quality. Significant differences in SQi’s were also found between soils of acceptable (Sq &amp;amp; LE; 3) and degraded (Sq &amp;gt; 3) structure. Likewise, grouping soils into the same categories resulted in significant differences in the soil water retention and hydraulic conductivity curves in their wet ranges. There were good significant relationships between the SQi values and CoreVESS-based Sq scores, with for example Pearson R correlation coefficients of 0.64 for both penetration resistance and bulk density. Also, Sq scores related well with an SQi-based soil quality index (SQI) value averaged per layer and texture class (Pearson R of 0.60). The study confirmed that agricultural operations and their intensity clearly affect soil structural quality across various soil textures, with CoreVESS being as responsive to variation in soil structure quality as traditional quantitative methods, even when applied in the subsoil. VESS methods thus have a potential for monitoring soil structural quality over a variety of textures in a rapid, intuitive, practical and cheap way, as an alternative for or being complementary to more expensive labour-intensive traditional quantitative methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;from-point-to-field-scale-indirect-monitoring-of-soil-moisture-variations-at-the-dwd-test-site-in-falkenberg&quot;&gt;From point to field scale-indirect monitoring of soil moisture variations at the DWD test site in Falkenberg&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information regarding the spatial distribution of soil water content is key in many disciplines and applications including soil and atmospheric sciences, hydrology, and agricultural engineering. Thus, within the past decades various experimental methods and strategies have been developed to map spatial variations in soil moisture distribution and to monitor temporal changes. Our study examines the combination of electrical resistivity mapping and point observations of soil moisture to infer the spatial and the temporal variability of soil moisture. Over a period of around two years, we performed field measurements on six days to collect repeated electrical resistivity mapping data for a nine-hectare test site south-east of Berlin, Germany. Permanently installed TDR probes, temporary TDR measurements within permanently installed tubes, and gravimetric measurements using soil samples provided soil moisture data at various selected points. In addition, soil analysis and classification results are available for 132 regularly distributed positions up to depths of 1.2 m. We compare and link three-dimensional resistivity models obtained via data inversion to soil composition and soil moisture as provided by our point data. Both the soil samples and the resistivity models indicate a two-layer medium characterized by a sandy top layer with varying thickness and a loamy bottom soil. For all six field campaigns, we observe similar resistivity patterns reflecting the temporally stable influence of soil texture. While the overall patterns are stable, the range of resistivity values changes with soil moisture. Finally, to estimate spatial models of soil moisture, we link our soil moisture and resistivity data using empirical petrophysical models relying on a second order polynomial function. We observe a mean prediction error for soil moisture of +/-0.034 m3 &amp;amp; BULL; m? 3 using all observation points while we notice that point-specific models further reduce the error. Thus, we conclude that our experimental and data analysis strategies represent a reliable approach to establish site-specific models and to estimate three-dimensional moisture distribution including temporal variations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evaluation-of-aggregate-stability-methods-for-soil-health&quot;&gt;Evaluation of aggregate stability methods for soil health&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aggregate stability is a commonly used indicator of soil health because improvements in aggregate stability are related to reduced erodibility and improved soil-water dynamics. During the past 80 to 90 years, numerous methods have been developed to assess aggregate stability. Limited comparisons among the methods have resulted in varied magnitudes of response to soil health management practices and varied influences of inherent soil properties and climate. It is not clear whether selection of a specific method creates any advantage to the investigator. This study assessed four commonly used methods of measuring aggregate stability using data collected as part of the North American Project to Evaluate Soil Health Measurements. The methods included water stable aggregates using the Cornell Rainfall Simulator (WSACASH), wet sieved water stable aggregates (WSAARS), slaking captured and adapted from SLAKES smart-phone image recognition software (STAB10), and the mean weight diameter of water stable aggregates (MWD). Influence of climate and inherent soil prop-erties at the continental scale were analyzed in addition to method responses to rotation diversity, cash crop count, residue management, organic nutrient amendments, cover crops, and tillage. The four methods were moderately correlated with each other. All methods were sensitive to differences in climate and inherent soil properties between sites, although to different degrees. None measured significant effects from rotation diversity or crop count, but all methods detected significant increases in aggregate stability resulting from reduced tillage. Significant increases or positive trends were observed for all methods in relation to cover cropping, increased residue retention, and organic amendments, except for STAB10, which expressed a slightly negative response to organic amendments. Considering these results, no single method was clearly superior and all four are viable options for measuring aggregate stability. Therefore, secondary considerations (e.g., cost, method availability, increased sensitivity to a specific management practice, or minimal within-treatment variability) driven by the needs of the investigator, should determine the most suitable method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;visual-assessment-of-soil-structural-quality-across-soil-textures-and-compaction-levels---part-ii-examination-of-profile-walls-vs-intact-soil-cores&quot;&gt;Visual assessment of soil structural quality across soil textures and compaction levels - Part II: Examination of profile walls vs Intact soil cores&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visual Evaluation of Soil Structure (VESS) methods receive increasing attention and are gaining popularity. Since in modern agriculture, soil structure degradation becomes very common, it is essential to protect and improve soil structure quality. Methods that enable its straightforward monitoring are therefore needed. Numerous visual soil evaluation techniques that serve this purpose exist, and are varying in objective, evaluation depth (topsoil/ subsoil), evaluation method, number of criteria assessed and their final scoring. In this study, we mainly focus on three VESS methods, two of which were employed in the field along a profile wall (Visual Evaluation of Subsoil Structure, SubVESS, and Double Spade VESS method, DSVESS), and one in the laboratory on soil cores (Cor-eVESS). The main aim of this research was to test and compare these VESS-based methods in terms of their feasibility and repeatability in detecting soil structure degradation in the topsoil and subsoil. Sixteen cropped fields were chosen in Belgium covering six of seven major soil texture classes according to the Belgian soil textural triangle (i.e., sand, loamy sand, light sandy loam, silt loam, clay, and heavy clay). SubVESS and DSVESS were performed in the same pits until 80 cm and 40 cm, respectively. Soil cores for CoreVESS and for the determination of soil quality indicators (SQi) with conventional laboratory methods were taken from three layers, that is, the ploughed topsoil (-10–20 cm, “TOP”), the compacted subsoil (-30–40 cm, “CSUB”), and the deeper subsoil (-60–70 cm, “SUB”), totalling 96 horizons. While SubVESS and CoreVESS were originally developed to evaluate subsoil and topsoil, respectively, they were thus used here beyond those zones. Moreover, all sampling and field evaluation was done at two positions per field -the more compacted headland and the less compacted in-field zone. It was shown that the soil quality (Sq) scores assigned to the cores with CoreVESS were not significantly influenced by operators with different backgrounds but all having received basic VESS training. When comparing field and laboratory results, positive relationships were found between Sq scores of SubVESS, DSVESS and CoreVESS. All VESS methods were able to assign significantly better soil quality (lower scores) at in-field positions (IN-FIELD) as compared to headland positions (HEAD), and significantly lower quality (higher scores) to CSUB layers than to the other two layers. Laboratory-derived SQi values presented a similar trend, with CSUB layers always indicating worse situations. There were good significant relationships between the SQi values and the different VESS-based Sq scores as well, with DSVESS showing the best correlations among the three VESS methods. The study thus confirmed that the different VESS methods all have a potential for moni-toring soil structure quality in a fast, cheap, intuitive and practical way, although they all have their own ad-vantages and disadvantages. Additionally, those methods that were employed at depths other than those for which they were developed did perform well.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/11/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on November 07, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2022/11/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2022/11/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2022-11-04T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2022-11-04T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2022-19&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2022 #19&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Characterizing Groundwater Chemistry and Recharge in the Critical Zone of an Agricultural Claypan Watershed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Halving nitrogen waste in the European Union food systems requires both dietary shifts and farm level actions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anthropogenic dark earth: Evolution, distribution, physical, and chemical properties&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;LUCAS Soil Biodiversity and LUCAS Soil Pesticides, new tools for research and policy development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Explainable AI for earth observation: A review including societal and regulatory perspectives&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Knowledge representation in digital agriculture: A step towards standardised model&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monitoring changes in global soil organic carbon stocks from space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;monitoring-changes-in-global-soil-organic-carbon-stocks-from-space&quot;&gt;Monitoring changes in global soil organic carbon stocks from space&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soils are under threat globally, with declining soil productivity and soil health in many places. As a key indicator of soil functioning, soil organic carbon (SOC) is crucial for ensuring food, soil, water and energy security, together with biodiversity protection. While there is a global effort to map SOC stock and status, SOC is a dynamic soil property and can change rapidly as a function of land management and land use. Here, we introduce a semi-mechanistic model to monitor SOC stocks at a global scale, underpinned by one of the largest worldwide soil database to date. Our model generates a SOC stock baseline for the year 2001, which is then propagated through time by keeping track of annual landcover changes obtained from remote sensing products with loss and gain dynamics dependent on temperature and precipitation, which finally define the magnitude, rate and direction of the SOC changes. We estimated a global SOC stock in the top 30 cm of around 793 Pg with annual losses due to landcover change of 1.9 Pg SOC yr-1 from 2001 to 2020, 20% larger than the annual production-based emissions of the United States in 2018. The biggest losses were found in the tropic and sub-tropical regions, accounting for almost 50% of the total global loss. This is a considerable contribution to greenhouse gas emissions but it also has a direct impact on agricultural production with more than 16 million hectares yr-1 falling below critical SOC limits. The proposed modelling framework is flexible, allowing it to be updated as more remote sensing and soil data becomes available, offering a first-of-its-kind global spatio-temporal SOC stock assessment and monitoring system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;knowledge-representation-in-digital-agriculture-a-step-towards-standardised-model&quot;&gt;Knowledge representation in digital agriculture: A step towards standardised model&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent years, data science has evolved significantly. Data analysis and mining processes become routines in all sectors of the economy where datasets are available. Vast data repositories have been collected, curated, stored, and used for extracting knowledge. And this is becoming commonplace. Subsequently, we extract a large amount of knowledge, either directly from the data or through experts in the given domain. The challenge now is how to exploit all this large amount of knowledge that is previously known for efficient decision-making processes. Until recently, much of the knowledge gained through a number of years of research is stored in static knowledge bases or ontologies, while more diverse and dynamic knowledge acquired from data mining studies is not centrally and consistently managed. In this research, we propose a novel model called ontology-based knowledge map to represent and store the results (knowledge) of data mining in crop farming to build, maintain, and enrich the process of knowledge discovery. The proposed model consists of six main sets: concepts, attributes, relations, transformations, instances, and states. This model is dynamic and facilitates the access, updates, and exploitation of the knowledge at any time. This paper also proposes an architecture for handling this knowledge-based model. The system architecture includes knowledge modelling, extraction, assessment, publishing, and exploitation. This system has been implemented and used in agriculture for crop management and monitoring. It is proven to be very effective and promising for its extension to other domains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;explainable-ai-for-earth-observation-a-review-including-societal-and-regulatory-perspectives&quot;&gt;Explainable AI for earth observation: A review including societal and regulatory perspectives&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence and machine learning are ubiquitous in the domain of Earth Observation (EO) and Remote Sensing. Congruent to their success in the domain of computer vision, they have proven to obtain high accuracies for EO applications. Yet experts of EO should also consider the weaknesses of complex, machine-learning models before adopting them for specific applications. One such weakness is the lack of explainability of complex deep learning models. This paper reviews published examples of explainable ML or explainable AI in the field of Earth Observation. Explainability methods are classified as: intrinsic versus post-hoc, model-specific versus model -agnostic, and global versus local explanations and examples of each type are provided. This paper also iden-tifies key explainability requirements identified the social sciences and upcoming regulatory recommendations from UNESCO Ethics of Artificial Intelligence and requirements from the EU draft Artificial Intelligence Act and analyzes whether these limitations are sufficiently addressed in the field of EO.The findings indicate that there is a lack of clarity regarding which models can be considered interpretable or not. EO applications often utilize Random Forests as an “interpretable” benchmark algorithm to compare to complex deep-learning models even though social sciences clearly argue that large Random Forests cannot be considered as such. Secondly, most explanations target domain experts and not possible users of the algorithm, regulatory bodies, or those who might be affected by an algorithm’s decisions. Finally, publications tend to simply provide explanations without testing the usefulness of the explanation by the intended audience. In light of these societal and regulatory considerations, a framework is provided to guide the selection of an appropriate machine learning algorithm based on the availability of simpler algorithms with a high predictive accuracy as well as the purpose and intended audience of the explanation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lucas-soil-biodiversity-and-lucas-soil-pesticides-new-tools-for-research-and-policy-development&quot;&gt;LUCAS Soil Biodiversity and LUCAS Soil Pesticides, new tools for research and policy development&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The European Green Deal puts a healthy environment at the core of policy-making initiatives in the European Union (EU). Soil, due to its nature, is a central actor to be considered when developing and implementing actions in many areas, from biodiversity and agriculture to climate and pollution. New means for monitoring the impact of decisions taken in these sectors are needed. The Land Use and Coverage Area frame Survey (LUCAS modules of Soil Biodiversity and Pesticides provide both policy-makers and the research community with tools in this direction. The first component corresponds to the largest analysis of soil biodiversity across the EU through molecular biology techniques. The second component is the most extensive harmonised pan-European assessment of pesticide residues in agricultural soils. Specific features, together with policy and research potential of these instruments for achieving Green Deals targets under the Biodiversity 2030 Strategy, the Farm to Fork Strategy and the Zero Pollution Action Plan, are presented. All generated data are made available to the public through the EU Soil Observatory and European Soil Data Centre. Highlights LUCAS Soil Biodiversity is a monitoring survey of biodiversity in the European Union. LUCAS Soil Pesticides is a monitoring survey of pesticide residues in the European Union. Protocols and data from LUCAS Soil Biodiversity and Pesticides are open access. LUCAS Soil Biodiversity and Pesticides can support policy and research development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;anthropogenic-dark-earth-evolution-distribution-physical-and-chemical-properties&quot;&gt;Anthropogenic dark earth: Evolution, distribution, physical, and chemical properties&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anthropogenic dark earth (ADE) is a category of Anthrosols (anthropogenic soils) characterised by dark colour from homogeneous charcoal inclusion and extraordinary fertility compared with non-anthropogenic soils. The study aims to provide a detailed overview of the origin and distributions of ADEs, together with their physical and chemical characteristics, to reveal their fertility status for arable land use. According to this study, most studied ADEs are well distributed in tropical (Amazonian and African dark earth) and temperate (European dark earth) climatic regions. Middens are localised, with large-sized ones well preserved in the Arctic region due to the wet and cold weather conditions. The formation of ADE is mainly associated with deliberate and unintentional ancient human activities: deposition of domestic and occupational wastes, charred residues, biomass ashes, burning, and fertilisation of fields. The characteristic dark colour of ADE resulted mainly from charcoal and the decomposition of organic wastes. The material composition of ADEs (including charcoal, organic matter, and clay) contributes to the formation of sizable pores for the retention of water and elements and aeration. ADE exhibits a C:N ratio for good mineralization, stable organic matter stock, and higher cation exchange capacity. Additionally, ADEs are characterised by circum-neutral reactions and enriched by nutrients (C, N, P, Ca, Mg, Mn, Cu, Zn, Mn, and Fe) and other elements (Sr, Rb, and Ba) compared with surrounding non-anthropogenic soils. Although generally highly productive, a comparison of herbage production and crop yields between ADEs and natural soils is not well studied. The persistence of anthropogenic activities that lead to the formation of ADE indicates that these soils are still subject to continuous development, especially in rural settings. Adopting the process of ADE development in recent arable land can represent a promising future for sustainable agriculture. Highlights Anthropogenic dark earths (ADEs) are characterized by their physical and chemical signatures. Characteristic high pore size of ADEs due to charcoal inclusion support the retention of nutrients. ADEs are often have reduced acidity and high C, N, P, Ca, Mg, Mn, Cu, Zn, Mn, and Fe contents. ADEs represent an archive of fertile soils suitable for sustainable agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;halving-nitrogen-waste-in-the-european-union-food-systems-requires-both-dietary-shifts-and-farm-level-actions&quot;&gt;Halving nitrogen waste in the European Union food systems requires both dietary shifts and farm level actions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pivotal role of nitrogen to achieve environmental sustainable development goals and transform our food system is recognized in an ambitious nitrogen waste reduction target in the Farm to Fork Strategy of the European Commission. But is this a realistic objective and if so, what are the pathways that lead to success? To answer these questions, we first established, as a baseline, an updated food system nitrogen budget for the EU for the year 2015. The EU used 20 Tg of virgin (new) N to deliver 2.5 Tg N in food and 1.2 Tg N in fibres to consumers, yielding a food-system nitrogen use efficiency (NUE) of 18%. We then built a simple model to combine intervention options that (a) increase farm level nitrogen use efficiencies, (b) reduce food waste increase recycling of waste and improve waste treatment, or (c) achieve a dietary shift towards healthier dietary patterns. The largest potential to increase N efficiency of the current agro-food system was found to lie in the livestock sector. From 144 possible combinations of intervention options analysed, we found that 12 combinations of interventions would reduce nitrogen losses by about 50%, 11 involving diet change. We further carried out an assessment of the societal appreciation of combinations of interventions considering private and public costs of the intervention measures, public benefit through effects on health and increased biodiversity of ecosystems, and public costs for overcoming socio-cultural barriers. Results show that a combination of moderate intervention options achieve halving of N losses at lowest societal costs. We conclude that systemic approaches are paramount to achieve deep nitrogen reduction targets and diet change appears to be an essential condition for success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;characterizing-groundwater-chemistry-and-recharge-in-the-critical-zone-of-an-agricultural-claypan-watershed&quot;&gt;Characterizing Groundwater Chemistry and Recharge in the Critical Zone of an Agricultural Claypan Watershed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soils with low permeability horizons (e.g., claypans) are vulnerable to loss of nutrients through surface runoff along with preferential flow paths through the restrictive horizon to deeper aquifers. Partitioning between these hydrologic pathways is important to determine transport processes and develop strategies that mitigate stream contamination. Our objective was to investigate controls on groundwater chemistry and recharge pathways using natural geochemical tracers in the Goodwater Creek Experimental Watershed in Missouri, U.S. Groundwater samples were collected during 2011-2017 from 32 piezometers ranging from 0.13 to 16 m deep along with stream water and precipitation. Diagnostic tools of mixing models indicated that chemistry of perched water directly above the claypan and shallow groundwater immediately below was controlled primarily by chemical equilibrium. Five solutes behaved conservatively in most deep piezometers (&amp;gt;5 m), reflecting mixing of two end members and the lack of significant denitrification processes. End member mixing analysis showed that the deeper groundwater originated primarily from groundwater at similar depths, often upslope or from strata directly above, with small contributions from perched water, highlighting the importance of both horizontal and vertical preferential recharge pathways. Vertical pathways are likely dictated by soil heterogeneity throughout the critical zone and do not occur synchronously with precipitation events or simultaneously over all piezometer locations. The complex recharge pathways provide stochastic conduits for nitrate transport to deeper aquifers where legacy stores accumulate, presenting a significant challenge for water quality management in watersheds with restrictive soil horizons and spatially and temporally heterogeneous preferential flow pathways, including the Mississippi River Basin.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/11/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on November 04, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2022/09/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2022/09/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2022-09-15T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2022-09-15T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2022-18&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2022 #18&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover crop functional types differentially alter the content and composition of soil organic carbon in particulate and mineral-associated fractions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design and development of low-power, long-range data acquisition system for beehives-BeeDAS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the Uncertainty Induced by Pedotransfer Functions in Terrestrial Biosphere Modeling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deep-C storage: Biological, chemical and physical strategies to enhance carbon stocks in agricultural subsoils&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil health and microplastics: a review of the impacts of microplastic contamination on soil properties&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil acidification induced by intensive agricultural use depending on climate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-acidification-induced-by-intensive-agricultural-use-depending-on-climate&quot;&gt;Soil acidification induced by intensive agricultural use depending on climate&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Purpose Soil acidification is a major issue in agricultural ecosystems. However, how agricultural land uses shape the soil pH pattern and affect soil acidification on a regional scale are still poorly understood. The research aims to investigate the influences of typical agricultural practices on soil acidification across different climate zones of eastern China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Materials and methods Soil samples were collected from 240 sites and 3 land uses per site (uplands, paddies, and adjacent woodlands) across four climate zones (mid-temperate, warm temperate, subtropical, and tropical regions) of eastern China. Soil pH was quantified for each soil samples. The mean annual temperature (MAT) and mean annual precipitation (MAP) at each site were also analyzed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Results and discussion Climate was significantly associated with soil acidification. The differences in soil pH between adjacent land use types ranged from 0.02 to 1.12, whereas those between climate zones ranged from 0.34 to 2.22. Alkaline soils (cooler climates) exhibited a stronger acidification pace than acidic soils (warmer climates). Uplands resulted in alarming decrease in soil pH by 1.12 units relative to adjacent woodlands in mid-temperate zone, which may be induced by the dramatic loss of soil carbon. Acidification of uplands was stronger than that of paddies, owing to higher soil nitrification and carbon mineralization. Croplands had higher soil pH than adjacent woodlands only in the subtropics, indicating that agricultural practices in this zone were effective to retard soil acidification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusion We demonstrated, for the first time, the direction and intensity of the differences in soil pH levels among adjacent agricultural lands and woodlands depending on climate. As the two common agricultural croplands across eastern China, uplands have stronger acidification relative to paddies, particularly in the mid-temperate zone. Proper agricultural management practices to avoid carbon losses and preserve the flooding status of paddies should be considered to resist acidification of cropland soils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-health-and-microplastics-a-review-of-the-impacts-of-microplastic-contamination-on-soil-properties&quot;&gt;Soil health and microplastics: a review of the impacts of microplastic contamination on soil properties&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Purpose Soil is a thin coating of matter that covers the earth’s surface, formed through the process of rock weathering. It is a natural filter for impurities in groundwater and is very important to human health. Recently, some studies from around the world have confirmed that the presence of microplastics in soil is increasing. However, most of these studies only examined the impacts of soil microplastic contamination one or two soil health indicators, rather than study all three soil health indicators at once. Methods In this review, we selected papers published internationally in the past decade and examined the trend of the effects of soil microplastic contamination on all three soil health indicators. Results and discussion Soil microplastic contamination resulted in either an increase or decrease in the trend of the effects on physicochemical and biological soil properties. In other cases, microplastic contaminants do not affect soil properties. The alteration of soil health properties by microplastics was associated with a couple of reasons such as microplastic concentrations and types, changes in soil mechanics and microorganisms. Conclusions The current impact and severity of soil microplastic contamination on soil health properties are expected to persist for a long time, especially with increasing global plastic production. Therefore, more research is required to continuously assess the impact of microplastic contamination on other indicators of soil health that has not been studied previously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deep-c-storage-biological-chemical-and-physical-strategies-to-enhance-carbon-stocks-in-agricultural-subsoils&quot;&gt;Deep-C storage: Biological, chemical and physical strategies to enhance carbon stocks in agricultural subsoils&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to their substantial volume, subsoils contain more of the total soil carbon (C) pool than topsoils. Much of this C is thousands of years old, suggesting that subsoils offer considerable potential for long-term C sequestration. However, knowledge of subsoil C behaviour and manageability remains incomplete, and subsoil C storage potential has yet to be realised at a large scale, particularly in agricultural systems. A range of biological (e.g. deep-rooting), chemical (e.g. biochar burial) and physical (e.g. deep ploughing) C sequestration strategies have been proposed, but are yet to be assessed. In this review, we identify the main factors that regulate subsoil C cycling and critically evaluate the evidence and mechanistic basis of subsoil strategies designed to promote greater C storage, with particular emphasis on agroecosystems. We assess the barriers and opportunities for the implementation of strategies to enhance subsoil C sequestration and identify 5 key current gaps in scientific understanding. We conclude that subsoils, while highly heterogeneous, are in many cases more suited to long-term C sequestration than topsoils. The proposed strategies may also bring other tangible benefits to cropping systems (e.g. enhanced water holding capacity and nutrient use efficiency). Furthermore, while the subsoil C sequestration strategies we reviewed have large potential, more long-term studies are needed across a diverse range of soils and climates, in conjunction with chronosequence and space-for-time substitutions. Also, it is vital that subsoils are more consistently included in modelled estimations of soil C stocks and C sequestration potential, and that subsoil-explicit C models are developed to specifically reflect subsoil processes. Finally, further mapping of subsoil C is needed in specific regions (e.g. in the Middle East, Eastern Europe, South and Central America, South Asia and Africa). Conducting both immediate and long-term subsoil C studies will fill the knowledge gaps to devise appropriate soil C sequestration strategies and policies to help in the global fight against climate change and decline in soil quality. In conclusion, our evidence-based analysis reveals that subsoils offer an untapped potential to enhance global C storage in terrestrial ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;on-the-uncertainty-induced-by-pedotransfer-functions-in-terrestrial-biosphere-modeling&quot;&gt;On the Uncertainty Induced by Pedotransfer Functions in Terrestrial Biosphere Modeling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hydrological, ecohydrological, and terrestrial biosphere models depend on pedotransfer functions for computing soil hydraulic parameters based on easily measurable variables, such as soil textural and physical properties. Several pedotransfer functions have been derived in the last few decades, providing divergent estimates of soil hydraulic parameters. In this study, we quantify how uncertainties embedded in using different pedotransfer functions propagate to ecosystem dynamics, including simulated hydrological fluxes and vegetation response to water availability. Using a state-of-the-art ecohydrological model applied at 79 sites worldwide, we show that uncertainties related to pedotransfer functions can affect both hydrological and vegetation dynamics. Uncertainties in evapotranspiration, plant productivity, and vegetation structure, quantified as leaf area, are in the order of similar to 10% at annual time scales. Runoff and groundwater recharge uncertainties are one order of magnitude larger. All uncertainties are largely amplified when small-scale topography is taken into account in a distributed domain, especially for water-limited ecosystems with low permeability soils. Overall, pedotransfer function related uncertainties for a given soil type are higher than uncertainties across soil types in both hydrological and ecosystem dynamics. The magnitude of uncertainties is climate-dependent but not soil type-dependent. Evapotranspiration, vegetation structure, and plant productivity uncertainties are higher in water-limited semiarid climates, whereas groundwater recharge uncertainties are higher in climates where potential evapotranspiration is comparable to precipitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cover-crop-functional-types-differentially-alter-the-content-and-composition-of-soil-organic-carbon-in-particulate-and-mineral-associated-fractions&quot;&gt;Cover crop functional types differentially alter the content and composition of soil organic carbon in particulate and mineral-associated fractions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cover crops (CCs) can increase soil organic carbon (SOC) sequestration by providing additional OC residues, recruiting beneficial soil microbiota, and improving soil aggregation and structure. The various CC species that belong to distinct plant functional types (PFTs) may differentially impact SOC formation and stabilization. Biogeochemical theory suggests that selection of PFTs with distinct litter quality (C:N ratio) should influence the pathways and magnitude of SOC sequestration. Yet, we lack knowledge on the effect of CCs from different PFTs on the quantity and composition of physiochemical pools of SOC. We sampled soils under monocultures of three CC PFTs (legume [crimson clover]; grass [triticale]; and brassica [canola]) and a mixture of these three species, from a long-term CC experiment in Pennsylvania, USA. We measured C content in bulk soil and C content and composition in contrasting physical fractions: particulate organic matter, POM; and mineral-associated organic matter, MAOM. The bulk SOC content was higher in all CC treatments compared to the fallow. Compared to the legume, monocultures of grass and brassica with lower litter quality (wider C:N) had higher proportion of plant-derived C in POM, indicating selective preservation of complex structural plant compounds. In contrast, soils under legumes had greater accumulation of microbial-derived C in MAOM. Our results for the first time, revealed that the mixture contributed to a higher concentration of plant-derived compounds in POM relative to the legume, and a greater accumulation of microbial-derived C in MAOM compared to monocultures of grass and brassica. Mixtures with all three PFTs can thus increase the short- and long-term SOC persistence balancing the contrasting effects on the chemistries in POM and MAOM imposed by monoculture CC PFTs. Thus, despite different cumulative C inputs in CC treatments from different PFTs, the total SOC stocks did not vary between CC PFTs, rather PFTs impacted whether C accumulated in POM or MAOM fractions. This highlights that CCs of different PFTs may shift the dominant SOC formation pathways (POM vs. MAOM), subsequently impacting short- and long-term SOC stabilization and stocks. Our work provides a strong applied field test of biogeochemical theory linking litter quality to pathways of C accrual in soil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;design-and-development-of-low-power-long-range-data-acquisition-system-for-beehives-beedas&quot;&gt;Design and development of low-power, long-range data acquisition system for beehives-BeeDAS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decision making capability of a system is highly dependent upon the quality and quantity of training data. Majority of beehive monitoring systems developed for research purposes are designed to collect data through a small set of sensors, and from locations with little geographic diversity. This hinders the development of a dataset that can be used to effectively train machine learning models. In this work, we explain the design and development of a multi-sensory, remote data acquisition system for beehives (BeeDAS), with focus on low-power consumption and long-range communication. We address design challenges associated with such systems and highlight the critical issues that need consideration. The proposed system enables collection of data from beehives at remote locations and harsh environment. Results of field deployments elucidate the effectiveness of various sensors which measure temperature, humidity, atmospheric pressure, CO2, acoustics, vibrations and the weight of a hive in hostile environment. This work also uses random forest regression to evaluate the feature importance of different sensors, environmental variables such as temperature, humidity, rain, wind speed as well as the information related to seasons, towards estimating the daily hive weight change, on a dataset comprised of 1,250 days of sensor recordings. We also evaluate the protocol designed for communication using Narrow Band Internet of Things (NB-IoT). The issues related to power optimization, sleep intervals and data storage in remote monitoring are also discussed.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/09/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on September 15, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2022/09/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2022/09/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2022-09-07T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2022-09-07T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2022-17&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2022 #17&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An evaluation of carbon indicators of soil health in long-term agricultural experiments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new criterion based on estimator variance for model sampling in precision agriculture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forest and Freshwater Ecosystem Responses to Climate Change and Variability at US LTER Sites&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cross-Site Comparisons of Dryland Ecosystem Response to Climate Change in the US Long-Term Ecological Research Network&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Responses of Coastal Ecosystems to Climate Change: Insights from Long-Term Ecological Research&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Long-Term Ecological Research on Ecosystem Responses to Climate Change&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spatiotemporal assessments of nutrients and water quality in coastal areas using remote sensing and a spatiotemporal deep learning model&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tillage strategies optimize SOC distribution to reduce carbon footprint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tillage-strategies-optimize-soc-distribution-to-reduce-carbon-footprint&quot;&gt;Tillage strategies optimize SOC distribution to reduce carbon footprint&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tillage methods and nitrogen (N) application are critical for soil organic carbon (SOC) sequestration and crop production. However, both tillage and N are the main contributors to the carbon footprint (CF) in agricultural production. A 6-year-long field experiment was conducted under a winter wheat-summer maize cropping system in Northern China to test how tillage methods (RT, annual rotary tillage; DT, annual deep tillage; and TT, RT applied annually with a DT interval of two years) and N rates (300 kg ha(-1), N300; 225 kg ha(-1), N225; 165 kg ha(-1), N165) affect SOC sequestration, greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions, and annual grain yield. And, the CF was used to evaluate ecological sustainability. RT preferentially sequestrated SOC in the 0-10 cm soil layer. In the 10-30 cm soil layers, 2.87-3.82 and 1.85-2.53 Mg ha(-1) greater SOC were respectively observed under DT and TT than RT, which was conducive to maximizing annual grain yield with less N application (N225) relative to traditional farming practice (RT-N300). Both increasing N rate and deep tillage resulted in obvious increases in the total GHG emissions. N fertilizer production and transportation were the greatest contributors, accounting for 40.4-47.0% of the total GHG emissions, followed by direct N2O and CH4 emissions (23.5-30.5%). TT-N225 significantly reduced CF (CF including SOC sequestration was 0.49 Mg CO2 eq ha(-1) year(-1) lower than DT -N225, and was 1.87 Mg CO2 eq ha(-1) year(-1) lower than RT-N300) and maintained high crop productivity while creating appropriate soil conditions and thus may be a much cleaner agricultural strategy in Northern China. And, the strategy of reducing N application in agricultural production by improving soil properties of the plow layer in this study can also be referred to in other ecological regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spatiotemporal-assessments-of-nutrients-and-water-quality-in-coastal-areas-using-remote-sensing-and-a-spatiotemporal-deep-learning-model&quot;&gt;Spatiotemporal assessments of nutrients and water quality in coastal areas using remote sensing and a spatiotemporal deep learning model&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Revealing the spatiotemporal variations of nutrients in coastal waters is crucial to the understanding and evaluation of coastal environment, thereby providing efficient guidance for the aquatic environmental treatment. This study proposed a spatiotemporal-incorporated deep learning model, which is easily applicable to establish the quantitative relationships between measured environmental factors and large-scale satellite maps, and can reduce estimation errors by more than 40% compared with non-spatiotemporal-incorporated deep learning model. The spatiotemporal distributions of dissolved inorganic nitrogen (DIN) and dissolved inorganic phosphate (DIP) over 44400 km(2) of the East China Sea on 8-day scale from 2010 to 2018 were obtained. Based on the spatiotemporal variations, the water quality patterns were depicted, and the fluctuation variations of the two essential nutrients were found in the harbors with complex anthropogenic influences, in the typical estuaries with multiple river inputs, and in the open seas with important fisheries. Although the concentration of DIN and DIP decreased by 24% and 19% in 9 years, respectively, the water quality level in the inshore sea has not been significantly improved, especially in autumn and winter. Further, we quantitatively analyzed the main factors of deteriorated water and provided scientific suggestions for targeted monitoring and regional cooperative governances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;long-term-ecological-research-on-ecosystem-responses-to-climate-change&quot;&gt;Long-Term Ecological Research on Ecosystem Responses to Climate Change&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article marking the 40th anniversary of the US National Science Foundation’s Long Term Ecological Research (LTER) Network, we describe how a long-term ecological research perspective facilitates insights into an ecosystem’s response to climate change. At all 28 LTER sites, from the Arctic to Antarctica, air temperature and moisture variability have increased since 1930, with increased disturbance frequency and severity and unprecedented disturbance types. LTER research documents the responses to these changes, including altered primary production, enhanced cycling of organic and inorganic matter, and changes in populations and communities. Although some responses are shared among diverse ecosystems, most are unique, involving region-specific drivers of change, interactions among multiple climate change drivers, and interactions with other human activities. Ecosystem responses to climate change are just beginning to emerge, and as climate change accelerates, long-term ecological research is crucial to understand, mitigate, and adapt to ecosystem responses to climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;responses-of-coastal-ecosystems-to-climate-change-insights-from-long-term-ecological-research&quot;&gt;Responses of Coastal Ecosystems to Climate Change: Insights from Long-Term Ecological Research&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coastal ecosystems play a disproportionately large role in society, and climate change is altering their ecological structure and function, as well as their highly valued goods and services. In the present article, we review the results from decade-scale research on coastal ecosystems shaped by foundation species (e.g., coral reefs, kelp forests, coastal marshes, seagrass meadows, mangrove forests, barrier islands) to show how climate change is altering their ecological attributes and services. We demonstrate the value of site-based, long-term studies for quantifying the resilience of coastal systems to climate forcing, identifying thresholds that cause shifts in ecological state, and investigating the capacity of coastal ecosystems to adapt to climate change and the biological mechanisms that underlie it. We draw extensively from research conducted at coastal ecosystems studied by the US Long Term Ecological Research Network, where long-term, spatially extensive observational data are coupled with shorter-term mechanistic studies to understand the ecological consequences of climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cross-site-comparisons-of-dryland-ecosystem-response-to-climate-change-in-the-us-long-term-ecological-research-network&quot;&gt;Cross-Site Comparisons of Dryland Ecosystem Response to Climate Change in the US Long-Term Ecological Research Network&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long-term observations and experiments in diverse drylands reveal how ecosystems and services are responding to climate change. To develop generalities about climate change impacts at dryland sites, we compared broadscale patterns in climate and synthesized primary production responses among the eight terrestrial, nonforested sites of the United States Long-Term Ecological Research (US LTER) Network located in temperate (Southwest and Midwest) and polar (Arctic and Antarctic) regions. All sites experienced warming in recent decades, whereas drought varied regionally with multidecadal phases. Multiple years of wet or dry conditions had larger effects than single years on primary production. Droughts, floods, and wildfires altered resource availability and restructured plant communities, with greater impacts on primary production than warming alone. During severe regional droughts, air pollution from wildfire and dust events peaked. Studies at US LTER drylands over more than 40 years demonstrate reciprocal links and feedbacks among dryland ecosystems, climate-driven disturbance events, and climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;forest-and-freshwater-ecosystem-responses-to-climate-change-and-variability-at-us-lter-sites&quot;&gt;Forest and Freshwater Ecosystem Responses to Climate Change and Variability at US LTER Sites&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forest and freshwater ecosystems are tightly linked and together provide important ecosystem services, but climate change is affecting their species composition, structure, and function. Research at nine US Long Term Ecological Research sites reveals complex interactions and cascading effects of climate change, some of which feed back into the climate system. Air temperature has increased at all sites, and those in the Northeast have become wetter, whereas sites in the Northwest and Alaska have become slightly drier. These changes have altered streamflow and affected ecosystem processes, including primary production, carbon storage, water and nutrient cycling, and community dynamics. At some sites, the direct effects of climate change are the dominant driver altering ecosystems, whereas at other sites indirect effects or disturbances and stressors unrelated to climate change are more important. Long-term studies are critical for understanding the impacts of climate change on forest and freshwater ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-evaluation-of-carbon-indicators-of-soil-health-in-long-term-agricultural-experiments&quot;&gt;An evaluation of carbon indicators of soil health in long-term agricultural experiments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil organic carbon (SOC) is closely tied to soil health. However, additional biological indicators may also provide insight about C dynamics and microbial activity. We used SOC and the other C indicators (potential C mineralization, permanganate oxidizable C, water extractable organic C, and beta-glucosidase enzyme activity) from the North American Project to Evaluate Soil Health Measurements to examine the continental-scale drivers of these indicators, the relationships among indicators, and the effects of soil health practices on indicator values. All indicators had greater values at cooler temperatures, and most were greater with increased precipitation and clay content. The indicators were strongly correlated with each other at the site-level, with the strongest relationship between SOC and permanganate oxidizable C. The indicator values responded positively to decreased tillage, inclusion of cover crops, application of organic nutrients, and retention of crop residue, but not the number of harvested crops in a rotation. The effect of decreased tillage on the C indicators was generally greater at sites with higher precipitation. The magnitude and direction of the response to soil health practices was consistent across indicators within a site but measuring at least two indicators would provide additional confi-dence of the effects of management, especially for tillage. All C indicators responded to management, an essential criterion for evaluating soil health. Balancing the cost, sensitivity, interpretability, and availability at commercial labs, a 24-hr potential C mineralization assay could deliver the most benefit to measure in conjunction with SOC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-new-criterion-based-on-estimator-variance-for-model-sampling-in-precision-agriculture&quot;&gt;A new criterion based on estimator variance for model sampling in precision agriculture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Model sampling has proven to be an interesting approach to optimize the sampling of an agronomic variable of interest at the field level. The use of a model improves the quality of the estimates by making it possible to integrate the information provided by one or more auxiliary data. It has been shown that such an approach gives better estimations compared to more traditional approaches.Through a statistical work describing the properties of model sampling variance, this paper details how the different factors either related to sample characteristics or to the correlation between the auxiliary data and the variable of interest, affect estimation error. The resulting equations show that the use of samples with a mean close to the field mean and with a substantial dispersion reduces the estimation variance. On the basis of these statistical considerations, a variance criterion is defined to compare sample properties. The lower the value of the criterion of a sample, the lower the variance of the estimate and the expected errors. These theoretical insights were applied to real commercial vine fields in order to validate the demonstration.Nine vine fields were considered with the objective to provide the best yield estimation. High resolution vegetative index derived from airborne multispectral image was used to drive the sampling and the estimation. The theoretical considerations were verified on the nine fields; as the observed estimation errors correspond quite well to the values predicted by the equations. The selection of a large number of random samples from these fields confirms that samples associated with higher values of the chosen criterion result, on average, in larger yield estimation errors. Samples with the highest criterion values are associated with mean estimation errors up to two times larger than those of average samples. Random sampling is also compared to two target sampling approaches (Clustering based on quantiles or on k-means algorithm) commonly considered in the literature, whose characteristics improve the value of the proposed criterion. It is shown that these sampling strategies produce samples associated with criterion values up to 100 times smaller than random sampling. The use of these easy-to-implement methods thus guarantees to reduce the variance of the estimation and the esti-mation errors.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/09/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on September 07, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2022/08/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2022/08/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2022-08-15T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2022-08-15T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2022-16&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2022 #16&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Effects of antecedent soil moisture on rill erodibility and critical shear stress&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using Nix color sensor and Munsell soil color variables to classify contrasting soil types and predict soil organic carbon in Eastern India&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Statistically rigorous, model-based inferences from maps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conterminous United States Landsat-8 top of atmosphere and surface reflectance tasseled cap transformation coefficients&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Machine learning for cation exchange capacity prediction in different land uses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pedogenetic processes operating at different intensities inferred by geophysical sensors and machine learning algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drought legacies and ecosystem responses to subsequent drought&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ecosystem health, ecosystem services, and the well-being of humans and the rest of nature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ecosystem-health-ecosystem-services-and-the-well-being-of-humans-and-the-rest-of-nature&quot;&gt;Ecosystem health, ecosystem services, and the well-being of humans and the rest of nature&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An ecosystem is healthy if it is active, maintains its organization and autonomy over time, and is resilient to stress. Healthy ecosystems provide human well-being via ecosystem services, which are produced in interaction with human, social, and built capital. These services are affected by different ecosystem stewardship schemes. Therefore, society should be aiming for ecosystem health stewardship at all levels to maintain and improve ecosystem services. We review the relationship between ecosystem health and ecosystem services, based on a logic chain framework starting with (1) a development or conservation policy, (2) a management decision or origin of the driver of change, (3) the driver of change itself, (4) the change in ecosystem health, (5) the change in the provision of ecosystem services, and (6) the change in their value to humans. We review two case studies to demonstrate the application of this framework. We analyzed 6,131 records from the Ecosystem Services Valuation Database (ESVD) and found that in approximately 58% of the records data on ecosystem health were lacking. Finally, we describe how the United Nations’ System of Environmental-Economic Accounting (SEEA) incorporates ecosystem health as part of efforts to account for natural capital appreciation or depreciation at the national level. We also provide recommendations for improving this system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;drought-legacies-and-ecosystem-responses-to-subsequent-drought&quot;&gt;Drought legacies and ecosystem responses to subsequent drought&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Climate change is expected to increase the frequency and severity of droughts. These events, which can cause significant perturbations of terrestrial ecosystems and potentially long-term impacts on ecosystem structure and functioning after the drought has subsided are often called ‘drought legacies’. While the immediate effects of drought on ecosystems have been comparatively well characterized, our broader understanding of drought legacies is just emerging. Drought legacies can relate to all aspects of ecosystem structure and functioning, involving changes at the species and the community scale as well as alterations of soil properties. This has consequences for ecosystem responses to subsequent drought. Here, we synthesize current knowledge on drought legacies and the underlying mechanisms. We highlight the relevance of legacy duration to different ecosystem processes using examples of carbon cycling and community composition. We present hypotheses characterizing how intrinsic (i.e. biotic and abiotic properties and processes) and extrinsic (i.e. drought timing, severity, and frequency) factors could alter resilience trajectories under scenarios of recurrent drought events. We propose ways for improving our understanding of drought legacies and their implications for subsequent drought events, needed to assess the longer-term consequences of droughts on ecosystem structure and functioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pedogenetic-processes-operating-at-different-intensities-inferred-by-geophysical-sensors-and-machine-learning-algorithms&quot;&gt;Pedogenetic processes operating at different intensities inferred by geophysical sensors and machine learning algorithms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pedogenetic processes such as ferralitization and argilluviation control various soil attributes. Understanding the intensities of pedogenesis can provide answers for several fields of environmental studies, including soil science and the geosciences. Recently, new geotechnologies such as geophysics applied to soil science and machine learning algorithms have proven to be a potential tool in pedosphere studies. In this research, we performed component principal analyses and determined the ideal number of clusters based on geophysical soil data and satellite images. Then, we used the ideal number of clusters, and ferralitization and argilluviation indices, as input data in five modeling (prediction and spatialization) algorithms to infer different ferralitization and argilluviation intensities in soils formed from the same soil parent material. The results showed that avNNet had the best model performance for modeling the clusters showing that the ideal number of clusters was three. The variables which contributed the most to the modeling were the solar diffuse radiation, topographic wetness index, and digital elevation model. The model’s specificity was greater than its sensitivity. The areas over diabase and Nitisols in the east of the study area presented greater ferralitization rates than diabase and Nitisols over western areas. On the other hand, the areas over siltite and Lixisols in the east presented greater argilluviation rates than metamorphosed siltite/siltite and Lixisols over western areas. The relief and topographic position strongly affected the evaluated pedogenetic processes, since they controlled the hydric dynamics in the area. The geophysical variables were related to soil attributes and pedogenesis, which contributed to modeling and clusterization processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;machine-learning-for-cation-exchange-capacity-prediction-in-different-land-uses&quot;&gt;Machine learning for cation exchange capacity prediction in different land uses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cation exchange capacity (CEC) is a major indicator of soil quality and nutrient retention capacity. Despite the considerable progress in CEC prediction using various models, studies to develop CEC pedotransfer functions (PTFs) using machine learning algorithms precisely, such as support vector regression (SVR) and random forest (RF), have not yet been performed in various land uses globally. This study aims to develop, evaluate, and compare the effectiveness of RF and SVR algorithms in determining CEC in different land uses that included agriculture, plantations, grasslands, forests, fallow land and deserts in five countries (Sudan, India, Italy, Iran, and Senegal). A total of 2418 soil samples were fully analyzed and clay, silt, sand, pH, and soil organic carbon (SOC) were the selected covariates for modelling. Both RF and SVR were calibrated with a training dataset (70%, 1693 samples) and validated by the remaining data (30%, 725 samples). The performance and accuracy of both models were evaluated using the Lin’s concordance correlation coefficient (LCCC), root mean square error (RMSE), and normalized root mean square error (NRMSE). The accuracy of the modeling predictions was further analyzed via the Taylor diagram. The findings revealed that clay content showed a positive significant correlation with CEC in all land uses, with highest correlation in desert land use (r = 0.94; p &amp;lt; 0.05). Conversely, CEC was significantly and negatively correlated with sand in all land uses, with highest negative correlation obtained in desert land use (r = -0.84; p &amp;lt; 0.05). The RF algorithm was able to predict the CEC better than SVR in nearly 67% of the validated land use datasets precisely in desert (RMSE = 2.68 cmol(c) kg(-1), NRMSE = 29.9%, and LCCC = 0.94), fallow land (RMSE = 5.12 cmol(c) kg(-1), NRMSE = 55.6%, and LCCC = 0.82), forest (RMSE = 4.78 cmol(c) kg(-1), NRMSE = 78.2%, and LCCC = 0.59), and grassland (RMSE = 8.39 cmol(c) kg(-1), NRMSE = 50.5%, and LCCC = 0.84). Conversely, SVR better predicted CEC in agriculture (RMSE = 5.82 cmol(c) kg(-1), NRMSE = 57.9%, and LCCC = 0.78) and plantation (RMSE = 4.64 cmol(c) kg(-1), NRMSE = 57.9%, and LCCC = 0.74). Therefore, RF represents a promising technique to estimate soil CEC and can be used to derive effective CEC-PTFs in case of limited data availability, due to the lack of time and financial resources when the few basic soil properties are available. The findings reported in this study can be used to verify the suggested CEC-PTFs and/or their improvement. We recommend that further similar studies based on RF and SVR algorithms should consider including land use type in the Whole dataset and clay minerals in the modelling, and then compare the performance of both algorithms considering the climatic regions of the different studied countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conterminous-united-states-landsat-8-top-of-atmosphere-and-surface-reflectance-tasseled-cap-transformation-coefficients&quot;&gt;Conterminous United States Landsat-8 top of atmosphere and surface reflectance tasseled cap transformation coefficients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasseled cap transformation (TCT) has been widely used to decompose satellite multi-spectral information into “brightness”, “greenness”, and “wetness” components. Published TCT coefficients for the Landsat sensor series have mainly been derived using top of atmosphere (TOA) reflectance and sparse data sets. Studies to derive TCT coefficients for Landsat surface reflectance (SR) are lacking. In this study, the TCT coefficients were derived independently for Landsat-8 Operational Land Imager (OLI) SR and TOA reflectance using the Gram-Schmidt orthogonalization (GSO) method. To ensure that the derived TCT coefficients are robust and broadly applicable, representative samples of soil, vegetation, and water were selected from summer and autumn Landsat-8 OLI Analysis Ready Data (ARD) sampled from 40.4 million 30 m pixel locations across the conterminous United States (CONUS). Given that the blue band is susceptible to atmospheric contamination due to its shorter wavelength, two groups of TCT coefficients were derived: one from 6 bands (Blue, Green, Red, NIR, SWIR1, SWIR2) and one from 5 bands without the blue band. As TCT results cannot be validated in a formal way, the TCT components for CONUS summer TOA and SR composites were generated and compared with National Land Cover Database (NLCD) land cover classes to provide a synoptic assessment and provide confidence in the results. In addition, three ARD tiles selected to encompass a mix of land cover types, predominantly, desert in Nevada, wetland and urban in Florida, and agriculture in North Dakota, were used to analyze the seasonal variation of the TCT components. The results demonstrate that the derived Landsat-8 TCT coefficients can effectively characterize brightness, greenness, and wetness components across the CONUS, and show good consistency for discrimination of land cover types and track seasonal surface variations. There was no significant difference between each TCT component derived using the 6-band and 5-band TCT coefficients considering a large sample of CONUS pixels. Therefore, the 5-band TCT coefficients provided in this study are recommended for use, as the blue band is atmospherically sensitive and difficult to atmospherically correct reliably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;statistically-rigorous-model-based-inferences-from-maps&quot;&gt;Statistically rigorous, model-based inferences from maps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Statistically rigorous inferences in the form of confidence intervals for map-based estimates require model-based inferential methods. Model-based mean square errors (MSE) incorporate estimates of both residual variability and sampling variability, of which the latter includes population unit variance estimates and pairwise population unit covariance estimates. Bootstrapping, which can be used with any prediction technique, provides a means of estimating the required variances and covariances. The objectives of the study were to to demonstrate a method for estimating the sampling variability, (Var) over cirucumflex(sam)((mu) over cirucumflex) that can be used with all prediction techniques, to develop an efficient method that map makers can use to disseminate metadata that facilitates calculation of (Var) over cirucumflex(sam)((mu) over cirucumflex) for arbitrary subregions of maps, and to estimate the individual contributions of sampling variability and residual variability to the overall standard error of the prediction of the population mean. The primary results were fourfold: (i) map makers must provide metadata that facilitate estimation of population unit variances and covariances for arbitrary map subregions, (ii) bootstrapping was demonstrated as an effective means of estimating the variances and covariances, (iii) the very large matrix of pairwise population unit covariances can be aggregated into a much smaller matrix that can be readily communicated by map makers to map users, and (iv) MSEs that include only estimates of residual variability and/or estimates of population unit variances, but not estimates of the pairwise population unit covariances, grossly under-estimate the actual MSEs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-nix-color-sensor-and-munsell-soil-color-variables-to-classify-contrasting-soil-types-and-predict-soil-organic-carbon-in-eastern-india&quot;&gt;Using Nix color sensor and Munsell soil color variables to classify contrasting soil types and predict soil organic carbon in Eastern India&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Optimal soil management depends on rapid and frequent monitoring of key soil properties, which are conventionally measured in the laboratory using laborious wet-chemistry protocols. The Nix color sensor has recently exhibited promise for predicting several soil properties using soil color. This study evaluated the relationship between the Munsell Soil Color Chart (MSCC) color values of dry and ground surface soil samples to those re-ported by the Nix color sensor with (Nix(STD)) and without MSCC standardization (Nix(NON-STD)) to classify 371 samples collected from three contrasting soil types, collected from three agroclimatic zones (coastal saline zone, red and laterite zone, and Gangetic alluvial zone) and to predict soil organic carbon (OC) using different multivariate data mining algorithms. Comparing the CIEL&lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt;b* color values reported by the MSCC and the Nix(STD), an acceptable mean color difference (delta E&lt;em&gt;(ab)) value of 5.20 was obtained, indicating the potential accuracy of the Nix sensor. Principal component analysis efficiently clustered the soil types using the RGB variables extracted from the MSCC color chips in tandem with the Nix(STD)/Nix(NON-STD) data. Both classification tree and linear support vector machine algorithms perfectly classified all three contrasting soil types using Nix(NON-STD) data alone. Besides, the combination of the MSCC and the Nix(NON-STD) datasets produced the best OC prediction (R2 = 0.66) via random forest (RF) algorithm and indicated the potential of Nix in digital soil morphometrics. In most of the RF models, redness (a&lt;/em&gt;), yellowness (b*), and yellow (Y) variables appeared influential, presumably because of their negative correlation with OC in red and laterite soils. More research is warranted to measure the impacts of variable soil moisture and other confounding soil morphological features on the soil classification and OC prediction performance to extend the approach for classifying soil types and predicting OC in-situ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;effects-of-antecedent-soil-moisture-on-rill-erodibility-and-critical-shear-stress&quot;&gt;Effects of antecedent soil moisture on rill erodibility and critical shear stress&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antecedent soil moisture is known to exert a complex, perhaps controversial, effect on rill erodibility and critical shear stress. To understand their dynamic nature as a function of antecedent soil moisture, the rill erodibility and critical shear stress for sandy loam and silty loam soil, representing coarse-grained and fine-grained soil, respectively, were measured using a hydraulic flume under six antecedent soil moisture contents, i.e., 3, 6, 9, 12, 15, and 18%. The results show that antecedent soil moisture had a different effect on critical shear stress and rill erodibility for the two different soil textures. As antecedent soil moisture increased, rill erodibility for the finegrained soil first increased and then decreased, whereas for coarse-grained soil, rill erodibility exhibited a decreasing pattern. Conversely, as the antecedent soil moisture increased, the critical shear stress decreased first and then increased for the fine-grained soil, but for coarse-grained soil, the critical shear stress decreased after a slight increase. These different patterns can be interpreted by aggregate slaking, capillary force, soil cementation, and water separation. However, when the patterns of critical shear stress and rill erodibility were neglected, the differences in critical shear stress and rill erodibility between the coarse- and fine-grained soils were not statistically significant (P &amp;lt; 0.05). Therefore, indiscriminate treatments of critical shear stress and rill erodibility for different textural soils under changing antecedent soil moisture regimes may cause errors in soil erosion modeling. The relationship between rill erodibility and critical shear stress for coarse- and fine-grained soils could be fitted by a power and a polynomial function, with R-2 value of 0.94 and 0.78, respectively. Future work should include additional soil textures to study the influence of soil physical characteristics in combination with antecedent soil moisture on soil erosion.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/08/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on August 15, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2022/08/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2022/08/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2022-07-08T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2022-08-03T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2022-15&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2022 #15&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calibration set optimization and library transfer for soil carbon estimation using soil spectroscopy-A review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Figures, landscapes and landsystems: Digital locations, connectivity and communications COMMENT&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sub-sampling a large physical soil archive for additional analyses to support spatial mapping; a pre-registered experiment in the Southern Nations, Nationalities, and Peoples Region (SNNPR) of Ethiopia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A scalable method for the estimation of spatial disaggregation models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-scalable-method-for-the-estimation-of-spatial-disaggregation-models&quot;&gt;A scalable method for the estimation of spatial disaggregation models&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gaining information about detailed processes using aggregation information is a frequent challenge in research involving geospatial data, with examples in different fields of knowledge such as agronomy, soil science, meteorology, public health, epidemiology, and others. Analyses using aggregated data lead to distorted conclusions since they disregard local patterns, and such a problem has motivated different approaches for reconstructing the information in a finer resolution from the aggregated data. However, most existing methods focus on the particular case where the volume of data does not exceed the amount of memory available for computations, a situation that has become increasingly less frequent with the fast pace of data generation nowadays. In practice, this problem limits either spatial resolution or coverage of applications, thus precluding their use in a more general context. In this paper, we address the problem of disaggregation of spatial data with huge datasets by proposing a scalable method to estimate the parameters of a well-established model. We propose an iterative scheme for model estimation and prove its convergence to a critical point of the likelihood function derived. To test the method, we provide a controlled simulation and a real example for sugarcane production in Brazil. In the simulation, the results indicate a successful reconstruction of 1 million pixels from 90 block areas. In the real example, the results had a compatible match with the agronomic literature, indicating a reasonable prediction of sugarcane production in a 100 m spatial resolution (i.e., approx. 5 x 10(8) pixels) from 5,565 block-areas. Compared to the most similar previous work, scalability allowed us to use a nearly 100 times higher resolution, which corresponds to 10,000 times more pixels. With our methods, we expect to assist researchers from different fields in disaggregating spatial information to larger areas or higher resolutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sub-sampling-a-large-physical-soil-archive-for-additional-analyses-to-support-spatial-mapping-a-pre-registered-experiment-in-the-southern-nations-nationalities-and-peoples-region-snnpr-of-ethiopia&quot;&gt;Sub-sampling a large physical soil archive for additional analyses to support spatial mapping; a pre-registered experiment in the Southern Nations, Nationalities, and Peoples Region (SNNPR) of Ethiopia&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The value of physical archives of soil material from field sampling activities has been widely recognized. If we want to use archive material for new destructive analyses to support a task, such as spatial mapping, then an efficient sub-sampling strategy is needed, both to manage analytical costs and to conserve the archive material. In this paper we present an approach to this problem when the objective is spatial mapping by ordinary kriging. Our objective was to subsample the physical archive from the Ethiopia Soil Information System (EthioSIS) survey of the Southern Nations, Nationalities and Peoples Region (SNNPR) for spatial mapping of two variables, concentrations of particular fractions of selenium and iodine in the soil, which had not been measured there. We used data from cognate parts of surrounding regions of Ethiopia to estimate variograms of these properties, and then computed prediction error variances for maps in SNNPR based on proposed subsets of the archive of different size, selected to optimize a spatial coverage criterion (with some close sample pairs included). On this basis a subsample was selected. This is a preregistered experiment in that we have proposed criteria for evaluating the success of our approach, and are publishing that in advance of receiving analytical data on the subsampled material from the laboratories where they are being processed. A subsequent short report will publish the outcome. The use of preregistered trials is widely recommended and used in areas of science including public health, and we believe that it is a sound strategy to promote reproducible research in soil science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;figures-landscapes-and-landsystems-digital-locations-connectivity-and-communications-comment&quot;&gt;Figures, landscapes and landsystems: Digital locations, connectivity and communications COMMENT&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current geomorphological research tends to give preference to landforms rather than landscapes. This commentary brings these notions closer together and incorporates varied views of ‘landscape’ (such as landscapes in art and poetry) as well as showing the difficulties of communicating them to audiences wider than geomorphology. The paper promotes the use of decimal Latitude Longitude (dLL) values to assist better location of samples, analyses and especially landforms, to produce ‘information surfaces’ within landscape and landsystem approaches to geomorphology. This will also help the development of geomorphic visual literacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;calibration-set-optimization-and-library-transfer-for-soil-carbon-estimation-using-soil-spectroscopy-a-review&quot;&gt;Calibration set optimization and library transfer for soil carbon estimation using soil spectroscopy-A review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resource-efficient techniques for accurate soil property estimation are necessary to satisfy the increasing demand for soil data to support environmental monitoring, precision agriculture, and spatial modeling. Over the last 30 yr, infrared soil spectroscopy has developed into a rapid, robust, and cost-effective technique for soil carbon analysis. Ongoing global efforts to make soil spectroscopy operational require the development of soil spectral libraries, which are the main source of data for the construction of calibration models. Understanding calibration optimization is important to ensure the efficient use of soil spectral libraries for the accurate estimation of soil carbon. Moreover, spectral library transfer can benefit new data collection, soil monitoring, and modeling efforts. This review presents techniques for optimization of calibration models and library transfer. Selection of calibration set size and subsetting are presented as current calibration optimization techniques. Moreover, spiking is discussed as an effective technique for spectral library transfer. Overall, studies have suggested that an increase in calibration size improves model performance and this continues until an optimal size is reached. Additionally, subsetting can improve model performance if the resulting subsets reduce the variability of spectrally active components. Studies have also suggested that spiking is effective when used in conjunction with subsetting techniques. These findings denote the current applicability and potential of optimization and library transfer techniques for the accurate estimation of soil carbon with soil spectroscopy. Future efforts should focus on refining optimization techniques to further expand the operability of soil spectroscopy for soil carbon estimation.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/08/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on August 03, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2022/07/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2022/07/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2022-07-29T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2022-07-29T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2022-14&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2022 #14&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Comparison of bagging, boosting and stacking algorithms for surface soil moisture mapping using optical-thermal-microwave remote sensing synergies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Same soil, different climate: Crop model intercomparison on translocated lysimeters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Machine learning in vadose zone hydrology: A flashback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil water potential: A historical perspective and recent breakthroughs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimating textural fractions of the USDA using those of the International System: A quantile approach&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Will fungi solve the carbon dilemma?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Realistic rates of nitrogen addition increase carbon flux rates but do not change soil carbon stocks in a temperate grassland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;realistic-rates-of-nitrogen-addition-increase-carbon-flux-rates-but-do-not-change-soil-carbon-stocks-in-a-temperate-grassland&quot;&gt;Realistic rates of nitrogen addition increase carbon flux rates but do not change soil carbon stocks in a temperate grassland&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changes in the biosphere carbon (C) sink are of utmost importance given rising atmospheric CO2 levels. Concurrent global changes, such as increasing nitrogen (N) deposition, are affecting how much C can be stored in terrestrial ecosystems. Understanding the extent of these impacts will help in predicting the fate of the biosphere C sink. However, most N addition experiments add N in rates that greatly exceed ambient rates of N deposition, making inference from current knowledge difficult. Here, we leveraged data from a 13-year N addition gradient experiment with addition rates spanning realistic rates of N deposition (0, 1, 5, and 10 g N m−2 year−1) to assess the rates of N addition at which C uptake and storage were stimulated in a temperate grassland. Very low rates of N addition stimulated gross primary productivity and plant biomass, but also stimulated ecosystem respiration such that there was no net change in C uptake or storage. Furthermore, we found consistent, nonlinear relationships between N addition rate and plant responses such that intermediate rates of N addition induced the greatest ecosystem responses. Soil pH and microbial biomass and respiration all declined with increasing N addition indicating that negative consequences of N addition have direct effects on belowground processes, which could then affect whole ecosystem C uptake and storage. Our work demonstrates that experiments that add large amounts of N may be underestimating the effect of low to intermediate rates of N deposition on grassland C cycling. Furthermore, we show that plant biomass does not reliably indicate rates of C uptake or soil C storage, and that measuring rates of C loss (i.e., ecosystem and soil respiration) in conjunction with rates of C uptake and C pools are crucial for accurately understanding grassland C storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;will-fungi-solve-the-carbon-dilemma&quot;&gt;Will fungi solve the carbon dilemma?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soils are hotspots of diversity and sustain many globally important functions. Here we focus on the most burning issue: how to keep soils as carbon sinks while maintaining their productivity. Evidence shows that life in soils plays a crucial role in improving soil health yet soil ecological processes are often ignored in soil sciences. In this review, we highlight the potential of fungi to increase soil carbon sequestration while maintaining crop yield, functions needed to sustain human population on Earth and at same time keep the Earth livable. We propose management strategies that steer towards more fungal activity but also high functional diversity of fungi which will lead to more stable carbon sources in soil but also affects the structure of the soil food web up to ecosystem level. We list knowledge gaps that limit our ability to steer soil fungal communities such that stabilising carbon in top soils becomes more effective. Using the natural capacity of a biodiverse soil community to sequester carbon delivers double benefit: reduction of atmospheric carbon dioxide by storing photosynthesized carbon in soil and increasing agricultural yields by restoring organic matter content of degraded soils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;estimating-textural-fractions-of-the-usda-using-those-of-the-international-system-a-quantile-approach&quot;&gt;Estimating textural fractions of the USDA using those of the International System: A quantile approach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In soil science, the two most frequently used classification systems for the soil particle size distribution are the schemes by the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA) and the so-called International System (IS), whose difference is the upper particle size limit of the silt fraction, namely, 0.02 mm for the IS and 0.05 mm for the USDA system. The existence of these and other systems creates a disparity that hinders and prevents the use and exchange of soil information worldwide. To solve this problem, it is necessary to devise methodologies for the conversion of textural fractions between the different classification systems. This work focuses on the estimation of the USDA silt fraction from the basic textural fractions (sand, silt and clay) in the IS. Five models are currently available for that purpose: the log-linear interpolation method, the Minasny-McBratney-Bristow regression formula, the Shirazi-Boersma-Johnson interpolation method, the Minasny-McBratney regression formula, and the Padarian-Minasny-McBratney regression formula. The accuracy of some of these methods has already been assessed, but in this work we develop a new methodology, based on a local quantile regression, which improves and enriches this evaluation, providing both the regions of the textural triangle where the predictions of the models are acceptable, and the regions where each model is most appropriate. The data used were taken from the publicly available National Cooperative Soil Survey Soil Characterization Database, from which more than 270,000 soil horizon samples were selected for having valid texture data. The analysis carried out concludes that the Padarian-Minasny-McBratney regression formula is the best model of those evaluated. In addition, the tool developed for the evaluation of the models becomes a new model that provides point estimates of the USDA silt fraction from the basic textural fractions in the IS, with further improvement, compared to the 5 models evaluated, as it also provides a prediction interval for those estimates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-water-potential-a-historical-perspective-and-recent-breakthroughs&quot;&gt;Soil water potential: A historical perspective and recent breakthroughs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil water potential is a cornerstone in defining the thermodynamic state of soil water required to quantify phenomena such as water phase change, water movement, heat transfer, electric current, chemical transport, and mechanical stress and deformation in the earth’s shallow subsurface environment. This potential has historically been conceptualized as free energy stored in a until volume of soil water. Though the concept of soil water potential has been evolving over the past 120 yr, a consensual definition is still lacking, and answers to some fundamental questions remain controversial and elusive. What are the origins and mechanisms for the free energy of soil water? Can the common mathematical expression of soil water potential as superposition of gravitational, osmotic, and matric potentials be used to define water phase transitions in soil? Are these major components of soil water potential independent or coupled? Is pore water pressure always tensile under unsaturated conditions? If so, how can soil water density be as high as 1.7 g cm(-3)? How do adsorptive soil-water interactions originating from the electromagnetic field around and within soil particles transfer to mechanical pore pressure? In this review, the authors (a) provide critical analysis of historical definitions of soil water potential to identify their strengths, limitations, and flaws; (b) synthesize the origins of electromagnetic energies in soil to clarify the fundamental differences between adsorptive and capillary soil water potential mechanisms; (c) introduce a recently emerging concept of soil matric potential that unifies contributions of adsorption and capillarity to soil water potential; and (d) illustrate the generality and promise of the unified definition of soil water potential for answering some of the fundamental questions that remain elusive to the hydrology, geoengineering, and geoscience communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;machine-learning-in-vadose-zone-hydrology-a-flashback&quot;&gt;Machine learning in vadose zone hydrology: A flashback&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML) have been recently applied extensively in various disciplines of vadose zone hydrology. However, not much attention has been paid to their database-dependent accuracy and uncertainty, reproducibility, and delivery, which undermines their applications to real-world problems. We discuss lessons from the past and emphasize the need for and lack of fundamental protocols (i.e., detailed clarification on data processing, ML models accessibility, and a clear path for reproducing results).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;same-soil-different-climate-crop-model-intercomparison-on-translocated-lysimeters&quot;&gt;Same soil, different climate: Crop model intercomparison on translocated lysimeters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crop model intercomparison studies have mostly focused on the assessment of predictive capabilities for crop development using weather and basic soil data from the same location. Still challenging is the model performance when considering complex interrelations between soil and crop dynamics under a changing climate. The objective of this study was to test the agronomic crop and environmental flux-related performance of a set of crop models. The aim was to predict weighing lysimeter-based crop (i.e., agronomic) and water-related flux or state data (i.e., environmental) obtained for the same soil monoliths that were taken from their original environment and translocated to regions with different climatic conditions, after model calibration at the original site. Eleven models were deployed in the study. The lysimeter data (2014-2018) were from the Dedelow (Dd), Bad Lauchstadt (BL), and Selhausen (Se) sites of the TERENO (TERrestrial ENvironmental Observatories) SOILCan network. Soil monoliths from Dd were transferred to the drier and warmer BL site and the wetter and warmer Se site, which allowed a comparison of similar soil and crop under varying climatic conditions. The model parameters were calibrated using an identical set of crop- and soil-related data from Dd. Environmental fluxes and crop growth of Dd soil were predicted for conditions at BL and Se sites using the calibrated models. The comparison of predicted and measured data of Dd lysimeters at BL and Se revealed differences among models. At site BL, the crop models predicted agronomic and environmental components similarly well. Model performance values indicate that the environmental components at site Se were better predicted than agronomic ones. The multi-model mean was for most observations the better predictor compared with those of individual models. For Se site conditions, crop models failed to predict site-specific crop development indicating that climatic conditions (i.e., heat stress) were outside the range of variation in the data sets considered for model calibration. For improving predictive ability of crop models (i.e., productivity and fluxes), more attention should be paid to soil-related data (i.e., water fluxes and system states) when simulating soil-crop-climate interrelations in changing climatic conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comparison-of-bagging-boosting-and-stacking-algorithms-for-surface-soil-moisture-mapping-using-optical-thermal-microwave-remote-sensing-synergies&quot;&gt;Comparison of bagging, boosting and stacking algorithms for surface soil moisture mapping using optical-thermal-microwave remote sensing synergies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil moisture information is key to irrigation water management, drought monitoring, and yield prediction. It plays a vital role in the water cycle and energy budget between the earth’s surface and atmosphere. Hence, its monitoring is crucial for both natural and anthropogenic environments. While the current remote sensing-based global SM products available at coarser resolution (3/15 km) are unsuitable for field-level operations, the most widely used microwave remote sensing suffers from model complexities and in-situ data requirements. Weather conditions limit the alternate approaches such as optical/thermal. This study aims to map surface soil moisture (SSM) at 30 m spatial resolution in a semi-arid region by fusing optical, thermal, and microwave remote sensing data using bagging, boosting, and stacking machine learning approaches. The reference data were collected using a soil moisture meter. The covariates included radar backscatter from Sentinel-1, visible, near-infrared, shortwave infrared, land surface temperature, and spectral indices derived from Landsat 8. Boruta algorithm was used for feature selection which identified radar backscatter, modified normalized difference water index, and land surface temperature as the most critical covariates impacting the SSM. The random forest (RF) showed the highest correlation coefficient (r = 0.71), and least root mean square error (RMSE = 5.17%). The cubist model had the least mean bias error (MBE = 0.21%) during independent validation. Stacking of cubist, gradient boosting machine (GBM), and RF using elastic net (ELNET) as meta-learner further reduced the MBE (0.18%) and RMSE (5.03%) during the validation. Overall, stacking multiple machine learning models improved model prediction and can be recommended to improve the digital soil moisture mapping.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/07/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on July 29, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2022/07/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2022/07/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2022-07-17T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2022-07-17T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2022-13&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2022 #13&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil-water characteristic curves and their estimated hydraulic parameters in no-tilled and conventionally tilled soils.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fusion of visible-to-near-infrared and mid-infrared spectroscopy to estimate soil organic carbon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Capacity and Intensity Indicators to evaluate the effect of different crop sequences and cover crops on soil physical quality of two different textured soils from Pampas Region&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Discrete element modeling of aggregate shape and internal structure effects on Weibull distribution of tensile strength&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Diffuse reflectance spectroscopy characterises the functional chemistry of soil organic carbon in agricultural soils&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rigorous, empirical, and quantitative: a proposed pipeline for soil health assessments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The benefits and trade-offs of agricultural diversity for food security in low-and middle-income countries: A review of existing knowledge and evidence&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accounting for ecosystem service values in climate policy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-benefits-and-trade-offs-of-agricultural-diversity-for-food-security-in-low-and-middle-income-countries-a-review-of-existing-knowledge-and-evidence&quot;&gt;The benefits and trade-offs of agricultural diversity for food security in low-and middle-income countries: A review of existing knowledge and evidence&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diversity in agricultural systems is often presented as having benefits for multiple purposes like food and nutrition security in low- and middle-income countries. Our review aims to give an overview of the strength and direction of the diversity-food security relationship as presented in research published since 2010, based on a comprehensive search in Web of Science. We present an overview and synthesize results for different spatial scales and units of observation, from individual to global and for the four dimensions of food security: availability, access, stability and utilisation. Eighty-eight of the 924 surveyed publications meet the inclusion criteria and report the direction and magnitude of 314 individual diversity-food security relationships. In almost two thirds of all cases, agricultural diversity had a positive effect on food security. In about one third of the relationships there was no effect of agricultural diversity on food security, or the results were mixed. These numbers hold for the availability, access and utilisation dimensions of food security and at individual, household and farm scales, but the number of studies was too small to draw robust conclusions on the stability dimension and at global scale. Diversity can be an important driver of food security, but the magnitude of the contribution depends on the broader socio-economic and biophysical characteristics of the local farming system. We conclude that diversification can be a potential strategy to improve food and nutrition security. Yet, it is not a necessary characteristic of all agricultural systems at all costs especially in the presence of other strategies that can potentially achieve similar outcomes. We make several recommendations to strengthen future studies that can help identify how strongly related agricultural diversity and food security are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rigorous-empirical-and-quantitative-a-proposed-pipeline-for-soil-health-assessments&quot;&gt;Rigorous, empirical, and quantitative: a proposed pipeline for soil health assessments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil health is a promising lens through which to approach land management, having the potential to serve as a descriptor of biophysical processes and as an effective communication tool across stakeholders. However, this potential has been largely unrealized due to difficulty in quantitatively assessing soil health and linking those assessments to outcomes. Here we discuss many multiple persistent obstacles to quantitative soil health assessment and outline a suite of analyses to help address those obstacles. Specifically, we propose a quantitative approach to developing and selecting soil health indicators that help connect management-induced changes in soil health to specific outcomes (e.g., yield or water quality). To demonstrate the utility of this approach, we perform a small case study using published data from North Carolina and New York cropping systems. Additionally, we outline how this approach is scalable and flexible enough to integrate future soil health metric development. The proposed approach stands to provide a quantitative, empirical basis for future measurement, assessment, and interpretation of soil health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;diffuse-reflectance-spectroscopy-characterises-the-functional-chemistry-of-soil-organic-carbon-in-agricultural-soils&quot;&gt;Diffuse reflectance spectroscopy characterises the functional chemistry of soil organic carbon in agricultural soils&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil organic carbon (SOC) originates from a complex mixture of organic materials, and to better understand its role in soil functions, one must characterise its chemical composition. However, current methods, such as solid-state C-13 nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) spectroscopy, are time-consuming and expensive. Diffuse reflectance spectroscopy in the visible, near infrared and mid-infrared regions (vis-NIR: 350-2500 nm; mid-IR: 4000-400 cm(-1)) can also be used to characterise SOC chemistry; however, it is difficult to know the frequencies where the information occurs. Thus, we correlated the C functional groups from the C-13 NMR to the frequencies in the vis-NIR and mid-IR spectra using two methods: (1) 2-dimensional correlations of C-13 NMR spectra and the diffuse reflectance spectra, and (2) modelling the NMR functional C groups with the reflectance spectra using support vector machines (SVM) (validated using 5 times repeated 10-fold cross-validation). For the study, we used 99 mineral soils from the agricultural regions of Sweden. The results show clear correlations between organic functional C groups measured with NMR and specific frequencies in the vis-NIR and mid-IR spectra. While the 2D correlations showed general relationships (mainly related to the total SOC content), analysing the importance of the wavelengths in the SVM models revealed more detail. Generally, models using mid-IR spectra produced slightly better estimates than the vis-NIR. The best estimates were for the alkyl C group (R-2 = 0.83 and 0.85, vis-NIR and mid-IR, respectively), and the O/N-alkyl C group was the most difficult to estimate (R-2 = 0.34 and 0.38, vis-NIR and mid-IR, respectively). Combining C-13 NMR with the cost-effective diffuse reflectance methods could potentially increase the number of measured samples and improve the spatial and temporal characterisation of SOC. However, more studies with a wider range of soil types and land management systems are needed to further evaluate the conditions under which these methods could be used. Highlights Diffuse reflectance spectroscopy was used to characterise and model SOC functional chemistry. NMR derived C functional groups could be modelled with vis-NIR and mid-IR diffuse reflectance spectra. The methods allow for characterisation of SOC chemical composition on whole mineral soil samples. The approach can improve the spatial and temporal characterisation of SOC composition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;discrete-element-modeling-of-aggregate-shape-and-internal-structure-effects-on-weibull-distribution-of-tensile-strength&quot;&gt;Discrete element modeling of aggregate shape and internal structure effects on Weibull distribution of tensile strength&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many soil processes and functions, including carbon storage, water and element cycling, and crop productivity, are directly or indirectly affected by soil aggregates. As a key property, aggregate tensile strength is usually quantified by the Weibull distribution. This distribution was found to depend on soil texture, organic matter content, and aggregate shape; however, effects of cementing agents (i.e., clay mineral and organic compounds) on aggregate tensile strength cannot be empirically studied independent of shape. The objective was to apply Discrete Element Modeling (DEM) to simulate the rupture of soil aggregates of different shapes but the same assumed distributions of cementing agents. The hypothesis was that the Weibull modulus of aggregate tensile strength could be used to describe the heterogeneity of the particle binding forces within the aggregate. Multiple DEM simulations of aggregate rupture were carried out for sets of randomly generated binding force distributions between particles of the same diameter. Aggregate properties and shapes were obtained from those observed in arable Gleyic Cambisol topsoil from plots with and without vegetation of a soil compaction trial; additional aggregate shapes were simulated to increase the predictive range. The simulation results showed that (i) the sensitivity of Weibull modulus of aggregate tensile strength to the heterogeneity of particle binding force distribution increased with aggregate sphericity, (ii) the value of the Weibull modulus decreased with increasing heterogeneity of this distribution, and (iii) internal heterogeneity also reduced the crack surface area produced by aggregate rupture. Results corresponded to friability theory implying that small values of Weibull modulus indicated more complex soil structural organization. The DEM simulations could help explaining complex interactions between aggregate shape cementing agents and stability. Our DEM approach also uncovered the importance of Weibull modulus to assess structural features of soil aggregates and to describe the heterogeneity of the particle binding forces within the aggregate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;capacity-and-intensity-indicators-to-evaluate-the-effect-of-different-crop-sequences-and-cover-crops-on-soil-physical-quality-of-two-different-textured-soils-from-pampas-region&quot;&gt;Capacity and Intensity Indicators to evaluate the effect of different crop sequences and cover crops on soil physical quality of two different textured soils from Pampas Region&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil physical degradation is a current problem in Molisols of the Pampas Region under no-tillage (NT), that has been related to over-simplified agricultural systems with scarce or no rotations and long winter bare fallows. Soil physical quality (SPQ) is a key factor of soil health and productivity, as it controls root development and air and water fluxes and storage in the soil, which in turn affect nutrient uptake and plant growth. Cover crops have been proposed as a companion agricultural practice to improve NT performance and SPQ. The aim of this study was to evaluate the effect of the inclusion of winter cover crops in different cropping sequences on capacity and intensity indicators of SPQ in two soils of different texture under NT and to compare it with different traditional crop sequences, including non-agricultural plots. SPQ was evaluated at two different sites, one with a silty loam Argiudoll and the other with a sandy loam Hapludoll. Treatments included plots with and without cover crops, with different summer crop sequences (continuous soybean and corn - soybean rotations). Also, a corn - wheat/soybean rotation with and without pastures was evaluated. All treatments had more than 15 years under the same management. We measured soil organic carbon (SOC), and capacity SPQ indicators (bulk density, total porosity, pore size distribution, air capacity, plant available water, relative field capacity and S index). We also measured dynamic SPQ indicators derived from field infiltration tests (saturated and near saturation hydraulic conductivity, effective macro and mesoporosity, and porosity connectivity indexes for different pore families). On the silty loam Argiudoll, cover crops increased SOC but failed to improve SPQ. This was related to soil physical degradation and the low ability of these soils for structure regeneration. On the sandy loam Hapludoll, cover crops had mixed effects on SOC and pore size distribution, but increased near saturation hydraulic conductivity, in the case of the corn - soybean rotation with cover crops, reaching values similar to those of a natural grassland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fusion-of-visible-to-near-infrared-and-mid-infrared-spectroscopy-to-estimate-soil-organic-carbon&quot;&gt;Fusion of visible-to-near-infrared and mid-infrared spectroscopy to estimate soil organic carbon&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spectral techniques such as visible-to-near-infrared (VIS-NIR) and mid-infrared (MIR) spectroscopies have been regarded as effective alternatives to laboratory-based methods for determining soil organic carbon (SOC). Research to explore the potential of the fusion of VIS-NIR and MIR absorbance for improving SOC prediction is needed, since each individual spectral range may not contain sufficient information to yield reasonable estimation accuracy. Here, we investigated two data fusion strategies that differed in input data, including direct concatenation of full-spectral absorbance and concatenation of selected predictors by optimal band combination (OBC) algorithm. Specifically, continuous wavelet transform (CWT) was adopted to optimize the spectral data before and after data fusion. Prediction models for SOC were developed using partial least squares regression. Results demonstrated that estimations for SOC using MIR absorbance (i.e., validation R-2 = 0.45-0.64) generally outperformed those using VIS-NIR (i.e., validation R-2 = 0.20-0.44). Compared to the raw absorbance counterparts, CWT decomposing could improve the prediction accuracy for SOC, for both the individual absorbance and the fusion of VIS-NIR and MIR absorbance. Among all the models investigated, the combinational use of VIS-NIR and MIR using OBC fusion at CWT scale of 1 yielded the optimal prediction, providing the highest validation R-2 of 0.66. This model with 10 selected spectral parameters as input is of small total data volume, large processing speed and efficiency, confirming the potential of OBC in fusing both types of spectral data. In summary, CWT decomposing and OBC strategy are powerful algorithms in analyzing the spectral data, and allow the VIS-NIR and MIR spectral fusion models to improve the SOC estimation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-water-characteristic-curves-and-their-estimated-hydraulic-parameters-in-no-tilled-and-conventionally-tilled-soils&quot;&gt;Soil-water characteristic curves and their estimated hydraulic parameters in no-tilled and conventionally tilled soils&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tillage loosens soil, reduces bulk density, alters soil structure and pore size distribution, consequently affecting the shape of the soil-water retention curve (SWRC) and related hydraulic properties and parameters in the top layer of soil. Knowledge of SWRC and hydraulic properties are needed for many soil, agronomic, irrigation, hydrological and environmental studies. This work compares the effect of no-tillage (NT) and conventional tillage (CT) practices on SWRCs and their estimated parameters at 0-15 and 15-30 cm soil depths based on soil samples collected in 2014, 2015, 2016, and 2017. Undisturbed soil cores were extracted using stainless steel cylinders (8 cm in diameter and 5 cm in height) from 0 to 15 cm and 15-30 cm depths in planted corn rows. Soil core sampling was replicated five times in a randomized block design. Soil cores were saturated prior to measurement by the capillarity method and SWRC were measured using the HYPROP evaporative method. Measured soil-water retention curve data were fitted for no-tilled and tilled soils using the van Genuchten (vG) equation for each depth. Results indicated that differences existed in SWRC properties and estimated parameters of vG equation between the two tillage management practices. Averaged across 4 years and two depths, the SWRC parameters alpha, n, and theta(s) were significantly greater under CT than under NT, however, theta(r) was not affected by tillage. The higher alpha, n, and theta(s) values in CT were likely associated with greater soil loosening and disturbance induced by CT operations, thereby forming greater macroporosity and pore volume that, in turn, caused a decrease in bulk density in CT compared to NT. Regardless of the tillage method, SWRCs enable growers and researchers to select farming and irrigation management practices that improve water use efficiency, sustain crop productivity and maintain environmental quality.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/07/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on July 17, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2022/07/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2022/07/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2022-07-10T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2022-07-10T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2022-12&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2022 #12&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lessons from a landmark 1991 article on soil structure: distinct precedence of non-destructive assessment and benefits of fresh perspectives in soil research&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Development of a crop water use monitoring system using electromagnetic induction survey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When do cover crops reduce nitrate leaching? A global meta-analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Local scale optimization of geomorphometric land surface parameters using scale-standardized Gaussian scale-space&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High-Resolution Field Measurement of Soil Heat Capacity and Changes in Soil Moisture Using a Dual-Probe Heat-Pulse Distributed Temperature Sensing Approach&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beyond prediction: methods for interpreting complex models of soil variation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can pedology and soil classification contribute towards sustainable development as a data source and information carrier?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-can-pedology-and-soil-classification-contribute-towards-sustainable-development-as-a-data-source-and-information-carrier&quot;&gt;How can pedology and soil classification contribute towards sustainable development as a data source and information carrier?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil classification is based on both the properties of the soil material and the pedogenetic pathways responsible for those properties. Because soil properties are linked to soil function and potential, information on soil classification has formed the basis for empirical interpretations of mapping units in terms of limitations or suit abilities for a wide range of land uses. In this way, a soil type acts as an accessible “carrier of information” presenting “the story of..”. Though valuable for broad land-use assessments, these empirical interpretations of soil functionality are inadequate to answer modern interdisciplinary questions focused on sustainable development. Four case studies are presented showing various quantitative approaches focusing on soil functions contributing to ecosystem services in line with the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) and the European Green Deal, demonstrating that: (i) the use of soil surveys and associated databases feeding soil-water-atmosphere-plant simulation models can contribute to defining soil functions and ecosystem services; (ii) hydropedological characterization of soil types can allow a strong reduction in the number of landscape units to be considered, improving practical applicability; (iii) pedotransfer functions can successfully link soil data to modeling parameters; (iv) functionality requires expression of soil management effects on properties of a given soil type, to be expressed by phenoforms; (v) only models can be applied to explore important future effects of climate change by running IPCC scenarios; and (vi) the most effective level of soil classification-acting as carriers of information when defining soil functionality-will differ depending on the spatial scale being considered, whether local, regional or higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;beyond-prediction-methods-for-interpreting-complex-models-of-soil-variation&quot;&gt;Beyond prediction: methods for interpreting complex models of soil variation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding the spatial variation of soil properties is central to many sub-disciplines of soil science. Commonly in soil mapping studies, a soil map is constructed through prediction by a statistical or non-statistical model calibrated with measured values of the soil property and environmental covariates of which maps are available. In recent years, the field has gradually shifted attention towards more complex statistical and algorithmic tools from the field of machine learning. These models are particularly useful for their predictive capabilities and are often more accurate than classical models, but they lack interpretability and their functioning cannot be readily visualized. There is a need to understand how these models can be used for purposes other than making accurate prediction and whether it is possible to extract information on the relationships among variables found by the models. In this paper we describe and evaluate a set of methods for the interpretation of complex models of soil variation. An overview is presented of how model-independent methods can serve the purpose of interpreting and visualizing different aspects of the model. We illustrate the methods with the interpretation of two mapping models in a case study mapping topsoil organic carbon in France. We reveal the importance of each driver of soil variation, their interaction, as well as the functional form of the association between environmental covariate and the soil property. Interpretation is also conducted locally for an area and two spatial locations with distinct land use and climate. We show that in all cases important insights can be obtained, both into the overall model functioning and into the decision made by the model for a prediction at a location. This underpins the importance of going beyond accurate prediction in soil mapping studies. Interpretation of mapping models reveal how the predictions are made and can help us formulating hypotheses on the underlying soil processes and mechanisms driving soil variation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;high-resolution-field-measurement-of-soil-heat-capacity-and-changes-in-soil-moisture-using-a-dual-probe-heat-pulse-distributed-temperature-sensing-approach&quot;&gt;High-Resolution Field Measurement of Soil Heat Capacity and Changes in Soil Moisture Using a Dual-Probe Heat-Pulse Distributed Temperature Sensing Approach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Increasing interest in studying the variability of soil water content and its spatial scale dependency necessitates the development of new techniques to accurately monitor soil water over a wide range of spatial scales. Distributed Temperature Sensing (DTS) techniques offer unprecedented opportunities to measure temperature with a spatial resolution of a few centimeters over several kilometers, which can be used to measure soil moisture. This study is the first of its kind that investigates under field conditions the feasibility of combining the Dual-Probe Heat-Pulse (DPHP) technique with the DTS technology to measure soil thermal properties and variation in soil moisture. A field experiment was conducted over a 30 m transect in the Lake Wheeler Field laboratory in Raleigh, NC. Three different DPHP sensors were constructed from combinations of different fiber optic cables and heating elements and were tested to assess their performance and the effect of their construction characteristics on their accuracy. Measurements were taken over different soil moisture conditions and the system performance was compared against independent soil water content sensors. The system was able to track changes in soil water content with a mean RMSE of 0.02 m(3) m(-3) using the optimal DPHP sensor. The key advantage of the tested system is that it does not need any site-specific calibrations typically required for other DTS-based systems. The findings of this study provide some practical information and measures that need to be taken for successful DTS-DPHP construction and application under field conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;local-scale-optimization-of-geomorphometric-land-surface-parameters-using-scale-standardized-gaussian-scale-space&quot;&gt;Local scale optimization of geomorphometric land surface parameters using scale-standardized Gaussian scale-space&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is long recognized that the processes that define the shape of the landscape operate at specific scales, and that mismatch between the scale of analysis and the scale of the process leads to erroneous results. A priori knowledge is often used in specific applications when appropriate scales are known; otherwise selecting an optimal scale of analysis has proven much more challenging. Existing attempts to address scale optimization treat scale as a spatially stationary parameter, and often rely on the generation and analysis of large volumes of data. This research introduces a method to represent topographically complex information at locally optimized scales. A constant time Gaussian scale-space implementation is used to manipulate topographic structure prior to the computation of local derivatives, followed by scale-standardization to facilitate cross-scale comparison. The method demonstrates how Gaussian smoothing can be used to efficiently explore the scaling characteristics of many topographic metrics, and how scale-standardization facilitates the identification of characteristic scales. The spatial distributions of the optimal scale and both the measured value and scale-standardized value measured at the optimal scale provide new information with which to characterize topography. These data improve topographic characterization while eliminating the redundancy of homogenous scale representation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;when-do-cover-crops-reduce-nitrate-leaching-a-global-meta-analysis&quot;&gt;When do cover crops reduce nitrate leaching? A global meta-analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The global increases in the surface and groundwater nitrate (NO3-) concentrations due to synthetic fertilizer input have emerged as major sustainability threats to terrestrial and aquatic ecosystems. Cover crops can reportedly reduce nitrate leaching from croplands. However, the underlying mechanisms and the effectiveness of cover crops in reducing nitrate leaching across species, soil types, agronomic management, and climates remain elusive. We conducted a global meta-analysis to evaluate the effects of cover crops on nitrate leaching and water drainage. A random-effects analysis was established to investigate seven moderating variables in 41 articles. Results showed that globally, cover crops reduced nitrate leaching by 69% compared with fallow while demonstrating no effect on water drainage. Overall, cover crops from Brassicaceae and Poaceae families showed the greatest effect with 75% and 52% reduction in nitrate leaching, respectively. Cover cropping on Ultisols, Histosols, and Inceptisols resulted in the greatest reduction in nitrate leaching (77%, 78%, and 77%, respectively). Greater efficacy of cover crops at reducing nitrate leaching was evident with increasing soil sand content. In general, cover crops appeared to perform better to reduce nitrate leaching in vegetable systems compared to field crops. Cover cropping on conventional tillage resulted in a 63% reduction in nitrate leaching compared with no-tillage (50%) and reduced tillage (38%) systems. The impact of cover crops on water drainage was nonsignificant which implies that nitrate leaching control by cover crops is unlikely exerted through reducing water drainage. This study brings further insight into the intrinsic factors affecting cover crop efficacy and management practices that enhance cover crop potential in reducing nitrate leaching from agricultural systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lessons-from-a-landmark-1991-article-on-soil-structure-distinct-precedence-of-non-destructive-assessment-and-benefits-of-fresh-perspectives-in-soil-research&quot;&gt;Lessons from a landmark 1991 article on soil structure: distinct precedence of non-destructive assessment and benefits of fresh perspectives in soil research&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1991, at the launch of a national symposium devoted to soil structure, the Australian Society of Soil Science invited Professor John Letey to deliver a keynote address, which was later published in the society’s journal. In his lecture, he shared the outcome of his reflexion about what the assessment of soil structure should amount to, in order to produce useful insight into the functioning of soils. His viewpoint was that the focus should be put on the openings present in the structure, rather than on the chunks of material resulting from its mechanical dismantlement. In the present article, we provide some historical background for Letey’s analysis, and try to explain why it took a number of years for the paradigm shift that he advocated to begin to occur. Over the last decade, his perspective that soil structure needs to be characterised via nondestructive methods appears to have gained significant momentum, which is likely to increase further in the near future, as we take advantage of recent technological advances. Other valuable lessons that one can derive from Letey’s pioneering article relate to the extreme value for everyone, even neophytes, to constantly ask questions about where research on given topics is heading, what its goals are, and whether the methods that are used at a certain time are optimal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;development-of-a-crop-water-use-monitoring-system-using-electromagnetic-induction-survey&quot;&gt;Development of a crop water use monitoring system using electromagnetic induction survey&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monitoring soil water use at the plot level is essential for studying the plant’s response to drought or irrigation. However, the current soil monitoring system using moisture sensors is impractical. Soil electromagnetic induction (EMI) surveys can be a rapid, convenient, and non-invasive solution for monitoring soil moisture changes at the plot level. This study developed a crop water use monitoring system for the plot level using an EMI instrument that collects measurements at 0, 20, 40, 60, and 80 cm above the ground surface. The EMI data were converted to bulk soil electrical conductivity (sigma) to the depth 1.5 m via an inversion technique and correlated with measured volumetric moisture contents. The EMI system was first tested for variation in ambient temperature. Within the temperature range of 25.5-34 degrees C, the standard deviation varied between 0.84 and 3.45 mS m-1 with coefficient of variations 1.54-9.26%. The system was then tested on a field trial at Narrabri, New South Wales, Australia, to measure the water use of chickpea genotypes grown over a season. The total water use of chickpeas obtained from EMI surveys correlated highly with values obtained from the Neutron Moisture Meter (NMM) (R2 = 0.73). Time-series of water content, as measured by the EMI survey, could differentiate the water use of different genotypes. In conclusion, the EMI survey is an efficient technique for monitoring crop water use.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/07/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on July 10, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2022/06/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2022/06/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2022-06-03T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2022-06-03T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2022-11&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2022 #11&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;LIBS in agriculture: A review focusing on revealing nutritional and toxic elements in soil, water, and crops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;libs-in-agriculture-a-review-focusing-on-revealing-nutritional-and-toxic-elements-in-soil-water-and-crops&quot;&gt;LIBS in agriculture: A review focusing on revealing nutritional and toxic elements in soil, water, and crops&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent years, rapid urbanization and industrialization have caused severe damage to the agro-ecological environment, such as heavy metal pollution of soil, eutrophication, and pollution of water, and excessive harmful substances in crops. Traditional atomic spectroscopy detection techniques, like atomic absorption spectroscopy (AAS), atomic fluorescence spectroscopy (AFS), atomic mass spectrometry (AMS), and X-ray fluorescence spectroscopy (XRFS), enable high-quality detection of agricultural pollution, but they are time-consuming and labor-intensive. Laser Induced Breakdown Spectroscopy (LIBS) technology is widely applied in agro-ecological monitoring because of its strengths in situ and non-destructive, no (little) sample pre-processing, fast and accurate. This review summarizes the applications of LIBS in agriculture in the last five years from 2017 to 2021. The detailed contents of the review are as follow: (a) analysis of soil and fertilizers elemental composition, (b) water quality detection, and (c) pests, diseases, and elements in crops. Lastly, the challenges and developing prospects of LIBS in agriculture are presented.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/06/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on June 03, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2022/04/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2022/04/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2022-04-08T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2022-04-08T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2022-10&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2022 #10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A global 1-km downscaled SMAP soil moisture product based on thermal inertia theory&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A device to simulate contaminant transfer and surface and subsurface flow through intact soil monoliths&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lasting Effects of Soil Compaction on Soil Water Regime Confirmed by Geoelectrical Monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Writing Accessible Theory in Ecology and Evolution: Insights from Cognitive Load Theory&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Confronting the water potential information gap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;confronting-the-water-potential-information-gap&quot;&gt;Confronting the water potential information gap&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Water potential directly controls the function of leaves, roots and microbes, and gradients in water potential drive water flows throughout the soil-plant-atmosphere continuum. Notwithstanding its clear relevance for many ecosystem processes, soil water potential is rarely measured in situ, and plant water potential observations are generally discrete, sparse, and not yet aggregated into accessible databases. These gaps limit our conceptual understanding of biophysical responses to moisture stress and inject large uncertainty into hydrologic and land-surface models. Here, we outline the conceptual and predictive gains that could be made with more continuous and discoverable observations of water potential in soils and plants. We discuss improvements to sensor technologies that facilitate in situ characterization of water potential, as well as strategies for building new networks that aggregate water potential data across sites. We end by highlighting novel opportunities for linking more representative site-level observations of water potential to remotely sensed proxies. Together, these considerations offer a road map for clearer links between ecohydrological processes and the water potential gradients that have the ‘potential’ to substantially reduce conceptual and modelling uncertainties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuous and discoverable observations of water potential could vastly improve understanding of biophysical processes throughout the soil-plant-atmosphere continuum and are achievable thanks to recent technological advances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;writing-accessible-theory-in-ecology-and-evolution-insights-from-cognitive-load-theory&quot;&gt;Writing Accessible Theory in Ecology and Evolution: Insights from Cognitive Load Theory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theories underpin science. In biology, theories are often formalized in the form of mathematical models, which may render them inaccessible to those lacking mathematical training. In the present article, we consider how theories could be presented to better aid understanding. We provide concrete recommendations inspired by cognitive load theory, a branch of psychology that addresses impediments to knowledge acquisition. We classify these recommendations into two classes: those that increase the links between new and existing information and those that reduce unnecessary or irrelevant complexities. For each, we provide concrete examples to illustrate the scenarios in which they apply. By enhancing a reader’s familiarity with the material, these recommendations lower the mental capacity required to learn new information. Our hope is that these recommendations can provide a pathway for theoreticians to increase the accessibility of their work and for empiricists to engage with theory, strengthening the feedback between theory and experimentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lasting-effects-of-soil-compaction-on-soil-water-regime-confirmed-by-geoelectrical-monitoring&quot;&gt;Lasting Effects of Soil Compaction on Soil Water Regime Confirmed by Geoelectrical Monitoring&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite its importance for hydrological and ecological soil functioning, characterizing, and quantifying soil structure in the field remains a challenge. Traditional characterization of soil structure often relies on point measurements, more recently, we advanced the use of minimally invasive geophysical methods that operate at plot-field scales and provide information under natural conditions. In this study, we expand the application using geoelectrical and time-domain reflectometry (TDR) monitoring of soil water dynamics to infer impacts of compaction on soil structure and function. We developed a modeling scheme combining a new pedophysical model of soil electrical conductivity and a soil-structure-informed one-dimensional water flow and heat-transfer model. The model was used to interpret Direct Current (DC)-resistivity and TDR monitoring data in compacted soils at the Soil Structure Observatory (SSO) located in the vicinity of Zurich, Switzerland. We find that (1) soil compaction leads to a persistent decrease in soil electrical resistivity and (2) that compacted soils are typically drier than non-compacted soils during long drying events. The main decrease in electrical resistivity is attributed to decreasing macroporosity and increasing connectivity of soil aggregates due to compaction. Higher water losses in compacted soils are explained in terms of enhanced evaporation. Our work advances characterization of soil structure at the field scale with electrical methods by offering a physically based explanation of the impact of soil compaction on electrical properties and by interpreting DC-resistivity data in terms of soil water dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-device-to-simulate-contaminant-transfer-and-surface-and-subsurface-flow-through-intact-soil-monoliths&quot;&gt;A device to simulate contaminant transfer and surface and subsurface flow through intact soil monoliths&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many contaminants of agricultural origin are released into rural environments, particularly at the soil surface. Their fate has been extensively investigated in repacked soils, but only few studies have addressed their transport in structurally preserved natural soils. Much remains unknown about their fate and transfer within and between environmental compartments, while the susceptibility of these compartments to the contaminants adverse effects can vary considerably. The lack of studies regarding surface and subsurface transfer of contaminants through intact soil compared with studies on repacked soil led us to propose a device and protocol for sampling intact soil monoliths (60 x 30 x 22 cm(3), length, width, depth [LWD]) without heavy machinery. This is achieved by a modular design with removable top and bottom lid and a protocol of cutting the soil and replacing the affected bottom soil with a drainage layer of glass beads. The device allows the application of artificial rainfall events with simultaneous highly resolved quantification of infiltration excess overland flow and drainage discharge. It is designed to facilitate the collection of samples for physical, biological, and chemical analyses that fulfill cleanliness standards for organic contaminant analysis at trace levels using only poorly reactive stainless steel and glass materials. Testing of the device was performed by measuring the transfer of the antiparasitic drug ivermectin (IVM) through and over a silt-loam pasture soil. This test case illustrates how the device can be used to gain valuable information on the transfer of trace organic contaminants through topsoils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-global-1-km-downscaled-smap-soil-moisture-product-based-on-thermal-inertia-theory&quot;&gt;A global 1-km downscaled SMAP soil moisture product based on thermal inertia theory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microwave remote sensing technology has been applied to produce soil moisture (SM) retrievals on a global scale for various studies and applications. However, due to the limitations of current technology, the native spatial resolution of currently available passive microwave SM products is on the order of tens of kilometers, and this resolution cannot be used to characterize SM variability on a regional scale. To overcome this limitation, a downscaling algorithm based on the thermal inertia theory-derived relationship between SM and temperature difference was developed using outputs from the Global Land Data Assimilation System-Noah Land Surface Model and the land long-term data record-Advanced Very High Resolution Radiometer normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI) dataset and applied to the Aqua Moderate Resolution Imaging Spectroradiometer land surface temperature/NDVI data to produce a downscaled 1-km Soil Moisture Active Passive (SMAP) radiometer daily SM product, respectively, at 6:00 a.m. and 6:00 p.m. on a global scale from 2015 to 2020. The evaluation results reveal that the downscaling model performs better in the middle or low latitudes than in high latitudes. It also performs better in warm months than in cold months. The in situ SM observations from dense networks around the world were used to validate the 1-km and enhanced 9-km SMAP SM data. The validation metrics indicated that both the 1-km and 9-km SM data have overall overestimation trends, and the unbiased RMSE (0.063 m(3) m(-3) on average), mean absolute error (0.052 m(3) m(-3) on average), and spatial standard deviation (0.025 m(3) m(-3) on average) of the 1 km data are generally more accurate than the metrics of the 9-km SM data, which indicates that the downscaled data provide reliable observed SM information.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/04/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on April 08, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2022/03/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2022/03/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2022-03-31T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2022-03-31T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2022-9&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2022 #9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fuzzy map comparisons enable objective hydro-morphodynamic model validation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Farming and Earth Observation: Sentinel-2 data to estimate within-field wheat grain yield&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil moisture as an essential component for delineating and forecasting agricultural rather than meteorological drought&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rapid intensification of the emerging southwestern North American megadrought in 2020-2021&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rapid-intensification-of-the-emerging-southwestern-north-american-megadrought-in-2020-2021&quot;&gt;Rapid intensification of the emerging southwestern North American megadrought in 2020-2021&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Southwestern North America has been experiencing lower than average precipitation and higher temperatures since 2000. This emerging megadrought, spanning 2000-2021, has been the driest 22-year period since the year 800 and 19% of the drought severity in 2021 can be attributed to climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A previous reconstruction back to 800 ce indicated that the 2000-2018 soil moisture deficit in southwestern North America was exceeded during one megadrought in the late-1500s. Here, we show that after exceptional drought severity in 2021, similar to 19% of which is attributable to anthropogenic climate trends, 2000-2021 was the driest 22-yr period since at least 800. This drought will very likely persist through 2022, matching the duration of the late-1500s megadrought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-moisture-as-an-essential-component-for-delineating-and-forecasting-agricultural-rather-than-meteorological-drought&quot;&gt;Soil moisture as an essential component for delineating and forecasting agricultural rather than meteorological drought&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drought is a recurring, complex, and extreme climatic phenomenon characterized by subnormal precipitation for months to years triggering negative impacts on agriculture, energy, tourism, recreation, and transportation sectors. Agricultural drought assessment is based on a deficit of soil moisture (SM) during the plant-growing season, whereas meteorological drought corresponds to subnormal precipitation over months to years. However, satellite-derived agricultural and meteorological drought indices (including those comprising root-zone SM) have not been comprehensively compared to evaluate their ability for drought delineation and particularly forecasting across climate regimes, land cover and soil types, and irrigation management (irrigated vs. rainfed) in the contiguous USA (CONUS). Here, we did so from 2015 to 2019 within the CONUS. In most regions except the US Midwest and Southeast, SM-based indices (e.g., Palmer Z, SMAP, SWDI) delineated agricultural drought better than meteorological (e.g., SPI, SPEI) and hybrid (Comprehensive Drought Index, CDI) drought indices. In contrast, the SPI and SPEI showed strong correlation with the aridity index in most part of the CONUS except the Midwest. SM-based and hybrid indices also demonstrated skills for agricultural drought forecasting (represented by end-of-year cumulative GPP), predominantly in the early growing season and particularly in irrigated rather than rainfed croplands. These findings indicate the leading role of SM in controlling ecosystem dryness and confirm “drought memory”, possibly due to SM-memory in land-atmosphere coupling. Proper application of meteorological and agricultural drought indices and their contrasting spatial-temporal controls on plant growth and ecosystem dryness has the potential to improve our understanding of drought evolution and provide early drought forecasting across large regions with diverse climate regimes, land cover types, soil textural classes, and irrigation management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;farming-and-earth-observation-sentinel-2-data-to-estimate-within-field-wheat-grain-yield&quot;&gt;Farming and Earth Observation: Sentinel-2 data to estimate within-field wheat grain yield&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wheat grain yield (GY) is a crop feature of central importance affecting agricultural, environmental, and socioeconomic sustainability worldwide. Hence, the estimation of within-field variability of GY is pivotal for the agricultural management, especially in the current global change context. In this sense, Earth Observation Systems (EOS) are key technologies that use satellite data to monitor crop yield, which can guide the application of precision farming. Yet, novel research is required to improve the multiplatform integration of data, including data processing, and the application of this discipline in agricultural management. This article provides a novel methodological analysis and assessment of its applications in precision farming. It presents an integration of wheat GY, Global Positioning Systems (GPS), combine harvester data, and EOS Sentinel-2 multispectral bands. Moreover, it compares several indices and machine learning (ML) approaches to map within-field wheat GY. It also analyses the importance of multi-date remote sensing imagery and explores its potential applications in precision agriculture. The study was conducted in Spain, a major European wheat producer. Within-field GY data was obtained from a GPS combine harvester machine for 8 fields over three seasons (2017-2019) and consecutively processed to match Sentinel-2 10 m pixel size. Seven vegetation indices (NDVI, GNDVI, EVI, RVI, TGI, CVI and NGRDI) as well as the biophysical parameter LAI (leaf area index) retrieved with radiative transfer models (RTM) were calculated from Sentinel-2 bands. Sentinel-2 10 m resolution bands alone were also used as variables. Random forest, support vector machine and boosted regressions were used as modelling approaches, and multilinear regression was calculated as baseline. Different combinations of dates of measurement were tested to find the most suitable model feeding data. LAI retrieved from RTM had a slightly improved performance in estimating within-field GY in comparison with vegetation indices or Sentinel-2 bands alone. At validation, the use of multi-date Sentinel-2 data was found to be the most suitable in comparison with single date images. Thus, the model developed with random forest regression (e.g. R-2 = 0.89, and RSME = 0.74 t/ha when using LAI) outperformed support vector machine (R-2 = 0.84 and RSME = 0.92 t/ha), boosting regression (R-2 = 0.85 and RSME = 0.88 t/ha) and multilinear regression (R-2 = 0.69 and RSME = 1.29 t/ha). However, single date images at specific phenological stages (e.g. R-2 = 0.84, and RSME = 0.88 t/ha using random forest at stem elongation) also posed relatively high R-2 and low RMSE, with potential for precision farming management before harvest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fuzzy-map-comparisons-enable-objective-hydro-morphodynamic-model-validation&quot;&gt;Fuzzy map comparisons enable objective hydro-morphodynamic model validation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numerical modeling represents a state-of-the-art technique to simulate hydro-morphodynamic processes in river ecosystems. Numerical models are often validated based on observed topographic change in the form of pixel information on net erosion or deposition over a simulation period. When model validation is performed by a pixel-by-pixel comparison of exactly superimposed simulated and observed pixels, zero or negative correlation coefficients are often calculated, suggesting poor model performance. Thus, a pixel-by-pixel approach penalizes quantitative simulation errors, even if a model conceptually works well. To distinguish between reasonably well-performing and non-representative models, this study introduces and tests fuzzy map comparison methods. First, we use a fuzzy numerical map comparison to compensate for spatial offset errors in correlation analyses. Second, we add a level of fuzziness with a fuzzy kappa map comparison to additionally address quantitative inaccuracy in modeled topographic change by categorizing data. Sample datasets from a physical lab model and datasets from a 6.9 km long gravel-cobble bed river reach enable the verification of the relevance of fuzzy map comparison methods. The results indicate that a fuzzy numerical map comparison is a viable technique to compensate for model errors stemming from spatial offset. In addition, fuzzy kappa map comparisons are suitable for objectively expressing subjectively perceived correlation between two maps, provided that a small number of categories is used. The methods tested and the resulting spatially explicit comparison maps represent a significant opportunity to improve the evaluation and potential calibration of numerical models of river ecosystems in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/03/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on March 31, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2022/03/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2022/03/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2022-03-25T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2022-03-25T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2022-8&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2022 #8&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil moisture retrieval over croplands using dual-pol L-band GRD SAR data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using soil library hyperspectral reflectance and machine learning to predict soil organic carbon: Assessing potential of airborne and spaceborne optical soil sensing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From energy to (soil organic) matter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Century-long changes and drivers of soil nitrous oxide (N2O) emissions across the contiguous United States&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil profile analysis using interactive visualizations, machine learning, and deep learning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimating soil chemical properties by diffuse reflectance spectroscopy: Promise versus reality&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A simple method for estimating the optimum water content for tillage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RUSSELL REVIEW Are plant roots only “in” soil or are they “of” it? Roots, soil formation and function&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Statistical modelling of measurement error in wet chemistry soil data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The cost-effectiveness of reflectance spectroscopy for estimating soil organic carbon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mapping depth to Pleistocene sand with Bayesian generalized linear geostatistical models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mapping-depth-to-pleistocene-sand-with-bayesian-generalized-linear-geostatistical-models&quot;&gt;Mapping depth to Pleistocene sand with Bayesian generalized linear geostatistical models&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spatial soil applications frequently involve binomial variables. If relevant environmental covariates are available, using a Bayesian generalized linear model (BGLM) might be a solution for mapping such discrete soil properties. The geostatistical extension, a Bayesian generalized linear geostatistical model (BGLGM), adds spatial dependence and is thus potentially better equipped. The objective of this work was to evaluate whether it pays off to extend from a BGLM to a BGLGM for mapping binary soil properties, evaluated in terms of prediction accuracy and modelling complexity. As motivating example, we mapped the presence/absence of the Pleistocene sand layer within 120 cm from the land surface in the Dutch province of Flevoland, using the BGLGM implementation in the R-package geoRglm. We found that BGLGM yields considerably better statistical validation metrics compared to a BGLM, especially with - as in our case - a large (n = 1,000) observation sample and few relevant covariates available. Also, the inferred posterior BGLGM parameters enable the quantification of spatial relationships. However, calibrating and applying a BGLGM is quite demanding with respect to the minimal required sample size, tuning the algorithm, and computational costs. We replaced manual tuning by an automated tuning algorithm (which eases implementing applications) and found a sample composition that delivers meaningful results within 50 h calculation time. With the gained insights and shared scripts spatial soil practitioners and researchers can - for their specific cases - evaluate if using BGLGM is feasible and if the extra gain is worth the extra effort. Highlights Does adding spatial correlation to a Bayesian GLM for mapping a binary soil variable pay off? We aim to make spatial Bayesian hierarchical modelling accessible for pedometricians. Most hierarchical models work well when enough observations are provided, even without covariates. Including spatial correlation might sometimes be worth the extra effort and computational costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-cost-effectiveness-of-reflectance-spectroscopy-for-estimating-soil-organic-carbon&quot;&gt;The cost-effectiveness of reflectance spectroscopy for estimating soil organic carbon&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reflectance spectra of soil can be used to estimate the concentrations of organic carbon in soil (SOC). The estimates are more or less imprecise, but spectroscopy is quicker, less laborious and cheaper than conventional dry combustion analysis. Are the greater economy and efficiency sufficient to justify the loss of information arising from errors in estimation? We measured soil spectra with three instruments: a bench-top mid-infrared (mid-IR) (mid-IRb) spectrometer, a portable mid-IR (mid-IRp) spectrometer and a portable visible-near infrared (vis-NIRp) spectrometer. We calculated a quantity E to express the cost-effectiveness of spectroscopic estimates relative to the conventional analysis, by accounting for their inaccuracy, their cost and their capacity, namely the maximum number of samples that can be prepared and measured daily. In all, 562 samples of soil were collected from 150 locations at four depths on a farm. The samples were dried and ground to particle sizes of &amp;lt;= 2 and &amp;lt;= 0.5 mm before measurements were made by dry-combustion analysis. The machine learning algorithm Cubist was used to derive spectroscopic models of SOC concentrations and their uncertainties. We found that the mid-IRb on the &amp;lt;= 0.5 mm samples was the most accurate and expensive but nevertheless sufficiently cost-effective (large value of E) for determining the organic C. The mid-IRp was somewhat more accurate, but its E was smaller than vis-NIRp on corresponding samples because it required more time to record the spectra. We also found that, with the portable spectrometers, the SOC predictions made on the &amp;lt;= 0.5 mm samples were somewhat more accurate than those made on the &amp;lt;= 2 mm samples, but their E was smaller because of the additional cost of sample preparation. The vis-NIRp on the &amp;lt;= 2 mm samples was the most cost-effective for estimating SOC because it is cheap, accurate and has a large capacity for measurements. Highlights Concentrations of soil organic carbon (SOC) were determined by standard dry combustion and estimated from reflectance spectra recorded by three instruments. The labour required for each of the techniques and the cost, including that of the equipment, were recorded. A quantity E, expressing the cost-effectiveness relative to dry combustion was calculated for each spectral technique, taking into account both accuracy and cost. Dry combustion was always more accurate than estimates from spectra for individual samples, and the technique was also more cost-effective for small numbers of samples. The cost-effectiveness of the spectral techniques varied among themselves, but all were more cost-effective than dry combustion for large numbers of samples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;statistical-modelling-of-measurement-error-in-wet-chemistry-soil-data&quot;&gt;Statistical modelling of measurement error in wet chemistry soil data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a growing demand for high-quality soil data. However, soil measurements are subject to many error sources. We aimed to quantify uncertainties in synthetic and real-world wet chemistry soil data through a linear mixed-effects model, including batch and laboratory effects. The use of synthetic data allowed us to investigate how accurately the model parameters were estimated for various experimental measurement designs, whereas the real-world case served to explore if estimates of the random effect variances were still accurate for unbalanced datasets with few replicates. The variance estimates for synthetic pHH2O data were unbiased, but limited laboratory information led to imprecise estimates. The same was observed for unbalanced synthetic datasets, where 20, 50 and 80% of the data were removed randomly. Removal led to a sharp increase of the interquartile range (IQR) of the variance estimates for batch effect and the residual. The model was also fitted to real-world pHH2O and total organic carbon (TOC) data, provided by the Wageningen Evaluating Programmes for Analytical Laboratories (WEPAL). For pHH2O, the model yielded unbiased estimates with relatively small IQRs. However, the limited number of batches with replicate measurements (5.8%) caused the batch effect to be larger than expected. A strong negative correlation between batch effect and residual variance suggested that the model could not distinguish well between these two random effects. For TOC, batch effect was removed from the model as no replicates were available within batches. Again, unbiased model estimates were obtained. However, the IQRs were relatively large, which could be attributed to the smaller dataset with only a single replicate measurement. Our findings demonstrated the importance of experimental measurement design and replicate measurements in the quantification of uncertainties in wet chemistry soil data. Highlights Accurate uncertainty quantification depends on the experimental measurement design. Linear mixed-effects models can be used as a tool to quantify uncertainty in wet chemistry soil data. Lack of replicate measurements leads to poor estimates of error variance components. Measurement error in wet chemistry soil data should not be ignored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;russell-review-are-plant-roots-only-in-soil-or-are-they-of-it-roots-soil-formation-and-function&quot;&gt;RUSSELL REVIEW Are plant roots only “in” soil or are they “of” it? Roots, soil formation and function&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roots are near-ubiquitous components of soils globally but have often been regarded as separate from the soil rather than a substantial factor in determining what soil is and how it functions. The start of rapid soil formation commenced about 400 million years ago with the emergence of vascular plants and the evolution of roots and associated microbes. Roots and associated microorganisms contribute significantly to soil formation by altering rocks and soil minerals through a variety of biogeochemical processes and supply carbon to a depth that can have long residence times. Living root inputs of carbon via rhizodeposits are more efficient than shoot and root litter inputs in forming slow-cycling, mineral-associated soil organic carbon pools. The current functionality of soils in providing food and fuel and fibres, supplying plant nutrients, filtering water and flood regulation, and disease suppression are all dependent on the activities of plant roots. Roots are actively communicating and collaborating with other organisms for mutual benefit, and the signals underlying this modulation of the rhizosphere microbiome are being identified. In this review I examine how plant roots (an organ not an organism) affect soil formation and function and conclude that, from several perspectives, roots are not just “in” soil but “of” it and that definitions of soil should recognise this. A possible definition is: “Soils are altered surficial rock or sediment, composed of organic matter, minerals, fluids, and organisms whose formation and functionality are influenced by biogeochemical weathering and interactions of these components with plant roots.” Highlights Paleoclimatic and paleosoil research shows the key role of roots and mycorrhiza in soil formation. Deep roots and living root inputs are substantial contributors to long-term C storage. Root/microbe signalling facilitates mutualistic symbioses, nutrient uptake and disease suppression. Definitions of soil should explicitly include roots as an important component of the soil system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-simple-method-for-estimating-the-optimum-water-content-for-tillage&quot;&gt;A simple method for estimating the optimum water content for tillage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple and quick determination of the optimum water content for tillage (theta(OPT)) is helpful to guide tillage operations. Based on the definition of theta(OPT) that is the water content at the inflection point of the soil water retention curve, a simple method was established to estimate the theta(OPT) from saturated water content (theta(s)) (theta(OPT) = 0.75 theta(s)). The validation results on 132 soils with varying texture showed that the root mean squared error and mean error were 0.021 and 0.009 g g(-1), respectively. These results confirmed that the theta(s) was valuable information for estimating theta(OPT) and the proposed method could give a reasonable estimation for theta(OPT).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;estimating-soil-chemical-properties-by-diffuse-reflectance-spectroscopy-promise-versus-reality&quot;&gt;Estimating soil chemical properties by diffuse reflectance spectroscopy: Promise versus reality&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diffuse reflectance spectroscopy in the visible and near-infrared (VNIR) spectral range has increasingly been utilised in recent years to measure soil properties, including organic carbon and macronutrient content, cation exchange capacity, pH, and even trace metal concentration. Proponents have even suggested that conventional laboratory soil testing methods can ultimately be replaced by these less laborious and more rapid spectroscopic methods. However, to this point in time, reflectance spectroscopy has not demonstrated accuracy comparable to that of conventional physical-chemical testing methods. This review explains why correlations between VNIR spectral features and specific chemical properties within selected sets of soil samples are indirect at best and therefore cannot be trusted more universally to predict soil chemical properties in larger and less homogeneous sample sets. Because mathematical manipulation of the raw spectral data has become increasingly complex and obscure to the users, particularly when machine learning is employed, the possibility exists that the correlations found and the predictions made are based on chance relationships resulting from overfitting the spectral data to include random noise in addition to any real trends. It is concluded that, for real-world soil testing for agronomic and environmental purposes (e.g. available nutrient and trace metal levels), spectral reflectance methods are not sufficiently reliable to replace conventional testing. Conversely, these reflectance methods show utility and convenience in measuring general trends across landscapes in levels of soil organic matter, carbonates, soluble salts and specific clay minerals. Highlights VNIR reflectance spectroscopy is reviewed as a method to measure soil properties. Estimating most soil chemical properties by VNIR relies on indirect or proxy correlations. Complex regression models used in predicting soil properties may overstate accuracy. Reflectance spectroscopy has lower reliability and extrapolability than conventional soil testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-profile-analysis-using-interactive-visualizations-machine-learning-and-deep-learning&quot;&gt;Soil profile analysis using interactive visualizations, machine learning, and deep learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil is an essential element of life, and soil properties are crucial in analyzing soil health. Recent developments of proximal sensor technologies, such as portable X-ray fluorescence (pXRF) spectroscopy or visible and near-infrared (Vis-NIR) spectroscopy, offer rapid and non-destructive alternatives for quantifying data from soil profiles. While the data collection time using these technologies decreases significantly, the subsequent analysis remains time-consuming, and current analysis solutions only provide basic visualizations. Furthermore, the use of collected data from proximal sensors to predict high-level soil properties has garnered worldwide attention in the past decade, owing to its convenience. Therefore, this paper discusses the objectives for software solutions in this area, consolidated from interviewing 102 stakeholders. Following these requirements, data visualizers work closely with soil scientists to propose a set of interactive visualizations for analyzing soil profiles using pXRF data. These interactive visualizations receive positive feedback from the domain experts. This project also explores various machine learning and deep learning approaches to predict soil properties from spectral data. This work then proposes a deep learning model called RDNet that achieves state-of-the-art results in predicting pH(H2O) and pH(KCl) from Vis-NIR spectra acquired from a set of globally distributed soil samples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;century-long-changes-and-drivers-of-soil-nitrous-oxide-n2o-emissions-across-the-contiguous-united-states&quot;&gt;Century-long changes and drivers of soil nitrous oxide (N2O) emissions across the contiguous United States&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The atmospheric concentration of nitrous oxide (N2O) has increased by 23% since the pre-industrial era, which substantially destructed the stratospheric ozone layer and changed the global climate. However, it remains uncertain about the reasons behind the increase and the spatiotemporal patterns of soil N2O emissions, a primary biogenic source. Here, we used an integrative land ecosystem model, Dynamic Land Ecosystem Model (DLEM), to quantify direct (i.e., emitted from local soil) and indirect (i.e., emissions related to local practices but occurring elsewhere) N2O emissions in the contiguous United States during 1900-2019. Newly developed geospatial data of land-use history and crop-specific agricultural management practices were used to force DLEM at a spatial resolution of 5 arc-min by 5 arc-min. The model simulation indicates that the U.S. soil N2O emissions totaled 0.97 +/- 0.06 Tg N year(-1) during the 2010s, with 94% and 6% from direct and indirect emissions, respectively. Hot spots of soil N2O emission are found in the US Corn Belt and Rice Belt. We find a threefold increase in total soil N2O emission in the United States since 1900, 74% of which is from agricultural soil emissions, increasing by 12 times from 0.04 Tg N year(-1) in the 1900s to 0.51 Tg N year(-1) in the 2010s. More than 90% of soil N2O emission increase in agricultural soils is attributed to human land-use change and agricultural management practices, while increases in N deposition and climate warming are the dominant drivers for N2O emission increase from natural soils. Across the cropped acres, corn production stands out with a large amount of fertilizer consumption and high-emission factors, responsible for nearly two-thirds of direct agricultural soil N2O emission increase since 1900. Our study suggests a large N2O mitigation potential in cropland and the importance of exploring crop-specific mitigation strategies and prioritizing management alternatives for targeted crop types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;from-energy-to-soil-organic-matter&quot;&gt;From energy to (soil organic) matter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this concept paper, we propose a new view on soil organic matter (SOM) formation: microorganisms use most of the organics entering the soil as energy rather than as a source of carbon (C), while SOM accumulates as a residual by-product because the microbial energy investment in its decomposition exceeds the energy gain. During the initial stages of decomposition, the nominal oxidation state of C (NOSC) in remaining litter decreases, and the energy content increases. This reflects the rapid mineralization of available compounds with positive and neutral NOSC (carboxylic acids, sugars, some amino acids). Consequently, the NOSC of the remaining compounds drops to -0.3 units, and the oxidation rate decreases due to the residual relative accumulation of aromatic and aliphatic compounds (which are hydrolized later) and entombment of the necromass. Ultimately, incompletely decomposed plant residues will have 1%-2.5% more energy per C unit than the initial litter. The linear decrease in energy density of a broad range of organic substances by 106 kJ mol(-1) C per NOSC unit upon oxidation is supported by experimental data on litter decomposition. Preferential recycling of energy-rich reduced (lipids, aromatics, certain amino acids, amino sugars) and the microbial degradation of oxidized compounds (carboxylic acids) also energetically enrich SOM. Despite the high energy content, the availability of energy stored in SOM is lower than in litter. This explains why SOM is not fully mineralized (thermodynamically unfavorable), especially in the absence of plant C to provide new energy (e.g., in bare soil). Energy from litter activates decomposers to mine nutrients stored in SOM (the main ecological function of priming effects) because the nutrient content in SOM is 2-5 times higher than that of litter. This results in only 0.4%-5% year(-1) of litter-derived C being sequestered in SOM, whereas SOM stores 1%-10% year(-1) of the total litter-derived energy. Thus, the energy captured by photosynthesis is the main reason why microorganisms utilize organic matter, whereby SOM is merely a residual by-product of nutrient storage and a mediator of energy fluxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-soil-library-hyperspectral-reflectance-and-machine-learning-to-predict-soil-organic-carbon-assessing-potential-of-airborne-and-spaceborne-optical-soil-sensing&quot;&gt;Using soil library hyperspectral reflectance and machine learning to predict soil organic carbon: Assessing potential of airborne and spaceborne optical soil sensing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil organic carbon (SOC) is a key variable to determine soil functioning, ecosystem services, and global carbon cycles. Spectroscopy, particularly optical hyperspectral reflectance coupled with machine learning, can provide rapid, efficient, and cost-effective quantification of SOC. However, how to exploit soil hyperspectral reflectance to predict SOC concentration, and the potential performance of airborne and satellite data for predicting surface SOC at large scales remain relatively underknown. This study utilized a continental-scale soil laboratory spectral library (37,540 full-pedon 350-2500 nm reflectance spectra with SOC concentration of 0-780 g.kg(-1) across the US) to thoroughly evaluate seven machine learning algorithms including Partial-Least Squares Regression (PLSR), Random Forest (RF), K-Nearest Neighbors (KNN), Ridge, Artificial Neural Networks (ANN), Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN), and Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) along with four preprocessed spectra, i.e. original, vector normalization, continuum removal, and first-order derivative, to quantify SOC concentration. Furthermore, by using the coupled soil-vegetation-atmosphere radiative transfer model, we simulated twelve airborne and spaceborne hyper/multi-spectral remote sensing data from surface bare soil laboratory spectra to evaluate their potential for estimating SOC concentration of surface bare soils. Results show that LSTM achieved best predictive performance of quantifying SOC concentration for the whole data sets (R-2 = 0.96, RMSE = 30.81 g.kg(-1)), mineral soils (SOC &amp;lt;= 120 g.kg(-1), R-2 = 0.71, RMSE = 10.60 g.kg(-1)), and organic soils (SOC &amp;gt; 120 g.kg(-1), R-2 = 0.78, RMSE = 62.31 g.kg(-1)). Spectral data preprocessing, particularly the first-order derivative, improved the performance of PLSR, RF, Ridge, KNN, and ANN, but not LSTM or CNN. We found that the SOC models of mineral and organic soils should be distinguished given their distinct spectral signatures. Finally, we identified that the shortwave infrared is vital for airborne and spaceborne hyperspectral sensors to monitor surface SOC. This study highlights the high accuracy of LSTM with hyperspectral/multispectral data to mitigate a certain level of noise (soil moisture &amp;lt;0.4 m(3).m(-3), green leaf area &amp;lt; 0.3 m(2).m(-2), plant residue &amp;lt;0.4 m(2).m(-2)) for quantifying surface SOC concentration. Forthcoming satellite hyperspectral missions like Surface Biology and Geology (SBG) have a high potential for future global soil carbon monitoring, while high-resolution satellite multispectral fusion data can be an alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-moisture-retrieval-over-croplands-using-dual-pol-l-band-grd-sar-data&quot;&gt;Soil moisture retrieval over croplands using dual-pol L-band GRD SAR data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vegetation cover significantly influences the hydrometeorological processes of land surfaces. The heterogeneity of vegetation cover makes these processes more complex and impacts the interaction between water held in the soil matrix and vegetation cover. The backscatter measured by Synthetic Aperture Radar (SAR) is sensitive to target dielectric and morphological properties. In addition, SAR acquisitions are weather-independent, providing a major advantage over optical imaging during periods of cloud cover. Most often, vegetation properties are measured using vegetation indices, including simple ratios of backscatter intensities. However, this approach can miss the scattered wave purity from vegetation targets. The scattered wave characteristic is an essential parameter as it is susceptible to the complex random structure of vegetation. In this study, we propose a novel dual-polarimetric SAR vegetation descriptor based on the co-pol purity component of the wave. We use this descriptor within a semi-empirical vegetation model to estimate soil moisture. It is noteworthy that this proposed method to retrieve soil moisture uses only the dual-polarimetric Ground Range Detected (GRD) SAR product, i.e., only backscatter intensities. Therefore, the proposed method has the potential for operational scale monitoring applications at a global scale. This study validated different crop types (viz. canola, oats, forage, maize, soybeans, sugar beet, wheat, winter wheat, winter barley) over two test sites using airborne SAR data. The Root Mean Square Error (RMSE) values for soil moisture are within the range of 4.3% to 7.7% with the Pearson correlation coefficient r greater than 0.6. This novel descriptor will facilitate the operational use of dual-polarimetric GRD SAR data for vegetation monitoring and soil moisture estimation.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/03/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on March 25, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2022/03/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2022/03/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2022-03-10T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2022-03-10T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2022-7&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2022 #7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Optimal smart contract for autonomous greenhouse environment based on IoT blockchain network in agriculture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Advances in gas sensors and electronic nose technologies for agricultural cycle applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;advances-in-gas-sensors-and-electronic-nose-technologies-for-agricultural-cycle-applications&quot;&gt;Advances in gas sensors and electronic nose technologies for agricultural cycle applications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agricultural cycle is the annual cycle of activities for planting and harvesting. The global warming and climate change currently cause serious impacts on the agricultural cycle leading to reduced crop quantity and quality. In the past decade, the gas sensors and electronic nose (E-nose) technologies have shown great promise and utility in monitoring and prediction of important parameters related to the growth and harvest of a crop. This review summarizes overall the evolution of utilizing gas sensors and E-nose technologies for guideline of agricultural best management practices including applications on cultivation preparation, crop production, harvesting and storage of crops. Advantages and limitations of these technologies in agricultural applications are reviewed to highlight potential research directions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;optimal-smart-contract-for-autonomous-greenhouse-environment-based-on-iot-blockchain-network-in-agriculture&quot;&gt;Optimal smart contract for autonomous greenhouse environment based on IoT blockchain network in agriculture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Things (IoT) has been widely adopted in many smart applications such as smart cities, healthcare, smart farms, industry etc. In recent few years, the greenhouse industry has earned significant consideration from the agriculture community due to its ability to produce fresh agricultural products with immense growth and production rate. However, labour and energy consumption costs increase the production cost of the greenhouse by 40-50% approximately. Moreover, the security and authenticity of agriculture data, particularly for yield monitoring and analysis, is also a challenging issue in current greenhouse systems.The greenhouse require optimal parameter settings with controlled environment to produce increase food production. Therefore, slight advancement can bring remarkable improvements concerning the increase in production with reduced overall cost. In this work, we contributed blockchain enabled optimization approach for greenhouse system. The proposed approach works in three steps to provide optimal greenhouse environment that are; prediction, optimization, and finally controlling. Initially, the Kalman filter algorithm is employed for predicting the greenhouse sensor data. In next step, the optimal parameters are computed for the indoor greenhouse environment. Finally, the optimized parameters are utilized by the control module to operate and regulate the actuator’s state to meet the desired settings in the indoor environment. To evaluate the performance of our proposed greenhouse system, we have developed an emulation tool. The proposed system has been investigated and compared against baseline approach concerning production rate and energy consumption. The obtained results reveal that the proposed optimization approach has improved the energy consumption by 19% against the prediction based approach and 41% against the Baseline scheme. Furthermore, the proof-of-concept based on the Hyperledger Fabric network is implemented on the top of the proposed greenhouse platform. For experimental analysis, we have conducted a series of experiments using Hyperledger calliper concerning throughput, latency, and resource utilization. These results advocates the efficiency of the proposed optimal greenhouse system.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/03/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on March 10, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2022/03/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2022/03/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2022-03-04T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2022-03-04T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2022-6&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2022 #6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carbon stocks in umbric ferralsols driven by plant productivity and geomorphic processes, not by mineral protection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NASA’s surface biology and geology designated observable: A perspective on surface imaging algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transforming food systems: Multi-stakeholder platforms driven by consumer concerns and public demands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;transforming-food-systems-multi-stakeholder-platforms-driven-by-consumer-concerns-and-public-demands&quot;&gt;Transforming food systems: Multi-stakeholder platforms driven by consumer concerns and public demands&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food systems governance for healthy and sustainable diets remains a challenge. New structures are needed to better connect food systems actors. This paper argues that existing multi-stakeholder platforms (MSPs) have the potential to contribute to food systems governance by facilitating linkages between actors and scales. In a nonexperimental study existing MSPs (n = 89) were explored in four countries addressing food and nutrition security. A diagnostic framework was used to identify MSP’s capacities to address governance principles like system-based problem framing, boundary spanning, adaptability, inclusiveness, and transformative capacity. Existing MSPs can play a role in spanning boundaries, thereby increasing adaptability and learning, but seem less promising in shifting to systems-based narratives and thus may have limited capacity to truly transform food systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;carbon-stocks-in-umbric-ferralsols-driven-by-plant-productivity-and-geomorphic-processes-not-by-mineral-protection&quot;&gt;Carbon stocks in umbric ferralsols driven by plant productivity and geomorphic processes, not by mineral protection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Umbric ferralsols (UF) have organic carbon stocks within the first 1 m of soil profile depth that are nearly double the size (similar to 19 kg Cm-2) compared to the average carbon stocks of all other ferralsols (similar to 10 kg Cm-2). Here, we investigate processes that allow UF to gain and maintain such extraordinary carbon stocks. Using the International Soil Research and Information Center database, complemented with recently published datasets, we show that the carbon saturation capacity of the clay + silt fractions in UF (22.8 +/- 5.7 g C kg(-1) soil, n = 59) does not exceed the carbon saturation capacity in other ferralsols (23.3 +/- 6.2 g C kg(-1) soil, n = 165), thus eliminating a particularly retentive mineral matrix as a possible explanation. Rather, carbon stocks were correlated with the thickness of A horizons (106 +/- 49 cm, n = 59 in umbric versus 35 +/- 22 cm, n = 165 in non-umbric ferralsols). We subsequently hypothesized that differences in A-horizon thickness arose from two pedogenic scenarios: (i) superior carbon accrual resulting from a unique vegetation cover capable of allocating large quantities of carbon to belowground plant organs; and (ii) geomorphic processes that led to carbon burial. We evaluated the plausibility of these scenarios considering landscape history and associated carbon flux rates, hillslope position, as well as delta C-13 values and Ti/Zr ratios for subsets of ferralsol profiles studied by us in a region that encompasses latitudes from 26 to 7 degrees S in eastern Brazil. We found that exceptional carbon stocks were most prevalent in the gradual transition zone (ecotone) between savanna and rainforest, likely resulting from erosion-deposition processes, historic changes of vegetation cover composed of grasses and arboreal elements, and active bioturbation. We suggest that attempts to sequester carbon in non-umbric ferralsols will be most successful if they emulate or promote the biotic and abiotic processes prevalent in the savanna/rainforest ecotone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nasas-surface-biology-and-geology-designated-observable-a-perspective-on-surface-imaging-algorithms&quot;&gt;NASA’s surface biology and geology designated observable: A perspective on surface imaging algorithms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2017-2027 National Academies’ Decadal Survey, Thriving on Our Changing Planet, recommended Surface Biology and Geology (SBG) as a “Designated Targeted Observable” (DO). The SBG DO is based on the need for agriculture, natural habitats, water use/quality, and urban development. We review existing algorithms in the community-state-of-practice in each category. This effort synthesizes the findings of more than 130 scientists.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/03/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on March 04, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2022/02/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2022/02/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2022-02-25T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2022-02-25T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2022-5&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2022 #5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Variations and controlling factors of soil denitrification rate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uncovering the critical soil moisture thresholds of plant water stress for European ecosystems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;variations-and-controlling-factors-of-soil-denitrification-rate&quot;&gt;Variations and controlling factors of soil denitrification rate&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The denitrification process profoundly affects soil nitrogen (N) availability and generates its byproduct, nitrous oxide, as a potent greenhouse gas. There are large uncertainties in predicting global denitrification because its controlling factors remain elusive. In this study, we compiled 4301 observations of denitrification rates across a variety of terrestrial ecosystems from 214 papers published in the literature. The averaged denitrification rate was 3516.3 +/- 91.1 mu g N kg(-1) soil day(-1). The highest denitrification rate was 4242.3 +/- 152.3 mu g N kg(-1) soil day(-1) under humid subtropical climates, and the lowest was 965.8 +/- 150.4 mu g N kg(-1) under dry climates. The denitrification rate increased with temperature, precipitation, soil carbon and N contents, as well as microbial biomass carbon and N, but decreased with soil clay contents. The variables related to soil N contents (e.g., nitrate, ammonium, and total N) explained the variation of denitrification more than climatic and edaphic variables (e.g., mean annual temperature (MAT), soil moisture, soil pH, and clay content) according to structural equation models. Soil microbial biomass carbon, which was influenced by soil nitrate, ammonium, and total N, also strongly influenced denitrification at a global scale. Collectively, soil N contents, microbial biomass, pH, texture, moisture, and MAT accounted for 60% of the variation in global denitrification rates. The findings suggest that soil N contents and microbial biomass are strong predictors of denitrification at the global scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;uncovering-the-critical-soil-moisture-thresholds-of-plant-water-stress-for-european-ecosystems&quot;&gt;Uncovering the critical soil moisture thresholds of plant water stress for European ecosystems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding the critical soil moisture (SM) threshold (theta(crit)) of plant water stress and land surface energy partitioning is a basis to evaluate drought impacts and improve models for predicting future ecosystem condition and climate. Quantifying the theta(crit) across biomes and climates is challenging because observations of surface energy fluxes and SM remain sparse. Here, we used the latest database of eddy covariance measurements to estimate theta(crit) across Europe by evaluating evaporative fraction (EF)-SM relationships and investigating the covariance between vapor pressure deficit (VPD) and gross primary production (GPP) during SM dry-down periods. We found that the theta(crit) and soil matric potential threshold in Europe are 16.5% and -0.7 MPa, respectively. Surface energy partitioning characteristics varied among different vegetation types; EF in savannas had the highest sensitivities to SM in water-limited stage, and the lowest in forests. The sign of the covariance between daily VPD and GPP consistently changed from positive to negative during dry-down across all sites when EF shifted from relatively high to low values. This sign of the covariance changed after longer period of SM decline in forests than in grasslands and savannas. Estimated theta(crit) from the VPD-GPP covariance method match well with the EF-SM method, showing this covariance method can be used to detect the theta(crit). We further found that soil texture dominates the spatial variability of theta(crit) while shortwave radiation and VPD are the major drivers in determining the spatial pattern of EF sensitivities. Our results highlight for the first time that the sign change of the covariance between daily VPD and GPP can be used as an indicator of how ecosystems transition from energy to SM limitation. We also characterized the corresponding theta(crit) and its drivers across diverse ecosystems in Europe, an essential variable to improve the representation of water stress in land surface models.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/02/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on February 25, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2022/02/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2022/02/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2022-02-16T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2022-02-16T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2022-5&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2022 #5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil enzymes as indicators of soil function: A step toward greater realism in microbial ecological modeling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What type of gully is that? The need for a classification of gullies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The naturalness index for the identification of natural areas on regional scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-enzymes-as-indicators-of-soil-function-a-step-toward-greater-realism-in-microbial-ecological-modeling&quot;&gt;Soil enzymes as indicators of soil function: A step toward greater realism in microbial ecological modeling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil carbon (C) and nitrogen (N) cycles and their complex responses to environmental changes have received increasing attention. However, large uncertainties in model predictions remain, partially due to the lack of explicit representation and parameterization of microbial processes. One great challenge is to effectively integrate rich microbial functional traits into ecosystem modeling for better predictions. Here, using soil enzymes as indicators of soil function, we developed a competitive dynamic enzyme allocation scheme and detailed enzyme-mediated soil inorganic N processes in the Microbial-ENzyme Decomposition (MEND) model. We conducted a rigorous calibration and validation of MEND with diverse soil C-N fluxes, microbial C:N ratios, and functional gene abundances from a 12-year CO2 x N grassland experiment (BioCON) in Minnesota, USA. In addition to accurately simulating soil CO2 fluxes and multiple N variables, the model correctly predicted microbial C:N ratios and their negative response to enriched N supply. Model validation further showed that, compared to the changes in simulated enzyme concentrations and decomposition rates, the changes in simulated activities of eight C-N-associated enzymes were better explained by the measured gene abundances in responses to elevated atmospheric CO2 concentration. Our results demonstrated that using enzymes as indicators of soil function and validating model predictions with functional gene abundances in ecosystem modeling can provide a basis for testing hypotheses about microbially mediated biogeochemical processes in response to environmental changes. Further development and applications of the modeling framework presented here will enable microbial ecologists to address ecosystem-level questions beyond empirical observations, toward more predictive understanding, an ultimate goal of microbial ecology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-type-of-gully-is-that-the-need-for-a-classification-of-gullies&quot;&gt;What type of gully is that? The need for a classification of gullies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite over a century of investigations into gullies and gully erosion, the characterization and categorization of gullies and the varied definitions, nomenclatures and terminology used has caused some confusion in understanding and communicating the relationships of gully forms and processes around the world. We firstly review the gully literature and highlight how a lack of consistency in gully definition and characterization prevents unifying theory from being developed within this important field of research, since it is often unclear whether different landscape features being discussed are comparable. We propose that conventionally employed qualitative planform and cross-sectional characteristics of gullies alone are inadequate to define gully types, yet both these features remain central to most modern gully descriptions. We discuss the need to revise and augment these basic characteristics with clearly defined morphogenetic attributes such as landscape context, soil material characteristics, erosion processes, hydrological integrity, modes of development, and head/side-wall morphology for an effective, practicable, generic gully classification scheme. Central to a gully classification scheme is the need for a clear definition of what a gully is - and is not - for which geomorphological criteria are proposed to differentiate a ‘gully’ from other ‘incisional land surface forms’. This gully definition hinges largely on the identification of a retreating head scarp and the internal erosion by mass-movement and other sidewall slope erosion processes, coupled with the transport of the soil materials from the gully void. By defining a gully and synthesizing descriptions of gully ‘types’ from the literature and our own experience, we propose key morphogenetic attributes of gullies necessary to form a framework for a systematic gully classification scheme. An initial, eclectic classification framework is presented as both a summation and a synthesis of the literature review, and as a progenitor to a dynamic generic classification scheme that is proposed in a follow-up article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-naturalness-index-for-the-identification-of-natural-areas-on-regional-scale&quot;&gt;The naturalness index for the identification of natural areas on regional scale&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers have been trying to measure the influence of humankind on our environment for several decades. Among the technical solutions for this goal, approaches for a rule-based fusion of different geospatial information layers have reached the greatest level of maturity, enabling the (semi-)automatic production of maps at resolutions of about 1 square kilometer. While those existing approaches aim at a global analysis of human influence, conservation efforts are usually implemented on a regional scale. To bridge the gap between a global, lowresolution analysis and a local, high-resolution analysis, with this paper, we propose the Naturalness Index (NI), which represents the naturalness of the Earth’s surface as a metric between 0 and 100 at a spatial resolution of 10 m per pixel. Our approach builds on the established Human Influence Index, but replaces different geospatial input layers with more recent, higher resolution counterparts. Using the cloud computing platform Google Earth Engine, regional maps at a resolution of 10 m x 10 m per pixel can be produced efficiently in a fully automatic manner. We demonstrate the functionality by creating maps for three different localities in Europe - Bavaria, Lapland, and Scotland. A comparison of the NI values achieved with our approach to official conservation areas as well as a correlation with existing similar maps indicate the validity of our approach.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/02/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on February 16, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2022/02/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2022/02/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2022-02-10T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2022-02-10T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2022-4&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2022 #4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A miniaturized method for fast, simple, and sensitive pesticide analysis in soils&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bio-mediated soil improvement: An introspection into processes, materials, characterization and applications&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil salinity: A global threat to sustainable development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Responding to Ecological Transformation: Mental Models, External Constraints, and Manager Decision-Making&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Management Foundations for Navigating Ecological Transformation by Resisting, Accepting, or Directing Social-Ecological Change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;management-foundations-for-navigating-ecological-transformation-by-resisting-accepting-or-directing-social-ecological-change&quot;&gt;Management Foundations for Navigating Ecological Transformation by Resisting, Accepting, or Directing Social-Ecological Change&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite striking global change, management to ensure healthy landscapes and sustained natural resources has tended to set objectives on the basis of the historical range of variability in stationary ecosystems. Many social-ecological systems are moving into novel conditions that can result in ecological transformation. We present four foundations to enable a transition to future-oriented conservation and management that increases capacity to manage change. The foundations are to identify plausible social-ecological trajectories, to apply upstream and deliberate engagement and decision-making with stakeholders, to formulate management pathways to desired futures, and to consider a portfolio approach to manage risk and account for multiple preferences across space and time. We use the Kenai National Wildlife Refuge in Alaska as a case study to illustrate how the four foundations address common land management challenges for navigating transformation and deciding when, where, and how to resist, accept, or direct social-ecological change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;responding-to-ecological-transformation-mental-models-external-constraints-and-manager-decision-making&quot;&gt;Responding to Ecological Transformation: Mental Models, External Constraints, and Manager Decision-Making&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ecological transformation creates many challenges for public natural resource management and requires managers to grapple with new relationships to change and new ways to manage it. In the context of unfamiliar trajectories of ecological change, a manager can resist, accept, or direct change, choices that make up the resist-accept-direct (RAD) framework. In this article, we provide a conceptual framework for how to think about this new decision space that managers must navigate. We identify internal factors (mental models) and external factors (social feasibility, institutional context, and scientific uncertainty) that shape management decisions. We then apply this conceptual framework to the RAD strategies (resist, accept, direct) to illuminate how internal and external factors shape those decisions. Finally, we conclude with a discussion of how this conceptual framework shapes our understanding of management decisions, especially how these decisions are not just ecological but also social, and the implications for research and management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-salinity-a-global-threat-to-sustainable-development&quot;&gt;Soil salinity: A global threat to sustainable development&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil is a vital resource for feeding the burgeoning global population, and it is also essential for realizing most of the ‘United Nations Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs)’. For example, it is vital to realizing the ‘Zero hunger (SDG2), Good health and well-being (SDG3), Clean water and sanitation (SDG6), and Life on land (SDG15)’. Excess salts present in the soil make it saline, and it poses a significant threat to agricultural production and environmental health. Soil salinity is an extensive problem and spreads over one billion hectares extended over 100 countries. This paper presents a comprehensive review of global soil salinity management through the applications of remote sensing and GIS. All possible sources of relevant and current literature were accessed and more than 260 publications were collected and carefully analysed, for this review. The rationale and severity of the salinity problem are provided. The impact of salinity on plant yield and the effect of climate change on soil salinity are detailed. The salinity indicators and salinity monitoring and mapping are provided, and the global cases of soil salinity management through remote sensing and GIS applications under different agro-hydro-climatic environments are discussed, followed by a summary of conclusions and challenges along with future research directions. The analysis of past investigations showed that remote sensing strategy might be a practical approach to adequately assess plant response such as evapotranspiration under diverse salinity environments, yet it additionally has various difficulties. The lower spatial and temporal resolution of imagery may reason errors because of subpixel heterogeneity. However, with the improvement of the better-resolution thermal infrared remote method, there is the possibility to spot spatial variations at a smaller scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bio-mediated-soil-improvement-an-introspection-into-processes-materials-characterization-and-applications&quot;&gt;Bio-mediated soil improvement: An introspection into processes, materials, characterization and applications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time in the practice of geotechnical engineering, soil has been viewed as an inert material, comprising only inorganic phases. However, microorganisms including bacteria, archaea and eukaryotes are ubiquitous in soil and have the capacity and capability to alter bio-geochemical processes in the local soil environment. The cumulative changes could consequently modify the physical, mechanical, conductive and chemical properties of the bulk soil matrix. In recent years, the topic of bio-mediated geotechnics has gained momentum in the scientific literature. It involves the manipulation of various bio-geochemical soil processes to improve soil engineering performance. In particular, the process of microbial-induced calcium carbonate precipitation (MICP) has received the most attention for its superior performance for soil improvement. The present work aims to shape a comprehensive understanding of recent developments in bio-mediated geotechnics, with a focus on MICP. Referring to around one hundred studies published over the past five years, this review focuses on popular and alternative MICP processes, innovative raw materials and additives for MICP, emerging tools and testing methodologies for characterizing MICP at multi-scale, and applications in emerging and/or unconventional geotechnical fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-miniaturized-method-for-fast-simple-and-sensitive-pesticide-analysis-in-soils&quot;&gt;A miniaturized method for fast, simple, and sensitive pesticide analysis in soils&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Purpose Organochlorine pesticides (OCPs) like lindane and DDT have been used extensively after World War II until the 1990s. Still, residues of these pesticides can be found in agricultural soils all over the world, especially in developing countries. Often, they occur in extensive areas and elevated concentrations so that food safety is jeopardized. Hence, simple, cheap, and fast analytical methods are needed for a straight-forward assessment of risks. A miniaturized solid-liquid extraction combined with solid-phase microextraction (SPME) based on a proven ISO method is presented. Methods The performance of the method is evaluated by extracting three different soils which were spiked with HCH and DDT congeners, and trifluralin, and aged for 35 days. The results are compared with those of a modified quick, easy, cheap, efficient, rugged, and safe (QuEChERS) method. For further validation, both methods are applied to three environmental soil samples. Results Validation results show limits of detection and quantification as well as recovery rates in good agreement with standard requirements. The new method was found to be quicker than QuEChERS, which requires time-consuming preparation of reagents. Conclusion Merits include low time and sample volume requirements (0.5 g) and the possibility to extract many samples simultaneously, which allows the screening of large sample sizes to determine the pollution status of whole landscape regions. However, access to an automated SPME apparatus is assumed. The authors can recommend this method as a cheap and fast alternative where SPME is available.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/02/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on February 10, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2022/01/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2022/01/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2022-01-29T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2022-01-29T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2022-3&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2022 #3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimating cation exchange capacity from agronomic soil tests: Comparing Mehlich-3 and ammonium acetate sum of cations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evaluation of Mehlich-3 for determination of cation exchange capacity in Kansas soils&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The meaning of net zero and how to get it right&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-meaning-of-net-zero-and-how-to-get-it-right&quot;&gt;The meaning of net zero and how to get it right&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of net-zero carbon emissions has emerged from physical climate science. However, it is operationalized through social, political and economic systems. We identify seven attributes of net zero, which are important to make it a successful framework for climate action. The seven attributes highlight the urgency of emission reductions, which need to be front-loaded, and of coverage of all emission sources, including currently difficult ones. The attributes emphasize the need for social and environmental integrity. This means carbon dioxide removals should be used cautiously and the use of carbon offsets should be regulated effectively. Net zero must be aligned with broader sustainable development objectives, which implies an equitable net-zero transition, socio-ecological sustainability and the pursuit of broad economic opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Net-zero emissions is more than a concept of physical climate science. It is implemented in social, political and economic contexts. This Perspective proposes seven attributes that are critical for the practical and effective implementation of net zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;estimating-cation-exchange-capacity-from-agronomic-soil-tests-comparing-mehlich-3-and-ammonium-acetate-sum-of-cations&quot;&gt;Estimating cation exchange capacity from agronomic soil tests: Comparing Mehlich-3 and ammonium acetate sum of cations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil cation exchange capacity (CEC) measures the capability of soils to hold and release nutrients. It is an important measure for classifying soils and planning nutrient additions, but it is not included in routine soil tests offered to farmers. In this study, we compared CEC measured with standard laboratory practices (neutral ammonium acetate [AAc]) with CEC estimated from agronomic soil test data (Mehlich-3 and AAc). We applied previously published estimation methods to a dataset of 48 soil samples. Based on the results, traditional methods underestimate measured cation exchange capacity by 36% for Mehlich-3 and 24% for AAc. The estimation can be improved by including aluminium (12% overestimate) or by fitting a localized pedotransfer function (3% underestimate), which offers a possibility for informing land managers about their soil nutrient holding capacity without adding costs to the analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evaluation-of-mehlich-3-for-determination-of-cation-exchange-capacity-in-kansas-soils&quot;&gt;Evaluation of Mehlich-3 for determination of cation exchange capacity in Kansas soils&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil testing laboratories across the United States have implemented the Mehlich-3 (M3) extraction method for phosphorus (P) and other nutrients. Though M3 is known to work well as a multinutrient extractant, it raises concerns for measuring exchangeable cations, particularly in calcareous soils. The objectives of this study were (a) to evaluate M3 as an extractant for base cations for Kansas soils, (b) to identify a range of soil pH where M3 may be a suitable replacement for ammonium acetate (AA), and (c) to examine the relationship between cation exchange capacity (CEC) summation and CEC displacement. A study was conducted evaluating 308 soils collected from across Kansas and extracted using both the M3 and AA soil extraction methods. Cation exchange capacity was estimated using the summation approach from measurements of both the M3 and AA, and the displacement method. Results indicate a strong correlation among M3 and AA methods for K, Mg, and Na (R-2 = .98, .96, .97, respectively). However, these relationships were considerably weaker for extractable Ca (R-2 = .78), where extractable Ca was higher in the M3 extracts for high pH soils. Estimated CEC was also affected by soil pH for the M3 method, with an estimated critical pH value of 7.3. Extractable Ca and CEC for soils with a pH below 7.3 showed a strong correlation between M3 and AA methods (R-2 = .9). Using M3 as a multinutrient extractant can improve turnaround time for sample analysis in soil testing laboratories. However, the use of the M3 procedure in soils with a pH of 7.3 or above will likely result in overestimation of exchangeable Ca and CEC.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/01/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on January 29, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>
