<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Smart Digital Agriculture</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2021-08-31T09:31:31+10:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/08/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/08/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-08-31T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-08-31T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-28&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #28&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proposed algorithm for the identification of rural areas with regard to variability of soil quality.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use of metabolomics to quantify changes in soil microbial function in response to fertiliser nitrogen supply and extreme drought&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Altered mineral mapping based on ground-airborne hyperspectral data and wavelet spectral angle mapper tri-training model: Case studies from Dehua-Youxi-Yongtai Ore District, Central Fujian, China&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Iterative Deep Learning (IDL) for agricultural landscape classification using fine spatial resolution remotely sensed imagery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;proposed-algorithm-for-the-identification-of-rural-areas-with-regard-to-variability-of-soil-quality&quot;&gt;Proposed algorithm for the identification of rural areas with regard to variability of soil quality&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The development of agriculture in many countries and its productivity are considerably differentiated in terms of space. At present, Poland has agricultural areas which in many respects can compete with agriculture in the member states of the European Union. However, in some areas agricultural production run by private farms owned by individuals is on the verge of or falls below the limit of profitability. The priorities of the common agricultural policy in the European Union (EU) include a willingness to improve the quality of life in rural areas and effective utilization of their resources. Another goal is to support agricultural activity and align development chances for farms in areas featuring adverse environmental conditions and low soil productivity. This article presents the results of studies regarding the development of a method for identifying useless agricultural land. The study covered 44 villages with a registered surface area totalling 53941.00 ha, situated in the district of Brzoz ‘ ow, Subcarpathian voivodeship, in south-eastern Poland. Studies showed that it is possible to identify problem areas for agriculture, thanks to which the produced methodology may prove to be a useful tool in land consolidation works facilitating reasonable planning of the development of such areas. Thus, a universal tool can be designed for analysing large areas, e.g., communes, districts or voivodeships, and a high level of consistency of results can be a guarantee of reliable decisions regarding the development strategy for the specific area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-of-metabolomics-to-quantify-changes-in-soil-microbial-function-in-response-to-fertiliser-nitrogen-supply-and-extreme-drought&quot;&gt;Use of metabolomics to quantify changes in soil microbial function in response to fertiliser nitrogen supply and extreme drought&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Climate change is expected to increase the frequency and severity of droughts in many regions of the world. Soil health is likely to be negatively impacted by these extreme events. It is therefore important to understand the impact of drought on soil functioning and the delivery of soil-related ecosystem services. This study aimed to assess the resilience and change in physiological status of the microbial community under extreme moisture stress conditions using novel metabolic profiling approaches, namely complex lipids and untargeted primary metabolites. In addition, we used phospholipid fatty acid (PLFA) profiling to identify changes in microbial community structure. Soil samples were collected during a natural, extreme drought event and post-drought from replicated grassland split plots, planted with either deep-rooting Festulolium (cv. AberNiche) or Lolium perenne L. (cv. AberEcho), receiving nitrogen (N) fertiliser loading rates at either 0 or 300 kg N ha-1 yr- 1. These plots were split at the start of the drought period, and half of each subplot was irrigated with water throughout the drought period at a rate of 50 mm week-1 to alleviate moisture stress. PLFA analysis revealed a distinct shift in microbial community between drought and post-drought conditions, primarily driven by N loading and water deficit. Complex lipid analysis identified 239 compounds and untargeted analysis of primary metabolites identified 155 compounds. Both soil complex lipids and primary metabolites showed significant changes under drought conditions. Additionally, the irrigated ‘reference’ plots had a significantly higher cumulative greenhouse gas (CO2 and N2O) flux over the period of sampling. Recovery of the microbial lipidome and metabolome to reference plot levels post-drought was rapid (within days). Considerable changes in soil primary metabolomic and lipidomic concentrations shown in this study demonstrate that while soil metabolism was strongly affected by moisture stress, the system (plant and soil) was highly resilient to an intense drought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;altered-mineral-mapping-based-on-ground-airborne-hyperspectral-data-and-wavelet-spectral-angle-mapper-tri-training-model-case-studies-from-dehua-youxi-yongtai-ore-district-central-fujian-china&quot;&gt;Altered mineral mapping based on ground-airborne hyperspectral data and wavelet spectral angle mapper tri-training model: Case studies from Dehua-Youxi-Yongtai Ore District, Central Fujian, China&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mineral mapping is an important procedure for the utilization of mineral resources, and it is also significant to the analysis of mineralization zone especially for altered minerals. The emergence of remote sensing, especially hyperspectral data has become a new approach for mineral mapping on a wide scale. In addition, spectral angle mapping (SAM) is a commonly used classifier to distinguish the minerals, but the discrimination ability is weak on a mapping scale, and the identification accuracy is poor for a series of minerals with similar spectral curves when a single classifier is applied. In this work, altered minerals are identified at Dehua-Youxi-Yongtai Ore District uniting ground and airborne hyperspectral data, and wavelet SAM (WSAM) tri-training model is constructed to discriminate the category of 9 altered minerals. Experimental results demonstrate that the proposed technique provides the identification accuracy of 82% and 70% for virtual and XRD verifications, and the mapping result is believable compared with measured sampling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;iterative-deep-learning-idl-for-agricultural-landscape-classification-using-fine-spatial-resolution-remotely-sensed-imagery&quot;&gt;Iterative Deep Learning (IDL) for agricultural landscape classification using fine spatial resolution remotely sensed imagery&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The agricultural landscape can be interpreted at different semantic levels, such as fine low-level crop (LLC) classes (e.g., Wheat, Almond, and Alfalfa) and broad high-level crop (HLC) classes (e.g., Winter crops, Tree crops, and Forage). The LLC and HLC are hierarchically correlated with each other, but such intrinsically hierarchical relationships have been overlooked in previous crop classification studies in remote sensing. In this research, a novel Iterative Deep Learning (IDL) framework was proposed for the classification of complex agricultural landscapes using remotely sensed imagery. The IDL adopts an object-based convolutional neural network (OCNN) as the basic classifier for both the LLC and HLC classifications, which has the advantage of maintaining precise crop parcel boundaries. In IDL, the HLC classification implemented by the OCNN is conditional upon the LLC classification probabilities, whereas the HLC probabilities combined with the original imagery are, in turn, re-used as inputs to the OCNN to enhance the LLC classification. Such an iterative updating procedure forms a Markov process, where both the LLC and HLC classifications are refined and evolve collaboratively. The effectiveness of the IDL was tested on two heterogeneous agricultural fields using fine spatial resolution (FSR) SAR and optical imagery. The experimental results demonstrate that the iterative process of IDL helps to resolve contradictions within the class hierarchies. The new proposed IDL consistently increased the accuracies of both the LLC and HLC classifications with iteration, and achieved the highest accuracies for each at four iterations. The average overall accuracies were 88.4% for LLC and 91.2% for HLC, for both study sites, far greater than the accuracies of the state-of-the-art benchmarks, including the pixel-wise CNN (81.7% and 85.9%), object-based image analysis (OBIA) (84.0% and 85.8%), and OCNN (84.0% and 88.4%). To the best of our knowledge, the proposed model is the first to identify and use the relationship between the class levels in an ontological hierarchy in a remote sensing classification process. It is applied here to increase progressively the accuracy of classification at two levels for a complex agricultural landscape. As such IDL represents an entirely new paradigm for remote sensing image classification. Moreover, the promising results demonstrate the great potential of the proposed IDL with wide application prospect.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/08/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on August 31, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/08/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/08/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-08-30T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-08-30T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-29&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #29&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;VNIR and MIR spectroscopy of PLFA-derived soil microbial properties and associated soil physicochemical characteristics in an experimental plant diversity gradient.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The blue carbon wealth of nations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Both carbon sequestration and yield are related to particulate organic carbon stability affected by organic amendment origins in mollisol&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A two-field geostatistical model combining point and areal observations-A case study of annual runoff predictions in the Voss area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vnir-and-mir-spectroscopy-of-plfa-derived-soil-microbial-properties-and-associated-soil-physicochemical-characteristics-in-an-experimental-plant-diversity-gradient&quot;&gt;VNIR and MIR spectroscopy of PLFA-derived soil microbial properties and associated soil physicochemical characteristics in an experimental plant diversity gradient&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hutengs, C; Eisenhauer, N; (…); Vohland, M
Sep 2021 | SOIL BIOLOGY &amp;amp; BIOCHEMISTRY 160 , pp.8319-8319
Improving our understanding of the functions and processes of soil microbial communities and their interactions with the physicochemical soil environment requires large amounts of timely and cost-efficient soil data, which is difficult to obtain with routine laboratory-analytical methods. Soil spectroscopy with portable visible-to-near infrared (VNIR) and mid-infrared (MIR) instruments can fill this gap by facilitating the rapid acquisition of biotic and abiotic soil information. In this study, we evaluated the capabilities of VNIR and MIR spectroscopy to analyze soil physicochemical and microbial properties in a long-term grassland biodiversity-ecosystem functioning experiment. Soil samples were collected at the Jena Experiment (Jena, Germany) and measured with portable VNIR and MIR spectrometers in field-moist condition to determine their potential for on-site data collection and analysis. Reference data to calibrate spectroscopic models were acquired with routine analytical methods, including PLFA extractions of microbial biomarkers. We further collected reference VNIR and MIR data on pre-treated soils (dried and finely ground) to assess the anticipated impact of field measurements on spectroscopic calibrations. MIR spectra allowed more accurate estimates of soil physicochemical and microbial properties than VNIR data on pre-treated samples. For soils in field condition, MIR calibrations were more accurate for physicochemical properties, but VNIR data gave significantly better estimates of microbial properties. Combined VNIR/MIR estimates achieved the most accurate estimation results for all soil properties in each case. Soil physicochemical properties could be estimated from VNIR/MIR data with high accuracy (R2 = 0.72-0.99) on pre-treated soil samples, whereas the results for soil microbial properties were more moderate (R2 = 0.66-0.72). On field-moist soils, estimation accuracies decreased notably for organic and inorganic carbon (Delta RMSE = 52-72%), improved slightly for soil texture (Delta RMSE = 4-7%) and decreased slightly for microbial properties (Delta RMSE = 4-9%). The VNIR/MIR estimates derived from soils in field condition were sufficiently accurate to detect experimental plant treatment effects on organic carbon, as well as bacterial and fungal biomass. We further found that spectroscopic estimates of soil microbial properties were primarily enabled through indirect correlations with spectrally active soil constituents, i.e., associations between soil microbial properties and the physicochemical soil environment. Our findings highlight the capacity of VNIR and MIR spectroscopy to analyze the physicochemical soil environment, including potential on-site data collection and analysis on soils in field condition, and indicate that VNIR/MIR data can estimate soil microbial properties when soil physicochemical properties shape the distribution of soil microbial communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-blue-carbon-wealth-of-nations&quot;&gt;The blue carbon wealth of nations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bertram, C; Quaas, M; (…); Rickels, W
Aug 2021 | NATURE CLIMATE CHANGE 11 (8) , pp.704-+
Carbon sequestration and storage in mangroves, salt marshes and seagrass meadows is an essential coastal ‘blue carbon’ ecosystem service for climate change mitigation. Here we offer a comprehensive, global and spatially explicit economic assessment of carbon sequestration and storage in three coastal ecosystem types at the global and national levels. We propose a new approach based on the country-specific social cost of carbon that allows us to calculate each country’s contribution to, and redistribution of, global blue carbon wealth. Globally, coastal ecosystems contribute a mean +/- s.e.m. of US190.67 +/- 30 bn yr(-1) to blue carbon wealth. The three countries generating the largest positive net blue wealth contribution for other countries are Australia, Indonesia and Cuba, with Australia alone generating a positive net benefit of US$22.8 +/- 3.8 bn yr(-)(1) for the rest of the world through coastal ecosystem carbon sequestration and storage in its territory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blue carbon ecosystems take up and store substantial amounts of carbon. This represents an important ecosystem service in the context of climate change, with coastal ecosystems contributing nearly US$200 bn yr(-)(1) to blue carbon wealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;both-carbon-sequestration-and-yield-are-related-to-particulate-organic-carbon-stability-affected-by-organic-amendment-origins-in-mollisol&quot;&gt;Both carbon sequestration and yield are related to particulate organic carbon stability affected by organic amendment origins in mollisol&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Purpose Exploring how organic amendments influence carbon sequestration by affecting particulate organic carbon (POC) and determining the optimum amendment for protecting and restoring mollisol and increasing yields. Methods Differences of POC properties and maize yields in 3-year soils amended with organic material of different origins were studied. POC was separated by a wet sieving method, and the structure was analyzed by C-13 NMR spectroscopy. Results We found that SOC accumulation in soils amended with plant origin organic materials resulted from increasing organic fractions other than POC, while that in soils amended with animal origin materials resulted from increasing POC. The proportion of POC net variation in SOC net variation was significantly negatively correlated with SOC (p &amp;lt; 0.01). POC, mainly composed of alkyl C and alkoxyl C (more than 68%), had its stability more accurately evaluated through combined analysis of the carbonyl C content and alkyl C/alkoxyl C ratio. The addition of organic materials improved POC stability by increasing the alkyl C/alkoxyl C ratio and decreasing the carbonyl C content. Maize yields were positively correlated with SOC content and POC stability (p &amp;lt; 0.01), which increased by at least 2012 kg ha(-1) with the addition of organic materials. Conclusion Increasing more stable POC will promote the carbon sink. The order of the stability of POC in mollisol amended with organic materials of different origins was woody plant material &amp;gt; herb material &amp;gt; livestock dung &amp;gt; poultry dung. The woody plant material was the optimum organic amendment for mollisol, enhanced POC stability, and promoted SOC sequestration while increasing the yield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-two-field-geostatistical-model-combining-point-and-areal-observations-a-case-study-of-annual-runoff-predictions-in-the-voss-area&quot;&gt;A two-field geostatistical model combining point and areal observations-A case study of annual runoff predictions in the Voss area&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We estimate annual runoff by using a Bayesian geostatistical model for interpolation of hydrological data of different spatial support: streamflow observations from catchments (areal data), and precipitation and evaporation data (point data). The model contains one climatic spatial effect that is common for all years under study, and 1 year specific spatial effect. Hence, the framework enables a quantification of the spatial variability caused by long-term weather patterns and processes. This can contribute to a better understanding of biases and uncertainties in environmental modelling. The suggested model is evaluated by predicting annual runoff for catchments around Voss in Norway and through a simulation study. We find that on average we benefit from combining point and areal data compared to using only one of the data types, and that the interaction between nested areal data and point data gives a spatial model that takes us beyond smoothing. Another finding is that when climatic effects dominate over annual effects, systematic under- and overestimation of runoff can be expected over time. However, a dominating climatic spatial effect also implies that short records of runoff from an otherwise ungauged catchment can lead to large improvements in the predictive performance.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/08/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on August 30, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/08/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/08/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-08-07T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-08-07T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-27&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #27&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Toward Developing a Generalizable Pedotransfer Function for Saturated Hydraulic Conductivity Using Transfer Learning and Predictor Selector Algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Robust Drought Index Accounting Changing Precipitation Characteristics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The impact of climate change on the productivity of conservation agriculture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Global patterns of geo-ecological controls on the response of soil respiration to warming&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Microplastics in terrestrial ecosystems: Moving beyond the state of the art to minimize the risk of ecological surprise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;toward-developing-a-generalizable-pedotransfer-function-for-saturated-hydraulic-conductivity-using-transfer-learning-and-predictor-selector-algorithm&quot;&gt;Toward Developing a Generalizable Pedotransfer Function for Saturated Hydraulic Conductivity Using Transfer Learning and Predictor Selector Algorithm&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pedotransfer functions (PTFs) are being instrumental in saturated hydraulic conductivity (K-s) estimation. Despite various advancements, the performance of existing generic K-s predicting PTFs need augmentation. This study developed a robust K-s predicting PTF using a machine learning (ML) algorithm and exhaustive data set for 324 soils with 28 properties sampled over a tropical savanna region of India. Four ML algorithms were evaluated for this purpose, and random forest (RF) outperformed all others. A substantial improvement to the prediction by RF-based PTF was achieved through predictor selection using a hybrid wrapper-embedded algorithm. The predictor selection algorithm selected eight pertinent predictors (HID-S): S, Si, C, FSF, C-u, GMD, D-60, and D-10. The mean absolute error (MAE), root mean squared error (RMSE), coefficient of determination (R-2), and Nash-Sutcliffe efficiency (NSE) obtained as average tenfold cross-validation scores for RF algorithm training with HID-S were 0.87, 1.47, 0.94, and 0.94, respectively. The developed PTF (RF-HID-S) was evaluated alongside the recently published PTFs by Araya and Ghezzehei (2019, ), within and outside the study region. In that process, it was observed that the RF-HID-S possessed superior prediction proficiency compared to the recently published and commonly used PTFs in both cases. These findings mark RF-HID-S as the most robust generalizable PTF, which may further be evaluated in different parts of the world. Moreover, looking at the performance of the eight selected predictors within and outside the study region, they can be considered for experiment design globally to make K-s estimation accurate and cost-effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-robust-drought-index-accounting-changing-precipitation-characteristics&quot;&gt;A Robust Drought Index Accounting Changing Precipitation Characteristics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A realistic evaluation of drought onset is inevitable for the effective implementation of mitigation strategies. Meteorological droughts indicating the onset of drought propagation are usually quantified through unbiased indices that consider the month-wise magnitude variations in historical climatic variables, while completely ignoring their intramonthly distributions. However, the applicability of such indices under the present scenario of changing climate, where intense short wet spells are reportedly increasing, is questionable. Such changes in the wet spells could eventually lead to prolonged intramonthly dry spells, which in turn will pose many agricultural and socioeconomic risks. To monitor the changed scenario realistically, we propose a new drought index-the Standardized Net-Precipitation Distribution Index (SNEPI), which incorporates the distribution characteristics of the daily net-precipitation variable. The applicability of SNEPI is critically evaluated using synthetically generated and observed precipitation series over six diverse climatic locations of India, at 1-, 3-, 6-, and 12-month time scales. The utility of SNEPI is more profound for longer time scales, understandably due to the enhanced emphasis imparted on the distribution of rainfall spells by the longer periods. Standardized Net-Precipitation Distribution Index proves to be efficient in capturing the present scenario of increasing dryness (wetness) in wet (dry) regions when compared with the traditional Standardized Precipitation Evapotranspiration Index. Hence, the proposed index, which incorporates the changing precipitation characteristics, may aid in better quantification and monitoring of meteorological drought under the scenario of changing climate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-impact-of-climate-change-on-the-productivity-of-conservation-agriculture&quot;&gt;The impact of climate change on the productivity of conservation agriculture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors assess the productivity of conservation agriculture systems for eight major crops under current and future climate using a global-scale probabilistic machine-learning approach, revealing substantial differences in yield gain probabilities across crop type, management practice, climate zone and geography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conservation agriculture (CA) is being promoted as a set of management practices that can sustain crop production while providing positive environmental benefits. However, its impact on crop productivity is hotly debated, and how this productivity will be affected by climate change remains uncertain. Here we compare the productivity of CA systems and their variants on the basis of no tillage versus conventional tillage systems for eight major crop species under current and future climate conditions using a probabilistic machine-learning approach at the global scale. We reveal large differences in the probability of yield gains with CA across crop types, agricultural management practices, climate zones and geographical regions. For most crops, CA performed better in continental, dry and temperate regions than in tropical ones. Under future climate conditions, the performance of CA is expected to mostly increase for maize over its tropical areas, improving the competitiveness of CA for this staple crop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;global-patterns-of-geo-ecological-controls-on-the-response-of-soil-respiration-to-warming&quot;&gt;Global patterns of geo-ecological controls on the response of soil respiration to warming&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While soil respiration is known to be controlled by a range of biotic and abiotic factors, its temperature sensitivity in global models is largely related to climate parameters. Here, we show that temperature sensitivity of soil respiration is primarily controlled by interacting soil properties and only secondarily by vegetation traits and plant growth conditions. Temperature was not identified as a primary driver for the response of soil respiration to warming. In contrast, the nonlinearity and large spatial variability of identified controls stress the importance of the interplay among soil, vegetation and climate parameters in controlling warming responses. Global models might predict current soil respiration but not future rates because they neglect the controls exerted by soil development. To accurately predict the response of soil respiration to warming at the global scale, more observational studies across pedogenetically diverse soils are needed rather than focusing on the isolated effect of warming alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding the temperature sensitivity of soil respiration is critical to determining soil carbon dynamics under climate change. Spatial heterogeneity in controls highlights the importance of interactions between vegetation, soil and climate in driving the response of respiration to warming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;microplastics-in-terrestrial-ecosystems-moving-beyond-the-state-of-the-art-to-minimize-the-risk-of-ecological-surprise&quot;&gt;Microplastics in terrestrial ecosystems: Moving beyond the state of the art to minimize the risk of ecological surprise&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microplastic (plastic particles measuring &amp;lt;5mm) pollution is ubiquitous. Unlike in other well-studied ecosystems, for example, marine and freshwater environments, microplastics in terrestrial systems are relatively understudied. Their potential impacts on terrestrial environments, in particular the risk of causing ecological surprise, must be better understood and quantified. Ecological surprise occurs when ecosystem behavior deviates radically from expectations and generally has negative consequences for ecosystem services. The properties and behavior of microplastics within terrestrial environments may increase their likelihood of causing ecological surprises as they (a) are highly persistent global pollutants that will last for centuries, (b) can interact with the abiotic environment in a complex manner, (c) can impact terrestrial organisms directly or indirectly and (d) interact with other contaminants and can facilitate their transport. Here, we compiled findings of previous research on microplastics in terrestrial environments. We systematically focused on studies addressing different facets of microplastics related to their distribution, dispersion, impact on soil characteristics and functions, levels of biological organization of tested terrestrial biota (single species vs. assemblages), scale of experimental study and corresponding ecotoxicological effects. Our systematic assessment of previous microplastic research revealed that most studies have been conducted on single species under laboratory conditions with short-term exposures; few studies were conducted under more realistic long-term field conditions and/or with multi-species assemblages. Studies targeting multi-species assemblages primarily considered soil bacterial communities and showed that microplastics can alter essential nutrient cycling functions. More ecologically meaningful studies of terrestrial microplastics encompassing multi-species assemblages, critical ecological processes (e.g., biogeochemical cycles and pollination) and interactions with other anthropogenic stressors must be conducted. Addressing these knowledge gaps will provide a better understanding of microplastics as emerging global stressors and should lower the risk of ecological surprise in terrestrial ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/08/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on August 07, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/08/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/08/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-08-06T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-08-06T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-26&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #26&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Returning lands to nature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Boosting the generalization ability of Vis-NIR-spectroscopy-based regression models through dimension reduction and transfer learning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One shot evaluation of NPK in soils by “electronic tongue”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trafficking intensity index for soil compaction management in grasslands&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Geophysics conquering new territories: The rise of “agrogeophysics”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developing a strategy for the national coordinated soil moisture monitoring network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;returning-lands-to-nature&quot;&gt;Returning lands to nature&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Land-use-induced ecosystem reduction and degradation has profound impacts on the Earth system. Proceeding with currently unsustainable land use may jeopardize climate and ecosystem restoration targets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;boosting-the-generalization-ability-of-vis-nir-spectroscopy-based-regression-models-through-dimension-reduction-and-transfer-learning&quot;&gt;Boosting the generalization ability of Vis-NIR-spectroscopy-based regression models through dimension reduction and transfer learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calibration regression models based on visible and near-infrared (Vis/NIR) spectroscopy are now widely used in the rapid non-destructive prediction of agricultural products’ quality parameters. However, the distributions of products’ quality parameters and spectral responses are different in various batches of products, so a calibration regression model built on one dataset might be ineffective when tested in another. How to improve the generalization ability of models is a crucial problem and is formulated as ‘Calibration Transfer’. Calibration transfer was firstly proposed to eliminate the difference of spectral responses between spectrometers, but now it has been applied in the transfer between different domains of spectral samples or different components. In this paper, we proposed two robust models with great generalization ability in the calibration transfer task, respectively using dimension reduction and transfer learning, namely SPRS (Standard normal variate, Partial least squares dimension reduction, Ridge regression, Slope/bias) and SNV-based Aug-TrAdaBoost.R2. We tested the two models in spectral datasets of tea leaves to predict the moisture content of samples, it was found that SPRS and SNV-based Aug-TrAdaBoost.R2 can reach great performance over both source and target domains across different batches, different varieties, and different classes of tea leaf samples. SPRS and SNV-based Aug-TrAdaBoost.R2 achieved R2 values of 0.9314 and 0.9895 in cross-tea-class prediction whereas traditional calibration method PLSR + S/B only achieved 0.4874. SPRS had low computation complexity and was more robust while SNV-based Aug-TrAdaBoost.R2 had higher accuracy in target domain prediction but was computationconsuming. The two proposed models showed the potentials of online automatic quality parameters prediction and high-accuracy prediction across domains of various samples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;one-shot-evaluation-of-npk-in-soils-by-electronic-tongue&quot;&gt;One shot evaluation of NPK in soils by “electronic tongue”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart introduction of fertilizers in the soil should help to decrease the negative impact of chemicals on the environment without dramatic reduction of crop yield. The amounts of fertilizers have to be carefully tuned according to actual nutrients content in the soil and vegetation period of the plants. Since most of the chemical soil analyses are performed in the laboratory nowadays, fast and simple analytical tools have to be developed for this task. In this study, a potentiometric multisensor system was used for simultaneous determination of the N, P and K in the water extracts of the soils. It was shown that potentimetric sensors with multivariate data processing can be used for assessment of all three macronutrients, along with estimation of pH and conductivity of soil samples. Correlation coefficients between targeted parameters and sensor responses varied from 0.69 to 0.96. The quantification of N was possible with RMSE of 50 mg/kg in the range 60-426 mg/kg. The main benefits of the proposed approach are the short measurement duration - just 8 min for all the parameters, and reagentless procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;assessment-of-apparent-n-mineralization-at-field-scale&quot;&gt;Assessment of apparent N mineralization at field scale&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quantification of nitrogen mineralization at the field scale is necessary to improve current N fertilizer recommendations. The objective of this study was to identify a suitable set of explanatory variables and an appropriate modelling framework to estimate the average daily amount of N mineralized (DANM) during a corn (Zea mays L.) growing season. In six field experiments in Flat Inland Pampas, Argentina, DANM was evaluated in three different homogeneous zones (HZ), which were defined based on terrain elevation. Mixed-effect generalized linear models were developed that included growing season as random effect as well as HZ, sand, clay, silt, soil organic carbon, and normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI) as fixed effects. Results showed that DANM ranged from 0.19 to 1.25 kg N ha(-1) day(-1) with a mean of 0.64 kg N ha(-1) day(-1), which is equivalent to 110 kg N ha(-1) for the corn growing season. The best model included HZ, sand, and early NDVI measurements, and predicted DANM with an RMSE of 0.19 kg N ha(-1) day(-1). Thus, the model should be improved and tested in the Inland Flat Pampas before it could be used to assess N fertilizer application rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;trafficking-intensity-index-for-soil-compaction-management-in-grasslands&quot;&gt;Trafficking intensity index for soil compaction management in grasslands&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good soil structure provides multiple benefits for society but in grass-based production systems is underpinned by trafficking management regime. For Irish soils, there is no soil trafficking intensity index that considers the effect of geo-climatic variability or differences in drainage classes on soil compaction risk. Grazing and machinery activity data were compiled across 38 managed grasslands along with common soil structural quality indicators in order to develop and validate a ‘soil trafficking intensity index for compaction (STICi)’. Two component indices ofSTIC(i)were developed: (a) a grazing trafficking index (G(i), kg x year ha(-1)) and (b) a machinery trafficking index (M-i, kg x year ha(-1)). The average annual grazing trafficking pressure observed was 213,914 kg x year ha(-1), and the average annual machinery trafficking pressure was 4,412 kg x year ha(-1). These figures represent thresholds above which soils are at higher risk of compaction. M(i)spanned a wider range (-2.1 &amp;lt;= M-i &amp;lt;= 2.8) compared with G(i)(-1.32 &amp;lt;= G(i) &amp;lt;= 1.06).STIC(i)and components, when disaggregated by soil drainage class, were able to detect changes in direct indicators of soil structural quality, such as bulk density, total porosity, water holding capacity, water conductivity and visual soil assessment.STICi(M(i)and G(i)) were also related to indirect indicators, such as, soil carbon content, earthworms and microbial biomass. In general, poorly drained sites showed higher vulnerability to machinery trafficking intensity compared with grazing trafficking pressure. At national scale,STIC(i)can be utilized to identify soils at risk of compaction and underpin targeted management advice for supporting sustainable grassland production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;geophysics-conquering-new-territories-the-rise-of-agrogeophysics&quot;&gt;Geophysics conquering new territories: The rise of “agrogeophysics”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agriculture is facing immense challenges. We have to produce enough food while safe-guarding the environment for future generations. This results in the need to use less water and fertilizer, and to harness soil quality. Key to achieving this goal is improving the understanding of processes and interactions governing the soil-plant-atmosphere continuum of agricultural ecosystems. Geophysical tools have great potential to better characterize and quantify these processes noninvasively from the plot to landscape scale. Nevertheless, a number of challenges remain for geophysical results to be better exploited by different scientific communities and by decision-makers. In this special section, we explore ongoing research in the relatively new field of agrogeophysics, and we provide an overview of potential applications and highlight future research needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;developing-a-strategy-for-the-national-coordinated-soil-moisture-monitoring-network&quot;&gt;Developing a strategy for the national coordinated soil moisture monitoring network&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil moisture is a critical land surface variable, affecting a wide variety of climatological, agricultural, and hydrological processes. Determining the current soil moisture status is possible via a variety of methods, including in situ monitoring, remote sensing, and numerical modeling. Although all of these approaches are rapidly evolving, there is no cohesive strategy or framework to integrate these diverse information sources to develop and disseminate coordinated national soil moisture products that will improve our ability to understand climate variability. The National Coordinated Soil Moisture Monitoring Network initiative has developed a national strategy for network coordination with NOAA’s National Integrated Drought Information System. The strategy is currently in review within NOAA, and work is underway to implement the initial milestones of the strategy. This update reviews the goals and steps being taken to establish this national-scale coordination for soil moisture monitoring in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/08/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on August 06, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/08/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/08/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-08-05T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-08-05T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-25&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #25&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A comparison between three legacy soil maps of Zambia at national scale: The spatial patterns of legend units and their relation to soil properties.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dielectric models for moisture determination of soils with variable organic matter content&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ten challenges for the future of pedometrics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pedotransfer functions for estimating soil hydraulic properties from saturation to dryness&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil weathering behavior assessed by combined spectral ranges: Insights into aggregate analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-comparison-between-three-legacy-soil-maps-of-zambia-at-national-scale-the-spatial-patterns-of-legend-units-and-their-relation-to-soil-properties&quot;&gt;A comparison between three legacy soil maps of Zambia at national scale: The spatial patterns of legend units and their relation to soil properties&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We examined three soil maps of Zambia, two published at scales of 1:1 million - the Exploratory Soil Map of Zambia (ESMZ) and the Vegetation-Soil Map produced by Trapnell and colleagues in 1947 - and one at 1:3 million, the Soil Atlas of Africa (SAA). We estimated components of variance for measurements of clay, sand and organic carbon content and bulk density of the soil across the country using models which included different mean values for soil map units as random effects. For all but organic carbon content there was significant variation accounted for by differences between legend units for two of the maps, ESMZ with legend units based on the FAO-Unesco and SAA with legend units based on the World Reference Base respectively. This was despite their small cartographic scale. For the Vegetation-Soil Map, we examined differences between broad soil physiographic units. These did not account for significant variation in the soil properties. There were clear similarities between the soil physiographic units of the Soil-Vegetation Map and broader physiographic units into which the legend units of the ESMZ are grouped. The spatial pattern of soil units of the SAA was the most spatially heterogeneous, as measured by the sum of indicator variograms, despite being at the smallest published scale. It was apparent that some of the soil variation within the largest physiographic unit of the Soil-Vegetation Map, the Plateau Soils, as expressed by the map units of the SAA was significantly associated with the different vegetation units mapped in 1947. These studies show how quantitative assessment of legacy soil information may help us understand its potential and limitations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dielectric-models-for-moisture-determination-of-soils-with-variable-organic-matter-content&quot;&gt;Dielectric models for moisture determination of soils with variable organic matter content&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An accurate calibration function relating soil dielectric permittivity to its volumetric water content is essential for reliable measurements of soil moisture with the use of dielectric sensors. In the operational frequency range of popular capacitance and impedance sensors, various soil properties may influence the relation between the soil moisture and dielectric permittivity, which may worsen the measurement accuracy of a sensor. The aim of this paper is to investigate the relations among the organic matter content, dry bulk density, volumetric water content and dielectric permittivity in the 10-500 MHz frequency range, which covers the frequency range of operation of common soil moisture dielectric sensors operating in the frequency domain. Samples of soil material of belonging to sand, sandy loam and silt loam texture classes with varied organic matter content were measured with the use of a coaxial-like open-ended seven-rod probe connected to a vector-network-analyzer. A new simplified dielectric model is presented in order to accurately describe the obtained spectra. Next, several models connecting the real part of dielectric permittivity and volumetric water content, taking account of the impact of bulk density, were examined. It was found that two linear segmented models fitted to the obtained data better in the case of soil materials of sandy loam and silt loam textures. The best segmented model exhibited RMSE of about 0.023 m(3) m(-3) in comparison to about 0.04 m(3) m(-3) in the case of a simple linear model without density correction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ten-challenges-for-the-future-of-pedometrics&quot;&gt;Ten challenges for the future of pedometrics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pedometrics, the application of mathematical and statistical methods to the study of the distribution and genesis of soils, has broadened its scope over the past two decades. The primary focus of pedometricians has traditionally been on spatial and spatio-temporal soil inventories with numerical soil classification, geostatistical modelling of spatial variation and mapping. The rapid development of remote and proximal soil sensing as well as data-driven statistical modelling techniques have had a major impact on pedometrics over the past decades. During this time, a general demand for quantitative digital soil information for environmental modelling and management has compelled pedometricians to address other soil-related questions from a quantitative point of view: soil genesis and utility and quality of soil. While scientific progress is largely an autonomous process that is difficult to steer, research efforts could benefit from an agenda with pressing pedometric research topics. This paper defines and discusses ten recent or longstanding pedometrics challenges, with the attempt to identify knowledge gaps and suggest new concepts and methods to overcome them. The ten challenges were selected through a collaborative effort and may serve as a guidance for future pedometrics research and to foster collaboration among soil scientists. The challenges discussed in this paper are also indicators of the current understanding and state of knowledge from which progress can be measured in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pedotransfer-functions-for-estimating-soil-hydraulic-properties-from-saturation-to-dryness&quot;&gt;Pedotransfer functions for estimating soil hydraulic properties from saturation to dryness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current pedotransfer functions (PTFs) for estimating soil hydraulic curves are mostly developed to predict parameters of the Mualem-van Genuchten hydraulic functions. The Mualem-van Genuchten functions are recognised to be inadequate in representing soil water retention hydraulic conductivity curves at low pressure head ranges. This study presents neuroFX, a suite of PTFs, for estimating soil water retention and unsaturated hydraulic conductivity curves from saturation to complete dryness based on the Fredlund-Xing-Wang (FXW) model. The PTFs were calibrated using the neuro-m neural networks approach with three different sets of inputs: (1) SSCBD uses the sand, silt, and clay fractions, and bulk density; (2) SSC uses the sand, silt and clay fractions, and (3) soil textural class input. NeuroFX PTFs were trained using fitted parameters of the FXW model from selected data in the UNSODA database and validated using 5-fold cross-validation that was repeated 10 times. NeuroFX provides an uncertainty estimate of hydraulic parameters. The prediction quality of neuroFX was compared with two existing PTFs: ROSETTA and Brunswick-Weber (BW) PTFs. Based on multiple criteria, we found that neuroFX performed better than ROSETTA and BW PTFs in the same test sample. NeuroFX PTF with the SSCBD input yielded the best prediction of soil water retention and unsaturated hydraulic conductivity curves with RMSE in water content of 0.052 cm(3) cm(-3) and RMSE in log(10)(K) = 0.732 (in the magnitude of cm day(-1)), indicating the importance of including bulk density in the input of PTFs. NeuroFX was then used to map parameters of the FXW model for the whole of the continental USA over 6 depth intervals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-weathering-behavior-assessed-by-combined-spectral-ranges-insights-into-aggregate-analysis&quot;&gt;Soil weathering behavior assessed by combined spectral ranges: Insights into aggregate analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most research applying spectral sensors has focused on soil attributes quantification, with strong statistics and hundreds of data. Nevertheless, the explanation of the fundamental relationship between several spectral ranges and specific soil processes remains unclear. Soil sensing can be performed in many spectral ranges, however, the focus is usually on a specific one, which limits the knowledge of the phenomenon. Thus, this work investigated the synergistic performance of several spectral ranges (Gamma-ray; X-ray fluorescence, XRF; visible, Vis; near infrared, NIR; shortwave infrared, SWIR; and mid-infrared, MIR) on the weathering process of soils developed from magmatic material. Two soil profiles from Southeast Brazil (Sao Paulo state) were analyzed, assessing their chemical, physical and mineralogical data. The same profiles were analyzed by the indicated spectral ranges, which were related to mineralogy, weathering indices and mass balance (MB). The elements provided by Gamma-ray were related to the soil mineralogy and weathering degree of horizons. The XRF data enabled the calculation of MB and weathering indices, which were similar to those calculated by the traditional analysis. The spectra of the Vis-NIR-SWIR-MIR region presented alterations in their behavior related to the weathering degree of horizons. This synergic approach separated soil horizons by weathering degree more efficiently than a single spectral region. Single spectral measurements identified several elements and indices, which explained the weathering process. These results support further understanding of large datasets and their validation in statistical modeling.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/08/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on August 05, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/08/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/08/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-08-04T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-08-04T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-24&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #24&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nitrogen and phosphorus co-limit mineralization of labile carbon in deep subsoil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spatial evaluation and trade-off analysis of soil functions through Bayesian networks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Towards a standardization of soil-related ecosystem service assessments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A decision support framework assessing management impacts on crop yield, soil carbon changes and nitrogen losses to the environment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Machine learning in space and time for modelling soil organic carbon change&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perspectives on data-driven soil research&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identifying the fingerprint of permanganate oxidizable carbon as a measure of labile soil organic carbon using Fourier transform mid-infrared photoacoustic spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil organic carbon in irrigated agricultural systems: A meta-analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nitrogen-and-phosphorus-co-limit-mineralization-of-labile-carbon-in-deep-subsoil&quot;&gt;Nitrogen and phosphorus co-limit mineralization of labile carbon in deep subsoil&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peixoto, L; Elsgaard, L; (…); Olesen, JE
Jul 2021 | EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF SOIL SCIENCE 72 (4) , pp.1879-1884
The growth of deep-rooted crops has the potential to increase carbon deposition within deep subsoil layers, thereby contributing to climate change mitigation. Yet, the mechanisms of labile carbon stabilization in deep subsoils remain uncertain. Here we studied the effect of nitrogen, phosphorus and sulphur limitations on the microbial mineralization of added glucose and an artificial root exudate mixture (both spiked with C-14-glucose) in intact soil samples from a deep subsoil (5-6 m) over a 10-week incubation period, where the temporal respiration of CO2 and (CO2)-C-14 were quantified. We found that mineralization was co-limited by nitrogen and phosphorus, but the cumulative amount of CO2 emitted was significantly larger from artificial root exudates than glucose, suggesting that the nitrogen carried in amino acids in root exudates (here, L-arginine) was sufficient to overcome the nitrogen limitation in this subsoil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highlights&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Labile C substrates and nutrients from deep-rooted crops may affect the potential for C sequestration in subsoil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deep subsoil was incubated with glucose and artificial root exudates amended with N, P, and S.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C mineralization was co-limited by N and P, but less so in soil amended with glucose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amino acid derived-N in exudates from deep-rooted crops may alleviate the N limitation in deep subsoils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spatial-evaluation-and-trade-off-analysis-of-soil-functions-through-bayesian-networks&quot;&gt;Spatial evaluation and trade-off analysis of soil functions through Bayesian networks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vrebos, D; Jones, A; (…); Meire, P
Jul 2021 | EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF SOIL SCIENCE 72 (4) , pp.1575-1589
There is increasing recognition that soils fulfil many functions for society. Each soil can deliver a range of functions, but some soils are more effective at some functions than others due to their intrinsic properties. In this study we mapped four different soil functions on agricultural lands across the European Union. For each soil function, indicators were developed to evaluate their performance. To calculate the indicators and assess the interdependencies between the soil functions, data from continental long-term simulation with the DayCent model were used to build crop-specific Bayesian networks. These Bayesian Networks were then used to calculate the soil functions’ performance and trade-offs between the soil functions under current conditions. For each soil function the maximum potential was estimated across the European Union and changes in trade-offs were assessed. By deriving current and potential soil function delivery from Bayesian networks a better understanding is gained of how different soil functions and their interdependencies can differ depending on soil, climate and management. Highlights&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When increasing a soil function, how do trade-offs affect the other functions under different conditions? Bayesian networks evaluate trade-offs between soil functions and estimate their maximal delivery. Maximizing a soil function has varied effects on other functions depending on soil, climate and management. Differences in trade-offs make some locations more suitable for increasing a soil function then others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;towards-a-standardization-of-soil-related-ecosystem-service-assessments&quot;&gt;Towards a standardization of soil-related ecosystem service assessments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of ecosystem services (ES) creates understanding of the value of ecosystems for human well-being. With regard to soils, it provides a framework for assessments of soil contributions and soil management impacts. However, a lack of standardization impedes comparisons between assessment studies and the building of synthesis information. The Common International Classification of Ecosystem Services (CICES) is an important step forward, although its application to soils is not without difficulty. CICES version 5.1 defines 83 ES classes, of which only some are relevant for soils. We compiled two subsets of CICES classes: one set of soil-related ES comprising 29 services defined as directly and quantifiably controlled by soils and their properties, processes and functions, and another set of 40 ES defined as being affected by agricultural soil management.Additionally, we conducted a systematic literature review, searching for published lists of soil-related ES that claim completeness. We identified 11 relevant lists. Of all CICES classes, 12 were included in more than 75% of the lists, whereas another 36 classes were included in 25-75% of them. Regarding the suitability of the CICES classification for addressing ES in the context of soils and their agricultural management, we identified constraints, such as overlaps, gaps, and highly specific or very broad class definitions.Close cooperation between the soil research and ES communities could ensure better consideration of soils in future CICES updates. A shortlist of 25 service classes affected by agricultural soil management facilitates a standardized approach and may function as checklists in impact assessments. Highlights&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standardized definitions are needed to allow meta-analysis of ecosystem service studies and improve assessments. CICES defines 83 detailed classes of ecosystem services, suggested as a “default list”. We identified 29 classes as soil related and 40 classes as affected by agricultural soil management. Both subsets facilitate ecosystem service assessments in soil research and comparability of results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-decision-support-framework-assessing-management-impacts-on-crop-yield-soil-carbon-changes-and-nitrogen-losses-to-the-environment&quot;&gt;A decision support framework assessing management impacts on crop yield, soil carbon changes and nitrogen losses to the environment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agricultural management practices have multiple impacts on farming systems, including crop yield, soil fertility parameters such as soil organic carbon (SOC), and environmental quality. Agricultural decision support tools (DSTs) are key in sustainable farm strategies to optimize yield and minimize environmental losses because both the current agroecosystem properties as well as the effectiveness of management practices are highly variable in time and space. Here, we introduce a highly data-driven framework focusing on the evaluation of agronomic measures to reach agronomic and environmental targets. We demonstrate the potential of this approach by a proof of principle for 81 selected farm types across Europe, focusing on measures with respect to crop rotation, fertilization and soil tillage. Synthesizing data from long-term experiments and meta-analytical models, we estimated the impact of these measures on crop yield, SOC and N surpluses, while accounting for site-specific properties for the current and desired situation. The impacts of these measures on all farm types have been quantified, and optimum sets of agronomic measures have been selected in order to maximize crop yield and SOC levels and minimize N surpluses to reach the critical values for NO(3)(-)concentrations in groundwater. Our results, quantifying trade-offs among sustainability indicators that have traditionally been analyzed separately, illustrate that the suitability of measures varies by soil, climate and crop types within Europe. Our approach is promising for mapping region-specific management recommendations and evaluating the effectiveness of agronomic measures over multiple environmental goals and targets. Highlights&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We find a lack of empirical-based DSTs holistically assessing agronomic practices and indicators. Meta-analytical models were used to assess impacts of best fertilizer, tillage and crop measures. Our multi-criteria analysis shows impacts vary with crop, soil and climate in European regions. We demonstrate our developed framework focusing on crop yield, soil carbon and nitrogen losses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;machine-learning-in-space-and-time-for-modelling-soil-organic-carbon-change&quot;&gt;Machine learning in space and time for modelling soil organic carbon change&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spatially resolved estimates of change in soil organic carbon (SOC) stocks are necessary for supporting national and international policies aimed at achieving land degradation neutrality and climate change mitigation. In this work we report on the development, implementation and application of a data-driven, statistical method for mapping SOC stocks in space and time, using Argentina as a pilot. We used quantile regression forest machine learning to predict annual SOC stock at 0-30 cm depth at 250 m resolution for Argentina between 1982 and 2017. The model was calibrated using over 5,000 SOC stock values from the 36-year time period and 35 environmental covariates. We preprocessed normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI) dynamic covariates using a temporal low-pass filter to allow the SOC stock for a given year to depend on the NDVI of the current as well as preceding years. Predictions had modest temporal variation, with an average decrease for the entire country from 2.55 to 2.48 kg C m(-2)over the 36-year period (equivalent to a decline of 211 Gg C, 3.0% of the total 0-30 cm SOC stock in Argentina). The Pampa region had a larger estimated SOC stock decrease from 4.62 to 4.34 kg C m(-2)(5.9%) during the same period. For the 2001-2015 period, predicted temporal variation was seven-fold larger than that obtained using the Tier 1 approach of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change and United Nations Convention to Combat Desertification. Prediction uncertainties turned out to be substantial, mainly due to the limited number and poor spatial and temporal distribution of the calibration data, and the limited explanatory power of the covariates. Cross-validation confirmed that SOC stock prediction accuracy was limited, with a mean error of 0.03 kg C m(-2)and a root mean squared error of 2.04 kg C m(-2). In spite of the large uncertainties, this work showed that machine learning methods can be used for space-time SOC mapping and may yield valuable information to land managers and policymakers, provided that SOC observation density in space and time is sufficiently large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;perspectives-on-data-driven-soil-research&quot;&gt;Perspectives on data-driven soil research&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil is a complex system in which biological, chemical and physical interactions take place. The behaviour of these interactions changes in spatial scale from the atomic to the global, and in time. To understand how this system works, soil scientists usually rely on incremental improvements in the knowledge by refinement of theories through hypothesis testing and development using carefully designed experiments. In the last two decades, the primacy of this knowledge construction process has been challenged by the development of large soil databases and algorithms such as machine learning. The data-driven research approach to soil science, the inference of soil knowledge directly from data by using computational tools and modelling techniques, is becoming more popular. Despite the wide adoption of a data-driven research approach to soil science, there has been little discussion on how a research driven by data instead of hypotheses affects scientific progress. In this paper, we provide an introductory perspective on data-driven soil research by discussing some of the issues and opportunities of knowledge discovery from soil data. We show that while data-driven soil research may seem revolutionary for some, soil science has a long history of exploratory efforts to generate knowledge from data. Empirical and factual soil classifications, for example, were data driven. We further discuss, with examples, (i) data, databases and the logic of data storage for data-driven soil research, (ii) the issues of extreme empiricist claims that arise corollary to the increase in the use of computational tools, and (iii) the challenge of formulating a scientific explanation based on patterns observed in the data and data analysis tools. By considering the epistemic challenges of the data-driven scientific research in the light of the historical literature, we found that there is a continuity of practices, some being certainly amplified by recent technological changes, but that the core methods of scientific enquiry from data remain essentially unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;identifying-the-fingerprint-of-permanganate-oxidizable-carbon-as-a-measure-of-labile-soil-organic-carbon-using-fourier-transform-mid-infrared-photoacoustic-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Identifying the fingerprint of permanganate oxidizable carbon as a measure of labile soil organic carbon using Fourier transform mid-infrared photoacoustic spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Permanganate oxidizable carbon (POXC) is a sub-pool of labile soil organic carbon (SOC) and is defined as the carbon (C) that can be oxidized by potassium permanganate (KMnO4). Determination of the content of POXC has been used as a way to measure labile C and may be related to soil microbial biomass and particulate organic C. Fourier transform mid-infrared photoacoustic spectroscopy (FTIR-PAS) has been used for characterizing the chemical composition of soil organic matter. The objective of the current study was to identify the chemical information in the FTIR-PAS spectra that is unique to POXC and therefore associated with labile C. FTIR-PAS was used for characterizing SOC using a set of soil samples collected in four different countries (Laos, Malaysia, Peru and Thailand, n = 575). Partial least squares (PLS) regression was used to correlate the collected FTIR-PAS spectra with both POXC and total SOC. The FTIR-PAS spectra combined with the PLS method was useful for predicting both SOC and POXC. However, SOC and POXC were also highly correlated (R-2 = 0.84), and because POXC can be seen as a fraction of total SOC, a method for extracting the FTIR-PAS fingerprint of the POXC model that is independent of SOC was applied for the first time. The results showed that the POXC prediction was mainly based on its strong correlation with SOC and there was little information unique to POXC. However, the results do indicate four dominant peaks at 1,574, 1,495, 1,138 and 1,041 cm(-1) to be specific for POXC. These peaks can be ascribed to amide II, aromatics, polysaccharides and carbohydrates, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highlights&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Permanganate oxidizable carbon (POXC) was predicted using FTIR-photoacoustic spectroscopy (FTIR-PAS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The POXC prediction using FTIR-PAS is mainly based on its high correlation with SOC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A method extracting the unique spectral features of POXC independently of SOC was applied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 11% of the information used to predict POXC was identified as unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four dominant peaks were found to represent the POXC fingerprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-organic-carbon-in-irrigated-agricultural-systems-a-meta-analysis&quot;&gt;Soil organic carbon in irrigated agricultural systems: A meta-analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last 200 years, conversion of non-cultivated land for agriculture has substantially reduced global soil organic carbon (SOC) stocks in upper soil layers. Nevertheless, practices such as no- or reduced tillage, application of organic soil amendments, and maintenance of continuous cover can increase SOC in agricultural fields. While these management practices have been well studied, the effects on SOC of cropping systems that incorporate irrigation are poorly understood. Given the large, and expanding, agricultural landbase under irrigation across the globe, this is a critical knowledge gap for climate change mitigation. We undertook a systematic literature review and subsequent meta-analysis of data from studies that examined changes in SOC on irrigated agricultural sites through time. We investigated changes in SOC by climate (aridity), soil texture, and irrigation method with the following objectives: (i) to examine the impact of irrigated agriculture on SOC storage; and (ii) to identify the conditions under which irrigated agriculture is most likely to enhance SOC. Overall, irrigated agriculture increased SOC stocks by 5.9%, with little effect of study length (2-47 years). However, changes in SOC varied by climate and soil depth, with the greatest increase in SOC observed on irrigated semi-arid sites at the 0-10 cm depth (14.8%). Additionally, SOC increased in irrigated fine- and medium-textured soils but not coarse-textured soils. Furthermore, while there was no overall change to SOC in flood/furrow irrigated sites, SOC tended to increase in sprinkler irrigated sites, and decrease in drip irrigated sites, especially at depths below 10 cm. This work sheds light on the nuances of SOC change across irrigated agricultural systems, highlights the importance of studying SOC storage in deeper soils, and will help guide future research on the impacts of irrigated agriculture on SOC.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/08/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on August 04, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/08/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/08/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-08-03T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-08-03T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-23&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #23&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evaluation of soil organic matter from integrated production systems using laser-induced fluorescence spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spatial decoupling of legacy phosphorus in cropland: Soil erosion and deposition as a mechanism for storage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How does soil compaction alter nitrous oxide fluxes? A meta-analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new model for an improved AMSR2 satellite soil moisture retrieval over agricultural areas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the impact of increasing drought on the relationship between soil water content and evapotranspiration of a grassland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evaluation-of-soil-organic-matter-from-integrated-production-systems-using-laser-induced-fluorescence-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Evaluation of soil organic matter from integrated production systems using laser-induced fluorescence spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agricultural areas under integrated production systems, such as Integrated Crop-Livestock-Forest System (CLFS), have the potential to sequestrate carbon (C) since both Soil Organic Matter (SOM) content and trees biomass increase thus mitigating the emission of greenhouse gases (GHGs) from agriculture. Regarding soil aspects, the C content stands out as the main indicator, but the structural aspect of SOM is also relevant since it plays a key role in the chemical stability of C compounds and the soil lifetime of C compounds. Laser-Induced Fluorescence Spectroscopy (LIFS) is an effective technique to evaluate the SOM humification index (HLIFS) from practically intact whole soil samples under different agricultural systems. Thus, the objective of this study was to analyze the SOM humification index in different integrated systems, such as Integrated Crop-Livestock-Forest System (CLFS), Integrated Livestock-Forest System (LFS), Integrated Crop-Livestock System (CLS), and in references areas, such as Intensive Pasture (INT), Extensive Pasture (EXT) and Native Forest (NF). For this purpose, samples of Redyellow Latosol (Haplorthox by Soil taxonomy) from the experimental site located at Embrapa Pecu ‘ aria Sudeste (Southeast of Brazil) were collected five years after the establishment of the integrated systems. Samples were collected at soil depths of 0-5, 5-10, 10-20, 20-30, 30-40, 40-60, 60-80, and 80-100 cm. Pellets of the whole soil samples were prepared for LIFS analysis. In these areas, SOM humification indices (HLIFS) presented the following descending order: CLS &amp;gt; EXT &amp;gt; INT &amp;gt; LFS &amp;gt; CLFS &amp;gt; NF. Previous results have shown a greater soil organic carbon stock in these integrated production systems than in the NF area, suggesting C sequestration in agricultural soil. In the present study, SOM was classified by LIFS as more chemically stable in integrated production systems than in native vegetation. Higher amounts of fluorescent compounds were identified from LIFS data, probably resulting from condensed aromatic groups. SOM with more recalcitrant groups normally has a longer lifetime in the soil, indicating a long-term contribution to mitigating climate change by avoiding fast SOM decomposition and CO2 return to the atmosphere. Also, for the first time, this study was able to identify a positive correlation (R = 0.79) between the SOM humification index (HLIFS) and the Cation Exchange Capacity (CEC)/C content ratio of whole soil samples, another innovative contribution from soil LIFS analyses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spatial-decoupling-of-legacy-phosphorus-in-cropland-soil-erosion-and-deposition-as-a-mechanism-for-storage&quot;&gt;Spatial decoupling of legacy phosphorus in cropland: Soil erosion and deposition as a mechanism for storage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agricultural production continues to be implicated as one cause of eutrophication of water courses and water bodies in many agro-ecosystems. The generally-held consensus is that soil erosion by water is a major mechanism for loss of phosphorus (P) to adjacent water bodies and down-stream reservoirs from crop and grazing lands. Nonetheless, it does not explain the whole story of the fate of P losses applied to soils. This study assessed the spatial distribution of P as a consequence of historical erosion and redistribution of soil in an agricultural field in the Lake Erie basin in southern Ontario. Combining stratified random sampling with geospatial analysis of landscape position, plant-available (Olsen) P concentrations and stocks were measured and compared to other soil properties and related to soil erosion and redistribution. Toe-slope and foot-slope positions had two to three times the Olsen P stocks compared to summit landscape positions (mean of 52 +1- 9 kg P ha(-1) and 47 +1- 9 kg P ha(-1) versus 20 +/- 2 kg P ha(-1), respectively) which was attributed to both water and tillage erosion. Burial of P beneath the plowing depth showed that the toe-slopes had over two to three times more Olsen P stocks below 25 cm depth compared to all other landscape positions. Olsen P stocks were significantly related (R-2 = 0.50; p &amp;lt; 0.001) to soil organic carbon (SOC) stocks which was a consequence of historical soil erosion and redistribution in the field. The fate of legacy P in soils may be dependent upon the history of erosion and redistribution resulting in deposition of P in toe-slope and foot-slope positions in an agricultural landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-does-soil-compaction-alter-nitrous-oxide-fluxes-a-meta-analysis&quot;&gt;How does soil compaction alter nitrous oxide fluxes? A meta-analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nitrous oxide (N2O) is a potent greenhouse gas and precursor of ozone layer depletion. Managed terrestrial ecosystems are major anthropogenic sources of N2O, primarily generated in the soil. The physical makeup of the soil interplays with the underlying biochemistry that produces N2O. Therefore, it has been conceptualized that either compacting or loosening the soil will alter N2O emissions; however, a unified framework of these relationships is yet to be established. Here, we compiled, reviewed and analyzed available field studies that have evaluated how applied compaction or alleviation of compacted soils impacts N2O emissions. Of the 108 available pairwise comparisons, 82 % of the cases showed detrimental increases in N2O emissions caused by increased compaction. Overall, N2O emissions nearly doubled because of soil compaction effects (P &amp;lt; 0.05). This doubling of N2O emissions was linked to a relative reduction of 9 % in soil porosity (i.e., 0.05 cm3 cm-3) caused by applied compaction. This linkage to soil porosity was clearly evident in both croplands and pastures. Across the managed terrestrial ecosystems evaluated, the strongest relative effects of compaction on N2O emissions were found in forest and pasture soils. Overall, N2O emissions in forest soils showed a fivefold increase caused by compaction (P &amp;lt; 0.05; n = 11). This massive response in forest soils can be attributed to: i) their low N2O emission baseline; ii) their acidic pH, which intrinsically favors N2O emissions; iii) having some of the heaviest traffic loads found across our meta-analysis (e.g., 16 Mg); and iv) an increase in soil microporosity. Pasture soils also displayed substantial compaction effects on N2O emissions, with a threefold increase (P &amp;lt; 0.05; n = 25). This was explained in part by the elevated nitrogen input rates in pastures (e.g., 600-1000 kg N ha-1). Conversely, alleviation of soil compaction by implementing controlled traffic farming (CTF) in vegetable and grain croplands reduced N2O emissions consistently in all available pairwise comparisons (P &amp;lt; 0.05; n = 19). At the field scale, CTF greatly decreased N2O emissions by one-third compared with farmlands managed with conventional random traffic (4.48 versus 2.86 kg N2O-N ha-1). However, after reviewing the available literature, we witnessed a paucity of information about how long it takes for soils to self-alleviate from the detrimental effects of compaction on N2O emissions. Additionally, insights gained through meta-analysis revealed the interplay of soil compaction with underlying heavy textures, acidic pH, and reduced porosities, which collectively exacerbate N2O emissions. Nevertheless, these complex interactions operate differentially across contrasting land use options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-new-model-for-an-improved-amsr2-satellite-soil-moisture-retrieval-over-agricultural-areas&quot;&gt;A new model for an improved AMSR2 satellite soil moisture retrieval over agricultural areas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This study evaluates the potential of AMSR2 (Advance Microwave Scanning Radiometer2) data for the estimation of Volumetric Soil Moisture (VSM) for bare and agricultural areas. At the first step, the sensitivity of the Microwave Polarization Difference Index (MPDI) to variations in soil and vegetation characteristics were examined at different frequencies. At lower frequencies, the signal attenuation due to vegetation is minimal and thus, denser vegetation usually depolarizes the soil emission. Interestingly, the results also reveal that at higher frequencies, the sensitivity of V and H polarizations over relatively dense vegetation covers is not the same at all. Therefore, MPDI at both low and high frequencies can be a good indicator of the soil moisture and Vegetation Water Content (VWC), respectively. After evaluation of AMSR2 datasets, a model called Multi-channel/MPDIbased Land Parameters Retrieval Model (MMLPRM) is proposed. The MMLPRM optimizes optical depth of vegetation and soil dielectric constant, with simultaneous retrieval of soil moisture and surface temperature by using the AMSR2 brightness temperature data. This algorithm also includes the surface roughness parameters to increase the soil moisture retrieval efficiency. In this way, calibration and validation have been done, using in situ observations of 50 monitoring stations obtained from the International Soil Moisture Network (ISMN) over the United States. Consequently, the analysis on the MMLPRM retrieval model demonstrates its potential and usefulness for soil moisture retrieval. The outcome of this study will help in estimating the accurate soil moisture to optimize the irrigation management strategies and help in water conservation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;on-the-impact-of-increasing-drought-on-the-relationship-between-soil-water-content-and-evapotranspiration-of-a-grassland&quot;&gt;On the impact of increasing drought on the relationship between soil water content and evapotranspiration of a grassland&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weighable lysimeters were used to study the relation between soil water content (SWC) and the actual evapotranspiration (ETa) of grassland under two different climate regimes of Rollesbroich and Selhausen but for an identical soil from Rollesbroich. All components of the water balance were determined from 2012 until 2018. Budyko analysis was used to characterize the hydrological status of the studied sites. Wavelet analysis was also applied to study the power spectrum of ETa, vegetation-height-adjusted reference evapotranspiration (ETcrop), and water stress index (WSI) defined as ETa/ETcrop, as well as SWC at three different depths and the coherence between SWC and ETa and WSI. The Budyko analysis showed that 2018 resulted in a shift of both locations towards more water-limited conditions, although Rollesbroich remained an energy-limited system. Based on the power spectrum analysis, the annual timescale is the dominant scale for the temporal variability of ETa, ETcrop, and SWC. The results also showed that increasing dryness at the energy-limited site led to more temporal variability of SWC at all depths at the annual timescale. Wavelet coherence analysis showed a reduction of the phase shift between SWC and ETa at an annual scale caused by the increase in dryness during the measurement period. We found that phase shifts between SWC and ETa and SWC and WSI were stronger at the water-limited site than at the energy-limited site. The wavelet coherence analysis also showed that from 2014 to 2018, the control of ETa and WSI on SWC increased due to higher dryness of soil.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/08/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on August 03, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/08/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/08/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-08-02T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-08-02T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-22&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #22&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shift to plant-based diets: are we missing the point?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can agroecology improve food security and nutrition? A review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assessing map accuracy from a suite of site-specific, non-site specific, and spatial distribution approaches.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hybrid LIBS-Raman-LIF systems for multi-modal spectroscopic applications: a topical review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-shift-to-plant-based-diets-are-we-missing-the-point&quot;&gt;The shift to plant-based diets: are we missing the point?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is increasing consensus that limiting consumption of meat and dairy products can contribute to lowering the environmental impact of diets. At the same time, the market for ultra-processed plant-based substitutes for meat and dairy (ie. ‘milk’, ‘cheese’ and ‘yoghurt’) is expanding to meet changing consumer demands. This shift far outpaces the revision of dietary guidelines and other nutritional guidance. Here, we identify significant knowledge gaps in the nutritional composition of meat and dairy substitutes as well as the extent to which they comprise modern diets in many countries in the WHO European Region. We also highlight that most dietary models are not based on real-life dietary patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;can-agroecology-improve-food-security-and-nutrition-a-review&quot;&gt;Can agroecology improve food security and nutrition? A review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agroecology increasingly has gained scientific and policy recognition as having potential to address environmental and social issues within food production, but concerns have been raised about its implications for food security and nutrition, particularly in low-income countries. This review paper examines recent evidence (1998-2019) for whether agroecological practices can improve human food security and nutrition. A total of 11,771 articles were screened by abstract and title, 275 articles included for full review, with 56 articles (55 cases) selected. A majority of studies (78%) found evidence of positive outcomes in the use of agroecological practices on food security and nutrition of households in low and middle-income countries. Agroecological practices included crop diversification, intercropping, agroforestry, integrating crop and livestock, and soil management measures. More complex agroecological systems, that included multiple components (e.g., crop diversification, mixed crop-livestock systems and farmer-to-farmer networks) were more likely to have positive food security and nutrition outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;assessing-map-accuracy-from-a-suite-of-site-specific-non-site-specific-and-spatial-distribution-approaches&quot;&gt;Assessing map accuracy from a suite of site-specific, non-site specific, and spatial distribution approaches.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assessing a map’s accuracy and efficacy requires careful consideration and calculation of a comprehensive set of measures, particularly when characteristics in geospatial datasets may be used for addressing multiple objectives. We describe a map accuracy assessment framework for categorical geospatial data over large areas that utilizes site-specific (plot-pixel), non-site specific (area estimates), and comparative accuracy (spatial and statistical distributions) methods. This comprehensive framework spans the range of approaches applied in most other studies, maximizing opportunities for both within- and between-study comparisons. The analysis framework incorporated recommended good practices for sampling design, response design, analysis protocols, and designbased inference for providing rigorous estimates of accuracy and precision. Further partitioning of disagreement allows users to assess the relative importance of spatial location versus total abundance of map classes to map error; we introduced a ratio of allocation disagreement to quantity disagreement for comparing relative importance of each across datasets. Assessment of fuzzy membership with linguistic scales may have minimal effect on overall accuracy, but can provide substantial improvement in user’s accuracy and producer’s accuracy for uncommon classes. We adapted non-site specific approaches to provide metrics and insights into spatial variability of map accuracy of thematic classes. Comparing estimates based on reference data and co-located samples of map data may reveal potential issues with reference data. We demonstrated example applications all components of the assessment framework for thematic maps of early successional forest and other land cover classes across the western Great Lakes region, USA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hybrid-libs-raman-lif-systems-for-multi-modal-spectroscopic-applications-a-topical-review&quot;&gt;Hybrid LIBS-Raman-LIF systems for multi-modal spectroscopic applications: a topical review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This review discusses the importance of hyphenating different laser-based techniques such as Laser-Induced Breakdown Spectroscopy (LIBS), Raman spectroscopy and Laser-Induced Fluorescence spectroscopy (LIF) and the applications of the hybrid systems. These spectroscopic techniques, in single and multi-modes, are widely accepted as an efficient tool to retrieve information from atomic and molecular systems such as knowledge on chemical bonds, molecular structure and geometry, interactions and related mechanisms etc. Analytical capabilities of such systems which combine LIBS, Raman, and LIF are highly desirable since one can acquire complementary information from the same sample enabling a remarkable potential for various applications in diverse fields like archeology, mineralogy, planetary explorations, clinical chemistry, biomedical and environmental monitoring etc to extract more information. In this review, attention has been devoted to the works of combined LIBS-LIF-Raman technique in different fields and its significance, along with brief discussions on other combinations like LIBS-Raman, LIBS-LIF, and Raman-LIF.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/08/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on August 02, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/07/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/07/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-07-07T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-07-07T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-21&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #21&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil organic carbon estimation using VNIR-SWIR spectroscopy: The effect of multiple sensors and scanning conditions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using ground-penetrating radar to investigate the thickness of mollic epipedons developed from loessial parent material&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evaluating validation strategies on the performance of soil property prediction from regional to continental spectral data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Digital soil maps can perform as well as large-scale conventional soil maps for the prediction of catchment baseflows&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimation of root zone soil moisture from ground and remotely sensed soil information with multisensor data fusion and automated machine learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-organic-carbon-estimation-using-vnir-swir-spectroscopy-the-effect-of-multiple-sensors-and-scanning-conditions&quot;&gt;Soil organic carbon estimation using VNIR-SWIR spectroscopy: The effect of multiple sensors and scanning conditions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visible-near infrared-shortwave infrared (VNIR-SWIR) spectroscopy is being increasingly used for soil organic carbon (SOC) assessment. Common practice consists of scanning soil samples using a single spectrometer. Considerations have rarely been documented of the effects of using multiple instruments and scanning conditions on SOC model calibration that occur when merging soil spectral libraries (SSLs), particularly in soils with low SOC concentration and using both field spectroradiometers and laboratory fixed spectrometers. To address this gap, we scanned 143 low-SOC-content soil samples using three spectrometers (ASD FieldSpec 3, ASD FieldSpec 4, and FOSS XDS) and four setup features - FOSS, contact probe (CP), dark-box (DB), and open laboratory (LAB) - at three laboratories. The application of an internal soil standard (ISS) to align one laboratory spectrum with another for spectral correction and spectral merging of various SSLs was examined. SOC models were developed using i) data from each single spectrometer - single laboratory separately and ii) merged data from multiple spectrometers - different laboratories, applying the 1st derivatives of spectra and random forest (RF) regression. The results indicate that the spectral shape and wavelength position of key features obtained from all spectrometers and setups did not show any noticeable differences, though spectra based on FOSS setup, particularly on low-SOC samples, demonstrated greater range in absolute derivative values regardless of ISS application. The derivative ISS-corrected spectra showed less variation among different spectrometers compared to their uncorrected raw reflectance spectra. All single spectrometer models predicted SOC reasonably well. However, the spectra acquired by the FOSS setup predicted SOC more accurately (R2 = 0.77, RPIQ = 3.30, RMSE = 0.22 %, and SD = 0.04) than the spectra acquired by the other setups. The models derived from merged uncorrected raw reflectance spectra yielded poor results (R2 = 0.48, RPIQ = 2.33, RMSE = 0.33 %, and SD = 0.10); nevertheless, assessment of SOC using the 1st derivative ISS-corrected merged SSLs considerably improved the prediction accuracy (R2 = 0.70, RPIQ = 3.10, RMSE = 0.25 %, and SD = 0.06). Hence, the derivative spectra coupled with the ISS correction improved the accuracy of SOC prediction models obtained from the merged soil spectra collected in different environments using different instruments. We therefore recommend application of the ISS spectral alignment method linked to the 1st derivative approach to enhance the compilation of SSLs at the regional and global scales for SOC assessment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-ground-penetrating-radar-to-investigate-the-thickness-of-mollic-epipedons-developed-from-loessial-parent-material&quot;&gt;Using ground-penetrating radar to investigate the thickness of mollic epipedons developed from loessial parent material&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The information of mollic epipedon (ME) thickness was essential for evaluation and protection of Mollisol resource. However, the traditional methods including the soil profile method, soil probes, and the drilling method, are low efficient and accurate for large area survey of soil thickness. In this study, the ground penetrating radar (GPR) was employed to detect the thickness of ME with underlying loessial parent material (LPM) along three slopes in straight, convex, and concave shapes in northeast China. The accuracy of GPR for measuring the ME thickness was verified by using excavation profile and pre-buried iron pipes. The effects of soil moisture and bulk density on soil permittivity were also investigated based on indoor experiments. The results indicated that the soil permittivity increased and decreased with the increase of bulk density and soil moisture, respectively. The relationships among soil moisture, bulk density and permittivity of both Mollisol and LPM could be described by two fitted equations, and the errors of the prediction equations was in the range of 0.32 %-5.10 %. The errors of GPR to measure the ME thickness was in the range of 3.72 %-10.64 %. The spatial distribution of the ME thickness along the three slopes varied, and the concave slope had a thicker ME than the convex and straight slope. Meanwhile, similar trends were shown that the sedimentation at the slope foot led to the thickest ME, while soil erosion at the slope shoulder and back resulted in the thinnest ME. This study could provide an efficient and accurate method to investigate soil thickness for further evaluation and protection of soil resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evaluating-validation-strategies-on-the-performance-of-soil-property-prediction-from-regional-to-continental-spectral-data&quot;&gt;Evaluating validation strategies on the performance of soil property prediction from regional to continental spectral data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visible-near infrared (vis-NIR) spectroscopy has been widely used to characterize soil information from field to global scales. Before applying a calibrated spectral predictive model to acquire soil information, either independent validation or k-fold cross validation is used to evaluate model performance. However, there is no consensus on which validation strategy is more suitable and robust when evaluating model performance for the studies in different scales. The objective of this study is to evaluate and compare the model performance of two validation strategies coupling different calibration sizes (a ratio of calibration to validation of 2:1, 4:1 and 9:1) and calibration sampling strategies (random sampling (RS), rank, Kennard-Stone (KS), rank-Kennard-Stone (RKS) and conditioned Latin hypercube sampling (cLHS)) across scales. A total of 17,272 vis-NIR spectra of mineral soils from LUCAS data (continental scale) and their soil organic carbon (SOC) and clay contents were used in this study, and the dataset was further split into national (2761 samples in France) and five regional datasets (110 to 248 samples from five French administrative regions). To eliminate the effect of changing validation set on the model performance, a consistent test set (20% of total samples at each scale) was split to evaluate all the combinations involved in two validation strategies. The Lin’s concordance correlation coefficient (CCC) of the cubist model were stable for both SOC and clay for different calibration sizes, calibration sampling and validation strategies for a large calibration size (&amp;gt;1400) at the national and continental scales. A larger calibration size can potentially improve model performance for a small dataset (&amp;lt;300) at the regional scale, and a wider calibration range would result in better model performance. No silver bullet was found among the different calibration sampling strategies at the regional scale. For five French regions (small data set), we found a high variation (95th percentile minus the 5th percentile) in the CCC among the models built from 50 repeated RS (0.10-0.44 for SOC, 0.16-0.52 for clay) and cLHS (0.08-0.40 for SOC, 0.12-0.36 for clay). This finding indicates that a one-time RS or cLHS for selecting the calibration set has high uncertainty in model evaluation for a small dataset and therefore should be used with caution. Therefore, we suggest the following: (1) for a large data set (thousands), either one-time random sampling for independent validation or k-fold cross validation would be appropriate; (2) for a small data set (dozens to hundreds), k-fold cross validation and/or repeated random sampling for independent validation would be more robust for spectral predictive model evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;digital-soil-maps-can-perform-as-well-as-large-scale-conventional-soil-maps-for-the-prediction-of-catchment-baseflows&quot;&gt;Digital soil maps can perform as well as large-scale conventional soil maps for the prediction of catchment baseflows&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rapid advance of digital soil mapping (DSM) has resulted in the generation of fine resolution soils spatial datasets with associated uncertainty that can be as accurate but more cost-effective and faster to produce than conventional soil maps. There is documented and increasing interest by policy makers and end-users in moving from conventional soil mapping to DSM; however, the wider operational use of DSM depends on demonstrating the effectiveness of DSM in fulfilling user needs and requirements along with providing DSM products that can be easily used by non-specialists. In this study we used the Hydrology of Soil Types (HOST) classification scheme, which was devised to predict flows in ungauged catchments and is used by both the research and policy maker communities in the UK, as the exemplar for comparing the efficiency of HOST class maps produced using both DSM and conventional soil map approaches for predicting catchment hydrological response. The performance for hydrological predictions of a detailed (1:25,000 scale) polygon HOST class map and a HOST-DSM class map produced via spatial disaggregation was assessed by comparing Base Flow Index (BFI) calculated using HOST class proportions from both maps with BFI calculated using flow data from gauges in 39 selected catchments. Results showed that the disaggregated HOST-DSM class map gave similar or even better BFI predictions than the conventional polygon-based HOST class map, while also providing a better insight on spatial soil variability within map units and its effect on hydrological predictions. This study demonstrates the potential of DSM to produce soil hydrological maps that provide comparable or better baseflow predictions than maps produced using detailed and intensive soil surveying. The study results also suggest that translating DSM of classes to more easily interpretable mapping datasets and incorporating prediction uncertainty in the final DSM product, as in the case of BFI maps based on HOST-DSM classes, could help with facilitating the transition towards a wider operational use of DSM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;estimation-of-root-zone-soil-moisture-from-ground-and-remotely-sensed-soil-information-with-multisensor-data-fusion-and-automated-machine-learning&quot;&gt;Estimation of root zone soil moisture from ground and remotely sensed soil information with multisensor data fusion and automated machine learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Root zone soil moisture (RZSM) estimation and monitoring based on high spatial resolution remote sensing information such as obtained with an Unmanned Aerial System (UAS) is of significant interest for field-scale precision irrigation management, particularly in water-limited regions of the world. To date, there is no accurate and widely accepted model that relies on UAS optical surface reflectance observations for RZSM estimation at high spatial resolution. This study is aimed at the development of a new approach for RZSM estimation based on the fusion of high spatial resolution optical reflectance UAS observations with physical and hydraulic soil information integrated into Automated Machine Learning (AutoML). The H2O AutoML platform includes a number of advanced machine learning algorithms that efficiently perform feature selection and automatically identify complex relationships between inputs and outputs. Twelve models combining UAS optical observations with various soil properties were developed in a hierarchical manner and fed into AutoML to estimate surface, near-surface, and root zone soil moisture. The addition of independently measured surface and near-surface soil moisture information to the hierarchical models to improve RZSM estimation was investigated. The accuracy of soil moisture estimates was evaluated based on a comparison with Time Domain Reflectometry (TDR) sensors that were deployed to monitor surface, near-surface and root zone soil moisture dynamics. The obtained results indicate that the consideration of physical and hydraulic soil properties together with UAS optical observations improves soil moisture estimation, especially for the root zone with a RMSE of about 0.04 cm3 cm-3. Accurate RZSM estimates were obtained when measured surface and near-surface soil moisture data was added to the hierarchical models, yielding RMSE values below 0.02 cm3 cm-3 and R and NSE values above 0.90. The generated high spatial resolution RZSM maps clearly capture the spatial variability of soil moisture at the field scale. The presented framework can aid farm scale precision irrigation management via improving the crop water use efficiency and reducing the risk of groundwater contamination.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/07/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on July 07, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/07/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/07/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-07-01T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-07-01T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-22&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #22&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Responses of soil carbon and nitrogen cycles to the physical influences of rock fragment in soils&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A review on the possible factors influencing soil inorganic carbon under elevated CO2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Development of functions to predict soil hydraulic properties that account for solution sodicity and salinity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identification of minerals in subtropical soils with different textural classes by VIS-NIR-SWIR reflectance spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A rapid qualitative methodology for ecological integrity assessment across a Mediterranean island’s landscapes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A framework for ecosystem service assessment using GIS interoperability standards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;responses-of-soil-carbon-and-nitrogen-cycles-to-the-physical-influences-of-rock-fragment-in-soils&quot;&gt;Responses of soil carbon and nitrogen cycles to the physical influences of rock fragment in soils&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rock fragments (RFs, mineral particles with diameter &amp;gt; 2 mm) can substantially influence soil carbon (C) and nitrogen (N) cycles through different physical mechanisms. These physical mechanisms include changing soil hydraulic parameters (vSH) by reducing fine earth bulk density (vSHBD) and volume (vSHVo), and affecting soil C and N stocks (vCN) by reducing fine earth bulk density (vCNBD) and volume (vCNVo), and increasing fine earth C and N concentrations (vCNCo). In this study, based on soil and climate data in a typical hilly area of China, we construct scenarios by considering these physical mechanisms to investigate the responses of key soil C and N outputs (carbon dioxide or CO2, and nitrous oxide or N2O emissions, and N leaching) to RF content (RFC) in DNDC and DayCent models. Results showed that when considering vSH and vCN, parabolic relationships were observed between these soil C and N outputs and RFC, with maximum in RFC = 0.3-0.6 g g(-1). The vCN dominated the responses of soil CO2 emission to RFC, while vSH exerted comparative contributions to the responses of soil N2O emission and N leaching. When only considering vSH, opposite contributions of vSHBD and vSHVo were observed in DNDC model, and contributions of vSHBD overwhelmed those of vSHVo. However, vSHVo dominated these responses in DayCent model. When only considering vCN, the vCNCo dominated these responses, though considerable superimposed influences of vCNBD and vCNVo appeared under high RFC. The discrepancies between these responses to RFC in DNDC and DayCent models might be due to the different model complexities in simulating soil hydrology, biogeochemistry, and the role of bulk density in these models. Relatively, more distinct responses were achieved in DNDC model. These findings can extend our understandings of RFs and soil C and N cycles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-review-on-the-possible-factors-influencing-soil-inorganic-carbon-under-elevated-co2&quot;&gt;A review on the possible factors influencing soil inorganic carbon under elevated CO2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil inorganic carbon (SIC) is the largest pool (approximate to 950 Pg of soil carbonate + 1404 Pg of bicarbonate in groundwater; i.e., 1 Pg = 10(15) g = 1 gigaton) of the global carbon cycle at a 100 cm depth, and it might be a significant carbon source and sink in arid and semi-arid regions. The knowledge of the impacts of changing climatic conditions on this important soil structural component is minimal. This review paper provides an inclusive compilation of the available information on potential natural and anthropogenic factors triggering soil acidification and weathering mechanisms under elevated CO2. Furthermore, the consequences of elevated atmospheric CO2 on the SIC pool, soil quality, and compromised ecosystem services have been explored. Soil water content and precipitation are critical factors that influence the effects of elevated CO2 in the SIC pool. Soil microbiological properties, respiration, depth, weathering, precipitation, acidity, and fertilization are emphasized here owing to the high degree of interrelationship between these factors on influencing overall soil quality. These phenomena are then outlined together with comments about possible short and long-term consequences in SIC stock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;development-of-functions-to-predict-soil-hydraulic-properties-that-account-for-solution-sodicity-and-salinity&quot;&gt;Development of functions to predict soil hydraulic properties that account for solution sodicity and salinity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturated soil hydraulic conductivity (K-sat) and the soil water characteristic curve have been predicted from soil texture, bulk density, and other soil physical properties. These previous functions do not account for soil clay mineralogy or soil solution composition. The objectives of this study were to: (1) analyze the performance of previously developed pedotransfer functions (PTFs) on saline and sodic soils, (2) predict hydraulic properties of saline and sodic soils with a range of clay mineralogy, and (3) develop PTFs that account for clay mineralogy and solution composition. Most PTFs do not perform well on soils with smectitic clay mineralogy and usually overestimate K-sat and under-estimate soil water characteristic on smectite clay dominant soils. Accounting for soil cation exchange capacity (CEC) as an indicator of soil clay types and solution composition improved the prediction of K-sat which had a geometric root mean squared error of 3.28 cm day(-1) compared to 6.04 cm day(-1) for the best performing PTF from the literature. A PTF we developed to predict soil water characteristic curve was able to predict soil water characteristic curve with a root mean squared error of 0.032 g g(-1) compared to 0.082 g g(-1) for the best performing previously published PTF. The PTFs developed in this study improved prediction of soil hydraulic properties on salt affected soils by using soil CEC to account for soil clay behavior and responsiveness to the soil solution composition. The PTFs reported here can easily be used to predict the K-sat and the soil water characteristic curve of soils in response to changes in irrigation water quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;identification-of-minerals-in-subtropical-soils-with-different-textural-classes-by-vis-nir-swir-reflectance-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Identification of minerals in subtropical soils with different textural classes by VIS-NIR-SWIR reflectance spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The physical and chemical attributes of soils are strongly influenced by the nature of the minerals they contain and their concentration. Thus, soil texture is directly dependent on the content in clayey minerals, which influences a number of characteristics such as water dynamics. Although the mineralogical composition of soil is usually determined by X-ray diffraction spectroscopy, this technique is expensive and time-consuming, and uses toxic materials, all of which makes it impractical for obtaining large data sets. Also, available methods for acquiring, interpreting and examining visible-near infrared-shortwave infrared (VIS-NIR-SWIR) spectra are largely ineffective with tropical soils. The aim of this work was to ascertain whether VIS-NIR-SWIR reflectance spectroscopy (350-2500 nm) is useful for identifying minerals in subtropical soils as classified by textural class. For this purpose, soil samples were collected at 66 points at three different soil depths (0-20, 20-40 and 40-60 cm) over a study area located in the State of Rio Grande do Sul (Brazil). The soil texture were determined with the pipette method, and soil spectra were recorded on a FieldSpec Pro VIS-NIR-SWIR laboratory spectrophotometer. Soil minerals were identified, and their proportions determined, from the second-derivative of the Kubelka-Munk (KM) function for the spectra. Five main minerals were thus identified from their spectral signatures, namely: hematite, goethite, kaolinite, chlorite and illite. Identification of the minerals was facilitated by classifying the samples according to texture. The higher the clay content was, the higher was the spectral amplitude of the minerals identified. Those textural classes with the highest clay contents exhibited the greatest proportions of iron oxides and of clay minerals such as kaolinite. These relationships allowed more comprehensive analysis of the soils and expeditious characterization of the study area in terms of texture and mineralogy with a view to facilitating decision-making agricultural support policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-rapid-qualitative-methodology-for-ecological-integrity-assessment-across-a-mediterranean-islands-landscapes&quot;&gt;A rapid qualitative methodology for ecological integrity assessment across a Mediterranean island’s landscapes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rapid qualitative field methods can be used to evaluate ecological integrity (EI) at a landscape level. This study evaluates the EI of 63 landscape types (LCTs) in Cyprus derived from Landscape Character Mapping. Following a stratified sampling, LCTs were evaluated using 209 Land Description Units (LDUs) i.e., homogeneous map entities, sharing a similar pattern of natural and cultural elements. In every LDU, six ecological integrity (EI) indicators were visually assessed consistently namely naturalness, habitat continuity, number of habitats, dominant habitat type, management intensity and scale. TwoStep Cluster Analysis was employed to identify EI categories, and Categorical Principal Components Analysis (CATPCA) to associate the individual indicators with overall EI in the LDUs. Linear regressions were used to predict EI based on the most important indicators. Forested and shrubland landscapes have consistently good EI with low variation, while urbanized and agricultural landscapes have lower EI. There is great variation in the number of agricultural landscape types and their EI. There are significant linear relationships between EI and naturalness, habitat continuity and intensity. The novelty of this work lies with the fact that it provides the first island-wide study in the Mediterranean assessing EI spatially through a small number of indicators. Results indicate that LCA can be an appropriate consistent and inexpensive spatial framework for assessing EI, which can be directly associated with management intervention to maintain or improve EI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-framework-for-ecosystem-service-assessment-using-gis-interoperability-standards&quot;&gt;A framework for ecosystem service assessment using GIS interoperability standards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ecosystem Services Web Services (ESWS) are new web-based approaches to quantifying the benefits that humans derive from nature. Specifically, ESWS are the application of open web standards to ecosystem service assessment to facilitate creation, iteration, and dissemination in a seamless way. This integration streamlines collaboration, automation, and curation, while providing an open interface through which novel advances can be incorporated. The approach creates a new level of interoperability through data provenance whereby each transition between processing steps employs standards that ensure cohesive workflows across models and platforms. This imparts a modularity that can be examined and extended at every step.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/07/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on July 01, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/06/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/06/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-06-24T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-06-24T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-20&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #20&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One size does not fit all: Toward regional conservation practice guidance to reduce phosphorus loss risk in the Lake Erie watershed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Regional ensemble modeling reduces uncertainty for digital soil mapping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Concept, Practice, Application and Results of Locally Based Monitoring of the Environment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connecting Top-Down and Bottom-Up Approaches in Environmental Observing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Use of Digital Platforms for Community-Based Monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amalgamation and harmonization of soil survey reports into a multi-purpose database&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multisensor fusion of remotely sensed vegetation indices using space-time dynamic linear models&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do soil health tests match farmer experience? Assessing biological, physical, and chemical indicators in the Upper Midwest United States&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evaluating three calibration transfer methods for predictions of soil properties using mid-infrared spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continuous in situ soil nitrate sensors: The importance of high-resolution measurements across time and a comparison with salt extraction-based methods&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bayesian-based time-varying multivariate drought risk and its dynamics in a changing environment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transferring Hydrologic Data Across Continents - Leveraging Data-Rich Regions to Improve Hydrologic Prediction in Data-Sparse Regions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;one-size-does-not-fit-all-toward-regional-conservation-practice-guidance-to-reduce-phosphorus-loss-risk-in-the-lake-erie-watershed&quot;&gt;One size does not fit all: Toward regional conservation practice guidance to reduce phosphorus loss risk in the Lake Erie watershed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agricultural phosphorus (P) losses to surface water bodies remain a global eutrophication concern, despite the application of conservation practices on farm fields. Although it is generally agreed upon that the use of multiple conservation practices (“stacking”) will lead to greater improvements to water quality, this may not be cost effective to farmers, reducing the likelihood of adoption. At present, wholesale recommendations of conservation practices are given; however, the application of specific conservation practices in certain environments (e.g., no-till with surface application, cover crops) may not be effective and can even lead to unintended consequences. In this paper, we present the Lake Erie watershed as a case study. The Lake Erie watershed contains regions with unique physical geographies that include differences in climate, soil, topography, and land use, which have implications for both P transport from agricultural fields and the efficacy of conservation practices in mitigating P losses. We define major regions within the Lake Erie watershed where common strategies for conservation practice implementation are appropriate, and we propose a five-step plan for bringing regionally tailored, adaptive, and cost-conscious conservation practice into watershed planning. Although this paper is specific to the Lake Erie watershed, our framework can be transferred across broader geographic regions to provide guidance for watershed planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;regional-ensemble-modeling-reduces-uncertainty-for-digital-soil-mapping&quot;&gt;Regional ensemble modeling reduces uncertainty for digital soil mapping&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent country and continental-scale digital soil mapping efforts have used a single model to predict soil properties across large regions. However, different ecophysiographic regions within large-extent areas are likely to have different soil-landscape relationships so models built specifically for these regions may more accurately capture these relationships relative to a ‘global’ model. We ask the question: Is a single ‘global’ model sufficient or are regionally-specific models useful for accurate digital soil mapping? We test this question by modeling soil depth classes across the 432,000 km(2) upper Colorado River Basin in the Western USA using a single global model, multiple ecophysiographic models, and ensembles of the ecophysiographic models.
Effective soil depth class observations (n = 12,194) were derived from multiple soil databases. Fifty-seven environmental covariates were derived from a 30 m digital elevation model, climate data, satellite imagery, and aeroradiometric data. Three independent land classifications were used to stratify the area. Two expert-derived land classifications, USDA Major Land Resource Areas (MLRA) and US-EPA Level III ecoregions, divided the study area into multiple ecophysiographic regions based on vegetation and broad-scale physiographic differences. The third land classification divided the study area into broad landforms.
Soil depth observations were split into separate training (n = 10,470) and validation (n = 1,724) datasets. First, a ‘global’ random forest model was used to model soil depth classes using all training observations and covariates. ‘Global’ denotes a model built with all training data across the extent of the area, not a model at world extent. Second, the land classifications were used to subset the observations into ecophysiographic sub-datasets and random forest models were refit for each region. Models fit by ecophysiographic region are referred to as regional models. Thirdly, predictions from each regional model were fused into regional-ensemble models. Accuracy, Brier scores, and Shannon’s entropy were used to compare model accuracy and uncertainty. Regional ecophysiographic models were also compared to models built for geographic areas that were defined solely to be approximately equal in area. Training dataset density and the imbalance ratio were investigated to determine if data characteristics influenced regional accuracy/uncertainty metrics.
Accuracy for the global model using the validation set was 62.8%. Regional model accuracies ranged between 56.1% and 75.0%. We found: 1) useful inter-regional differences in global model accuracy were revealed when the global model was validated by region, 2) no consistent relationship between training observation density and accuracy/uncertainty metrics, 3) no meaningful differences in accuracy and uncertainty metrics between physiographic and geographic regions, 4) ensembles of regionally-specific models were approximately as accurate as global models, and 5) both region-specific models and ensembles of regional models were less uncertain than the global model. Overall, we recommend the use of soil depth class predictions made from MLRA regional ensemble models because this prediction had higher accuracy than the ecoregion ensemble model prediction, but lower uncertainty than both the global model and the landform ensemble model predictions. We answer our question: Ensembles of regionally-specific models are approximately as accurate as global models, but result in less uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-concept-practice-application-and-results-of-locally-based-monitoring-of-the-environment&quot;&gt;The Concept, Practice, Application and Results of Locally Based Monitoring of the Environment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Locally based monitoring is typically undertaken in areas in which communities have a close attachment to their natural resource base. We present a summary of work to develop a theoretical and practical understanding of locally based monitoring and we outline tests of this approach in research and practice over the past 20 years. Our tests show that locally based monitoring delivers credible data at local scale independent of external experts and can be used to inform local and national decision making within a short time frame. We believe that monitoring conducted by and anchored in communities will gain in importance where scientist-led monitoring is sparse or too expensive to sustain and for ecosystem attributes in cases in which remote sensing cannot provide credible data. The spread of smartphone technology and online portals will further enhance the importance and usefulness of this discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;connecting-top-down-and-bottom-up-approaches-in-environmental-observing&quot;&gt;Connecting Top-Down and Bottom-Up Approaches in Environmental Observing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Effective responses to rapid environmental change rely on observations to inform planning and decision-making. Reviewing literature from 124 programs across the globe and analyzing survey data for 30 Arctic community-based monitoring programs, we compare top-down, large-scale program driven approaches with bottom-up approaches initiated and steered at the community level. Connecting these two approaches and linking to Indigenous and local knowledge yields benefits including improved information products and enhanced observing program efficiency and sustainability. We identify core principles central to such improved links: matching observing program aims, scales, and ability to act on information; matching observing program and community priorities; fostering compatibility in observing methodology and data management; respect of Indigenous intellectual property rights and the implementation of free, prior, and informed consent; creating sufficient organizational support structures; and ensuring sustained community members’ commitment. Interventions to overcome challenges in adhering to these principles are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-use-of-digital-platforms-for-community-based-monitoring&quot;&gt;The Use of Digital Platforms for Community-Based Monitoring&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Environmental observing programs that are based on Indigenous and local knowledge increasingly use digital technologies. Digital platforms may improve data management in community-based monitoring (CBM) programs, but little is known about how their use translates into tangible results. Drawing on published literature and a survey of 18 platforms, we examine why and how digital platforms are used in CBM programs and illuminate potential challenges and opportunities. Digital platforms make it easy to collect, archive, and share CBM data, facilitate data use, and support understanding larger-scale environmental patterns through interlinking with other platforms. Digital platforms, however, also introduce new challenges, with implications for the sustainability of CBM programs and communities’ abilities to maintain control of their own data. We expect that increased data access and strengthened technical capacity will create further demand within many communities for ethically developed platforms that aid in both local and larger-scale decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;amalgamation-and-harmonization-of-soil-survey-reports-into-a-multi-purpose-database&quot;&gt;Amalgamation and harmonization of soil survey reports into a multi-purpose database&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a growing demand for standardized, easily accessible, and detailed information pertaining to soil and its variability across the landscape. Typically, this information is only available for selected areas in the form of local or regional soil surveys reports which are difficult, and costly, to develop. Additionally, soil surveying protocols have changed with time, resulting in inconsistencies between surveys conducted over different periods. This article describes systematic procedures applied to generate an aspatial, terminologically, and unit-consistent, database for forest soils from county-based soil survey reports for the province of New Brunswick, Canada. The procedures involved (i) amalgamating data from individual soil surveys following a hierarchical framework, (ii) summarizing and grouping soil information by soil associations, (iii) assigning correct soil associates to each association, with each soil associate distinguished by drainage classification, (iv) assigning pedologically correct horizon sequences, as identified in the original soil surveys, to each soil associate, (v) assigning horizon descriptors and measured soil properties to each horizon, as outlined by the Canadian System of Soil Classification, and (vi) harmonizing units of measurement for individual soil properties. Identification and summarization of all soil associations (and corresponding soil associates) was completed with reference to the principal soil-forming factors, namely soil parent material, topographic surface expressions, soil drainage, and dominant vegetation type(s). This procedure, utilizing 17 soil surveys, resulted in an amalgamated database containing 106 soil associations, 243 soil associates, and 522 soil horizon sequences summarizing the variability of forest soil conditions across New Brunswick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;multisensor-fusion-of-remotely-sensed-vegetation-indices-using-space-time-dynamic-linear-models&quot;&gt;Multisensor fusion of remotely sensed vegetation indices using space-time dynamic linear models&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High spatiotemporal resolution maps of surface vegetation from remote sensing data are desirable for vegetation and disturbance monitoring. However, due to the current limitations of imaging spectrometers, remote sensing datasets of vegetation with high temporal frequency of measurements have lower spatial resolution, and vice versa. In this research, we propose a space-time dynamic linear model to fuse high temporal frequency data (MODIS) with high spatial resolution data (Landsat) to create high spatiotemporal resolution data products of a vegetation greenness index. The model incorporates the spatial misalignment of the data and models dependence within and across land cover types with a latent multivariate Matern process. To handle the large size of the data, we introduce a fast estimation procedure and a moving window Kalman smoother to produce a daily, 30-m resolution data product with associated uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-soil-health-tests-match-farmer-experience-assessing-biological-physical-and-chemical-indicators-in-the-upper-midwest-united-states&quot;&gt;Do soil health tests match farmer experience? Assessing biological, physical, and chemical indicators in the Upper Midwest United States&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil health testing provides an integrated assessment of biological, physical, and chemical attributes to inform the sustainable management of farm fields. However, it is unclear how tests reflect farmers’ own assessments of soil quality and agronomic performance, which may disproportionately influence farm management practices. We asked farmers in three regions of Michigan to identify three fields to compare their own assessments against soil health tests: a “best,” a “worst,” and a “non-row crop” reference field. Each field was tested for soil aggregate stability, available water capacity, soil organic matter (SOM), mineralizable carbon (MinC), permanganate oxidizable carbon (POXC), pH, P, and K. We evaluated soil health scores using paired t tests to compare results from contrasting fields with farmers’ assessments of each field. Across all farms, the overall soil health test score for cropped fields was significantly higher on fields farmers rated as “Best.” This result was driven solely by physical and biological (including C) parameters; inorganic chemical tests did not distinguish among field types. On reference fields in all regions, biological parameters were consistently higher, but inorganic chemical and physical measures were not. The performance of soil C measures was inconsistent: SOM and MinC consistently detected significant differences between “Best” and “Worst” cropped fields, but POXC did not. Our results suggest that common soil health assays for physical and biological attributes generally align well with farmers’ assessments of their fields. That soil health tests match farmer experience reinforces the value of these tests as a meaningful guide for soil management decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evaluating-three-calibration-transfer-methods-for-predictions-of-soil-properties-using-mid-infrared-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Evaluating three calibration transfer methods for predictions of soil properties using mid-infrared spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mid-infrared (MIR) spectroscopy models have been developed for rapid assessment of soils but are often soil and instrument specific because of differences in laboratory conditions and sensor setup. Calibration transfer is required to apply a spectral model such as partial least squares (PLS) regression developed from a primary instrument to a spectral dataset measured by a secondary instrument with statistically retained accuracy and precision. The study aimed to compare the performance of three transfer methods (i.e., direct standardization [DS], piecewise direct standardization [PDS], and spectral space transfer [SST]) and investigate the effects of transfer sample size and sample selection methods. The transfer methods were developed for predicting total C, clay, silt, and sand contents, cation exchange capacity (CEC), pH in water (pH(W)) and CaCl2, CaCO3 equivalent, and -1,500-kPa water retention using spectral measurements of a secondary instrument. Calibration transfer methods of three PLS models for estimating soil properties with a high (total C), intermediate (clay content), and low (pH(W)) predictability were discussed. The effect of sample size required for the development of the calibration transfer and the selection method of the transferred samples were investigated. It was found that SST was most favorable for a relatively small sample size used in calibration transfer (&amp;lt;= 12 samples). The performance of transfer methods was optimal when the transfer samples accounted for the variability of MIR spectra from the secondary instrument. We conclude that SST and PDS have the potential to be applied in spectroscopy for predicting soil properties using secondary instruments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;continuous-in-situ-soil-nitrate-sensors-the-importance-of-high-resolution-measurements-across-time-and-a-comparison-with-salt-extraction-based-methods&quot;&gt;Continuous in situ soil nitrate sensors: The importance of high-resolution measurements across time and a comparison with salt extraction-based methods&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil NO3- affects microbial processes, plant productivity, and environmental N losses. However, the ability to measure soil NO3- is limited by labor-intensive sampling and laboratory analyses. Hence, temporal variation in soil solution NO3- concentration is poorly understood. We evaluated a new potentiometric sensor that continuously measures soil solution NO3- concentration with unprecedented specificity due to a novel membrane that serves as a barrier to interfering anions. First, we compared sensor and salt extraction-based measurements of soil NO3- in well-controlled laboratory conditions. Second, using 60 d of in situ soil NO3- measurements every 10 s, we quantified temporal variation and the effect of sampling frequency on field estimations of mean daily NO3- concentration both within and across days. In the laboratory, sensors measured soil NO3- concentration without significant difference from theoretical adjusted soil NO3- concentration or conventional salt extraction-based methods. In the field, the sensors demonstrated no within-day pattern in soil NO3- concentration, although individual measurements within a day differed by as much as 20% from the daily mean. Across days, when soil solution NO3- was dynamic (early spring) and sampling frequency was &amp;gt;5 d, estimates of mean daily NO3- concentration were &amp;gt;20% from the actual mean daily concentration. In situ soil sensors offer potential to improve fundamental and applied sciences. However, in most situations, sensors will measure soil properties in a different manner than conventional salt-extract soil sampling-based approaches. Research will be required to interpret sensor measurements and optimize sensor deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bayesian-based-time-varying-multivariate-drought-risk-and-its-dynamics-in-a-changing-environment&quot;&gt;Bayesian-based time-varying multivariate drought risk and its dynamics in a changing environment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drought is one of the most damaging but least understood environmental disasters. The time-varying multi variate drought risk and its dynamics have remained unresolved in a changing environment. To this end, a Bayesian framework with time in its location parameter as a covariate was introduced in this study to conduct time-varying distributions of duration and severity. Besides, the joint distribution of precipitation and runoff was developed by bivariate non-parameter density kernel estimation for multivariate drought index NKMSDI (Nonparametric Kernel Multivariate Standardized Drought Index) and Expected Waiting Time (EWT)-based return period was used to estimate drought risk. Finally, the time-varying risk trends were explored and verified via correlations between drought risk and Normalized Difference Vegetation Index series. Results indicate that: (1) bivariate return period is more accurate than univariate return period for drought risk assessment and return periods under non-stationary assumption are more reasonable than those under stationary assumption; (2) the multivariate drought risks present obviously increasing trends and the western basin shows the highest increasing rate; and (3) the increasing drought risks exhibit strong association with sunspot activities and local vegetation dynamics. In general, this study provides new insights into drought risk and its dynamics under the time-varying drought properties condition, which is highly important for robust and effective management practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;transferring-hydrologic-data-across-continents---leveraging-data-rich-regions-to-improve-hydrologic-prediction-in-data-sparse-regions&quot;&gt;Transferring Hydrologic Data Across Continents - Leveraging Data-Rich Regions to Improve Hydrologic Prediction in Data-Sparse Regions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a drastic geographic imbalance in available global streamflow gauge and catchment property data, with additional large variations in data characteristics. As a result, models calibrated in one region cannot normally be migrated to another without significant modifications. Currently in these regions, non-transferable machine learning models are habitually trained over small local data sets. Here we show that transfer learning (TL), in the senses of weight initialization and weight freezing, allows long short-term memory (LSTM) streamflow models that were pretrained over the conterminous United States (CONUS, the source data set) to be transferred to catchments on other continents (the target regions), without the need for extensive catchment attributes available at the target location. We demonstrate this possibility for regions where data are dense (664 basins in Great Britain), moderately dense (49 basins in central Chile), and scarce with only remotely sensed attributes available (5 basins in China). In both China and Chile, the TL models showed significantly elevated performance compared to locally trained models using all basins. The benefits of TL increased with the amount of available data in the source data set, and seemed to be more pronounced with greater physiographic diversity. The benefits from TL were greater than from pretraining LSTM using the outputs from an uncalibrated hydrologic model. These results suggest hydrologic data around the world have commonalities which could be leveraged by deep learning, and synergies can be had with a simple modification of the current workflows, greatly expanding the reach of existing big data. Finally, this work diversified existing global streamflow benchmarks.
Plain Language Summary We introduced a method to utilize available big data to better start and warm up a machine learning streamflow model that is later fine-tuned for prediction in basins on other continents (Asia, South America and Europe). This procedure noticeably improved streamflow volume prediction for different scenarios with varying amounts of data in the target basins (in terms of time period, length of collected data, and number of basins having data). This allows thousands of basins across the world with only a few years’ worth of streamflow observations to benefit from improved modeling and accuracy resulting from the use of deep learning.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/06/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on June 24, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/06/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/06/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-06-16T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-06-16T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-19&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #19&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evaluating the benefits of chlorophyll fluorescence for in-season crop productivity forecasting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Different climate sensitivity of particulate and mineral-associated soil organic matter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Effect of missing data on short time series and their application in the characterization of surface temperature by detrended fluctuation analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decomposition of multivariate spatial data into latent factors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prediction of various soil properties for a national spatial dataset of Scottish soils based on four different chemometric approaches: A comparison of near infrared and mid-infrared spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evaluating-the-benefits-of-chlorophyll-fluorescence-for-in-season-crop-productivity-forecasting&quot;&gt;Evaluating the benefits of chlorophyll fluorescence for in-season crop productivity forecasting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remote sensing of solar-induced chlorophyll fluorescence (SIF) shows promise for monitoring the productivity of global agricultural systems. SIF-based primary productivity metrics have demonstrated higher fidelity to largescale patterns of crop productivity than reflectance-based vegetation indices when averaged across the growing season. In-season crop yield forecasting typically relies upon reflectance-based vegetation indices, raising the question of whether in-season monitoring could be improved by utilizing SIF. Here, we analyze patterns of US agricultural productivity from USDA surveys and their in-season relationships with coarse-resolution GOME-2 SIF, high-resolution downscaled SIF, SIF-based primary productivity metrics, MODIS NDVI, and MODIS GPP. We find that coarse-resolution SIF-based metrics and NDVI exhibit similar out-of-sample in-season (April-July and April-August) predictive ability, even when spatially filtering higher-resolution NDVI data to cropland areas. The downscaled SIF product performed more poorly than the coarse-resolution SIF, and MODIS GPP performed more poorly than MODIS NDVI. All forecasts are improved by incorporating county fixed effects to control for crosssectional differences between counties. NDVI-based metrics allow for significantly better yield predictions during drought conditions than SIF-based metrics, suggesting limited added value of SIF for early warning of drought impacts. The benefits of SIF for crop monitoring should be continually evaluated as the frequency and quality of SIF measurements continue to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;different-climate-sensitivity-of-particulate-and-mineral-associated-soil-organic-matter&quot;&gt;Different climate sensitivity of particulate and mineral-associated soil organic matter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil carbon sequestration is seen as an effective means to draw down atmospheric CO2, but at the same time warming may accelerate the loss of extant soil carbon, so an accurate estimation of soil carbon stocks and their vulnerability to climate change is required. Here we demonstrate how separating soil carbon into particulate and mineral-associated organic matter (POM and MAOM, respectively) aids in the understanding of its vulnerability to climate change and identification of carbon sequestration strategies. By coupling European-wide databases with soil organic matter physical fractionation, we assessed the current geographical distribution of mineral topsoil carbon in POM and MAOM by land cover using a machine-learning approach. Further, using observed climate relationships, we projected the vulnerability of carbon in POM and MAOM to future climate change. Arable and coniferous forest soils contain the largest and most vulnerable carbon stocks when cumulated at the European scale. Although we show a lower carbon loss from mineral topsoils with climate change (2.5 +/- 1.2 PgC by 2080) than those in some previous predictions, we urge the implementation of coniferous forest management practices that increase plant inputs to soils to offset POM losses, and the adoption of best management practices to avert the loss of and to build up both POM and MAOM in arable soils.
Particulate and mineral-associated soil organic carbon have different climate sensitivity and distributions in Europe, according to analyses of measurements of soil carbon fractions from 352 topsoils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;effect-of-missing-data-on-short-time-series-and-their-application-in-the-characterization-of-surface-temperature-by-detrended-fluctuation-analysis&quot;&gt;Effect of missing data on short time series and their application in the characterization of surface temperature by detrended fluctuation analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Climate change is deeply impacting the society on different scales. Decision making becomes a complex task when, in adverse weather conditions, the meteorological records show missing data due to failures of measuring instruments. Several investigations have proposed optimized regression methods, K-nearest-neighbor imputation, and multiple imputations for the treatment of missing data; however, there is less information about the application of imputation methods for the treatment of missing data on short meteorological records. Therefore, the expected confidence in the results requires using robust analysis methods that depend the least as possible on the length of the records and the number of missing data. In this research, the performance of detrended fluctuation analysis applied on temperature short record was studied when K-nearest-neighbor and neural networks are used as imputation techniques, and compared with the performance without data imputation. The results showed the robustness when it is applied to a short time series with missing data and without data imputation. In this aspect, the DFA method only requires removing the seasonality from the temperature records to get good performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;decomposition-of-multivariate-spatial-data-into-latent-factors&quot;&gt;Decomposition of multivariate spatial data into latent factors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simulating spatial Gaussian realizations is one of the core components of geostatistics and numerous other fields involving uncertainty, risk, and reliability. The use of decorrelation methods and truncated Gaussian algorithms further promotes the use of Gaussian realizations. In multivariate cases, geological variables may represent different scales and exhibit different spatial structures and anisotropy that complicates decorrelation methods. For cases where spatial dependencies cannot be removed using techniques such as the projection pursuit multivariate transform coupled with maximum autocorrelation factors, cokriging is advocated and requires a model of coregionalization. However, blind source separation represents the original multivariate problem as a linear combination of latent source variables, each one having a spatial structure from the linear model of coregionalization (LMC). The latent source variables or factors are independent and follow a standard normal distribution facilitating the use of Gaussian simulation algorithms. Moreover, different algorithms may be utilized for each variable given that some are more efficient at generating realizations for different spatial covariance functions. Recovering the original variables afterwards is straightforward. The theory for this decomposition is presented. A small numerical example is used to explain the theory and the proposed approach is illustrated through a case study with geochemical sample data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prediction-of-various-soil-properties-for-a-national-spatial-dataset-of-scottish-soils-based-on-four-different-chemometric-approaches-a-comparison-of-near-infrared-and-mid-infrared-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Prediction of various soil properties for a national spatial dataset of Scottish soils based on four different chemometric approaches: A comparison of near infrared and mid-infrared spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Infrared spectroscopic techniques, in combination with chemometric approaches, have been widely used to estimate different physical and chemical properties in soil samples. This study aims to assess the performance of diffuse reflectance spectroscopy in the near-infrared (NIR) region and Attenuated Total Reflection Fourier Transform infrared spectroscopy (ATR-FTIR) in the mid-infrared (MIR) region to predict nine different soil properties: total carbon, total nitrogen, bulk density, clay, sand, silt, pH (in H2O), exchangeable Mg and exchangeable K using chemometric approaches. The predictive performance of four different regression methods i.e., Partial least square (PLS), support vector regression (SVR), Cubist and convolutional neural network (CNN) in combination with different pre-processing approaches were investigated. For CNN, the FTIR/NIR spectra were converted to spectrograms and fed into the CNN to examine the prediction accuracy of two-dimensional convolutional neural network (CNN-2D) and to compare its performance with one-dimensional convolutional neural networks (CNN-1D, spectral data as input). To achieve these objectives, we used a spectral library of 650 samples from National Soils Inventory of Scotland (NSIS) dataset collected in a 20 km grid throughout Scotland between 2007 and 2009. The FTIR and NIR data were both split into calibration (n(c) = 520) and validation (n(v) = 130) sets. Our results show that the regression models with FTIR data have better predictive performance than those created using NIR data for all the studied soil properties (improvement in root mean square error of prediction (RMSEP) of 3-61%), except for pH. Comparing the different chemometric approaches, for both the NIR and FTIR, the results indicated that the CNN-1D models performs better than PLS, SVR and CNN-2D for all the studied soil components in terms of RMSEP. We found that the CNN-1D models created using the NIR spectral dataset were superior (lower RMSEP values) to those developed using the Cubist approach for total carbon, total nitrogen, clay, silt, pH and exchangeable K, whereas the Cubist models for sand and exchangeable Mg performed slightly better than CNN-1D. For the FTIR data, Cubist models for total carbon and silt performed best (with lowest RMSEP and highest Residual Prediction Deviation (RPD) values), while for the rest of the components, CNN-1D outperformed the PLS, SVR, Cubist and CNN-2D. We also calculated the impact of the NIR and FTIR variables used by the Cubist and CNN-1D models in predicting different soil properties. We used the Shapley Additive Explanation (SHAP) values, a game theoretic approach, to interpret the output of the CNN-1D models.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/06/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on June 16, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/06/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/06/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-06-08T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-06-08T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-18&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #18&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simultaneously estimating surface soil moisture and roughness of bare soils by combining optical and radar data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The economics of liming in arable crop rotations: analysis of the 35-year Rothamsted and Woburn liming experiments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An integrated spatial econometric approach in valuing soil conservation using contingent valuation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Governing climate risks in the face of normative uncertainties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;simultaneously-estimating-surface-soil-moisture-and-roughness-of-bare-soils-by-combining-optical-and-radar-data&quot;&gt;Simultaneously estimating surface soil moisture and roughness of bare soils by combining optical and radar data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both radar and optical signals are sensitive to the change of surface soil moisture (SSM) and surface roughness properties (such as root mean squared height- RMSH), and the accuracy of retrieved SSM from single radar and optical remote sensing data is influenced by the spatiotemporal change of surface roughness. Here, we attempt to explore a method to simultaneously estimate SSM and RMSH of bare soil by combining optical and radar data, so as to weaken the effect of surface roughness on SSM inversion results. To achieve this goal, two satellite synchronous ground experiments were carried out, collecting 88 sampling plots each with an area of 50 m × 50 m. Radar backscattering coefficient and spectral reflectance are uniformly corrected to a fixed observation direction and solar incident direction respectively, which can eliminate the difference of satellite signal resulted from various sun-satellite geometry. Combining radar backscattering and optical reflectance model, Sentinel-1 and Sentinel-2 data are used to simultaneously retrieve SSM and RMSH of bared soils, and some conclusions are given as below: 1) a strong correlation is observed for (radar and optical) satellite signals and soil surface parameters (SSM and RMSH); 2) a higher accuracy was obtained by the combined use of optical and radar data, indicated by the decreased root mean squared error of retrieved SSM (~0.045 cm3/cm3) and RMSH (~0.8 cm); 3) the further improvement of retrieved SSM and RMSH was achieved by introducing their initial values, revealing that the prior knowledge of soil properties is also beneficial to improve the retrieval accuracy. This study proposed an framework for simultaneous estimation of SSM and RMSH by combining optical and radar data, and its feasibility is verified by experimental data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-economics-of-liming-in-arable-crop-rotations-analysis-of-the-35-year-rothamsted-and-woburn-liming-experiments&quot;&gt;The economics of liming in arable crop rotations: analysis of the 35-year Rothamsted and Woburn liming experiments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liming is a common management practice, but there exists uncertainty about the economic benefits. An economic analysis of the costs and profitability of liming arable crops was undertaken using data from the long-term liming experiment at Rothamsted and Woburn. There was a strong liming effect on gross margins, but large differences in the economic benefit between crops. For some crops (such as spring barley), liming greatly improved the gross margin, while for spring oats liming provided very little increase. Most economic benefit was achieved with the high lime treatment, but the cumulative discounted cash flow indicated that it took approximately 20 years before a distinct difference developed between the lime treatments. Therefore, lime should be considered a capital investment and economic evaluation undertaken over a long period. Liming rate increased the net present value expressed as an annual equivalent (NPVa). An additional £436 ha−1 year−1 at Rothamsted and £208 ha−1 year−1 at Woburn of profit was gained from the adoption of the most profitable liming treatments over not liming. Sensitivity analysis indicated that total liming costs had a weak effect on NPVa, but crop price had a strong effect. The economic performance of liming differed between sites and was higher at Rothamsted than at Woburn, mostly because of soil differences. Liming greatly improves economic returns of most arable crops, but the magnitude of the long-term economic benefit depends upon the sequence of crops within a given rotation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-integrated-spatial-econometric-approach-in-valuing-soil-conservation-using-contingent-valuation&quot;&gt;An integrated spatial econometric approach in valuing soil conservation using contingent valuation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The integration of soil value in agronomic micro-level decision-making and macro-scale policy development has grown immensely in recent years. Major threats to soil resources and their impact on human well-being require a comprehensive estimation of soil’s economic worth, highlighting the need for sustainable and pragmatic conservation strategies. However, the absence of formal markets for numerous soil amenities, coupled with the heterogeneity of stakeholder cognition and spatio-environmental factors, obfuscates the valuation process for soil and similar public goods. This paper aims to address such concerns by evaluating stakeholders’ willingness to pay (WTP) for soil conservation as a proxy indicator for its explicit value. Two contingent valuation method (CVM) formats, the payment card (PC) and the dichotomous choice (DC), were used to analyse WTP in Norzagaray, Philippines. Results suggest farmers’ income, education, land tenure type, level of environmental consciousness and proximity to amenities influence their inclination to spend on soil conservation measures. Econometric analyses indicate a compensating surplus corresponding to the mean WTP estimate of ₱79.98 (PC-CVM) and a Turnbull WTP estimate of ₱99.47 (DC-CVM). Estimated WTP values can be used in future benefit-transfer studies, and the findings of the econometric models can be used in developing strategies that would promote greater stakeholder acceptance and participation. The approach presented here provides another step towards a more comprehensive characterization of soil value that integrates environmental valuation and econometric modelling with geospatial data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;governing-climate-risks-in-the-face-of-normative-uncertainties&quot;&gt;Governing climate risks in the face of normative uncertainties&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Governing risks is not only a technical matter, but also a matter of ethical and societal considerations. In this article, we argue that in addition to scientific and technical uncertainties, we need to also address normative uncertainties of risk decisions. We define normative uncertainties as situations where there are different partially morally defensible – but incompatible – options or courses of action, or ones in which there is no fully morally defensible option. We conceptualize normative uncertainties, distinguishing between the four categories of evolutionary, theoretical, conceptual, and epistemic normative uncertainties. We will show different instances of normative uncertainties in climate adaptation strategies. We finally present two methods for identifying and dealing with normative uncertainties, namely, the Wide Reflective Equilibrium and adaptive planning. Situations of normative uncertainties have always been and will continue to be present in risk decisions and they have often been dealt with in an implicit manner. In this article, we make them explicit, which could lead to better morally informed and justified decisions about climate risks.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/06/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on June 08, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/06/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/06/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-06-03T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-06-03T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-17&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #17&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Comparison of soil organic matter composition under different land uses by DRIFT spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Role of Soils in Land Degradation Assessment: A Review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rapid soil and vegetation changes at regional scale in continental Antarctica&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compaction induced soil structural degradation affects productivity and environmental outcomes: A review and New Zealand case study&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ecosystem services of urban soils: A review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Potential benefits of liming to acid soils on climate change mitigation and food security&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Current carbon prices do not stack up to much land use change, despite bundled ecosystem service co-benefits&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reducing climate impacts of beef production: A synthesis of life cycle assessments across management systems and global regions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comparison-of-soil-organic-matter-composition-under-different-land-uses-by-drift-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Comparison of soil organic matter composition under different land uses by DRIFT spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study aimed to estimate and characterise soil organic matter under different land uses (cropland, grassland, and forest) and soil depths. The soil organic matter composition of the soil was assessed by diffuse reflectance infrared spectroscopy (DRIFT). Humic and fulvic acids (HAs, FAs) were extracted from soils and their compositions were evaluated by DRIFT. Low molecular mass organic acids content was also measured. Our result revealed that the largest differences of the spectra in the composition of organic matter were observed in the upper parts of the soil profile. The forest soil spectra had more intense aliphatic bands, carboxylic, and CH bands than spectra of grassland and cropland soils. The difference of HAs spectra was at 3 010 to 2 800/cm where the most intensive aliphatic bands were in forest soil HAs, followed by grassland and cropland soil HAs. The grassland topsoil FAs spectrum differs most from the other land uses. It has lower peaks around 1 660-1 600/cm and 1 200/cm than cropland and forest. The concentration of low molecular mass organic acid (LMMOA) was the highest in the forest soil and the most abundant acid was citrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-role-of-soils-in-land-degradation-assessment-a-review&quot;&gt;The Role of Soils in Land Degradation Assessment: A Review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the framework of the existing concepts of land degradation assessment, the main ideas about its causes and consequences are formulated, methodological provisions for studying the intensity of degradation processes are defined, and specific methods for assessing the economic component of degradation are developed. The problem of economic assessment of land degradation is complicated by differences in understanding of the nature of degradation processes and the role of soils in them. Soil indicators play the most significant role in the economic assessment of damage from land degradation. However, this methodology does not actually involve the use of modern concepts of ecosystem services. On the contrary, the methodology of land degradation economics, which uses a wide range of ecosystem services, largely ignores the need to take into account the dynamics of soil properties. The development of a unified methodology will solve many problems, among which an important place is occupied by the need to avoid legally regulated formulaic assessments of degradation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rapid-soil-and-vegetation-changes-at-regional-scale-in-continental-antarctica&quot;&gt;Rapid soil and vegetation changes at regional scale in continental Antarctica&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antarctica is the last pristine environment on Earth, its biota being adapted to the harsh and extreme polar climate. Until now, soil formation and vegetation development in continental Antarctica were considered very slow due to the extreme conditions of this polar desert. Since the austral summer 2002/2003, a long-term monitoring network of the terrestrial ecosystems (soils, vegetation, active layer thickness) has been established at Victoria Land (VL) across a &amp;gt; 500 km latitudinal gradient of coastal sites (73 degrees -77 degrees S). In only one decade large ecosystem changes were detected. Climate was characterized by a significant increase of thawing degree days in northern VL and of autumn air temperature. No extreme climatic events (such as hot spells) where detected in the study period. Soil chemistry suffered large quantitative changes, clearly indicating rapid pedogenetic processes. In most soils the upper layers exhibited a strong alkalinization (pH increases up to 3 units) and increases in conductivity, anions and cations (in particular of SO4 and Na). The largest changes were observed in soils with low vegetation cover. Statistically significant differences in soil chemistry were detected between soils with high and low vegetation cover, the former showing lower pH, conductivity, Na and Cl. Most plots exhibited changes of total cover, species richness and floristic composition, with vegetation expansion in soils with low vegetation cover and the largest increase recorded at Apostrophe Island (northern VL). Principal Component Analysis (PCA) identified the main trend of vegetation change, with a shift from lower to higher cover and a secondary trend of change associated with a gradient of water availability, consistent with an increase in water instead of snow. Redundancy analysis (RDA) identified the trend of change in soil chemistry with increases in pH, conductivity, anions and cations associated with the concomitant decrease in C, N, NO3, PO4. The RDA confirmed that soil changes were associated with a gradient of vegetation change (from low to high cover) as well as of water availability, as already indirectly outlined by the PCA. Field manipulation experiments carried out at five locations of the network between 73 degrees S and 77 degrees S, simulating increases of precipitation from snow or water additions didn’t induce changes in soil pH, indicating that pulse events of snow accumulation or melting could not trigger persistent soil pH changes. These data allow hypothesize the occurrence of a main ecosystem change occurring at regional scale at Victoria Land. The slight air warming and its consequences on soil chemistry and vegetation, further highlight the sensitivity of the fragile Antarctic ecosystems to the consequences of even small changes in climate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;compaction-induced-soil-structural-degradation-affects-productivity-and-environmental-outcomes-a-review-and-new-zealand-case-study&quot;&gt;Compaction induced soil structural degradation affects productivity and environmental outcomes: A review and New Zealand case study&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agricultural intensification has enhanced productivity, but has also negatively affected soil structure and environmental outcomes. Agriculture is among New Zealand (NZ)’s largest industries. Like other countries, significant land use intensification over the last 20-30 years has occurred in NZ, resulting in undesirable side-effect of soil structural degradation (SSD) (e.g., soil compaction, aggregate fragmentation). Using NZ as a case study, we reviewed and, where possible, quantified the extent of SSD in NZ and its impacts and implications on production, contaminant losses via drainage and runoff, and N2O emissions. Knowledge gaps were identified that will help guide future research both in NZ and internationally. Our review revealed that SSD is common in many regions and under different land uses in NZ. At the national scale, 44% of sites monitored between 2014 and 2017 were below the national target for macroporosity (pore diameter &amp;gt; 30 mu m). The occurrence of SSD was greater under more intensive land uses such as dairying and continuous cropping. Soil structural degradation from compaction is typically associated with reduced pasture and crop production. In NZ, pasture production was estimated to decrease by an average of 2.5% for every 1.0% (0.01 cm(3) cm (3)) decrease in macroporosity (0-10 cm soil). Compaction from livestock treading and wheel traffic has been shown to increase N2O emissions by 51-814% and 19-1300%, respectively, with no significant evidence that this increase is related to N loading. Effects of compaction on contaminant losses via runoff and drainage, and in particular via preferential flow, are less well researched and findings were less consistent and dependent on many factors including the degree of compaction. Important knowledge gaps include a lack of quantitative relationships between degree of SSD and soil hydraulic properties and processes (e.g., water movement and contaminant losses), and poor knowledge of critical thresholds or optimum ranges of soil physical indicators in relation to critical ecosystem services (e.g., pasture yield, gas and water regulation in soils). We also found few estimates of SSD-induced costs related to production and environmental outcomes (e.g., contaminant losses and N2O emissions) at either farm system, regional or national scales. More data are needed to better determine the true costs and implications for farm production and environmental effects associated with SSD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-ecosystem-services-of-urban-soils-a-review&quot;&gt;The ecosystem services of urban soils: A review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The expansion of urban areas worldwide is increasing the anthropogenic impact upon soil and highlights the important role of urban areas in supporting a sustainable future. As such, urban soils are becoming more important in the delivery of a broad range of ecosystem services (ESs), including carbon storage and climate regulation, biomass provision for food and water flow regulation, and recreational benefits. In this review, we aim to support the development of this emerging research area and, subsequently, support the improved treatment and management of urban soil and ES delivery. We present a systematic review of which ESs have been studied and examine trends in research using a co-occurrence analysis of key terms. We then provide a summary review of current knowledge on ESs and identify the gaps in knowledge. Our review highlights that this is a young, but growing, field of research, with a marked increase in publications since 2014. We found that supporting processes and regulating services were most commonly studied, with 88% and 71% of the papers relating to quantitative studies addressing these, respectively. Cultural, provisioning and water-related ESs were relatively understudied, suggesting key gaps for future research. However, this may be attributable to a disconnection between academic communities rather than a lack of knowledge. Fewer than 20% of quantitative studies addressed more than two ESs simultaneously, leading us to suggest that urban soil multifunctionality is a key area for future research, and highlighting the need to integrate understanding of urban soil ESs across disciplines and professions. In addition to this overarching suggestion, we propose six research gaps and opportunities: further research into biomass provision for food, water-related ESs and cultural ESs; greater geographical representation; further interconnection between research and practitioner communities; and a focus on the future drivers of soil change in urban environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;potential-benefits-of-liming-to-acid-soils-on-climate-change-mitigation-and-food-security&quot;&gt;Potential benefits of liming to acid soils on climate change mitigation and food security&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Globally, about 50% of all arable soils are classified as acidic. As crop and plant growth are significantly hampered under acidic soil conditions, many farmers, but increasingly as well forest managers, apply lime to raise the soil pH. Besides its direct effect on soil pH, liming also affects soil C and nutrient cycles and associated greenhouse gas (GHG) fluxes. In this meta-analysis, we reviewed 1570 observations reported in 121 field-based studies worldwide, to assess liming effects on soil GHG fluxes and plant productivity. We found that liming significantly increases crop yield by 36.3%. Also, soil organic C (SOC) stocks were found to increase by 4.51% annually, though soil respiration is stimulated too (7.57%). Moreover, liming was found to reduce soil N2O emission by 21.3%, yield-scaled N2O emission by 21.5%, and CH4 emission and yield-scaled CH4 emission from rice paddies by 19.0% and 12.4%, respectively. Assuming that all acid agricultural soils are limed periodically, liming results in a total GHG balance benefit of 633-749 Tg CO2-eq year(-1) due to reductions in soil N2O emissions (0.60-0.67 Tg N2O-N year(-1)) and paddy soil CH4 emissions (1.75-2.21 Tg CH4 year(-1)) and increases in SOC stocks (65.7-110 Tg C year(-1)). However, this comes at the cost of an additional CO2 release (c. 624-656 Tg CO2 year(-1)) deriving from lime mining, transport and application, and lime dissolution, so that the overall GHG balance is likely neutral. Nevertheless, liming of acid agricultural soils will increase yields by at least 6.64 x 10(8) Mg year(-1), covering the food supply of 876 million people. Overall, our study shows for the first time that a general strategy of liming of acid agricultural soils is likely to result in an increasing sustainability of global agricultural production, indicating the potential benefit of liming acid soils for climate change mitigation and food security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;current-carbon-prices-do-not-stack-up-to-much-land-use-change-despite-bundled-ecosystem-service-co-benefits&quot;&gt;Current carbon prices do not stack up to much land use change, despite bundled ecosystem service co-benefits&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biological sources of carbon sequestration such as revegetation have been highlighted as important avenues to combat climate change and meet global targets by the global community including the Paris Climate Agreement. However, current and projected carbon prices present a considerable barrier to broad-scale adoption of tree planting as a key mitigation strategy. One avenue to provide additional economic and environmental incentives to encourage wider adoption of revegetation is the bundling or stacking of additional co-beneficial ecosystem services that can be realized from tree planting. Using the World’s largest land-based carbon credit trading scheme, the Australian Emissions Reduction Scheme (ERF), we examine the potential for three pairs of ecosystem services, where the carbon sequestration value of land use change is paired with an additional co-benefit with strong prospects for local tangible benefits to land owners/providers. Two cases consider agricultural provisioning values that can be realized by the landowners in higher returns: increased pollination services and reduced lamb mortality. The third case examined payments for tree plantings along riparian buffers, with payments to farmers by a water utility who realizes the benefit from reduced treatment cost due to water quality improvements. Economic incentives from these co-benefit case studies were found to be mixed, with avoided treatment costs from water quality paired with carbon payments the most promising, while pollination and reduced lamb mortality paired with carbon payments were unable to bridge the economic gap except under the most optimistic assumptions. We conclude that the economics case for significant land use change are likely to be geographically dispersed and only viable in relatively niche landscape positions in high establishment, high opportunity cost areas even when carbon payments are augmented with the value of co-benefits classified as providing direct and local benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reducing-climate-impacts-of-beef-production-a-synthesis-of-life-cycle-assessments-across-management-systems-and-global-regions&quot;&gt;Reducing climate impacts of beef production: A synthesis of life cycle assessments across management systems and global regions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The global demand for beef is rapidly increasing (FAO, 2019), raising concern about climate change impacts (Clark et al., 2020; Leip et al., 2015; Springmann et al., 2018). Beef and dairy contribute over 70% of livestock greenhouse gas emissions (GHG), which collectively contribute similar to 6.3 Gt CO2-eq/year (Gerber et al., 2013; Herrero et al., 2016) and account for 14%-18% of human GHG emissions (Friedlingstein et al., 2019; Gerber et al., 2013). The utility of beef GHG mitigation strategies, such as land-based carbon (C) sequestration and increased production efficiency, are actively debated (Garnett et al., 2017). We compiled 292 local comparisons of “improved” versus “conventional” beef production systems across global regions, assessing net GHG emission data from Life Cycle Assessment (LCA) studies. Our results indicate that net beef GHG emissions could be reduced substantially via changes in management. Overall, a 46 % reduction in net GHG emissions per unit of beef was achieved at sites using carbon (C) sequestration management strategies on grazed lands, and an 8% reduction in net GHGs was achieved at sites using growth efficiency strategies. However, net-zero emissions were only achieved in 2% of studies. Among regions, studies from Brazil had the greatest improvement, with management strategies for C sequestration and efficiency reducing beef GHG emissions by 57%. In the United States, C sequestration strategies reduced beef GHG emissions by over 100% (net-zero emissions) in a few grazing systems, whereas efficiency strategies were not successful at reducing GHGs, possibly because of high baseline efficiency in the region. This meta-analysis offers insight into pathways to substantially reduce beef production’s global GHG emissions. Nonetheless, even if these improved land-based and efficiency management strategies could be fully applied globally, the trajectory of growth in beef demand will likely more than offset GHG emissions reductions and lead to further warming unless there is also reduced beef consumption.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/06/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on June 03, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/05/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/05/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-05-26T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-05-26T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-16&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #16&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil carbon dynamics during drying vs. rewetting: Importance of antecedent moisture conditions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Air-drying and long time preservation of soil do not significantly impact microbial community composition and structure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organic carbon pools and organic matter chemical composition in response to different land uses in southern Brazil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introducing digital twins to agriculture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A review of geostatistical simulation models applied to satellite remote sensing: Methods and applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-carbon-dynamics-during-drying-vs-rewetting-importance-of-antecedent-moisture-conditions&quot;&gt;Soil carbon dynamics during drying vs. rewetting: Importance of antecedent moisture conditions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil moisture influences soil carbon dynamics, including microbial growth and respiration. The response of such ‘soil respiration’ to moisture changes is generally assumed to be linear and reversible, i.e. to depend only on the current moisture state. Current models thus do not account for antecedent soil moisture conditions when determining soil respiration or the available substrate pool. We conducted a laboratory incubation to determine how the antecedent conditions of drought and flood influenced soil organic matter (SOM) chemistry, bioavailability, and respiration. We sampled soils from an upland coastal forest, Beaver Creek, WA USA, and subjected them to drying and rewetting treatments. For the drying treatment, field moist soils were saturated and then dried to 75, 50, 35, and 5% saturation. In the rewetting treatment, field moist soils were air-dried and then rewet to 35, 50, 75, and 100% saturation. We measured respiration and water extractable organic carbon (WEOC) concentrations and used H-1-NMR and FT-ICR-MS to characterize the WEOC pool across the treatments. The drying vs. wetting treatment strongly influenced SOM bioavailability, as rewet soils (with antecedent drought) had greater WEOC concentrations and respiration fluxes compared to the drying soils (with antecedent flood). In addition, air-dry soils had the highest WEOC concentrations, and the NMR-resolved peaks showed a strong contribution of protein groups in these soils. Both NMR and FT-ICR-MS analyses indicated increased contribution of complex aromatic groups/molecules in the rewet soils, compared to the drying soils. We suggest that drying introduced organic matter into the WEOC pool via desorption of aromatic molecules and/or by microbial cell lysis, and this stimulated microbial mineralization rates. Our work indicates that even short-term shifts in antecedent moisture conditions can strongly influence soil C dynamics at the core scale. The predictive uncertainties in current soil models may be reduced by a more accurate representation of soil water and C persistence that includes a mechanistic and quantitative understanding of the impact of antecedent moisture conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;air-drying-and-long-time-preservation-of-soil-do-not-significantly-impact-microbial-community-composition-and-structure&quot;&gt;Air-drying and long time preservation of soil do not significantly impact microbial community composition and structure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To determine whether archived air-dried soils can be potentially used to explore microbial information upon sampling, we examined microbial community dynamics during soil air-drying and long time preserving. Fresh soils from five long-term fertilization treatments were sampled, air-dried, and preserved. Soil microbial community was characterized at specific intervals (from 0 h to 8192 h) by Illumina sequencing. The results showed that both prokaryotic and fungal community profiles did not substantially change during air-drying and long time preserving. The fertilization effects on microbial community structure could still be identified using the airdried soils. These findings suggest that air-drying and preserving exerts an almost negligible impact on soil microbial community profiles, laying the foundation for utilizing worldwide archived soils to investigate microbial community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;organic-carbon-pools-and-organic-matter-chemical-composition-in-response-to-different-land-uses-in-southern-brazil&quot;&gt;Organic carbon pools and organic matter chemical composition in response to different land uses in southern Brazil&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The adoption of conservation agriculture (e.g., no-till system) has been recognized as pivotal to maintaining soil functions, but the potential of this system to enhance organic carbon (OC) quantity and quality and how this OC is stabilized in soils are not well established. In this study, we evaluated the effects of land-use types (native vegetation (NV) vs. no-till system (NT)) on OC stocks and on the chemical composition of organic matter (OM), and sought to understand the mechanisms that govern OC protection in the studied highly weathered soils. To achieve these objectives, we used an OC fractionation scheme in a combination of solid-state C-13 nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) spectroscopic analyses in soils from six farms in southern Brazil. Our results showed smaller OC stocks (whole soil) under NT than under NV in four of the six sites. In addition, the OC stock differences between land-use types were larger in coarser textured soils and in those where conventional tillage was used before the adoption of NT. Among fractions, particulate organic carbon (POC) represented only 8% of the whole OC stock but was the fraction most affected by land-use type. In contrast, the humus organic carbon (HOC) fraction contributed 78% of the whole OC stock and was little altered by land-use type. Resistant organic carbon (ROC) represented 14% of the whole OC stock and it was altered by land-use type, demonstrating that this fraction is not as inert as previously thought. Overall, OM chemical composition was quite similar between land uses, with O-alkyl-C being the predominant C type. This labile component was further highly correlated with OC stock and silt + clay contents, indicating that the accumulation of OC in these highly weathered soils is mainly a response to the association between labile C compounds and minerals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-review-of-geostatistical-simulation-models-applied-to-satellite-remote-sensing-methods-and-applications&quot;&gt;A review of geostatistical simulation models applied to satellite remote sensing: Methods and applications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite an ever-increasing number of spaceborne, airborne, and ground-based data acquisition platforms, remote sensing data are still often spatially incomplete or temporally irregular. While deterministic interpolation techniques are often used, they tend to create unrealistic spatial patterns and generally do not provide uncertainty quantification. Geostatistical simulation models are effective in generating an ensemble of realistic and equally probable realizations of an unmeasured phenomenon, allowing data uncertainty to be propagated. These models are commonly used in several fields of earth science, and in recent years, they have been applied widely to remotely sensed data. This study provides the first review of the applications of geostatistical simulation to remote sensing data. We review recent geostatistical simulation models relevant to satellite remote sensing data and discuss the characteristics and advantages of each approach. Finally, the applications of each geostatistical simulation model are categorized in different domains of natural sciences, including soil, vegetation, topography, and atmospheric science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;introducing-digital-twins-to-agriculture&quot;&gt;Introducing digital twins to agriculture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital twins are being adopted by increasingly more industries, transforming them and bringing new opportunities. Digital twins provide previously unheard levels of control over physical entities and help to manage complex systems by integrating an array of technologies. Recently, agriculture has seen several technological advancements, but it is still unclear if this community is making an effort to adopt digital twins in its operations. In this work, we employ a mixed-method approach to investigate the added-value of digital twins for agriculture. We examine the extent of digital twin adoption in agriculture, shed light on the concept and the benefits it brings, and provide an application-based roadmap for a more extended adoption. We report a literature review of digital twins in agriculture, covering years 2017-2020. We identify 28 use cases, and compare them with use cases in other disciplines. We compare reported benefits, service categories, and technology readiness levels to assess the level of digital twin adoption in agriculture. We distill the digital twin characteristics that can provide addedvalue to agriculture from the examined digital twin applications in agriculture and in other disciplines. Then, inspired by digital twin applications in other disciplines, we propose a roadmap for digital twins in agriculture, consisting of examples of growing complexity. We conclude this paper by identifying the distinctive characteristics of agricultural digital twins.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/05/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on May 26, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/05/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/05/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-05-25T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-05-25T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-15&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #15&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stochastic and deterministic interpretation of pool models&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Classifying human influences on terrestrial ecosystems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feasibility of the 4 per 1000 aspirational target for soil carbon: A case study for France&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Environmental covariates improve the spectral predictions of organic carbon in subtropical soils in southern Brazil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using autoencoders to compress soil VNIR-SWIR spectra for more robust prediction of soil properties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;classifying-human-influences-on-terrestrial-ecosystems&quot;&gt;Classifying human influences on terrestrial ecosystems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human activity is affecting every ecosystem on Earth, with terrestrial biodiversity decreasing rapidly. Human influences materialize in the form of numerous, jointly acting factors, yet the experimental study of such joint impacts is not well developed. We identify the absence of a systematic ordering system of factors according to their properties (traits) as an impediment to progress and offer an a priori trait-based factor classification to illustrate this point, starting at the coarsest level with the physical, biological or chemical nature of factors. Such factor classifications can serve in communication of science, but also can be used as heuristic tools to develop questions and formulate new hypotheses, or as predictors of effects, which we explore here. We hope that classifications such as the one proposed here can help shift the spotlight on the multitude of anthropogenic changes affecting ecosystems, and that such classifications can be used to help unravel joint impacts of a great number of factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stochastic-and-deterministic-interpretation-of-pool-models&quot;&gt;Stochastic and deterministic interpretation of pool models&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carbon and element cycling models can be expressed in terms of the dynamics of individual particles or collection of them in aggregated pools. In both cases, the models represent the same dynamics and provide similar predictions. The time required for individual particles to pass through a system, that is, the transit time, can be obtained from both approaches. Pool models can be analyzed from a stochastic or a deterministic point of view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;feasibility-of-the-4-per-1000-aspirational-target-for-soil-carbon-a-case-study-for-france&quot;&gt;Feasibility of the 4 per 1000 aspirational target for soil carbon: A case study for France&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Increasing soil organic carbon (SOC) stocks is a promising way to mitigate the increase in atmospheric CO2 concentration. Based on a simple ratio between CO2 anthropogenic emissions and SOC stocks worldwide, it has been suggested that a 0.4% (4 per 1000) yearly increase in SOC stocks could compensate for current anthropogenic CO2 emissions. Here, we used a reverse RothC modelling approach to estimate the amount of C inputs to soils required to sustain current SOC stocks and to increase them by 4 parts per thousand per year over a period of 30 years. We assessed the feasibility of this aspirational target first by comparing the required C input with net primary productivity (NPP) flowing to the soil, and second by considering the SOC saturation concept. Calculations were performed for mainland France, at a 1 km grid cell resolution. Results showed that a 30%-40% increase in C inputs to soil would be needed to obtain a 4 parts per thousand increase per year over a 30-year period. 88.4% of cropland areas were considered unsaturated in terms of mineral-associated SOC, but characterized by a below target C balance, that is, less NPP available than required to reach the 4 parts per thousand aspirational target. Conversely, 90.4% of unimproved grasslands were characterized by an above target C balance, that is, enough NPP to reach the 4 parts per thousand objective, but 59.1% were also saturated. The situation of improved grasslands and forests was more evenly distributed among the four categories (saturated vs. unsaturated and above vs below target C balance). Future data from soil monitoring networks should enable to validate these results. Overall, our results suggest that, for mainland France, priorities should be (1) to increase NPP returns in cropland soils that are unsaturated and have a below target carbon balance and (2) to preserve SOC stocks in other land uses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;environmental-covariates-improve-the-spectral-predictions-of-organic-carbon-in-subtropical-soils-in-southern-brazil&quot;&gt;Environmental covariates improve the spectral predictions of organic carbon in subtropical soils in southern Brazil&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Including environmental covariates, when available, can be a valuable strategy for achieving higher soil predictive performance, but it is still unknown whether environmental data should be used either as covariates, combined with Vis-NIR spectra, to predict soil organic carbon (SOC) or as criteria to stratify a soil spectral library (SSL). We hypothesized that the performance of Vis-NIR spectroscopy in predicting SOC could be improved by the inclusion of auxiliary environmental data as covariates in Cubist models and thereby overcome the data stratification limitations. To test this, we evaluated six covariate sets, in which the following covariates were combined: spectral data, spectral classes, pedological data, and environmental data calibrated using Cubist models. An SSL composed of 2,461 samples from southern Brazil was used to calibrate models considering different sets of covariates. Model 1 included Vis-NIR reflectance (350-2500 nm), and Model 2 included Vis-NIR reflectance and spectral class. Model 3 included physiographic region, land-use/land-cover (LULC), climate, parent material, elevation, and clay content, while Model 4 included the parameters from Model 3 with the addition of Vis-NIR reflectance. Model 5 included Vis-NIR reflectance, spectral class, physiographic region, LULC, and soil textural class, while Model 6 included Vis-NIR reflectance, spectral class, physiographic region, LULC, climate, parent material, elevation, and clay content. The inclusion of environmental data as covariates along with Vis-NIR improved the predictive performance for SOC. Among the six covariate sets tested, the set including all covariates (Model 6) showed the best performance, improving the accuracy in prediction by 12% and reducing the prediction error (RMSE) by 22% compared to Model 1. Model 6 was the most accurate, and the input of environmental data as covariates is a promising strategy to achieve more accurate SOC predictions. Thus, covariates (e.g. elevation, clay content) that correlate with SOC improved the prediction accuracy of VisNIR spectroscopy models. The Cubist model was able to achieve similar accuracy and overcome the limitations presented by the stratification strategy documented in the literature by preventing the reduction of the sample size in the calibration of the models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-autoencoders-to-compress-soil-vnir-swir-spectra-for-more-robust-prediction-of-soil-properties&quot;&gt;Using autoencoders to compress soil VNIR-SWIR spectra for more robust prediction of soil properties&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past two decades, research efforts have focused on using near infrared diffuse reflectance spectroscopy (350-2500 nm) as a rapid and cost-effective method for soil analysis. Given the multi-faceted importance of the soil ecosystem, and considering the increasing pressures exerted upon it due to climate change, degradation and urbanization, the advantages of soil spectroscopy are significant. Large soil spectral libraries have been developed to this end throughout the world. The soil matrix is however complex, posing a challenge in the determination of key soil properties from the spectra. To tackle this challenge, two methodologies are generally used: a) the use of spectral pre-processing techniques to transfer the spectra into a new space in which the association between spectrum and soil property is supposed to be more clear, and b) the use of more sophisticated machine learning models (e.g. deep learning). In this paper, we propose a novel methodology using stacked autoencoders to transform the initially recorded spectra in a new compressed (i.e. latent) space which can help the chemometric models enhance the accuracy of prediction. This is an unsupervised learning approach which only depends on the input data (i.e. the spectra). Following the significant results obtained in the literature using combinations of different spectra pre-processing techniques and the simultaneous prediction of multiple soil properties, the proposed methodology is extended to facilitate these approaches. We demonstrate this capacity by applying it in the mineral samples of the LUCAS 2009 topsoil database, and simultaneously predicting eight properties (the particle size distribution, pH, CEC, organic carbon, calcium carbonate, and total nitrogen) using an artificial neural network. Compared to standard pre-processing techniques and other transformations such as the principal components space, the proposed methodology using only one spectral source as input decreases the RMSE on average by 8.4% and by 3.5%, respectively. With respect to the current state-of-the-art and in particular a multi-input convolutional neural network which was recently proposed and outperformed the compared methodologies, the results of our multi-input methodology exhibit an average RMSE decrease of 9.9%. The interpretability aspect of the transformed feature space and the compressed spectra was also examined to identify how the compressed information encodes the input data and enables better associations between input and output.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/05/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on May 25, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/05/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/05/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-05-10T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-05-10T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-14&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #14&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time, Hydrologic Landscape, and the Long-Term Storage of Peatland Carbon in Sedimentary Basins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Predicting soil organic matter nitrogen mineralization&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A regional soil classification framework to improve soil health diagnosis and management&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two centuries of water-level records at Lake George, NSW&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Production of global daily seamless data cubes and quantification of global land cover change from 1985 to 2020-iMap World 1.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;time-hydrologic-landscape-and-the-long-term-storage-of-peatland-carbon-in-sedimentary-basins&quot;&gt;Time, Hydrologic Landscape, and the Long-Term Storage of Peatland Carbon in Sedimentary Basins&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peatland carbon may enter long-term storage in sedimentary basins preserved as either coal or lignite. The time required to account for the carbon in 1-10 m thick coal seams must represent 10(5)-10(6) years, an order of magnitude more than previously assumed. To understand the process by which this happens requires extrapolation of our understanding of peatland carbon accumulation over timescales that greatly exceed those of Holocene peat. We analyze the consequences of extrapolating peat growth to periods of 10(6) years. We deduce that that key to sustained peat growth are hydrologic landscapes that can maintain a saturated peat body above the level of clastic deposition. Contrary to current stratigraphic frameworks, we conclude that the generation of accommodation space at low rates of 0.1-0.2 mm/yr can adequately accommodate thick peat accumulation over periods &amp;gt;10(5) years. However, generation of accommodation space at rates &amp;gt;0.5 mm/yr cannot. The low rates that permit accommodation of thick peat are typical of the rates of subsidence in specific tectonic settings, particularly foreland basins, and this has implications for our understanding of the links between terrestrial carbon burial, tectonics and the carbon cycle. The long-term stability of extensive peatland required to form coal also requires sediment bypass, modifying basin wide sediment transport and deposition. Limits to peatland growth under very low accommodation rates must exist but the relative importance of the limiting process is not understood. Finally, we discuss the consequences of these factors for predicting the future of the peatland carbon reservoir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;predicting-soil-organic-matter-nitrogen-mineralization&quot;&gt;Predicting soil organic matter nitrogen mineralization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objectives of this study were to develop a model for soil organic matter (SOM) N mineralization that required minimal inputs, to test the model using independent datasets, and to determine if the results could be used in adjusting commercial N fertilizer recommendations. A first-order model was adjusted monthly for differences in soil temperature and moisture. A daily time step was used to allow N mineralization estimates from one date to another. Simulations began in the month where temperature exceeded 10 degrees C. Model predictions were compared with those in published studies in northern California and Illinois. In the first California study, model predictions were near observed values in four of five locations. In the second California study, model predictions were within the 95% confidence interval of those based on laboratory incubation corrected for field temperature and moisture regimes. In a third study, unfertilized corn (Zea mays L.) yields were compared with seasonal N mineralization predictions plus N from the prior crop for 15 Illinois soils. The result was 32.0 kg corn kg(-1) seasonal available N as compared with the typical value of 67.5 kg corn kg(-1) commercial N fertilizer. Nitrogen mineralization predictions for Illinois soils were related to total N, suggesting that an equation could replace simulation modeling for a given soil-location combination. It is proposed that the N mineralization model, which has readily obtainable inputs (total N, bulk density, monthly weather), could be used in conjunction with field studies to refine commercial N fertilizer recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-regional-soil-classification-framework-to-improve-soil-health-diagnosis-and-management&quot;&gt;A regional soil classification framework to improve soil health diagnosis and management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil health research has developed soil tests to validate management strategies for creating healthier soils, such as cover crops, compost, and reduced tillage. Missing in this research agenda are soil health management strategies and diagnostics tailored to the systematic variation of soils. The Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database offers comprehensive estimates for many properties linked to soil health indicators. This research uses unsupervised classification of soil surface (0-30 cm) properties and root restrictive horizons in an internationally important agricultural region, the Central and Coastal Valleys of California, covering 5.6 million ha of mostly cropland. K-means clustering of 10 soil properties derived from SSURGO revealed groups distinct from USDA-NRCS Soil Taxonomy. Clustering metrics, data visualization, and validation tests justified a seven-region soil health conceptual model that divided the landscape into two broad classes-those with and without performance limitations. Results revealed three pedogenic conditions limiting soil performance: (a) root restrictive horizons that impede root growth into deeper soil; (b) salinity and alkalinity harmful to crops; and (c) shrink-swell properties making soils challenging to cultivate. Soils without performance limitations, soils with restrictive horizons, and salt-affected soils are further divided by texture and/or organic matter for a total of seven soil health regions. In reality, variation in soil properties is often continuous across the landscape and sometimes fractal in nature, but this research establishes a testable framework for evaluating soil health diagnostics according to geographically coherent differences in soil properties, demonstrating potential for how soil health management and interpretation can be tailor-made to the landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;two-centuries-of-water-level-records-at-lake-george-nsw&quot;&gt;Two centuries of water-level records at Lake George, NSW&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year 2020 marked the 200th anniversary of European settlers first encountering the ‘noble expanse of water’ of Lake George in New South Wales. Since 1820, unofficial observations and official measurements of the lake’s water-level have been recorded almost continuously by various individuals, research teams, government departments and private companies. The lake’s recent hydrographic history has been characterised by periods of flood and drought, which correspond with the prevailing climate conditions of SE Australia. This is the longest water-level record of its sort in the Southern Hemisphere and hence of great scientific and historic value. Here, we have compiled all available historic water-level data for Lake George, referenced them to common datums and presented a methodology for continuing the record using satellite imagery in lieu of on-site measurements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;production-of-global-daily-seamless-data-cubes-and-quantification-of-global-land-cover-change-from-1985-to-2020-imap-world-10&quot;&gt;Production of global daily seamless data cubes and quantification of global land cover change from 1985 to 2020-iMap World 1.0&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Longer time high-resolution, high-frequency, consistent, and more detailed land cover data are urgently needed in order to achieve sustainable development goals on food security, high-quality habitat construction, biodiversity conservation and planetary health, and for the understanding, simulation and management of the Earth system. However, due to technological constraints, it is difficult to provide simultaneously high spatial resolution, high temporal frequency, and high quality observation data. Existing mapping solutions are limited by traditional remotely sensed data, that have shorter observation periods, poor spatio-temporal consistency and comparability. Therefore, a new mapping paradigm is needed. This paper develops a framework for intelligent mapping (iMap) of land cover based on state-of-the-art technologies such as cloud computing, artificial intelligence, virtual constellations, and spatio-temporal reconstruction and fusion. Under this framework, we built an automated, serverless, end-to-end data production chain and parallel mapping system based on Amazon Web Services (AWS) and produced the first 30 m global daily seamless data cubes (SDC), and annual to seasonal land cover maps for 1985?2020. The SDC was produced through a multi-source spatio-temporal data reconstruction and fusion workflow based on Landsat, MODIS, and AVHRR virtual constellations. Independent validation results show that the relative mean error of the SDC is less than 2.14%. As analysis ready data (ARD), it can lay a foundation for high-precision quantitative remote sensing information extraction. From this SDC, we produced 36-year long, 30 m resolution global land cover map data set by combining strategies of sample migration, machine learning, and spatio-temporal adjustment. The average overall accuracy of our annual land cover maps over multiple periods of time is 80% for level 1 classification and over 73% for level 2 classification (29 and 33 classes). Based on an objective validation sample consisting of FLUXNET sites, our map accuracy is 10% higher than that of existing global land cover datasets including Globeland30. Our results show that the average global land cover change rate is 0.36%/yr. Global forest decreased by 1.47 million km2 from 38.44 million km2, cropland increased by 0.84 million km2 from 12.49 million km2 and impervious surface increased by 0.48 million km2 from 0.57 million km2 during 1985? 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/05/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on May 10, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/04/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/04/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-04-26T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-04-26T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-13&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #13&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multi-sensor remote sensing for drought characterization: current status, opportunities and a roadmap for the future&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimation of soil water retention in conservation agriculture using published and new pedotransfer functions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the interpretation of surprisingly high variation of soil map diversity in country-wide study of flood-affected agroecosystems using the legacy data in the Czech Republic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Building a resilient and sustainable food system in a changing world -&amp;amp; nbsp;A case for climate-smart and nutrient dense crops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;multi-sensor-remote-sensing-for-drought-characterization-current-status-opportunities-and-a-roadmap-for-the-future&quot;&gt;Multi-sensor remote sensing for drought characterization: current status, opportunities and a roadmap for the future&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satellite based remote sensing offers one of the few approaches able to monitor the spatial and temporal development of regional to continental scale droughts. A unique element of remote sensing platforms is their multi-sensor capability, which enhances the capacity for characterizing drought from a variety of perspectives. Such aspects include monitoring drought influences on vegetation and hydrological responses, as well as assessing sectoral impacts (e.g., agriculture). With advances in remote sensing systems along with an increasing range of platforms available for analysis, this contribution provides a timely and systematic review of multi sensor remote sensing drought studies, with a particular focus on drought related datasets, drought related phenomena and mechanisms, and drought modeling. To explore this topic, we first present a comprehensive summary of large-scale remote sensing datasets that can be used for multi-sensor drought studies. We then review the role of multi-sensor remote sensing for exploring key drought related phenomena and mechanisms, including vegetation responses to drought, land-atmospheric feedbacks during drought, drought-induced tree mortality, drought-related ecosystem fires, post-drought recovery and legacy effects, flash drought, as well as drought trends under climate change. A summary of recent modeling advances towards developing integrated multi-sensor remote sensing drought indices is also provided. We conclude that leveraging multi-sensor remote sensing provides unique benefits for regional to global drought studies, particularly in: 1) revealing the complex drought impact mechanisms on ecosystem components; 2) providing continuous long-term drought related information at large scales; 3) presenting real-time drought information with high spatiotemporal resolution; 4) providing multiple lines of evidence of drought monitoring to improve modeling and prediction robustness; and 5) improving the accuracy of drought monitoring and assessment efforts. We specifically highlight that more mechanism-oriented drought studies that leverage a combination of sensors and techniques (e.g., optical, microwave, hyperspectral, LiDAR, and constellations) across a range of spatiotemporal scales are needed in order to progress and advance our understanding, characterization and description of drought in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;estimation-of-soil-water-retention-in-conservation-agriculture-using-published-and-new-pedotransfer-functions&quot;&gt;Estimation of soil water retention in conservation agriculture using published and new pedotransfer functions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conservation agriculture has been developed as a means to improve the sustainability of agricultural systems and reduce drawbacks of conventional agricultural practices. Cropping practices can have a large influence on soil properties such as water retention. Proper tools are needed to assess and model effects of conservation agriculture on soil properties. As measuring soil water retention is expensive and time consuming, pedotransfer functions (PTFs) are now commonly used to predict them. The objectives of this study were to (i) present a new dataset of conservation agriculture data, (ii) assess performances of existing PTFs in predicting soil water retention of soils under conservation agriculture and (iii) develop new specific PTFs to predict water retention in conservation agriculture more accurately. We used data collected only in fields under conservation agriculture in France to evaluate several published PTFs with three evaluation criteria (RMSE, prediction bias (ME) and Nash-Sutcliffe Efficiency (EF)). We then developed new PTFs using three methods - multiple linear regression, regression tree and random forest - to predict soil water content at matric heads of -100 (theta(100), field capacity for sandy soils), -330 (theta(330), field capacity for other soils) and -15 000 cm (theta(15) 000, wilting point). Soil tillage, presence of a cover crop, rotation length and previous reduced/no tillage were used as predictors in addition to basic soil properties for regression trees and random forests. The quality of prediction (RMSE, ME and EF) was calculated for each new PTF using a cross-validation procedure. Generally, predictions of wilting point had lower absolute error than those of sandy-soil field capacity (RMSE = 0.044 and 0.066 cm(3)/cm(3), respectively). EF was usually negative for all water contents. The cross-validation performance of the new PTFs was similar for multiple linear regression (RMSE: 0.028, ME: 0.000, EF: 0.34 for theta(100)) and random forest (RMSE: 0.027, ME: 0.000, EF: 0.36 for theta(100)), and generally worse for regression tree (especially EF). Multiple linear regression that did not consider cropping practices performed as well as random forest and thus did not identify any major influence of agricultural management on predicted water content. Future research on developing PTFs should focus on identifying more relevant predictors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;on-the-interpretation-of-surprisingly-high-variation-of-soil-map-diversity-in-country-wide-study-of-flood-affected-agroecosystems-using-the-legacy-data-in-the-czech-republic&quot;&gt;On the interpretation of surprisingly high variation of soil map diversity in country-wide study of flood-affected agroecosystems using the legacy data in the Czech Republic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Legacy soil data have been produced worldwide to provide maps of soil classes or properties. In this study, we joined the legacy results of conventional soil mapping with the application of the pedodiversity concept and compositional data analysis in a comprehensive spatial analysis of the mapped soil diversity within flood-prone agroecosystems in the Czech Republic. After the statistical differences in Shannon’s entropy (conventional and adjusted with taxonomic distances) over different regional inundation areas had been statistically examined, their interpretation was based on Aitchison’s geometry of simplex, rendering an appropriate statistical framework to avoid methodological bias through the use of raw proportions in soil taxa compositions. Working with tailored orthonormal coordinates enabled us to verify the dependency of the soil taxa composition on the multicategory factors of agroecosystem type and flood-periodicity through a conventional linear modelling. The supervised compositional approach improved interpretability of soil information within the Czech legacy soil maps, and hence general patterns of pedodiversity in floodplains might be effectively described in an informative and quantitative manner. The most obvious differences of the soil map diversity proved the regional inundation areas within the catchments with the enhanced complexity of drainage network that might arise from multiple sources (substrate diversity, climatic zonality, man-induced landscape alteration).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;building-a-resilient-and-sustainable-food-system-in-a-changing-world---nbspa-case-for-climate-smart-and-nutrient-dense-crops&quot;&gt;Building a resilient and sustainable food system in a changing world -&amp;amp; nbsp;A case for climate-smart and nutrient dense crops&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current food production and consumption practices have had negative impacts on the environment and are central to global health concerns. Using a mixed-methods review, we examined the nutritional and environmental impacts of our global food systems and addressed the apparent decrease in food sources and crop diversity, and its implication on sustainable and healthy diets. Moreover, we explored the merits of weighing the use of natural capital and agricultural inputs against the output generated in terms of nutrient density. Transforming our food systems to safeguard planetary health will require a shift towards sufficient production of nutrient dense crops that are environmentally sustainable. Such a transformation largely depends on valuing crops for their natural nutrient density and matching them to suitable environments.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/04/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on April 26, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/04/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/04/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-04-25T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-04-25T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-12&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #12&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Direct cell extraction from fresh and stored soil samples: Impact on microbial viability and community compositions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil aggregate size-dependent relationships between microbial functional diversity and multifunctionality&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finding exceedance locations in a large spatial database using nonparametric regression&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Natural and managed soil structure: On the fragile scaffolding for soil functioning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SLAKES and 3D Scans characterize management effects on soil structure in farm fields&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pattern analysis of Australia soil profiles for plant available water capacity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Factors of soil formation in the 21st century&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Information depth of NIR/SWIR soil reflectance spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paying the price for environmentally sustainable and healthy EU diets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The role of nitrogen in achieving sustainable food systems for healthy diets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;paying-the-price-for-environmentally-sustainable-and-healthy-eu-diets&quot;&gt;Paying the price for environmentally sustainable and healthy EU diets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We review consumer-side interventions and their effectiveness to support a transition to healthier and more environmentally sustainable diets and identify taxes/subsidies as relevant instruments. To quantify the scope of necessary tax levels to achieve dietary recommendations on EU average, we apply three established economic models. Our business-as-usual food intake projections stress the need for policy intervention to resolve continued divergence from nutrition guidelines. Our findings suggest that food group specific taxes are effective in reaching nutrition and environmental sustainability targets. However, considerable tax levels are required to achieve the targeted consumption shifts, inducing a discussion about alternative policy designs and current model limitations. A coherent policy package is suggested to approach nutrition and sustainability objectives simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;direct-cell-extraction-from-fresh-and-stored-soil-samples-impact-on-microbial-viability-and-community-compositions&quot;&gt;Direct cell extraction from fresh and stored soil samples: Impact on microbial viability and community compositions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The direct extraction of viable microbes from soil samples is critical for the application of many single-cell related technologies. However, there are many aspects of extraction technologies that can impact the viability and diversity of extractable cells from fresh or stored soil samples. In this study, physical dispersion method, chemical dispersion method, and Nycodenz density gradient medium concentration were optimized with two sequential rounds of cell extraction from four soil samples having diverse physicochemical properties. Cell viability was quantified with fluorescence staining and flow cytometry. The viable microbial community compositions in soil extractable cells and soil samples were assessed after selective removal of DNA from dead cells. Among the four different extraction and purification methods, a protocol that included physical blending, Tween 20 treatment, and centrifugation with 80% Nycodenz, had the highest cell viability and yield. Repeated extraction increased the yield but reduced the cell viability. The over- or under-represented taxa in extractable cells might contribute to the bias of the extractable microbial communities. Using the optimized cell extraction procedure, the effect of soil storage conditions (4 degrees C, -80 degrees C, and air-drying) on yield, viability, and community composition of soil extractable cells were assessed. Cell viability decreased in all stored soil samples, but significant decreases in cell yield was only observed in air-dried soil samples. Microbial community compositions changed significantly in all stored soil samples, with the least changes were observed in soil stored at 4 degrees C, confirming that 4 degrees C short-term storage is suitable for highly efficient viable cell extraction. Taken together, the developed method offers great potential for advancing our analyses and understanding of soil microbial ecology and the role of individual microbes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-aggregate-size-dependent-relationships-between-microbial-functional-diversity-and-multifunctionality&quot;&gt;Soil aggregate size-dependent relationships between microbial functional diversity and multifunctionality&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil stability and aggregates are important drivers of soil fertility and microbial diversity and are highly vulnerable to land degradation. However, the role of soil aggregates in driving the responses of microbial functional diversity and multiple ecosystem services and functions (multifunctionality) to further degradation (e. g., fertilization) remains largely unexplored and poorly understood. In this study, we used soils from long-term experiments involving inorganic and organic fertilization treatments to investigate the role soil aggregates (microscale) play in driving microbial functional gene diversity (via GeoChip) and the activity of multiple extracellular enzymes in an agricultural ecosystem. We found that microbial functional gene diversity has a significant and positive relationship with soil multifunctionality, which is enhanced in soil aggregates by organic fertilizer but is reduced by inorganic fertilizer. We also found that soil aggregate fractions indirectly controlled multiple ecosystem functions via changes in functional diversity. Smaller soil aggregates with higher resource availability (carbon and nitrogen) supported more ecological functions than larger aggregates under contrasting fertilizer management regimes. Soil multifunctionality is regulated by the differences in resource availability and not by microbial functional gene composition, which suggests that microbial functional diversity contributed more to multifunctionality than gene composition. Random forest analysis and structural equation modeling indicated that soil carbon and nitrogen and microbial functional diversity together determined the multifunctionality, whereas soil traits have more standardized total effects than functional diversity. Our study highlights that soil aggregation stratifies soil nutrition and microbial functional diversity, which leads to the differentiation of aggregate ecosystem multifunctionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;finding-exceedance-locations-in-a-large-spatial-database-using-nonparametric-regression&quot;&gt;Finding exceedance locations in a large spatial database using nonparametric regression&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the era of big data analysis, it is of interest to develop diagnostic tools for preliminary scanning of large spatial databases. One problem is identification of locations where certain characteristics exceed a given norm, e.g. timber volume or mean tree diameter exceeding a user-defined threshold. Some of the challenges are, large size of the database, randomness, complex shape of the spatial mean surface, heterogeneity and others. In a step-bystep procedure, we propose a method for achieving this for large spatial data sets. For illustration, we work through a simulated spatial data set as well as a forest inventory data set from Alaska (source: USDA Forest Services). Working within the framework of nonparametric regression modeling, the proposed method can attain a high degree of flexibility regarding the shape of the spatial mean surface. Taking advantage of the large sample size, we also provide asymptotic formulas that are easy to implement in any statistical software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;natural-and-managed-soil-structure-on-the-fragile-scaffolding-for-soil-functioning&quot;&gt;Natural and managed soil structure: On the fragile scaffolding for soil functioning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil structure in natural systems is a product of complex interactions between biological activity, climate and soil minerals that promote aggregation and accumulation of biopores. In arable lands, the management of soil structure often requires the mechanical fragmentation of hardened soil to improve seedbed, control weeds and bury plant residue. Despite difficulties in defining and quantifying soil structure, its critical role is evidenced by loss of productivity when natural structure is perturbed (e.g. compaction) and the long history of tillage in agriculture. To overcome persistent ambiguities among scientific disciplines regarding definition and function of soil structure, we propose a framework for distinguishing managed and natural soil structure based on their different formation processes and functions. Natural soil structure preserves ecological order and legacy that promotes biopore reuse, stabilizes foodwebs and protects soil organic carbon (SOC). The contribution of net primary productivity of natural lands to soil structure forming processes makes it a useful (surrogate) metric of soil structure. The benefits of managed soil structure for crops are quantified indirectly via comparisons with no till farming under similar conditions. The levels and trends of SOC are useful metrics for the status of natural and managed soil structure. The systematic consideration of soil structure state in natural and arable lands using suitable metrics is a prerequisite for rational decisions related to land management and ensuring sustainable functioning of a fragile and central resource such as soil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;slakes-and-3d-scans-characterize-management-effects-on-soil-structure-in-farm-fields&quot;&gt;SLAKES and 3D Scans characterize management effects on soil structure in farm fields&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adoption of no-till (NT) is low in the Lower and Middle Brazos River Watershed of Texas, leaving soil vulnerable to erosion, exacerbating flooding, and contributing to high nutrient and sediment levels in surface waters. To investigate the impact of NT on soil structure and hydraulic function in the region, we measured saturated hydraulic conductivity, organic carbon, bulk density, slaking index of soil aggregates (inversely related to aggregate stability), and soil structure in farm fields under three management systems: conventional tillage (CT), NT, and perennial grass (PG). Soil structure was measured using a novel method for 3D scanning of soil surface horizons - multistripe laser triangulation. Slaking index was measured using a recently developed smartphone application. Exploratory factor analysis combined with a semi-supervised cluster analysis showed that, in general, CT and PG fields were classified into different clusters from one another. Three fields managed with NT for 21, 21, and 7 years were classified in the same cluster as PG fields, while the remaining fields (managed with NT for 21, 21, 18, and 3 years) were classified with CT fields. Organic carbon was significantly higher in NT compared to CT fields. Conventional fields had significantly lower hydraulic conductivity than PG fields and hydraulic conductivity was 1.3 cm h-1 higher in NT than CT fields. Soil structure measured from 10-30 cm depth was significantly improved in NT compared to CT. Improvements in organic carbon and soil hydraulic function are meaningful indicators of improved physical soil health that can be used to promote NT adoption. Improvements in organic carbon and soil hydraulic function also provide ecosystem services to off-site stakeholders who are impacted by erosion and sedimentation resulting from soil tillage. The two novel measurements (a metric derived from scanning of soil structure and slaking index from a smartphone application) were particularly sensitive to management system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pattern-analysis-of-australia-soil-profiles-for-plant-available-water-capacity&quot;&gt;Pattern analysis of Australia soil profiles for plant available water capacity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plant available water capacity (PAWC), defined as the amount of water held in the soil between the drained upper limit (DUL) and crop lower limit (CLL), is a major determinant for crop yield in dryland cropping areas. However, measured soil profile data quantifying the physical soil parameters that determine PAWC are limited. Choosing a ‘representative’ soil profile in order to parameterise a deterministic model is often subjective and may not be appropriate, leading to biased conclusions. To help support these deterministic crop modelling studies, we analysed soil profile data in Australia available in the APSoil database; a database of field and laboratory measured physical soil properties used to parameterise the Agricultural Production Systems sIMulator (APSIM) model. Specifically, we developed typical soil pattern profiles utilizing wheat for CLL using statistical shape analysis and cluster analysis. Our method allows modellers to reduce the number of soil profile parameter choices using a statistically sound basis. We implement our method by grouping the APSoil soil profiles into five clusters, whereby each cluster is represented by a more general soil profile. The representative soil profiles reflect impact of the soil texture on PAWC. The five clusters and representative soil profiles can then be used in future modelling studies to investigate the impact of soil variation on systems performance. In turn, soil scientists will have a plausible and quantifiable collection of soil profiles to choose from for future studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;factors-of-soil-formation-in-the-21st-century&quot;&gt;Factors of soil formation in the 21st century&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year 2021 marks the 80th anniversary of the publication of Factors of Soil Formation. A System of Quantitative Pedology by Hans Jenny. Given the exponential surge in annual citations of the book over the past 30 years, and this important milestone in its history, it is an opportune time to examine what the book presents, and how it is relevant to transdisciplinary research in the 21st Century. The book did not originate the concept of soil forming factors, which were by then already widely accepted in soil science, but instead translated it into a quantitative scientific framework through rigorous definition of the soil system, and the identification and separation of dependent and independent variables. The initial formulation of the theoretical framework was inspired by thermodynamics, but with pedologically-relevant state variables. Subsequent formulations of the model by Jenny articulated the connection and utility to examining energy and mass fluxes through the soil system, a point of departure for recent efforts to bring open system, non-equilibrium thermodynamic methods to bear on soil research. The State Factor theory is a powerful lens to examine a number of academic and societally relevant issues in the 21st century, such as the role of the biotic factor and its interplay with the physical soil environment. However, the most critical, and understudied, state factor is the effect of humans on soil systems. Earth science must embrace the challenge, and obligation to society, to explore the human footprint on the planet, and devise ways to remediate its impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;information-depth-of-nirswir-soil-reflectance-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Information depth of NIR/SWIR soil reflectance spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proximal and remote sensing techniques in the optical domain are cost-effective alternatives to standard soil property characterization methods. However, the extent of light penetration into the soil sample, also termed soil information depth, is not well understood. In this study a new analytical model that links the particle size distribution and soil reflectance in the near infrared (NIR) and shortwave infrared (SWIR) bands of the electromagnetic spectrum is introduced. The model enables the partitioning of measured reflectance spectra into surface and volume (subsurface) contributions, thereby yielding insights about the soil information depth. The model simulations indicate that the surface reflectance contribution to the total reflectance is significantly higher than the volume reflectance contribution for a broad range of soils that vastly differ in texture, mineralogical composition and organic matter contents. The ratio of volume to total reflectance is higher for sandy soils than for clayey soils, especially at longer optical wavelengths, but the ratio rarely exceeds 15%. Therefore, the light reflection from dry soils is predominantly a surface phenomenon and the information depth in most soils rarely exceeds 1 mm. The results of this study reveal an intimate physical relationship between soil reflectance and the particle size distribution in the NIR/SWIR range, which opens a potential new avenue for retrieval of the particle size distribution from remotely sensed reflectance via a universal process-based approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-role-of-nitrogen-in-achieving-sustainable-food-systems-for-healthy-diets&quot;&gt;The role of nitrogen in achieving sustainable food systems for healthy diets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ‘food system’ urgently needs a sustainable transformation. Two major challenges have to be solved: the food system has to provide food security with healthy, accessible, affordable, safe and diverse food for all, and it has to do so within the safe operating space of the planetary boundaries, where the pollution from reactive nitrogen turned out to be the largest bottleneck. Here we argue that thinking strategically about how to balance nitrogen flows throughout the food system will make current food systems more resilient and robust. Looking from a material and a governance perspective on the food system, we highlight major nitrogen losses and policy blind spots originating from a compartmentalization of food system spheres. We conclude that a participatory and integrated approach to manage nitrogen flows throughout the food system is necessary to stay within regional and global nitrogen boundaries, and will additionally provide synergies with a sustainable and healthy diet for all.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/04/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on April 25, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/04/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/04/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-04-14T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-04-14T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-11&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #11&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Progress in recent airborne gamma ray spectrometry measurement technology&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Retrievals of soil moisture and vegetation optical depth using a multi-channel collaborative algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil organic carbon sequestration calculated from depth distribution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;progress-in-recent-airborne-gamma-ray-spectrometry-measurement-technology&quot;&gt;Progress in recent airborne gamma ray spectrometry measurement technology&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the development of deep resource exploration, rapid nuclear emergency response, environmental monitoring, great progress has been made in airborne gamma-ray spectrum (AGS) measurement technology during the past few decades. Its development prospects are closely related to the AGS instruments and data processing technology. The AGS technology can be used to retrieve radionuclide information, which makes it a hot research field to improve the sensitivity, accuracy and detection limit of the AGS detection effectively. This paper focuses on the progress made in the AGS instruments and data processing since 1940s’, deeply reviews the technology characteristics and development status, thoroughly discusses the typical AGS applications, summarizes the current technology trend, and puts forward potential research directions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;retrievals-of-soil-moisture-and-vegetation-optical-depth-using-a-multi-channel-collaborative-algorithm&quot;&gt;Retrievals of soil moisture and vegetation optical depth using a multi-channel collaborative algorithm&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the success of the SMOS (Soil Moisture and Ocean Salinity) and SMAP (Soil Moisture Active Passive) missions, new satellite missions are on the horizon. The current and future missions can benefit from investigations that seek to improve retrieval algorithms that quantitatively map global soil moisture and vegetation optical depth (tau) from Earth’s microwave emissions. In this study, we explore multi-angular and multi-frequency approaches for the retrieval of soil moisture and vegetation tau, considering the payload configurations of current and future satellite missions (such as the Copernicus Imaging Microwave Radiometer, the Water Cycle Observation Mission, and the Terrestrial Water Resources Satellite) using a new set of ground observations. Two ground-based microwave radiometry datasets collected in Inner Mongolia during the Soil Moisture Experiment in the Luan River from July to August 2017 (cropland) and August to September 2018 (grassland) are used for this study. The corn field, which covers an entire growth period, indicated that the degree of information increases linearly as the number of channels (in terms of the incidence angle and frequency) increases, and that the multi-frequency observations contain slightly more independent information than do the multi-angular observations under the same number of channels. The polarization difference in brightness temperature is sensitive to both soil moisture and vegetation water content, especially at L-band due to its penetrating ability. Soil moisture explains most of the variance in frequency differences of brightness temperature at adjacent frequencies (L- &amp;amp; C-bands, C- &amp;amp; X-bands), while the variance in incidence-angle differences of brightness temperature is mostly associated with the vegetation water content. A multi-channel collaborative algorithm (MCCA) is developed based on the two-component version of the omega-tau model, which utilizes information from collaborative channels expressed as an analytical form of brightness temperature at the core channel to rule out the parameters to be retrieved. Results of soil moisture retrieval show that the multi-angular approach used by the MCCA generally has a better performance, unbiased mot mean square difference (ubRMSD) varying from 0.028 cm(3)/cm(3) to 0.037 cm(3)/cm(3), than the multi-frequency approach (ubRMSD from 0.028 cm(3)/cm(3) to 0.089 cm(3)/cm(3)) for the corn field. This is attributed to the dependence of vegetation tau on the frequency being more significant than that on the incidence angle. Except for in the C- &amp;amp; X-band combination, the multi-frequency approach used by the MCCA performs better (ubRMSD from 0.018 cm(3)/cm(3) to 0.023 cm(3)/cm(3)) than the multi-angular version (ubRMSD from 0.026 cm(3)/cm(3) to 0.034 cm(3)/cm(3)) for the grass field due to reduced vegetation effects for this type of cover. It is affirmed that increasing the number of observation channels could make the soil moisture retrieval more robust, but might also limit the retrieval performance, as the probability that the model estimations will not match the observations is increased. This study provides new insights into the design of potential satellite missions to improve soil moisture retrieval. A satellite with simultaneous multi-angular and multi-frequency observation capabilities is highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-organic-carbon-sequestration-calculated-from-depth-distribution&quot;&gt;Soil organic carbon sequestration calculated from depth distribution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract
Sequestration of organic C in agricultural soils is necessary to improve soil health to meet the challenges of climate change, diminishing biodiversity, water quality deterioration, and rising demands for food and fiber production. New assessment approaches are needed to quantify how conservation agriculture might contribute to soil health improvement and soil organic C (SOC) sequestration. In the southeastern United States, conservation management has been repeatedly shown to stratify SOC concentration with depth. Starting immediately below a zone of tillage influence (i.e., 30-cm depth), SOC concentration is rarely affected by management due to low C inputs and high decomposition potential, whereas concentration increases toward the surface in a nonlinear manner, presumably with greater inputs of residue and root inputs and changing temperature and moisture conditions. Using these observations as an ecological foundation, SOC sequestration was calculated as the summation of SOC stock greater than the baseline condition at 30-cm depth. Data from literature sources were mathematically fitted with this new approach as a validation. Two on-farm surveys with different agricultural management practices (5-40 yr) in the southeastern United States yielded preliminary estimates of SOC sequestration. The interquartile range of calculated SOC sequestration was 4.2-9.4 Mg C ha(-1) for conventional-tillage cropland (n = 45 fields), 13.6-29.7 Mg C ha(-1) for no-tillage cropland (n = 97 fields), and 15.9-26.1 Mg C ha(-1) for perennial pasture (n = 29 fields). This new approach will be valuable to estimate SOC sequestration from a greater diversity of conservation agricultural systems practiced on farms within a region and independent of soil type.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/04/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on April 14, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>
