<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Brendan Malone</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2017-05-26T23:03:40+10:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Brendan Malone</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[NEW PAPER! Geochemical Fingerprinting of volcanic soils in West Sumatra, Indonesia]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/05/IndonFinger" />
  <id>/2017/05/IndonFinger</id>
  <updated>2017-05-16T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-05-16T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;geochemical-fingerprinting-of-volcanic-soils-used-for-wetland-rice-in-west-sumatra-indonesia&quot;&gt;Geochemical fingerprinting of volcanic soils used for wetland rice in West Sumatra, Indonesia&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Published in Geoderma Regional 10 (2017) 48-63.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Toward the end of 2016, Prof. Dian Fiantis (Department of Soil Science, Faculty of Agriculture, Universitas Andalas, Kampus Limau Manis) spent around 3 months in our soil science research group. With her in her kit bag, were a number of soil samples collected from various sites around a few different volcanoes situated in West Sumatra, Indonesia. Together with Budiman Minansy, Dian wanted to determine whether soils from different volcanoes had unique and identifiable geochemical fingerprints. We set about determining this using X-ray fluorescence technology and other soil analysis approaches to determine the concentration of the mineral elements of these soils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/downloads/journal/malone2017_5.pdf&quot;&gt;This paper&lt;/a&gt; is the outcome of some of Dian’s research. There are more research outputs to come! Prof. Fiantis is a credit to her university, and was a joy to have around our research group in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cultivation of paddy (rice) in volcanic soils is commonly practiced in West Sumatra, Indonesia. This study aims
to provide a detailed geochemical fingerprinting of topsoils of paddy fields derived from volcanic materials in
the vicinity of mount (Mt) Marapi, Mt. Sago, Mt. Singgalang, Mt. Tandikek and Caldera Maninjau in West
Sumatra, Indonesia as a function of different geochronology of volcanic parent materials. Seventy-nine topsoil
samples were collected along an altitudinal gradient ranging from 44 m in the Maninjau area to 1220 m above
sea level (a.s.l.) at Mt. Singgalang. In addition to conventional physical and chemical analysis, geochemical
analysis was carried out using a portable X-ray fluorescent spectrometer (XRF) and organic matter composition
was analyzed using mid-infrared Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (FTIR). The chemical composition of
the volcanic paddy soils in this area is controlled by the origin of parent materials and weathering processes.
Soils of Mt. Sago have lower soil pH (5.46) and smaller cation exchange capacity (CEC = 16.5 cmolc kg-1) compared to soils from the other three mountains. On the other hand, soils of Mt. Marapi have higher pH (6.05) and larger CEC (19.8 cmolc kg-1). Linear discriminant analysis revealed that the major geochemical elements in
volcanic paddy soils can be ascribed to the different volcanic origin. The results of Mahalanobis distance
statistics clearly separated soils of Mt. Sago with the other four soils. Soils from Mt. Marapi were also dissimilar
with the other three soils, while soils from Mt. Singgalang-Tandikek and Maninjau were more related. Clear
differentiation among weathering indices was also observed. Soils of Mt. Sago again showed higher weathering
stages when evaluated using indices with immobile elements (Al2O3, Fe2O3, TiO2 and Zr). The following
sequence of the degree of weathering can be concluded: Sago &amp;gt; Maninjau &amp;gt; Marapi &amp;gt; Singgalang-Tandikek.
Soil analysis using FTIR revealed that labile aliphatic (CeH) compounds were the dominant organic matter
fractions in these soils with abundances between 64 and 77%. Soils with total C less than 2% tend to be
dominated by aromatic fractions, while soils greater than 2% C are dominated by the more labile aliphatic
fractions. In conclusion, although the soils have been cultivated with paddy for hundreds of years, they still
retain distinct geochemical signatures that can be revealed using a portable XRF.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/05/IndonFinger&quot;&gt;NEW PAPER! Geochemical Fingerprinting of volcanic soils in West Sumatra, Indonesia&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on May 16, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/05/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2017/05/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2017-05-11T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-05-11T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2017-15&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2017 #15&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bioaccumulation-and-toxicity-of-lead-influenced-by-edaphic-factors-using-earthworms-to-study-the-effect-of-pb-on-ecological-health&quot;&gt;Bioaccumulation and toxicity of lead, influenced by edaphic factors: using earthworms to study the effect of Pb on ecological health&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Wijayawardena, MAA; Megharaj, M; Naidu, R&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF SOILS AND SEDIMENTS&lt;/em&gt;, 17 (4):1064-1072; APR 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Lead (Pb) is a highly studied contaminant with no known biological
function that causes harmful adverse effects on ecological and human
health. We tried to evaluate how protective the current soil regulatory
levels are for Pb towards safeguarding the ecological health. In order
to achieve this, our study evaluated the effect of soil texture and pH
on the toxicity and availability of lead to earthworms in soils varying
in soil properties.The earthworm Eisenia fetida was exposed to Pb in
three soils with different physico-chemical characteristics. Pb
solutions were homogenously mixed with soil to obtain concentrations
ranging from 0 to 10,000 mg/kg Pb dry soil. Avoidance behaviour, weight
loss and mortality were measured in this study to calculate the EC50 and
LC50 values.Weight loss and mortality in earthworms due to Pb toxicity
were in the following order: acidic &amp;gt; neutral &amp;gt; alkaline soil. The EC50
values resulting in 50% decrease in worm weight over control for Pb in
acidic, neutral and alkaline soils were 460, 3606 and 5753 mg/kg soil,
respectively. Thus, the acidic soil recorded an EC50 well below the soil
guideline value for Pb. Whereas, the LC50 values resulting in 50%
mortality in worms over control were 1161, 4648 and 7851 mg/kg,
respectively, for acidic, neutral and alkaline soils. The Pb
concentrations in earthworms ranged from 0.2 to 740 mg/kg wet weight.
Soils with low clay content and acidic to neutral pH values demonstrated
an increased Pb toxicity in earthworms compared to the soils with
alkaline pH.The worm weight loss is a more sensitive parameter than the
mortality. This study emphasizes that the soil regulatory levels for Pb
are not protective of worms in acidic soils. Therefore, care should be
taken when using the current regulatory limits to assess and predict the
safety of a contaminated site with acidic soils towards the ecological
health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;double-sided-sliding-paraboloid-dssp-a-new-tool-for-preprocessing-gpr-data&quot;&gt;Double-Sided Sliding-Paraboloid (DSSP): A new tool for preprocessing GPR data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Rashed, M; Rashed, EA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;COMPUTERS &amp;amp; GEOSCIENCES&lt;/em&gt;, 102 12-21; MAY 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Background noise in Ground Penetrating Radar (GPR) data is a nagging
problem that degrades the quality of GPR images and increases their
ambiguity. There are several methods adopting different strategies to
remove background noise. In this study, we present the Double-Sided
Sliding-Paraboloid (DSSP) as a new background removal technique.
Experiments conducted on field GPR data show that the proposed DSSP
technique has several advantages over existing background removal
techniques. DSSP removes background noise more efficiently while
preserving first arrivals and other strong horizontal reflections.
Moreover, DSSP introduces no artifacts to GPR data and corrects data for
DC-shift and wow noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;unsupervised-detection-of-topographic-highs-with-arbitrary-basal-shapes-based-on-volume-evolution-of-isocontours&quot;&gt;Unsupervised detection of topographic highs with arbitrary basal shapes based on volume evolution of isocontours&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Panagiotakis, C; Kokinou, E&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;COMPUTERS &amp;amp; GEOSCIENCES&lt;/em&gt;, 102 22-33; MAY 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
In this work, an unsupervised isocontour based segmentation method is
proposed, that is applied on the detection of topographic highs with
arbitrary basal shapes on Digital Elevation Models (DEMs). A series of
isocontour based segmentation maps is computed for decreasing altitude
levels. During this process, the isocontours are gradually merged
providing a topological hierarchy of highs in an inclusion tree
structure. A novel formulation of a topographic high is given taking
into account the volume evolution of an isocontour that starts from the
top of a high and grows, as decreasing the altitude level of isocontour,
until a high of higher altitude is reached. This formulation yields to a
robust unsupervised algorithm that can be sequentially applied. to
automatically recognize and discriminate the topographic highs of a
region according to the inclusion tree without any constraint on basal
shapes. The proposed method is applied on real and synthetic DEMs, in
order to automatically detect the exact shape of complex topographic
highs and some geomorphological based features useful for high
annotations, yielding high performance results, even if the highs are
partially visible in the given DEM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bayesian-modelling-of-dupuytren-disease-by-using-gaussian-copula-graphical-models&quot;&gt;Bayesian modelling of Dupuytren disease by using Gaussian copula graphical models&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Mohammadi, A; Abegaz, F; van den Heuvel, E; Wit, EC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF THE ROYAL STATISTICAL SOCIETY SERIES C-APPLIED STATISTICS&lt;/em&gt;, 66 (3):629-645; APR 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Dupuytren disease is a fibroproliferative disorder with unknown
aetiology that often progresses and eventually can cause permanent
contractures of the fingers affected. We provide a computationally
efficient Bayesian framework to discover potential risk factors and
investigate which fingers are jointly affected. Our Bayesian approach is
based on Gaussian copula graphical models, which provide a way to
discover the underlying conditional independence structure of variables
in multivariate data of mixed types. In particular, we combine the
semiparametric Gaussian copula with extended rank likelihood to analyse
multivariate data of mixed types with arbitrary marginal distributions.
For structural learning, we construct a computationally efficient search
algorithm by using a transdimensional Markov chain Monte Carlo algorithm
based on a birth-death process. In addition, to make our statistical
method easily accessible to other researchers, we have implemented our
method in C++ and provide an interface with R software as an R package
BDgraph, which is freely available from
http://CRAN.R-project.org/package=BDgraph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;life-cycle-assessment-needs-predictive-spatial-modelling-for-biodiversity-and-ecosystem-services&quot;&gt;Life cycle assessment needs predictive spatial modelling for biodiversity and ecosystem services&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Chaplin-Kramer, R; Sim, S; Hamel, P; Bryant, B; Noe, R; Mueller, C;
Rigarlsford, G; Kulak, M; Kowal, V; Sharp, R; Clavreul, J; Price, E;
Polasky, S; Ruckelshaus, M; Daily, G&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;NATURE COMMUNICATIONS&lt;/em&gt;, 8 15065-15065; APR 21 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
International corporations in an increasingly globalized economy exert a
major influence on the planet’s land use and resources through their
product design and material sourcing decisions. Many companies use life
cycle assessment (LCA) to evaluate their sustainability, yet
commonly-used LCA methodologies lack the spatial resolution and
predictive ecological information to reveal key impacts on climate,
water and biodiversity. We present advances for LCA that integrate
spatially explicit modelling of land change and ecosystem services in a
Land-Use Change Improved (LUCI)-LCA. Comparing increased demand for
bioplastics derived from two alternative feedstock-location scenarios
for maize and sugarcane, we find that the LUCI-LCA approach yields
results opposite to those of standard LCA for greenhouse gas emissions
and water consumption, and of different magnitudes for soil erosion and
biodiversity. This approach highlights the importance of including
information about where and how land-use change and related impacts will
occur in supply chain and innovation decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;scoping-for-scale-dependent-relationships-between-proximal-gamma-radiometrics-and-soil-properties&quot;&gt;Scoping for scale-dependent relationships between proximal gamma radiometrics and soil properties&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Holland, JE; Biswas, A; Huang, J; Triantafilis, J&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;CATENA&lt;/em&gt;, 154 40-49; JUL 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Soil varies from location to location as a result of complex
combinations of soil forming factors and processes operating at
different scales and intensities. The scale-dependent variability in
soil properties causes challenges for the characterization and mapping
of soils. With the advent of technologies, proximal sensors such as
gamma radiometrics can characterize soil spatial variability and the
digital mapping of soil properties. In this study we aim to characterize
scale-dependent variability of proximal gamma radiometrics and its
complex relationship with soil properties at different scales using
wavelet transform and wavelet coherency. We measured gamma radio metrics
(gamma-ray potassium (K-40), uranium (U-238), thorium (Th-232) and Total
Count (gamma-TC)) using a hand-held device in the field every 25 m along
a 3.0 km transect. At each point we measured elevation (m) and land use
and collected soil samples to determine key soil properties (electrical
conductivity EC1:5, pH (CaCl2), soil organic carbon (SOC), cation
exchange capacity (CEC), exchangeable potassium (exch. K), and Colwell
P). Wavelet spectra identified significant (P &amp;lt; 0.05) variations at
different scales and locations for both gamma-ray and soil properties.
There were significant localized variations with changes in elevation
and land use also important. In most cases a ‘global’ Pearson
correlation between the gamma-ray and soil properties was not
significant. In contrast, wavelet coherency provided a more powerful
scale-and location-specific relationship between gamma-ray, elevation
and land use with selected soil properties. For example, a strong
correlation (18% of the area was significant) was detected between land
use and soil EC1:5 at all scales (&amp;lt;100-800 m) in a low drainage
depression. This correlation was due to the localized mobilization of
salts and has implications for the identification of saline land. At
large spatial scales (&amp;gt;800 m) there was significant positive
correlations between gamma-TC and SOC (36% by area). At medium scales
(similar to 400 m) there was significant and positive correlations
between K-40 and CEC (23% by area), but only along the first half of the
transect which was underlain with Bushy Creek Granodiorite. These
findings provide an improved understanding of the spatial variability of
gamma-ray-soil relationships. The approach used shows the scope and
significant potential to use wavelet analysis of gamma-soil property
relationships that are scale-specific and would be useful for digital
soil mapping. Moreover, scale-specific spatial information of soil
properties aids understanding of soil formation processes and it
illustrates an approach to improve future soil sampling strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spatial-soil-nutrients-prediction-using-three-supervised-learning-methods-for-assessment-of-land-potentials-in-complex-terrain&quot;&gt;Spatial soil nutrients prediction using three supervised learning methods for assessment of land potentials in complex terrain&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Jeong, GY; Oeverdieck, H; Park, SJ; Huwe, B; Liess, M&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;CATENA&lt;/em&gt;, 154 73-84; JUL 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Mountain soils play an essential role in ecosystem management.
Assessment of land potentials can provide detailed spatial information
particularly concerning nutrient availability. Spatial distributions of
topsoil carbon, nitrogen and available phosphorus in mountain regions
were identified using supervised learning methods, and a functional
landscape analysis was performed in order to determine the spatial soil
fertility pattern for the Soyang Lake watershed in South Korea. Specific
research aims were (1) to identify important predictors; (2) to develop
digital soil maps; (3) to assess land potentials using digital soil
maps.Soil profiles and samples were collected by conditioned Latin
Hypercube Sampling considering operational field constraints such as
accessibility and no-go areas contaminated by landmines as well as
budget limitations. Terrain parameters and different vegetation indices
were derived for the covariates. We compared a generalized additive
model (GAM) to random forest (RF) and support vector regression (SVR).
For the predictor selection, we used the recursive feature elimination
(RFE). A land potential assessment for soil nutrients was conducted
using trimmed k-mean cluster analysis.Results suggested that vegetation
indices have powerful abilities to predict soil nutrients. Using
selected predictors via RFE improved prediction results. RF showed the
best performance. Cluster analysis identified four land potential
classes: fertile, medium and low fertile with an additional class
dominated by high phosphorus and low carbon and nitrogen contents due to
human impact. This study provides an effective approach to map land
potentials for mountain ecosystem management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-uav-acquired-photography-and-structure-from-motion-techniques-for-studying-glacier-landforms-application-to-the-glacial-flutes-at-isfallsglaciaren&quot;&gt;Using UAV acquired photography and structure from motion techniques for studying glacier landforms: application to the glacial flutes at Isfallsglaciaren&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Ely, JC; Graham, C; Barr, ID; Rea, BR; Spagnolo, M; Evans, J&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;EARTH SURFACE PROCESSES AND LANDFORMS&lt;/em&gt;, 42 (6):877-888; MAY 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Glacier and ice sheet retreat exposes freshly deglaciated terrain which
often contains small-scale fragile geomorphological features which could
provide insight into subglacial or submarginal processes. Subaerial
exposure results in potentially rapid landscape modification or even
disappearance of the minor-relief landforms as wind, weather, water and
vegetation impact on the newly exposed surface. Ongoing retreat of many
ice masses means there is a growing opportunity to obtain high
resolution geospatial data from glacier forelands to aid in the
understanding of recent subglacial and submarginal processes. Here we
used an unmanned aerial vehicle to capture close-range aerial
photography of the foreland of Isfallsglaciaren, a small polythermal
glacier situated in Swedish Lapland. An orthophoto and a digital
elevation model with similar to 2cm horizontal resolution were created
from this photography using structure from motion software. These
geospatial data was used to create a geomorphological map of the
foreland, documenting moraines, fans, channels and flutes. The
unprecedented resolution of the data enabled us to derive morphological
metrics (length, width and relief) of the smallest flutes, which is not
possible with other data products normally used for glacial landform
metrics mapping. The map and flute metrics compare well with previous
studies, highlighting the potential of this technique for rapidly
documenting glacier foreland geomorphology at an unprecedented scale and
resolution. The vast majority of flutes were found to have an associated
stoss-side boulder, with the remainder having a likely explanation for
boulder absence (burial or erosion). Furthermore, the size of this
boulder was found to strongly correlate with the width and relief of the
lee-side flute. This is consistent with the lee-side cavity infill model
of flute formation. Whether this model is applicable to all flutes, or
multiple mechanisms are required, awaits further study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;modeling-reference-evapotranspiration-using-extreme-learning-machine-and-generalized-regression-neural-network-only-with-temperature-data&quot;&gt;Modeling reference evapotranspiration using extreme learning machine and generalized regression neural network only with temperature data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Feng, Y; Peng, Y; Cui, NB; Gong, DZ; Zhang, KD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;COMPUTERS AND ELECTRONICS IN AGRICULTURE&lt;/em&gt;, 136 71-78; APR 15 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Accurate estimation of reference evapotranspiration (ET0) is essential
to agricultural water management. The present study developed two
artificial intelligence models for daily ET0 estimation only with
temperature data, including extreme learning machine (ELM) and
generalized regression neural network (GRNN) in 6 meteorological
stations of Sichuan basin, southwest China, and compared the proposed
ELM and GRNN with the corresponding temperature-based Hargreaves (HG)
model and its calibrated version considering FAO-56 Penman-Monteith ET0
as benchmark. Two data management scenarios were evaluated for
estimation of ET0: (1) the models were trained/calibrated and tested
using the local data of each station; and (2) the models were
trained/calibrated using the pooled data from all the stations and
tested in each station. In the first scenario, the results showed that
the temperature-based ELM model provided the better estimation than the
GRNN, HG and calibrated HG models, with average relative root mean
square error (RRMSE) of 0.198, mean absolute error (MAE) of 0.267 mmid
and Nash-Sutcliffe coefficient (NS) of 0.891, respectively. In the
second scenario, GRNN model provided the most accurate results among the
considered models, with average RRMSE of 0.194, MAE of 0.263 mm/d and NS
of 0.895, respectively. Both of the temperature-based GRNN and ELM
performed much better than the HG and calibrated HG models for the two
scenarios, and the temperature-based GRNN and ELM models are appropriate
alternatives for accurate estimation of ET0 for Sichuan basin of
southwest China, which is very helpful for farmers or irrigation system
operators to improve their irrigation scheduling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;webxtreme-r-based-web-tool-for-calculating-agroclimatic-indices-of-extreme-events&quot;&gt;webXTREME: R-based web tool for calculating agroclimatic indices of extreme events&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Klein, T; Samourkasidis, A; Athanasiadis, IN; Bellocchi, G; Calanca, P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;COMPUTERS AND ELECTRONICS IN AGRICULTURE&lt;/em&gt;, 136 111-116; APR 15 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
We document the release of webXTREME, a new online tool for the
evaluation of indices of climatic extremes (extreme temperatures and
aridity) having impact on agricultural production. The tool is globally
available and can be operated with either observed weather data or time
series representing future climatic conditions. It is thus suitable for
risk evaluation under climate change. webXTREME was implemented using
Shiny, an open-source programming framework for creating web
applications on the basis of the R Statistical Language&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-case-for-increasing-the-statistical-power-of-eddy-covariance-ecosystem-studies-why-where-and-how&quot;&gt;The case for increasing the statistical power of eddy covariance ecosystem studies: why, where and how?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Hill, T; Chocholek, M; Clement, R&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 23 (6):2154-2165; JUN 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Eddy covariance (EC) continues to provide invaluable insights into the
dynamics of Earth’s surface processes. However, despite its many
strengths, spatial replication of EC at the ecosystem scale is rare.
High equipment costs are likely to be partially responsible. This
contributes to the low sampling, and even lower replication, of
ecoregions in Africa, Oceania (excluding Australia) and South America.
The level of replication matters as it directly affects statistical
power. While the ergodicity of turbulence and temporal replication allow
an EC tower to provide statistically robust flux estimates for its
footprint, these principles do not extend to larger ecosystem scales.
Despite the challenge of spatially replicating EC, it is clearly of
interest to be able to use EC to provide statistically robust flux
estimates for larger areas. We ask: How much spatial replication of EC
is required for statistical confidence in our flux estimates of an
ecosystem? We provide the reader with tools to estimate the number of EC
towers needed to achieve a given statistical power. We show that for a
typical ecosystem, around four EC towers are needed to have 95%
statistical confidence that the annual flux of an ecosystem is nonzero.
Furthermore, if the true flux is small relative to instrument noise and
spatial variability, the number of towers needed can rise dramatically.
We discuss approaches for improving statistical power and describe one
solution: an inexpensive EC system that could help by making spatial
replication more affordable. However, we note that diverting limited
resources from other key measurements in order to allow spatial
replication may not be optimal, and a balance needs to be struck. While
individual EC towers are well suited to providing fluxes from the flux
footprint, we emphasize that spatial replication is essential for
statistically robust fluxes if a wider ecosystem is being studied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;global-changes-in-soil-stocks-of-carbon-nitrogen-phosphorus-and-sulphur-as-influenced-by-long-term-agricultural-production&quot;&gt;Global changes in soil stocks of carbon, nitrogen, phosphorus, and sulphur as influenced by long-term agricultural production&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Kopittke, PM; Dalal, RC; Finn, D; Menzies, NW&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 23 (6):2509-2519; JUN 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Quantifying changes in stocks of C, N, P, and S in agricultural soils is
important not only for managing these soils sustainably as required to
feed a growing human population, but for C and N, they are also
important for understanding fluxes of greenhouse gases from the soil
environment. In a global meta-analysis, 102 studies were examined to
investigate changes in soil stocks of organic C, total N, total P, and
total S associated with long-term land-use changes. Conversion of native
vegetation to cropping resulted in substantial losses of C (-1.6 kg
m(-2), -43%), N (-0.15 kg m(-2), -42%), P (-0.029 kg m(-2), -27%), and S
(-0.015 kg m(-2), -33%). The subsequent conversion of conventional
cropping systems to no-till, organic agriculture, or organic amendment
systems subsequently increased stocks, but the magnitude of this
increase (average of +0.47 kg m(-2) for C and +0.051 kg m(-2) for N) was
small relative to the initial decrease. We also examined the conversion
of native vegetation to pasture, with changes in C (-11%), N (+4.1%),
and P (+25%) generally being modest relative to changes caused by
conversion to cropping. The C: N ratio remained relatively constant
irrespective of changes in land use, whilst in contrast, the C: S ratio
decreased by 21% in soils converted to cropping - this suggesting that
biochemical mineralization is of importance for S. The data presented
here will assist in the assessment of different agricultural production
systems on soil stocks of C, N, P, and S -this information assisting not
only in quantifying the effects of existing agricultural production on
these stocks, but also allowing for informed decision-making regarding
the potential effects of future land-use changes.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/05/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on May 11, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/05/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2017/05/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2017-05-04T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-05-04T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2017-14&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2017 #14&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;improving-the-mapping-of-crop-types-in-the-midwestern-us-by-fusing-landsat-and-modis-satellite-data&quot;&gt;Improving the mapping of crop types in the Midwestern US by fusing Landsat and MODIS satellite data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Zhu, LK; Radeloff, VC; Ives, AR&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF APPLIED EARTH OBSERVATION AND GEOINFORMATION&lt;/em&gt;, 58 1-11; JUN 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Mapping crop types is of great importance for assessing agricultural
production, land-use patterns, and the environmental effects of
agriculture. Indeed, both radiometric and spatial resolution of
Landsat’s sensors images are optimized for cropland monitoring. However,
accurate mapping of crop types requires frequent cloud-free images
during the growing season, which are often not available, and this
raises the question of whether Landsat data can be combined with data
from other satellites. Here, our goal is to evaluate to what degree
fusing Landsat with MODIS Nadir Bidirectional Reflectance Distribution
Function (BRDF)-Adjusted Reflectance (NBAR) data can improve crop-type
classification. Choosing either one or two images from all cloud-free
Landsat observations available for the Arlington Agricultural Research
Station area in Wisconsin from 2010 to 2014, we generated 87
combinations of images, and used each combination as input into the
Spatial and Temporal Adaptive Reflectance Fusion Model (STARFM)
algorithm to predict Landsat-like images at the nominal dates of each
8-day MODIS NBAR product. Both the original Landsat and STARFM-predicted
images were then classified with a support vector machine (SVM), and we
compared the classification errors of three scenarios: 1) classifying
the one or two original Landsat images of each combination only, 2)
classifying the one or two original Landsat images plus all
STARFM-predicted images, and 3) classifying the one or two original
Landsat images together with STARFM-predicted images for key dates. Our
results indicated that using two Landsat images as the input of STARFM
did not significantly improve the STARFM predictions compared to using
only one, and predictions using Landsat images between July and August
as input were most accurate. Including all STARFM-predicted images
together with the Landsat images significantly increased average
classification error by 4% points (from 21% to 25%) compared to using
only Landsat images. However, incorporating only STARFM-predicted images
for key dates decreased average classification error by 2% points (from
21% to 19%) compared to using only Landsat images. In particular, if
only a single Landsat image was available, adding STARFM predictions for
key dates significantly decreased the average classification error by 4
percentage points from 30% to 26% (p &amp;lt; 0.05). We conclude that adding
STARFM-predicted images can be effective for improving crop-type
classification when only limited Landsat observations are available, but
carefully selecting images from a full set of STARFM predictions is
crucial. We developed an approach to identify the optimal subsets of all
STARFM predictions, which gives an alternative method of feature
selection for future research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-changing-pore-size-distribution-of-swelling-and-shrinking-soil-revealed-by-nuclear-magnetic-resonance-relaxometry&quot;&gt;The changing pore size distribution of swelling and shrinking soil revealed by nuclear magnetic resonance relaxometry&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Shi, FG; Zhang, CZ; Zhang, JB; Zhang, XN; Yao, J&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF SOILS AND SEDIMENTS&lt;/em&gt;, 17 (1):61-69; JAN 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Purpose Determining soil pore size distribution is difficult and
time-consuming using traditional methods. Additionally, for swelling and
shrinking soil, the specific volume of soil changes with soil moisture
conditions. Nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) relaxometry allows
observation of pore size distribution changes during the process of
dehydration and soil shrinkage.Materials and methods Naturally
structured soil cores of a Vertisol with characteristic swelling and
shrinking behavior were collected from the Huang-Huai-Hai Plain of
China. The samples were saturated with water and dehydrated gradually at
room temperature and relaxometry tests conducted at different moisture
contents as they air-dried. Then, the soil cores were oven-dried at 105
degrees C and saturated with n-octane, which prevented clay swelling.
The pore size distribution of soil cores at the end of the shrinking
process was determined through the description of n-octane-filled pores.
The shrinkage characteristic curves were determined as naturally
structured soil cores were air-dried from moisture content at full
expansion to constant volume, indicating the relationship between the
volume of bulk soil and moisture content.Results and discussion The
transverse relaxation time (T-2) distribution deduced from NMR
relaxometry gives a good description of the size distribution of pores
filled with protons (contained in water or n-octane). The T-2
distribution curves of soil cores at saturation were trimodal, due to
the presence of interlayer, interparticular, and interaggregate pores.
Combined with the shrinkage characteristic curves, it was deduced that
the structural pores were evacuated during the structural shrinkage
period. The normal and residual shrinkage was accompanied by the
narrowing and closure of the interlayer spaces. During the residual
shrinkage period, the frame structure of the soil particles prevented
further shrinkage of the bulk soil. The shrinkage process was
accompanied by the closure of interlayer spaces and the formation of
large cracks between aggregates.Conclusions H-1 NMR relaxometry was
especially suited to studying the changing pore size distribution of
swelling and shrinking soils. When the soil cores began shrinking,
almost all remaining water was retained in interlayer spaces. The volume
change of the interlayer space was the main cause of swelling and
shrinking. The swelling limit could be estimated from the T-2
distributions of soils at full expansion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;assessing-sampling-designs-for-determining-fertilizer-practice-from-yield-data&quot;&gt;Assessing sampling designs for determining fertilizer practice from yield data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Muhammed, SE; Marchant, BP; Webster, R; Whitmore, AP; Dailey, G; Milne,
AE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;COMPUTERS AND ELECTRONICS IN AGRICULTURE&lt;/em&gt;, 135 163-174; APR 1 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Many farmers sample their soil to measure the concentrations of plant
nutrients, so as to decide how much fertilizer to apply. Now that
fertilizer can be applied at variable rates farmers want to know whether
maps of nutrient concentration made from grid samples or of field
subdivisions (zones within their fields) are merited: do such maps lead
to greater profit than would a single measurement on a bulked sample for
each field when all costs are taken into account? We have examined the
merits of grid-based and zone-based sampling strategies over single
field-based averages using continuous spatial data on wheat yields at
harvest in six fields in southern England and simulated concentrations
of phosphorus (P) in the soil. We have taken into account current prices
of wheat, P fertilizer and sampling and laboratory analysis. Variograms
of yield provide guides for sampling. We show that where variograms have
large variances and long effective ranges grid-sampling and mapping are
feasible and have large probabilities of being cost-effective. Where
effective ranges are short, sampling must be dense to reveal the spatial
variation and be expensive, and variable-rate application of fertilizer
is likely to be impracticable and almost certainly not cost-effective.
We found zone-based sampling was less likely to be cost effective in a
similar situation when the management zones were poorly correlated to P
concentrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;modelling-the-passive-microwave-signature-from-land-surfaces-a-review-of-recent-results-and-application-to-the-l-band-smos--smap-soil-moisture-retrieval-algorithms&quot;&gt;Modelling the passive microwave signature from land surfaces: A review of recent results and application to the L-band SMOS &amp;amp; SMAP soil moisture retrieval algorithms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Wigneron, JP; Jackson, TJ; O’Neill, P; De Lannoy, G; de Rosnay, P;
Walker, JP; Ferrazzoli, P; Mironov, V; Bircher, S; Grant, JP; Kurum, M;
Schwank, M; Munoz-Sabater, J; Das, N; Royer, A; Al-Yaari, A; Al Bitar,
A; Fernandez-Moran, R; Lawrence, H; Mialon, A; Parrens, M; Richaume, P;
Delwart, S; Kerr, Y&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT&lt;/em&gt;, 192 238-262; APR 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Two passive microwave missions are currently operating at L-band to
monitor surface soil moisture (SM) over continental surfaces. The SMOS
sensor, based on an innovative interferometric technology enabling
multi-angular signatures of surfaces to be measured, was launched in
November 2009. The SMAP sensor, based on a large mesh reflector 6 m in
diameter providing a conically scanning antenna beam with a surface
incidence angle of 40, was launched in January of 2015. Over the last
decade, an intense scientific activity has focused on the development of
the SM retrieval algorithms for the two missions. This activity has
relied on many field (mainly tower-based) and airborne experimental
campaigns, and since 2010-2011, on the SMOS and Aquarius space-borne
L-band observations. It has relied too on the use of numerical, physical
and semi-empirical models to simulate the microwave brightness
temperature of natural scenes for a variety of scenarios in terms of
system configurations (polarization, incidence angle) and soil,
vegetation and climate conditions. Key components of the inversion
models have been evaluated and new parameterizations of the effects of
the surface temperature, soil roughness, soil permittivity, and
vegetation extinction and scattering have been developed. Among others,
global maps of select radiative transfer parameters have been estimated
very recently. Based on this intense activity, improvements of the SMOS
and SMAP SM inversion algorithms have been proposed. Some of them have
already been implemented, whereas others are currently being
investigated. In this paper, we present a review of the significant
progress which has been made over the last decade in this field of
research with a focus on L-band, and a discussion on possible
applications to the SMOS and SMAP soil moisture retrieval approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;water-retention-and-preferential-states-of-soil-moisture-in-a-cultivated-vertisol&quot;&gt;Water Retention and Preferential States of Soil Moisture in a Cultivated Vertisol&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Vanderlinden, K; Pachepsky, YA; Pederera-Parrilla, A; Martnez, G;
Espejo-Perez, AJ; Perea, F; Giraldez, JV&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;SOIL SCIENCE SOCIETY OF AMERICA JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, 81 (1):1-9; JAN-FEB 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Vertisols are well suited for rainfed agriculture in water-limited
environments as a result of their unique water transfer and retention
characteristics. Despite their importance, the agro-hydrological
behavior of these soils under seasonally dry climates is not yet fully
understood. We collected water retention data for a Vertisol, measured
from saturation to oven dryness on 27 undisturbed topsoil (0-0.05 m)
samples from an experimental field in southcentral Spain and related
this information to the occurrence of field-observed preferential soil
moisture states. A continuous function was fitted to the mean
gravimetric water retention data, circle minus, consisting of the sum of
a double exponential model and the Groenevelt and Grant model. An
inflection point at pressure head |h| = 1.1 X 10(5) cm, circle minus =
0.12 kg kg(- 1), and an equivalent pore radius, delta = 14 nm, was
interpreted as the boundary between the clay inter-and intra-aggregate
pore spaces, corresponding with the transition from the intermediate to
the dry field soil moisture state. The mode of the textural pore space
(|h| = 7.3 X 10(3) cm, circle minus = 0.21 kg kg(- 1), and delta = 200
nm) matched the transition from the wet to the intermediate field soil
moisture state. We related these characteristics of the soil water
retention curve with the spatiotemporal soil moisture dynamics and
patterns observed in the field, characterized by fast transitions
between preferential soil moisture states. The proposed framework is
suitable for comparing the effects of different soil management
strategies on the agro-hydrological performance of Vertisols.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/05/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on May 04, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/05/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2017/05/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2017-05-03T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-05-03T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2017-13&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2017 #13&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-like-bodies-on-mars&quot;&gt;Soil-like bodies on Mars&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Targulian, VO; Mergelov, NS; Goryachkin, SV&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;EURASIAN SOIL SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, 50 (2):185-197; FEB 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Soils sensu stricto are absent on Mars; most probably, they have never
been formed there, because, up to now, we have no evidence of the
presence of life, either relict or recent, on this planet. Numerous
references to “Martian soils” in scientific literature concern loose
substrates rather than Dokuchaev’s soils. In this context, surface
bodies on Mars can be described using the concept of planetary shells,
or exons. Exons can be subdivided into sitons formed via in situ
transformation of parent material, transons formed in the course of
lateral transportation and deposition of substances, and transsitons
formed by the combination of both in situ and lateral processes. Among
Martian exons, transons predominate. They represent loose sediments of
mainly eolian genesis related to extremely strong winds. Soil-like
bodies (soloids) on Mars are represented by sitons and transsitons.
These are abiotic formations having the profiles differentiated by the
contents of iron oxides, soluble salts, and clay minerals and mainly
formed in the presence of liquid water during the paleohumid eras of
Mars evolution more than 2.5/3 billion years ago. True deep sitons
(Martian weathering mantles) could only be formed under the impact of
long-term weathering on stable surfaces during humid eras. Then, they
were either buried by later deposited sediments, or eroded. Up to now,
such objects have not been discovered on Mars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;short-range-variation-in-a-wisconsin-soilscape-usa&quot;&gt;Short-range variation in a Wisconsin soilscape (USA)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Hartemink, AE; Gennadiyev, AN; Bockheim, JG; Bero, N&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;EURASIAN SOIL SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, 50 (2):198-209; FEB 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Here we report on the variation of a soilscape in south central
Wisconsin, USA. The variation in soil properties and soil features
results in four soil order (Entisols, Inceptisols, Alfisols and
Mollisols). Observations were made along a 200 m transect in a field
that was cultivated since 1870. Slopes ranged from 7.5% on the back
slope to 0% in the lower part. The soilscape had a total relief
difference of 7.0 m. The soils were studied by 41 soil pits (60 cm), 6
soil pits (125 cm), 15 soil augers (100 cm), and ground-penetrating
radar imagery. The summit and shoulder consist of coarse glacial outwash
(loamy sands) over limestone whereas the lower part is lacustrine
sediments over coarse outwash (loams, silty loams). The A-horizon
thickness ranged from 14 to 52 cm with thick A horizons at the toeslope
that also had the lowest soil pH. The soil organic carbon (SOC) contents
of the A horizons ranged from 11.6 to 46.9 g C kg(-1), and the higher
contents are in the lower part of the soilscape. SOC stocks (0-20 cm
depth) ranged from 50 to 70 Mg C ha(-1) on the summit and backslope, but
were 80 to 95 Mg C ha(-1) in the flat part of the soilscape. The lowest
soybean yields (1.6 Mg ha(-1)) were found at the summit and the highest
yield (6.3 Mg ha(-1)) at the lower end of the backslope. Soybean yields
were correlated to the thickness of the A horizon, and every 10 cm
increase in A horizon thickness yielded an extra 0.6 Mg soybeans ha(-1).
Analysis of spherical magnetic particles was used to estimate soil
erosion rates that were highest on the backslope (16.2 Mg ha(-1) yr(-1))
and rates of soil deposition in the lowest part of the soilscape was
18.8 Mg ha(P1) yr(-1). It seems that there is no net soil and SOC loss
within this soilscape. All in all, we found 4 soil taxonomic orders
within 200 m. The variation in this soilscape was substantial and
probably enhanced by 140 years of cultivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dust-outpaces-bedrock-in-nutrient-supply-to-montane-forest-ecosystems&quot;&gt;Dust outpaces bedrock in nutrient supply to montane forest ecosystems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Aciego, SM; Riebe, CS; Hart, SC; Blakowski, MA; Carey, CJ; Aarons, SM;
Dove, NC; Botthoff, JK; Sims, KWW; Aronson, EL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;NATURE COMMUNICATIONS&lt;/em&gt;, 8 14800-14800; MAR 28 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Dust provides ecosystem-sustaining nutrients to landscapes underlain by
intensively weathered soils. Here we show that dust may also be crucial
in montane forest ecosystems, dominating nutrient budgets despite
continuous replacement of depleted soils with fresh bedrock via erosion.
Strontium and neodymium isotopes in modern dust show that Asian sources
contribute 18-45% of dust deposition across our Sierra Nevada,
California study sites. The remaining dust originates regionally from
the nearby Central Valley. Measured dust fluxes are greater than or
equal to modern erosional outputs from hillslopes to channels, and
account for 10-20% of estimated millennial-average inputs of bedrock P.
Our results demonstrate that exogenic dust can drive the evolution of
nutrient budgets in montane ecosystems, with implications for predicting
forest response to changes in climate and land use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;potential-of-satellite-derived-ecosystem-functional-attributes-to-anticipate-species-range-shifts&quot;&gt;Potential of satellite-derived ecosystem functional attributes to anticipate species range shifts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Alcaraz-Segura, D; Lomba, A; Sousa-Silva, R; Nieto-Lugilde, D; Alves, P;
Georges, D; Vicente, JR; Honrado, JP&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF APPLIED EARTH OBSERVATION AND GEOINFORMATION&lt;/em&gt;, 57 86-92; MAY 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
In a world facing rapid environmental changes, anticipating their
impacts on biodiversity is of utmost relevance. Remotely-sensed
Ecosystem Functional Attributes (EFAs) are promising predictors for
Species Distribution Models (SDMs) by offering an early and integrative
response of vegetation performance to environmental drivers. Species of
high conservation concern would benefit the most from a better ability
to anticipate changes in habitat suitability. Here we illustrate how
yearly projections from SDMs based on EFAs could reveal short-term
changes in potential habitat suitability, anticipating mid-term shifts
predicted by climate-change-scenario models. We fitted two sets of SDM5
for 41 plant species of conservation concern in the Iberian Peninsula:
one calibrated with climate variables for baseline conditions and
projected under two climate-change-scenarios (future conditions); and
the other calibrated with EFAs for 2001 and projected annually from 2001
to 2013. Range shifts predicted by climate-based models for future
conditions were compared to the 2001-2013 trends from EFAs-based models.
Projections of EFAs-based models estimated changes (mostly contractions)
in habitat suitability that anticipated, for the majority (up to 64%) of
species, the mid-term shifts projected by traditional climate-change
scenario forecasting, and showed greater agreement with the
business-as-usual scenario than with the sustainable-development one.
This study shows how satellite-derived EFAs can be used as meaningful
essential biodiversity variables in SDM5 to provide early-warnings of
range shifts and predictions of short-term fluctuations in suitable
conditions for multiple species.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;laws-place-history-and-the-interpretation-of-landforms&quot;&gt;Laws, place, history and the interpretation of landforms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Phillips, JD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;EARTH SURFACE PROCESSES AND LANDFORMS&lt;/em&gt;, 42 (2):347-354; FEB 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The state of an Earth surface system (ESS) is determined by three sets
of factors: laws, place, and history. Laws (L=L-1, L-2, . . . , L-n) are
the n general principles applicable to any such system at any time.
Place factors (P=P1,P2,. . . , P-m) are the m relevant characteristics
of the local or regional environment. History factors (H=H-1, H-2, . . .
, H-q) include the previous evolutionary pathway of the ESS, its stage
of development, past disturbance, and initial conditions. Geoscience
investigation may focus on laws, place, or history, but ultimately all
three are necessary to understand and explain ESS. The LPH triad is
useful as a pedagogical device, illustrated here via application to
explaining the world’s longest cave (Mammoth Cave, KY). Beyond providing
a useful checklist, the LPH framework provides analytical traction to
some difficult research problems. For example, studies of the avulsions
of three southeast Texas rivers showed substantial differences in
avulsion regimes and resulting alluvial morphology, despite the
proximity and superficial similarity of the systems. Avulsions are
governed by the same laws in all cases [L(A)=L(B)=L(C)], and the three
rivers have undergone the same sea-level, climate, and tectonic
histories, as well as the same general anthropic impacts
[H(A)approximate to H(B)approximate to H(C)]. Though regional
environmental controls are similar, local details such as the location
of the modern main channel relative to Pleistocene meander channels
differ, and thus these place factors explain the differences between the
rivers. The LPH framework, or similar types of reasoning, is implicit in
many types of geoscience analysis. Explicit attention to the triad can
help solve or address many specific problems and remind us of the
importance of all three sets of factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;open-hardware-portable-dual-probe-heat-pulse-sensor-for-measuring-soil-thermal-properties-and-water-content&quot;&gt;Open hardware portable dual-probe heat-pulse sensor for measuring soil thermal properties and water content&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Ravazzani, G&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;COMPUTERS AND ELECTRONICS IN AGRICULTURE&lt;/em&gt;, 133 9-14; FEB 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
A portable probe based on open hardware architecture for the assessment
of soil thermal properties and water content using the DPHP method is
presented. The mean percentage errors for assessment of volumetric heat
capacity and thermal conductivity were 4.6% and 8.9% respectively,
computed after sensor spacing calibration in agar stabilized water. The
DPHP probe has been tested for soil thermal properties assessment and
compared to TDR probe for the water content estimation in four different
soils.The DPHP probe showed an accuracy comparable to TDR in estimating
water content, with DPHP showing lower values of error index in 3
samples out of 4. The DPHP can be used to investigate smaller volume of
soil than TDR probe can do however, TDR is much faster than DPHP in
measure acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-microbes-and-their-response-to-experimental-warming-over-time-a-meta-analysis-of-field-studies&quot;&gt;Soil microbes and their response to experimental warming over time: A meta-analysis of field studies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Romero-Olivares, AL; Allison, SD; Treseder, KK&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;SOIL BIOLOGY &amp;amp; BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, 107 32-40; APR 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Numerous field studies have found changes in soil respiration and
microbial abundance under experimental warming. Yet, it is uncertain
whether the magnitude of these responses remains consistent over the
long-term. We performed a meta-analysis on 25 field experiments to
examine how warming effects on soil respiration, microbial biomass, and
soil microbial C respond to the duration of warming. For each parameter,
we hypothesized that effect sizes of warming would diminish as the
duration of warming increased. In support of our hypothesis, warming
initially increased soil respiration, but the magnitude of this effect
declined significantly as warming progressed as evidenced by the two
longest studies in our meta-analysis. In fact, after 10 years of
warming, soil respiration in warmed treatments was similar to controls.
In contrast, warming effect sizes for fungal biomass, bacterial biomass,
and soil microbial C did not respond significantly to the duration of
warming. Microbial acclimation, community shifts, adaptation, or
reductions in labile C may have ameliorated warming effects on soil
respiration in the longterm. Accordingly, long-term soil C losses might
be smaller than those suggested by short-term warming studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;climate-trends-account-for-stalled-wheat-yields-in-australia-since-1990&quot;&gt;Climate trends account for stalled wheat yields in Australia since 1990&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Hochman, Z; Gobbett, DL; Horan, H&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 23 (5):2071-2081; MAY 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Global food security requires that grain yields continue to increase to
2050, yet yields have stalled in many developed countries. This
disturbing trend has so far been only partially explained. Here, we show
that wheat yields in Australia have stalled since 1990 and investigate
the extent to which climate trends account for this observation. Based
on simulation of 50 sites with quality weather data, that are
representative of the agro-ecological zones and of soil types in the
grain zone, we show that water-limited yield potential declined by 27%
over a 26 year period from 1990 to 2015. We attribute this decline to
reduced rainfall and to rising temperatures while the positive effect of
elevated atmospheric CO2 concentrations prevented a further 4% loss
relative to 1990 yields. Closer investigation of three sites revealed
the nature of the simulated response of water-limited yield to water
availability, water stress and maximum temperatures. At all three sites,
maximum temperature hastened time from sowing to flowering and to
maturity and reduced grain number per m 2 and average weight per grain.
This 27% climate-driven decline in water-limited yield is not fully
expressed in actual national yields. This is due to an unprecedented
rate of technology-driven gains closing the gap between actual and
water-limited potential yields by 25 kg ha(-1) yr(-1) enabling relative
yields to increase from 39% in 1990 to 55% in 2015. It remains to be
seen whether technology can continue to maintain current yields, let
alone increase them to those required by 2050.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-sensitivity-of-soil-respiration-to-soil-temperature-moisture-and-carbon-supply-at-the-global-scale&quot;&gt;The sensitivity of soil respiration to soil temperature, moisture, and carbon supply at the global scale&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Hursh, A; Ballantyne, A; Cooper, L; Maneta, M; Kimball, J; Watts, J&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 23 (5):2090-2103; MAY 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Soil respiration (Rs) is a major pathway by which fixed carbon in the
biosphere is returned to the atmosphere, yet there are limits to our
ability to predict respiration rates using environmental drivers at the
global scale. While temperature, moisture, carbon supply, and other site
characteristics are known to regulate soil respiration rates at plot
scales within certain biomes, quantitative frameworks for evaluating the
relative importance of these factors across different biomes and at the
global scale require tests of the relationships between field estimates
and global climatic data. This study evaluates the factors driving Rs at
the global scale by linking global datasets of soil moisture, soil
temperature, primary productivity, and soil carbon estimates with
observations of annual Rs from the Global Soil Respiration Database
(SRDB). We find that calibrating models with parabolic soil moisture
functions can improve predictive power over similar models with
asymptotic functions of mean annual precipitation. Soil temperature is
comparable with previously reported air temperature observations used in
predicting Rs and is the dominant driver of Rs in global models;
however, within certain biomes soil moisture and soil carbon emerge as
dominant predictors of Rs. We identify regions where typical
temperature-driven responses are further mediated by soil moisture,
precipitation, and carbon supply and regions in which environmental
controls on high Rs values are difficult to ascertain due to limited
field data. Because soil moisture integrates temperature and
precipitation dynamics, it can more directly constrain the heterotrophic
component of Rs, but global-scale models tend to smooth its spatial
heterogeneity by aggregating factors that increase moisture variability
within and across biomes. We compare statistical and mechanistic models
that provide independent estimates of global Rs ranging from 83 to 108
Pg yr(-1), but also highlight regions of uncertainty where more
observations are required or environmental controls are hard to
constrain.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/05/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on May 03, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/04/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2017/04/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2017-04-21T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-04-21T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2017-12&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2017 #12&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;state-and-transition-models-in-geomorphology&quot;&gt;State-and-transition models in geomorphology&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Phillips, JD; Van Dyke, C&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;CATENA&lt;/em&gt;, 153 168-181; JUN 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
State-and-transition models (STM) are used to describe, model,
interpret, and predict when landscapes will undergo a qualitative state
change. Although rangeland ecologists pioneered STMs, geomorphological
STM-type models were developed prior to and independently of ecological
STMs. This study categorized 47 geomorphological STMs according to
whether they were: based on single or multiple study areas; primarily
for description and interpretation or predictive and prescriptive use;
explicitly concerned with complex system dynamics; and the role of
biogeomorphic interactions in the model. Each STM was represented as a
graph and the structure identified. Spectral radii were calculated to
measure the complexity of each STM. Although STMs are associated with
conceptual frameworks that recognize the possibility of nonequilibrium,
alternative states, and path dependency, results show that an explicit
concern with complexity does not necessarily lead to the identification
of more states and transitions, or a more complex transition pattern.
The purpose for which a STM was created, as well as the number of study
sites it can be applied to, also had little bearing on the models’
complexity. This review suggests that geomorphic STMs, rather than being
used to fit explanations about landscape evolution into predefined
theoretical categories, are veridical representations of empirical
observations. Although STMs are particularly useful for grasping the
biogeomorphological dynamics of landscapes, this review indicates their
utility is not limited to biogeomorphology or to systems with a strong
ecological imprint. Time scales involved in geomorphic change can make
it difficult to observe a large number of states and transitions, which
may constrain what types of STM structure can be identified, as the
number of observed states and transitions required to develop particular
graph structures varies widely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-reference-library-of-thermal-infrared-mineral-reflectance-spectra-for-the-hylogger-3-drill-core-logging-system&quot;&gt;A reference library of thermal infrared mineral reflectance spectra for the HyLogger-3 drill core logging system&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Schodlok, MC; Green, A; Huntington, J&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;AUSTRALIAN JOURNAL OF EARTH SCIENCES&lt;/em&gt;, 63 (8):941-949; 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
A new reference library of thermal infrared spectral reflectance
measurements of the major rock-forming and alteration minerals has been
compiled to support and enhance analysis of data acquired using the
CSIRO HyLogger-3 drill-core logging system. The HyLogger-3 is a robotic
system that acquires large volumes of bidirectional reflectance spectra
from diamond drill core within the wavelength range of visible light,
the near infrared and shortwave infrared (400-2500 nm) as well as the
thermal infrared from 6000 to 14 000 nm. The library samples were
selected as single pure solid mineral crystals or monomineralic hand
samples judged to have a similar bidirectional spectral response to that
of typical diamond drill cores. Furthermore, a large number of
individual mineral samples were chosen to cover the various natural
spectral variations within single mineral groups such as, for example, a
range of solid solutions of plagioclase. Owing to the bidirectional
measurement geometry of the HyLogger-3, spectral variations caused by
crystal orientation effects are also expected. Accordingly, reflectance
measurements were made for multiple surfaces/facets of each sample, and
also for orthogonal orientations of the plane of incidence illumination
for each facet measured. All measured spectra were compared with
existing library spectra or with spectra measured from validated samples
to judge whether the mineral samples could be regarded as pure and,
where possible, their chemical composition and mineralogy were validated
by X-ray fluorescence and X-ray diffraction. For quality control, all
such relevant metadata, including macroscopic descriptions of each
sample, were collated in an associated database. In total, the spectral
library contains more than 2000 spectra, from 562 specimens,
representing 130 mineral groups. This library focuses on the most common
rock-forming minerals of relevance to metalliferous exploration and
mining, with a few limitations resulting from availability of suitable
samples, which will be addressed as new samples become available.
Comparisons with emission spectra from existing spectral libraries show
good agreement, indicating that this spectral library will also be
useful in the remote sensing domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;statistical-distributions-for-monthly-aggregations-of-precipitation-and-streamflow-in-drought-indicator-applications&quot;&gt;Statistical distributions for monthly aggregations of precipitation and streamflow in drought indicator applications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Svensson, C; Hannaford, J; Prosdocimi, I&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;WATER RESOURCES RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, 53 (2):999-1018; FEB 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Drought indicators are used as triggers for action and so are the
foundation of drought monitoring and early warning. The computation of
drought indicators like the standardized precipitation index (SPI) and
standardized streamflow index (SSI) require a statistical probability
distribution to be fitted to the observed data. Both precipitation and
streamflow have a lower bound at zero, and their empirical distributions
tend to have positive skewness. For deriving the SPI, the Gamma
distribution has therefore often been a natural choice. The concept of
the SSI is newer and there is no consensus regarding distribution. In
the present study, twelve different probability distributions are fitted
to streamflow and catchment average precipitation for four durations (1,
3, 6, and 12 months), for 121 catchments throughout the UK. The more
flexible three- and four-parameter distributions generally do not have a
lower bound at zero, and hence may attach some probability to values
below zero. As a result, there is a censoring of the possible values of
the calculated SPIs and SSIs. This can be avoided by using one of the
bounded distributions, such as the reasonably flexible three-parameter
Tweedie distribution, which has a lower bound (and potentially mass) at
zero. The Tweedie distribution has only recently been applied to
precipitation data, and only for a few sites. We find it fits both
precipitation and streamflow data nearly as well as the best of the
traditionally used three-parameter distributions, and should improve the
accuracy of drought indices used for monitoring and early warning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-carbon-sequestration-potential-in-semi-arid-grasslands-in-the-conservation-reserve-program&quot;&gt;Soil carbon sequestration potential in semi-arid grasslands in the Conservation Reserve Program&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Li, C; Fultz, LM; Moore-Kucera, J; Acosta-Martinez, V; Horita, J;
Strauss, R; Zak, J; Calderon, F; Weindorf, D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GEODERMA&lt;/em&gt;, 294 80-90; MAY 15 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The Conservation Reserve Program (CRP) in the USA plays a major role in
carbon (C) sequestration to help mitigate rising CO2 levels and climate
change. The Southern High Plains (SHP) region contains &amp;gt;900.000 ha
enrolled in CRP, but a regionally specific C sequestration rate has not
been studied, and identification of the C pools and processes important
in controlling C sequestration rates remain unresolved. We aimed to
address these gaps by utilizing a CRP chronosequence with historical
rangeland as a reference ecosystem. Soil samples (0-10 and 10-30 cm)
were collected in 2012 and 2014 from a total of 26 fields across seven
counties within the SHP and included seven croplands (0 y in CRP), 16
CRP fields that ranged from 6 to 26 y (as of 2012), plus three
rangelands. Multiple regression analysis was conducted to gauge the rate
of C sequestration under CRP within C pools: soil organic C (SOC),
particulate organic matter C (POM-C), and microbial biomass C (MBC),
with two additional predictors (soil clay + silt content and
precipitation). Despite attempts to control for soil texture by
targeting a dominant soil series (Amarillo fine sandy loam), the percent
of clay + silt (15.2-48.7%) significantly influenced C accrual. The C
sources (C-3 from previous cropping systems or C-4 from CRP grasses) in
SOC and POMC were assessed using stable C isotope signatures.
Additionally, the role of soil microbes in C sequestration was evaluated
by investigating the relationship between MBC and CO2 flux and C
sequestration. SOC increased at a rate of 69.82 and 132.87 kg C ha(-1)
y(-1) and would take approximately 74 and 77 y to reach the rangeland C
stocks at 0-10 and 0-30 cm, respectively. The C-4-C primarily from the
introduced grasses was the main source of C sequestration. SOC gains
were essentially due to increases in POM-C and MBC, accounting for 50.04
and 15.64% of SOC sequestration at 0-30 cm, respectively. The highest
semi-partial correlation coefficients between the increasing years under
CRP restoration and MBC indicated CRP had the strongest effect on MBC
compared to other C pools. In addition, increasing soil CO2 flux and
MBC:SOC ratio with years of CRP restoration indicated MBC played a
critical role in the C sequestration process. Conservation of CRP lands
and efforts to sustain perennial systems in this highly erodible
landscape should be a high priority of conservation programs. In doing
so, significant offsets to increasing atmospheric CO2 levels may be
achieved in addition to erosion control and improved wildlife habitat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evaluation-of-two-methods-to-eliminate-the-effect-of-water-from-soil-vis-nir-spectra-for-predictions-of-organic-carbon&quot;&gt;Evaluation of two methods to eliminate the effect of water from soil vis-NIR spectra for predictions of organic carbon&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Roudier, P; Hedley, CB; Lobsey, CR; Rossel, RAV; Leroux, C&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GEODERMA&lt;/em&gt;, 296 98-107; JUN 15 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Visible near infrared reflectance spectroscopy (vis-NIR) is an
increasingly popular measurement method that can provide cheaper and
faster predictions of soil properties, including soil organic carbon
content (SOC). The spectroscopic prediction method relies significantly
on the development of regressions of data in spectral databases or
libraries. While the vis-NIR estimation of SOC was developed in
controlled laboratory conditions, its natural development in recent
years has been to perform the vis-NIR measurements in situ, where soil
spectra are recorded under field conditions. However, environmental
factors, such as soil moisture content, have been shown to affect soil
spectra, making the use of regressions derived using soil spectral
libraries difficult. Direct standardization (DS) and external parameter
orthogonalisation (EPO) are two methods that were proposed for the
correction of variable moisture conditions and other environmental
factors. In this study, we compared DS and EPO on a set of 150 soil
samples (3 depths from each of 50 soil cores) from a farm in New
Zealand. The samples were re-wetted under controlled conditions, and
spectra were recorded at nine different moisture levels. Our results
show that DS and EPO are two effective strategies to mitigate the
effects of soil water content on vis-NIR spectra. While DS and EPO
results were similar when a large number of soil cores were reserved for
calibrating the moisture correction methods, SOC predictions using the
EPO correction significantly outperformed those using the DS correction
for a lower number of cores (5 cores, 15 samples).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-color-sensor-data-collection-using-a-gps-enabled-smartphone-application&quot;&gt;Soil color sensor data collection using a GPS-enabled smartphone application&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Stiglitz, R; Mikhailova, E; Post, C; Schlautman, M; Sharp, J; Pargas, R;
Glover, B; Mooney, J&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GEODERMA&lt;/em&gt;, 296 108-114; JUN 15 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Application of accurate and low-cost sensor technology to collect soil
color data provides an opportunity to increase the density, quality and
quantity of soil data to monitor our changing soil resources. The
objective of this study was to develop a mobile application that would
enable users to create their own soils database consisting of GPS
location and soil color data gathered using the application and a mobile
sensor. A mobile application was created utilizing the Nix(Tm) Pro color
sensor that produces multiple color results, including Munsell color
notation. The application also allows users to toggle between “in-field”
sampling as well as dry or moist soil samples. Users can choose to
record GPS location and a photo of the soil sample to upload into an
online database for storage. The application was tested for
functionality in the field and for its ability to match Munsell notation
values determined using a Munsell Soil Color Chart (MSCC). Field data
were synchronized to a cloud database and subsequently retrieved and
used to produce a Geographic Information Systems (GIS) layout showing
sample point locations and soil color attributes. The Soil Scanner
application allows for rapid analysis and collection of soils data that
can be stored for further study and reference using various color
systems and location data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;relationship-between-soil-clay-mineralogy-and-carbon-protection-capacity-as-influenced-by-temperature-and-moisture&quot;&gt;Relationship between soil clay mineralogy and carbon protection capacity as influenced by temperature and moisture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Singh, M; Sarkar, B; Biswas, B; Bolan, NS; Churchman, GJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;SOIL BIOLOGY &amp;amp; BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, 109 95-106; JUN 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Environmental conditions like temperature and moisture could affect the
carbon protection capacity of various clay types in soils. Using
dominantly kaolinitic-illitic, smectitic and allophanic soils, we
conducted systematic incubation experiments over 42 days at different
temperatures (4, 22 and 37 degrees C) and moisture contents (30, 60 and
90% of water holding capacity (available water)). The basal respiration
was monitored to study the relative effect of moisture contents and
temperature on the carbon protection capacities and mechanisms of the
three clay types. The results indicated that carbon decomposition
increased with increasing moisture and temperature. A two-component
quadratic equation could explain the carbon mineralisation process. The
highest C respiration was observed at 37 degrees C with a 60% moisture
level in each of the soil types. Under these conditions, the smectitic
soil recorded the highest carbon decomposition followed by the
kaolinitic-illitic and allophanic soils. The study of the priming effect
using C-14 lab-died malic acid confirmed the trend of the bulk
respiration results. The allophanic soil showed the lowest amount of
carbon mineralisation under all experimental conditions. A strong
inverse correlation (R-2 = 0.90 at p &amp;lt; 0.05) was observed between CO2
emission rate and total sesquioxides (Fe and Al oxides) content. As
evidenced by the pore size distribution, micromorphologies and
thermogravimetric analyses, the microporous structure and micrbaggregate
formation in the allophanic soil enhanced carbon sequestration. This
study indicated that soil carbon stabilisation was related more to the
sesquioxides content than to the clay types or their relative specific
surface areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;measuring-functional-pedodiversity-using-spectroscopic-information&quot;&gt;Measuring functional pedodiversity using spectroscopic information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0341816217300127&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Fajardo, MP; McBratney, AB; Minasny, B&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;CATENA&lt;/em&gt;, 152 103-114; MAY 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Pedodiversity studies greatly depend on the discretization of the soil
continuum via various soil classification standards. Soil taxonomic
systems are constructed considering soil properties and their
organization in the soil profile. Therefore, it seems logical that the
pedodiversity of an area could be calculated by considering the
simultaneous variation of multiple soil properties within that area.
With the aim of creating a bridge between these two lines of thinking,
this study presents the development of two new indices of pedodiversity
(HULLdiv and EIGENdiv) which consider continuous variables as input. The
soil input information tested was a) Visible and Near Infrared (Vis-NIR)
reflectance values and b) values of five soil properties predicted from
Vis-NIR spectra. Both indices were employed to measure the pedodiversity
at different extents in two perpendicular transects containing 27 (North
to South) and 22 (East to West) locations respectively in New South
Wales (NSW), Australia. Each location considered natural and intervened
land Use. The indices successfully represented the pedodiversity of the
area of study, however they were different depending on the input soil
information i.e., raw Vis-NIR and predicted properties. HULLdiv was
affected by extreme soil observations and as a result its discrimination
power between areas with different soil diversity was inferior. On the
other hand, EIGENdiv represented well the pedodiversity of an area,
despite the extreme observations. The results showed good agreement with
conventional methods for assessing pedodiversity i.e., Shannon’s and
Simpson’s indices. However, the new indices were more discriminating by
being able to better represent the landuse effect. This study represents
the first attempt to measure pedodiversity in a continuous way using
Vis-NIR information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-comparison-of-soil-quality-evaluation-methods-for-fluvisol-along-the-lower-yellow-river&quot;&gt;A comparison of soil quality evaluation methods for Fluvisol along the lower Yellow River&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Guo, LL; Sun, ZG; Ouyang, Z; Han, DR; Li, FD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;CATENA&lt;/em&gt;, 152 135-143; MAY 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Soil quality evaluation as a decision-making tool to improve
understanding of soil quality is essential for grading croplands and
adopting proper agricultural practices. Various methods of soil quality
evaluation have been developed, which have Occasionally generated
inconsistent evaluation results between differing soil types. The
applicability of these techniques is seldom tested before implementing
an evaluation method on a specific soil region. Fluvisol is an important
soil resource for agriculture in China, especially for irrigation
districts along the lower Yellow River. In the present study, the soil
quality of two typical agricultural counties (Yucheng and Kenli) along
the lower Yellow River was evaluated using four commonly utilized
methods. In the two counties, the overall spatial patterns of soil
quality derived from the four methods were similar, with differences in
details existing among these methods. The soil quality in Yucheng,
ranging from moderate to high, is superior to that observed in Kenli,
where salinity is the primary limiting factor. In addition, the
applicability of soil quality evaluation methods on the Fluvisol was
investigated. It was found that the integrated quality indexing-linear
scoring (IQI-LS) and the Nemoro indexing-Linear scoring (NQI-LS) methods
were the most accurate and practical of the four methods studied. These
methods, which are based on the total data set of indicators, show
better performance for soil quality evaluation on a Fluvisol. Further,
different evaluation methods based on the Minimum data set of indicators
were compared, considering both the accuracy of the evaluation and the
economic cost of obtaining the soil data. The results from the present
study indicate that the IQI-LS method based on the minimum data set of
indictors is recommended for large-scale soil quality evaluations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-microbes-and-their-response-to-experimental-warming-over-time-a-meta-analysis-of-field-studies&quot;&gt;Soil microbes and their response to experimental warming over time: A meta-analysis of field studies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Romero-Olivares, AL; Allison, SD; Treseder, KK&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;SOIL BIOLOGY &amp;amp; BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, 107 32-40; APR 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Numerous field studies have found changes in soil respiration and
microbial abundance under experimental warming. Yet, it is uncertain
whether the magnitude of these responses remains consistent over the
long-term. We performed a meta-analysis on 25 field experiments to
examine how warming effects on soil respiration, microbial biomass, and
soil microbial C respond to the duration of warming. For each parameter,
we hypothesized that effect sizes of warming would diminish as the
duration of warming increased. In support of our hypothesis, warming
initially increased soil respiration, but the magnitude of this effect
declined significantly as warming progressed as evidenced by the two
longest studies in our meta-analysis. In fact, after 10 years of
warming, soil respiration in warmed treatments was similar to controls.
In contrast, warming effect sizes for fungal biomass, bacterial biomass,
and soil microbial C did not respond significantly to the duration of
warming. Microbial acclimation, community shifts, adaptation, or
reductions in labile C may have ameliorated warming effects on soil
respiration in the longterm. Accordingly, long-term soil C losses might
be smaller than those suggested by short-term warming studies&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/04/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on April 21, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/04/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2017/04/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2017-04-03T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-04-19T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2017-11&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2017 #11&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;automated-detection-of-geological-landforms-on-mars-using-convolutional-neural-networks&quot;&gt;Automated detection of geological landforms on Mars using Convolutional Neural Networks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0098300416305532&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Palafox, LF; Hamilton, CW; Scheidt, SP; Alvarez, AM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;COMPUTERS &amp;amp; GEOSCIENCES&lt;/em&gt;, 101 48-56; APR 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The large volume of high-resolution images acquired by the Mars
Reconnaissance Orbiter has opened a new frontier for developing
automated approaches to detecting landforms on the surface of Mars.
However, most landform classifiers focus on crater detection, which
represents only one of many geological landforms of scientific interest.
In this work, we use Convolutional Neural Networks (ConvNets) to detect
both volcanic rootless cones and transverse aeolian ridges. Our system,
named MarsNet, consists of five networks, each of which is trained to
detect landforms of different sizes. We compare our detection algorithm
with a widely used method for image recognition, Support Vector Machines
(SVMs) using Histogram of Oriented Gradients (HOG) features. We show
that ConvNets can detect a wide range of landforms and has better
accuracy and recall in testing data than traditional classifiers based
on SVMs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;modeling-soil-processes-review-key-challenges-and-new-perspectives&quot;&gt;Modeling Soil Processes: Review, Key Challenges, and New Perspectives&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vzj.geoscienceworld.org/content/15/5/vzj2015.09.0131&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Vereecken, H; Schnepf, A; Hopmans, JW; Javaux, M; Or, D; Roose, DOT;
Vanderborght, J; Young, MH; Amelung, W; Aitkenhead, M; Allison, SD;
Assouline, S; Baveye, P; Berli, M; Bruggemann, N; Finke, P; Flury, M;
Gaiser, T; Govers, G; Ghezzehei, T; Hallett, P; Franssen, HJH; Heppell,
J; Horn, R; Huisman, JA; Jacques, D; Jonard, F; Kollet, S; Lafolie, F;
Lamorski, K; Leitner, D; McBratney, A; Minasny, B; Montzka, C; Nowak, W;
Pachepsky, Y; Padarian, J; Romano, N; Roth, K; Rothfuss, Y; Rowe, EC;
Schwen, A; Simunek, J; Tiktak, A; Van Dam, J; van der Zee, SEATM; Vogel,
HJ; Vrugt, JA; Wohling, T; Young, IM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;VADOSE ZONE JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, 15 (5):NIL_32-NIL_88; MAY 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The remarkable complexity of soil and its importance to a wide range of
ecosystem services presents major challenges to the modeling of soil
processes. Although major progress in soil models has occurred in the
last decades, models of soil processes remain disjointed between
disciplines or ecosystem services, with considerable uncertainty
remaining in the quality of predictions and several challenges that
remain yet to be addressed. First, there is a need to improve exchange
of knowledge and experience among the different disciplines in soil
science and to reach out to other Earth science communities. Second, the
community needs to develop a new generation of soil models based on a
systemic approach comprising relevant physical, chemical, and biological
processes to address critical knowledge gaps in our understanding of
soil processes and their interactions. Overcoming these challenges will
facilitate exchanges between soil modeling and climate, plant, and
social science modeling communities. It will allow us to contribute to
preserve and improve our assessment of ecosystem services and advance
our understanding of climate-change feedback mechanisms, among others,
thereby facilitating and strengthening communication among scientific
disciplines and society. We review the role of modeling soil processes
in quantifying key soil processes that shape ecosystem services, with a
focus on provisioning and regulating services. We then identify key
challenges in modeling soil processes, including the systematic
incorporation of heterogeneity and uncertainty, the integration of data
and models, and strategies for effective integration of knowledge on
physical, chemical, and biological soil processes. We discuss how the
soil modeling community could best interface with modern modeling
activities in other disciplines, such as climate, ecology, and plant
research, and how to weave novel observation and measurement techniques
into soil models. We propose the establishment of an international soil
modeling consortium to coherently advance soil modeling activities and
foster communication with other Earth science disciplines. Such a
consortium should promote soil modeling platforms and data repository
for model development, calibration and intercomparison essential for
addressing contemporary challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-consistent-ecosystem-services-valuation-method-based-on-total-economic-value-and-equivalent-value-factors-a-case-study-in-the-sanjiang-plain-northeast-china&quot;&gt;A consistent ecosystem services valuation method based on Total Economic Value and Equivalent Value Factors: A case study in the Sanjiang Plain, Northeast China&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1476945X16301131&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Zhang, L; Yu, X; Jiang, M; Xue, Z; Lu, X; Zou, Y&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;ECOLOGICAL COMPLEXITY&lt;/em&gt;, 29 40-48; MAR 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
In this study, a regional revision coefficient is proposed for the
Equivalent Value Factors to better valuate the Sanjiang Plain (in China)
ecosystem services. An index system suitable for the valuation of the
ecosystem services in the Sanjiang Plain is established. The proposed
method can realize the rapid valuation of nine ecosystem service types
of six different terrestrial ecosystems. Through the preliminary
application of the method, the calculated total value of ecosystem
services of the Sanjiang Plain in 2010 was 510.89 billion yuan, of which
the forest ecosystem contributed to 37.85%, followed by water bodies and
wetland ecosystems. The variations among the contributions of the
different ecosystem services are considerable. The contribution
attributed to regulation function was the highest, especially the value
from the hydrological regulation (36.17%) and climate regulation
(16.04%). The Total Economic Value (TEV) method and the Equivalent Value
Factors (EVF) method are compared in this study. Results show that
Equivalent Value Factors derived value of the Sanjiang Plain ecosystem
services is slightly lower than the value obtained by the Total Economic
Value method, i.e., 537.84 billion yuan, of which the total value of the
Feature Services has reached as high as 38.35 billion yuan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;changing-views-of-nitrous-oxide-emissions-from-agricultural-soil-key-controlling-processes-and-assessment-at-different-spatial-scales&quot;&gt;Changing views of nitrous oxide emissions from agricultural soil: key controlling processes and assessment at different spatial scales&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/ejss.12409/abstract&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Smith, KA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF SOIL SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, 68 (2):137-155; MAR 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Nitrous oxide, N2O, is the third most important of the long-lived
greenhouse gases, in terms of its contribution to global warming, and is
expected to be the dominant cause of stratospheric ozone depletion this
century. The concentration of N2O in the atmosphere was fairly constant
until the beginning of the industrial age, but has gone up by 20% since.
This is because of increased anthropogenic emissions, of which about 60%
come from agricultural soil. The cause is the increased use of synthetic
fertilizer nitrogen globally to meet the demands for increased
production of food and biofuels. This review examines the isotopic
evidence for this role of fertilizer N, the main mechanisms for
microbial production of N2O in soil, the key soil physical and other
variables that greatly affect the magnitude of emissions, and the
spatial and temporal variation in emissions and the associated problems
of measurement. The review also considers the methodology devised by the
Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) to enable countries to
compile national inventories of their emissions, direct and indirect,
that arise from anthropogenic activity related to agriculture and land
use. This methodology also enables modellers to make bottom-up’ global
estimates of N2O emissions. These estimates agree quite well at the
global scale with top-down’ estimates based on the relation between
reactive nitrogen newly introduced into agricultural ecosystems and
increases in the global atmospheric concentration of N2O, but not with
some recent regional-scale emission measurements. The discrepancy may be
related to problems of estimating indirect emissions. Top-down estimates
indicate that N2O emissions from crop-based biofuels are too great to
comply with national and international environmental regulations.
Finally, possible future trends in emissions and possible mitigation
measures are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;are-data-collected-to-support-farm-management-suitable-for-monitoring-soil-indicators-at-the-national-scale&quot;&gt;Are data collected to support farm management suitable for monitoring soil indicators at the national scale?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/ejss.12417/full&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Rawlins, BG; Marchant, B; Stevenson, S; Wilmer, W&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF SOIL SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, 68 (2):235-248; MAR 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Monitoring of topsoil properties (referred to as indicators) at the
national scale has been limited in general to government-funded
representative surveys. We consider a cost-effective complementary
source of soil information for monitoring agricultural soil across
England and Wales (E&amp;amp;W): soil measurements paid for by farmers that we
refer to as farmers’ data (FD). A potential problem in using FD for soil
monitoring is any unattributable sources of bias, such as the sample
design. Farmers may choose to focus their measurements (purposively)
where they perceive a particular problem. Such a source of bias is
avoided in the random sampling adopted by statistically designed
surveys, such as the Countryside Survey (CS2007) and LUCAS (Land
Use/Cover Area frame statistical Survey). We used measurements from 143
000 FD soil samples from a single laboratory to estimate national mean
values and confidence intervals of five topsoil indicators (pH,
available P (Olsen), K, Mg and organic matter (OM)) across three
combinations of nation (England or Wales) and land use (arable and
horticulture (A&amp;amp;H) or improved grassland (IG)). We computed mean
estimates for FD over two time periods (2004-9 and 2010-2105) and
assessed the significance of any change. We compared these estimates
with those from representative national surveys to establish whether
there was evidence for bias and whether it could be explained. Mean
estimates of topsoil pH for the FD and the LUCAS survey (same analytical
method) were consistent for both A&amp;amp;H and IG. Although FD estimates of
mean Olsen P (OP) concentrations were similar to previous surveys, we
show it is likely that the larger mean OP concentrations observed in the
LUCAS survey compared with FD for arable topsoil in England are partly
due to an attributable source of analytical bias. For such quantifiable
sources of bias, it might be possible to adjust estimated mean values
from FD. However, FD might also include sources of unattributable bias,
such as the effect of purposive sampling. It is important that
contemporaneous data from surveys with statistically unbiased designs
are available so that we can assess whether unattributable sources exert
a significant effect over estimates of mean values computed from FD.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/04/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on April 19, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/04/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2017/04/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2017-04-03T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-04-03T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2017-10&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2017 #10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-interactive-image-segmentation-method-for-lithological-boundary-detection-a-rapid-mapping-tool-for-geologists&quot;&gt;An interactive image segmentation method for lithological boundary detection: A rapid mapping tool for geologists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0098300416307579&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Vasuki, Y; Holden, EJ; Kovesi, P; Micklethwaite, S&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;COMPUTERS &amp;amp; GEOSCIENCES&lt;/em&gt;, 100 27-40; MAR 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Large volumes of images are collected by geoscientists using remote
sensing platforms. Manual analysis of these images is a time consuming
task and there is a need for fast and robust image interpretation tools.
In particular the reliable mapping of lithological boundaries is a
critical step for geological interpretation. In this contribution we
developed an interactive image segmentation algorithm that harnesses the
geologist’s input and exploits automated image analysis to provide a
practical tool for Ethology boundary detection, using photographic
images of rock surfaces.In the proposed method, the user is expected to
draw rough markings to indicate the locations of different geological
units in the image. Image segmentation is performed by segmenting
regions based on their homogeneity in colour. This results in a high
density of segmented regions which are then iteratively merged based on
the colour of different geological units and the user input. Finally, a
post-processing step allows the user to edit the boundaries.An
experiment was conducted using photographic rock surface images
collected by a UAV and a handheld digital camera. The proposed technique
was applied to detect lithology boundaries. It was found that the
proposed method reduced the interpretation time by a factor of four
relative to manual segmentation, while achieving more than 96%
similarity in boundary detection. As a result the proposed method has
the potential to provide practical support for interpreting large volume
of complex geological images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-porosity-in-physically-separated-fractions-and-its-role-in-soc-protection&quot;&gt;Soil porosity in physically separated fractions and its role in SOC protection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11368-016-1508-0&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Simonetti, G; Francioso, O; Dal Ferro, N; Nardi, S; Berti, A; Morari, F&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF SOILS AND SEDIMENTS&lt;/em&gt;, 17 (1):70-84; JAN 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Purpose Processes that lead to soil organic carbon (SOC) protection
depend on both soil porosity and structure organization, as well as
chemical and biological properties. In particular, the soil micro-nano
porosity (&amp;lt;30 mu m) regulates microorganism accessibility to the soil
pore system and offers surfaces for organic carbon adsorption and
intercalation into soil minerals. The aim of this work was to
investigate how pore size distribution can selectively protect specific
carbon pools in different aggregate size fractions, by considering the
effects of long-term application of farmyard manure (FYM) and mineral
(Min) fertilization.Materials and methods Macroaggregates (250-2000 mu
m), microaggregates (53-250 mu m), and silt-clay (&amp;lt;53 mu m) fractions of
three different soils (clayey, peaty, and sandy) were separated by wet
sieving technique and then subjected to chemical and physical analysis.
Sample porosity and pore size distribution were analyzed using mercury
intrusion porosimetry (MIP), while SOC chemical structure was
characterized by means of nuclear magnetic resonance (C-13
cross-polarization-magic angle spinning nuclear magnetic reso-nance (CP
MAS C-13 NMR)) and diffuse reflectance infrared Fourier transform
(DRIFT) spectroscopies.Results and discussion Results showed that FYM
increased organic (OC) and humic carbon (HC) content compared to the Min
fertilization and unfertilized soils. However, it caused a gradual
decrease in O,N-alkyl C, and alkyl C of humic C from macroaggregate to
silt-clay fractions, suggesting an advanced state of humic component
degradation as revealed by CP MAS C-13 NMR, DRIFT analyses. MIP analysis
showed a clear increase of micropores (5-30 mu m) and cryptopores
(0.0035-0.1 mu m) from macroaggregate to silt-clay fractions, while
minor differences were observed among the treatments. The application of
principal component analysis to mineral soil fractions identified the
formation of three main clusters, where (i) macroaggregates of clayey
soil were mainly associated to cryptopores and OC and (ii)
microaggregates and silt-clay fraction were mainly isolated by carbonyl
C, ultramicropores, and total porosity. The third cluster was associated
with medium and fine sand of the sand soil fraction as coupled with O,
N-alkyl C, anomeric C, mesopores, and HC/OC ratio.Conclusions Overall,
this study indicates that pore size distribution may be a valuable
indicator of soil capacity to sequester carbon, due to its direct
influence on SOC linkages with soil aggregates and the positive effects
against SOC decomposition phenomena. In this context, micropore- to
nanopore-dominated structures (e.g., clayey soil) were able to protect
OC compounds by interacting with mineral surfaces and intercalation with
phyllosilicates, while meso/macropore-dominated structures (i.e., sandy
soil) exhibited their low ability to protect the organic components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-moisture-remote-sensing-state-of-the-science&quot;&gt;Soil Moisture Remote Sensing: State-of-the-Science&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.sciencesocieties.org/publications/vzj/pdfs/16/1/vzj2016.10.0105&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Mohanty, BP; Cosh, MH; Lakshmi, V; Montzka, C&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;VADOSE ZONE JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, 16 (1):NIL_36-NIL_44; JAN 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
This is an update to the special section “Remote Sensing for Vadose Zone
Hydrology-A Synthesis from the Vantage Point” [Vadose Zone Journal
12(3)]. Satellites (e.g., Soil Moisture Active Passive [SMAP] and Soil
Moisture and Ocean Salinity [SMOS]) using passive microwave techniques,
in particular at L-band frequency, have shown good promise for global
mapping of near-surface (0-5-cm) soil moisture at a spatial resolution
of 25 to 40 km and temporal resolution of 2 to 3 d. C- and X-band soil
moisture records date back to 1978, making available an invaluable data
set for long-term climate research. Near-surface soil moisture is
further extended to the root zone (top 1 m) using process-based models
and data assimilation schemes. Validation of remotely sensed soil
moisture products has been ongoing using core monitoring sites, sparse
monitoring networks, intensive field campaigns, as well as
multi-satellite comparison studies. To transfer empirical observations
across space and time scales and to develop improved retrieval
algorithms at various resolutions, several efforts are underway to
associate soil moisture variability dynamics with land surface
attributes in various energy-and water-rich environments. We describe
the most recent scientific and technological advances in soil moisture
remote sensing. We anticipate that remotely sensed soil moisture will
find many applications in vadose zone hydrology in the coming decades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;senose-an-under-u50-electronic-nose-for-the-monitoring-of-soil-gas-emissions&quot;&gt;SENose: An under U$50 electronic nose for the monitoring of soil gas emissions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0168169916304070&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Pineda, DM; Perez, JC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;COMPUTERS AND ELECTRONICS IN AGRICULTURE&lt;/em&gt;, 133 15-21; FEB 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Tropical soils are major players on CO2 emissions and C cycling on
earth. However, it is in tropical countries where scientists can have
the most limited access to analytical tools needed for research on these
processes. This paper describes the construction and test of a less than
US 50 chamber for monitoring of multiple soil gas emissions. The system
consisted on an array of three MQ series gas sensors placed into an
airtight container, a PIC microcontroller and a custom-built software
developed for data capture and visualization running on a laptop. A
modified multiplexing of sensors was also incorporated in order to allow
the parallel analysis in up to eight samples. The chamber, hereafter
called SENose (short for Soil Electric Nose), was tested in two separate
experiments. The first study used the three sensor array system in soil
samples from Colombia and Ecuador, which were separated into two groups
in order to study their gas emission patterns in D(+) glucose induced
respiration tests. For a second experiment using a multiplexed sensor
array in a different set of Colombian soil samples, gas emission
patterns were obtained from autoclaved soil with reduced microbial
activity, which were further contaminated with diesel oil as C
source.During the first study, in replicated 22 h continuous runs SENose
clearly showed differences in soil respiration patterns of these soil
samples, and a prominent timing differential increase in gas production
after spiking D(+) glucose, a proxy for organic C, as a substrate.
Results of the second study showed a clearly different pattern of gas
emissions in diesel oil contaminated samples, when microbial activity
was reduced by soil autoclaving. Moreover, two groups of non-autoclaved
soil subsamples differing only in diesel oil addition could also be
differentiated with basis on their respiration patterns after some hours
of gas tracking. Based on these results we foresee a great potential
from the use of this low cost system in fields such as soil
microbiology, fertility, biotechnology and environmental sciences, where
processes such as microbial activity, plant nutrient availability or
soil pollutant turnover are tracked by monitoring their gas emission
patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;studying-drought-phenomena-in-the-continental-united-states-in-2011-and-2012-using-various-drought-indices&quot;&gt;Studying drought phenomena in the Continental United States in 2011 and 2012 using various drought indices&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0034425716304813&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Zhang, LF; Jiao, WZ; Zhang, HM; Huang, CP; Tong, QX&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT&lt;/em&gt;, 190 96-106; MAR 1 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Numerous drought indices have been developed to monitor drought
conditions. However, different drought indices have differing
characteristics, and are suitable for specific environments. The aim of
this study was to compare the occurrence of drought, as detected by
remote sensing across the Continental United States (CONUS). We used
drought events during 2011 and 2012 to compare various indices developed
for the study of drought phenomena. Three in situ drought indices, the
Palmer drought severity index (PDSI), Z-index and standardized
precipitation indices (SPI) with different time scales were used to
evaluate drought conditions in different climate divisions. The drought
indices compared in this study include the vegetation condition index
(VCI), the temperature condition index (TCI), the perpendicular drought
index (PDI) and modified PDI (MPDI) derived from moderate-resolution
imaging spectroradiometer (MODIS) data, the precipitation condition
index (PCI) derived from tropical rainfall measuring mission (TRMM)
data, and the soil moisture condition index (SMCI) derived from advanced
microwave scanning radiometer - earth observing system (AMSR-E). Other
synthesized drought indices, which combine indices such as VCI, TCI,
SMCI and PCI, were also compared in this study. These included the
vegetation health index (VHI), temperature vegetation dryness index
(TVDI), scaled drought condition index (SDCI), the microwave integrated
drought index (MIDI), the synthesized drought index (SDI), the optimized
meteorological drought index (OMDI), and the optimized vegetation
drought index (OVDI). The results include a wide variety of drought
conditions based on different drought indices. Meteorological drought
indices indicated that more regions were under severe drought than
agricultural drought indices did. Drought indices appear to be more
similar to standard drought indices than PDI, MPDI and TVDI. The results
also indicate that different indices have strengths and weaknesses in
different climates across CONUS. SMCI has a good correlation with
short-term SPI, and the sensitivity of SMCI is strongly dependent on
terrain, as it performs worse in regions with heavy tree cover than in
regions with a low density of vegetation. TCI, VCI, PDI and MPDI are
more similar to 3-month SPI data, but correlate weakly with
station-based indices located in areas of high precipitation, higher
soil permeability, large-scale agriculture and forests. PCI is more
strongly correlated with short-term drought conditions in almost all
climate divisions than other single indices. VCI would be more reliable
if there were only red and NIR surface reflectance bands available,
while VHI would be a better choice if only NDVI and LST data were
available. Condition index-based drought indices (PCI, TCI, VCI, SMCI,
VHI, SDCI, SDCI, MIDI, OVDI, OMDI) performed better than other
categories of drought indices, and the use of time series analysis may
be a contributing factor to this difference in performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bayesian-updating-of-land-cover-estimates-in-a-data-rich-environment&quot;&gt;Bayesian updating of land-cover estimates in a data-rich environment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0034425716303248&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Cardille, JA; Fortin, JA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT&lt;/em&gt;, 186 234-249; DEC 1 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Since the opening of the Landsat archive, the availability of remote
sensing data has increased dramatically, and algorithms that can
interpret large time series of satellite imagery are in rapid
development as additions to the decades of interpretation of
remotely-sensed images. To date, processing of these massive data
repositories has focused mostly on tracing forest growth and loss across
very large areas within pre-defined study periods. Despite these very
considerable advances, there is a need for methodology that could allow
analysts to use their own specific land-cover categories of interest,
and update existing land-cover classifications either forward or
backward to a desired point in time. Here we demonstrate an algorithm
(Bayesian Updating of Land-Cover, or BULC) developed for the continuous
updating of land-cover classifications through time in large data sets.
The BULC algorithm is designed to permit users to build new
classifications or update existing classifications based on long streams
of imagery, but with minimal storage and memory requirements. The
algorithm ingests a sequence of classified land-cover data for a
user-specified set of detectable classes, and maintains a continually
updated estimate of land-cover probabilities and the most probable class
at all time points along the sequence. We tested this algorithm in
central Quebec with Landsat 8 imagery for summer 2013, when a series of
large fires erupted and burned through forests. In this very dynamic
setting, many of the summer’s images were contaminated by ordinary
standards, yet parts of the region could be seen through the clouds,
smoke, and haze of each image. Across 11 dates of widely varying
quality, BULC tracked the fires, ignored contaminated image information,
and mapped fire borders consistently throughout the summer, autumn, and
subsequent winter and spring. Building on images having a median
accuracy of 78% and 8% NoData, the BULC algorithm created 11 sequenced
land-cover maps each having more than 90% overall accuracy and covering
the entire study area. BULC’s classifications mapped each of the
land-cover categories with user’s and producer’s accuracies that
compared well to the best individual images used as input, while
accurately tracking land-cover change that occurred between those
infrequent clear images. As we leave remote sensing’s data-poor era and
enter a period with many images of Earth’s surface supplied by multiple
sensors over a short period of time, the BULC algorithm may help to sift
through images of varying quality to extract the most useful information
for mapping time series of land-cover classifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comparison-of-remotely-sensed-and-modelled-soil-moisture-data-sets-across-australia&quot;&gt;Comparison of remotely sensed and modelled soil moisture data sets across Australia&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0034425716303583&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Holgate, CM; De Jeu, RAM; van Dijk, AIJM; Liu, YY; Renzullo, LJ;
Vinodkumar; Dharssi, I; Parinussa, RM; Van der Schalie, R; Gevaert, A;
Walker, J; McJannet, D; Cleverly, J; Haverd, V; Trudinger, CM; Briggs,
PR&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT&lt;/em&gt;, 186 479-500; DEC 1 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
This study compared surface soil moisture from 11 separate remote
sensing and modelled products across Australia in a common framework.
The comparison was based on a correlation analysis between soil moisture
products and in situ data collated from three separate ground-based
networks: OzFlux, OzNet and CosmOz. The correlation analysis was
performed using both original data sets and temporal anomalies, and was
supported by examination of the time series plots. The
interrelationships between the products were also explored using cluster
analyses. The products considered in this study include: Soil Moisture
Ocean Salinity (SMOS; both Land Parameter Retrieval Model (LPRM) and
L-band Microwave Emission of the Biosphere (LMEB) algorithms), Advanced
Microwave Scanning Radiometer 2 (AMSR2; both LPRM and Japan Aerospace
Exploration Agency (JAXA) algorithms) and Advanced Scatterometer (ASCAT)
satellite-based products, and WaterDyn, Australian Water Resource
Assessment Landscape (AWRA-L), Antecedent Precipitation Index (API),
Keetch-Byram Drought Index (KBDI), Mount’s Soil Dryness Index (MSDI) and
CABLE/BIOS2 model based products. The comparison of the satellite and
model data sets showed variation in their ability to reflect in situ
soil moisture conditions across Australia owing to individual product
characteristics. The comparison showed the satellite products yielded
similar ranges of correlation coefficients, with the possible exception
of AMSR2 JAXA. SMOS (both algorithms) achieved slightly better agreement
with in situ measurements than the alternative satellite products
overall. Among the models, WaterDyn yielded the highest correlation most
consistently across the different locations and climate zones
considered. All products displayed, a weaker performance in estimating
soil moisture anomalies than the original data sets (i.e. the absolute
values), showing all products to be more effective in detecting
interannual and seasonal soil moisture dynamics rather than individual
events. Using cluster analysis we found satellite products generally
grouped together, whereas models were more similar to other models. SMOS
(based on LMEB algorithm and ascending overpass) and ASCAT (descending
overpass) were found to be very similar to each other in terms of their
temporal soil moisture dynamics, whereas AMSR2 (based on LPRM algorithm
and descending overpass) and AMSR2 (based on JAXA algorithm and
ascending overpass) were dissimilar. Of the model products, WaterDyn and
CABLE were similar to each other, as were the API/AWRA-L and KBDI/MSDI
pairs. The clustering suggests systematic commonalities in error
structure and duplication of information may exist between products.
This evaluation has highlighted relative strengths, weaknesses, and
complementarities between products, so the drawbacks of each may be
minimised through a more informed assessment of fitness for purpose by
end users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;litter-decay-controlled-by-temperature-not-soil-properties-affecting-future-soil-carbon&quot;&gt;Litter decay controlled by temperature, not soil properties, affecting future soil carbon&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/gcb.13502/full&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Gregorich, EG; Janzen, H; Ellert, BH; Helgason, BL; Qian, BD; Zebarth,
BJ; Angers, DA; Beyaert, RP; Drury, CF; Duguid, SD; May, WE; McConkey,
BG; Dyck, MF&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 23 (4):1725-1734; APR 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Widespread global changes, including rising atmospheric CO2
concentrations, climate warming and loss of biodiversity, are predicted
for this century; all of these will affect terrestrial ecosystem
processes like plant litter decomposition. Conversely, increased plant
litter decomposition can have potential carbon-cycle feedbacks on
atmospheric CO2 levels, climate warming and biodiversity. But predicting
litter decomposition is difficult because of many interacting factors
related to the chemical, physical and biological properties of soil, as
well as to climate and agricultural management practices. We applied
C-13-labelled plant litter to soil at ten sites spanning a 3500-km
transect across the agricultural regions of Canada and measured its
decomposition over five years. Despite large differences in soil type
and climatic conditions, we found that the kinetics of litter
decomposition were similar once the effect of temperature had been
removed, indicating no measurable effect of soil properties. A two-pool
exponential decay model expressing undecomposed carbon simply as a
function of thermal time accurately described kinetics of decomposition.
(R-2 = 0.94; RMSE = 0.0508). Soil properties such as texture, cation
exchange capacity, pH and moisture, although very different among sites,
had minimal discernible influence on decomposition kinetics. Using this
kinetic model under different climate change scenarios, we projected
that the time required to decompose 50% of the litter (i.e. the labile
fractions) would be reduced by 1-4 months, whereas time required to
decompose 90% of the litter (including recalcitrant fractions) would be
reduced by 1 year in cooler sites to as much as 2 years in warmer sites.
These findings confirm quantitatively the sensitivity of litter
decomposition to temperature increases and demonstrate how climate
change may constrain future soil carbon storage, an effect apparently
not influenced by soil properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exploratory-assessment-of-aerial-gamma-radiometrics-across-the-conterminous-united-states&quot;&gt;Exploratory Assessment of Aerial Gamma Radiometrics across the Conterminous United States&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.sciencesocieties.org/publications/sssaj/pdfs/81/1/94&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Rouze, GS; Morgan, CLS; McBratney, AB; Neely, HL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;SOIL SCIENCE SOCIETY OF AMERICA JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, 81 (1):94-108; JAN-FEB 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Gamma radiometrics have recently been connected with soil properties at
field scales (10 m) and thus may have potential to characterize soil
across regional scales using data from preexisting aerial surveys.
However, the relationship between gamma radiometrics and soil properties
across these larger spatial extents (100-1000 km) has been largely
unexplored, particularly within the United States. Thus, the overall
purpose of this work was to test the effectiveness of aerial gamma
radiometrics in modeling soil properties across the conterminous United
States. After discovering that up to 19% of aerial gamma radiometric
variability could be explained by variations in physiography and parent
material type, linear regression models were created between soil
properties (clay and sand contents, cation exchange capacity, CaCO3
equivalent, and pH) and aerial gamma dose rate based on physiography and
parent material type. Overall, aerial gamma radiometrics was most
frequently suitable for mapping clay content within flat landscapes of
unconsolidated and sedimentary parent materials. Suitability maps for
all investigated soil properties are presented. The importance of aerial
gamma radiometrics relative to other covariates was then assessed. The
predictive power of aerial g radiometrics, relative to other covariates,
was mixed due to a non-optimized sampling scheme. Results suggest that
aerial gamma radiometrics can be useful in predicting soil properties
across large spatial extents after considering both physiography and
parent material type. However, a true assessment of the utility of
aerial gamma radiometrics across the United States requires a soil
sampling strategy that represents its feature space.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/04/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on April 03, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/03/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2017/03/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2017-03-28T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-03-28T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2017-9&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2017 #9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;greenhouse-gas-emissions-intensity-of-global-croplands&quot;&gt;Greenhouse gas emissions intensity of global croplands&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/nclimate/journal/v7/n1/full/nclimate3158.html&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;
Authors:
Carlson, KM; Gerber, JS; Mueller, ND; Herrero, M; MacDonald, GK;
Brauman, KA; Havlik, P; O’Connell, CS; Johnson, JA; Saatchi, S; West, PC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;NATURE CLIMATE CHANGE&lt;/em&gt;, 7 (1):63-+; JAN 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Stabilizing greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions fromcroplands as agricultural
demand grows is a critical component of climate change mitigation(1-3).
Emissions intensity metrics-including carbon dioxide equivalent
emissions per kilocalorie produced (‘production intensity’)-can
highlight regions, management practices, and crops as potential foci for
mitigation(4-7). Yet the spatial and crop-wise distribution of emissions
intensity has been uncertain. Here, we develop global crop-specific
circa 2000 estimates of GHG emissions and GHG intensity in high spatial
detail, reporting the effects of rice paddy management, peatland
draining, and nitrogen (N) fertilizer on CH4, CO2 and N-2O emissions.
Global mean production intensity is 0.16 Mg CO(2)e M kcal(-1), yet
certain cropping practices contribute disproportionately to emissions.
Peatland drainage (3.7 Mg CO(2)e M kcal(-1))-concentrated in Europe and
Indonesia-accounts for 32% of these cropland emissions despite peatlands
producing just 1.1% of total crop kilocalories. Methane emissions
fromrice (0.58 Mg CO(2)e M kcal(-1)), a crucial food staple supplying
15% of total crop kilocalories, contribute 48% of cropland emissions,
with outsized production intensity in Vietnam. In contrast, N2O
emissions from N fertilizer application (0.033 Mg CO(2)e M kcal(-1))
generate only 20% of cropland emissions. We find that current total GHG
emissions are largely unrelated to production intensity across crops and
countries. Climate mitigation policies should therefore be directed to
locations where crops have both high emissions and high intensities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mitigation-potential-and-global-health-impacts-from-emissions-pricing-of-food-commodities&quot;&gt;Mitigation potential and global health impacts from emissions pricing of food commodities&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/nclimate/journal/v7/n1/full/nclimate3155.html&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Springmann, M; Mason-D’Croz, D; Robinson, S; Wiebe, K; Godfray, HCJ;
Rayner, M; Scarborough, P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;NATURE CLIMATE CHANGE&lt;/em&gt;, 7 (1):69-+; JAN 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The projected rise in food-related greenhouse gas emissions could
seriously impede efforts to limit global warming to acceptable levels.
Despite that, food production and consumption have long been excluded
from climate policies, in part due to concerns about the potential
impact on food security. Using a coupled agriculture and health
modelling framework, we show that the global climate change mitigation
potential of emissions pricing of food commodities could be substantial,
and that levying greenhouse gas taxes on food commodities could, if
appropriately designed, be a health-promoting climate policy in
high-income countries, as well as in most low-and middle-income
countries. Sparing food groups known to be beneficial for health from
taxation, selectively compensating for income losses associated with
tax-related price increases, and using a portion of tax revenues for
health promotion are potential policy options that could help avert most
of the negative health impacts experienced by vulnerable groups, whilst
still promoting changes towards diets which are more environmentally
sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-changing-pore-size-distribution-of-swelling-and-shrinking-soil-revealed-by-nuclear-magnetic-resonance-relaxometry&quot;&gt;The changing pore size distribution of swelling and shrinking soil revealed by nuclear magnetic resonance relaxometry&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11368-016-1511-5&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Shi, FG; Zhang, CZ; Zhang, JB; Zhang, XN; Yao, J&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF SOILS AND SEDIMENTS&lt;/em&gt;, 17 (1):61-69; JAN 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Purpose Determining soil pore size distribution is difficult and
time-consuming using traditional methods. Additionally, for swelling and
shrinking soil, the specific volume of soil changes with soil moisture
conditions. Nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) relaxometry allows
observation of pore size distribution changes during the process of
dehydration and soil shrinkage.Materials and methods Naturally
structured soil cores of a Vertisol with characteristic swelling and
shrinking behavior were collected from the Huang-Huai-Hai Plain of
China. The samples were saturated with water and dehydrated gradually at
room temperature and relaxometry tests conducted at different moisture
contents as they air-dried. Then, the soil cores were oven-dried at 105
degrees C and saturated with n-octane, which prevented clay swelling.
The pore size distribution of soil cores at the end of the shrinking
process was determined through the description of n-octane-filled pores.
The shrinkage characteristic curves were determined as naturally
structured soil cores were air-dried from moisture content at full
expansion to constant volume, indicating the relationship between the
volume of bulk soil and moisture content.Results and discussion The
transverse relaxation time (T-2) distribution deduced from NMR
relaxometry gives a good description of the size distribution of pores
filled with protons (contained in water or n-octane). The T-2
distribution curves of soil cores at saturation were trimodal, due to
the presence of interlayer, interparticular, and interaggregate pores.
Combined with the shrinkage characteristic curves, it was deduced that
the structural pores were evacuated during the structural shrinkage
period. The normal and residual shrinkage was accompanied by the
narrowing and closure of the interlayer spaces. During the residual
shrinkage period, the frame structure of the soil particles prevented
further shrinkage of the bulk soil. The shrinkage process was
accompanied by the closure of interlayer spaces and the formation of
large cracks between aggregates.Conclusions H-1 NMR relaxometry was
especially suited to studying the changing pore size distribution of
swelling and shrinking soils. When the soil cores began shrinking,
almost all remaining water was retained in interlayer spaces. The volume
change of the interlayer space was the main cause of swelling and
shrinking. The swelling limit could be estimated from the T-2
distributions of soils at full expansion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;magnetic-signature-and-source-identification-of-heavy-metal-contamination-in-urban-soils-of-steel-industrial-city-northeast-china&quot;&gt;Magnetic signature and source identification of heavy metal contamination in urban soils of steel industrial city, Northeast China&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11368-016-1522-2&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Zong, YT; Xiao, Q; Lu, SG&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF SOILS AND SEDIMENTS&lt;/em&gt;, 17 (1):190-203; JAN 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Purpose Identifying the spatial distribution and degree of heavy metal
contamination in the soils is required for urban environmental
management. Magnetic measurement provides a rapidmeans of determining
spatial distribution and degree of soil pollution and identifying
various anthropogenic sources of heavy metals. The purpose of this study
was to characterize the magnetic signature of heavy metal contamination
and identify the sources of heavy metals in urban soils from steel
industrial city.Materials and methods A total of 115 urban topsoils from
Anshan city, Northeast China, were collected and determined for magnetic
properties and heavy metal concentration. Magnetic susceptibility (chi
lf) and saturation isothermal remanent magnetization (SIRM) were
determined as proxy for ferrimagnetic mineral concentration. Magnetic
minerals were identified by using Curie temperature, X-ray diffraction
(XRD), and scanning electron microscope (SEM) equipped with an
energy-dispersive X-ray spectrometer (EDS). The Pearson’ correlation and
matrix cluster analyses were used to establish the relationship between
magnetic parameters and heavy metal concentrations.Results and
discussion Urban topsoils exhibit characteristic magnetic enhancement.
The magnetic measurement in particle size fractions indicates that 50-2
mu m fraction has the highest low-field magnetic susceptibility (chi
lf), while &amp;lt; 2 mu m has the highest frequency-dependent magnetic
susceptibility (chi fd) value. The soil.lf and SIRM values are
significantly correlated with the contents of metals (Fe, Pb, Zn, Cu,
and Cr) and Tomlinson pollution load index (PLI), which indicates
that.lf and SIRM could be served as better indicators for the pollution
of heavy metals in the urban topsoil. Spatial distribution maps of.lf,
SIRM, and PLI indicate that the pollution hotspots tend to associate
with the regions within and close to steel industrial zones. XRD and
Curie temperature analyses indicate that the main magnetic minerals of
urban topsoils are magnetite (Fe3O4), hematite (alpha-Fe2O3), and
metallic iron. Magnetic minerals mostly occur in the pseudosingle-
domain/multidomain (PSD/MD) grain size range, which is the dominant
contributor to the magnetic enhancement of topsoils. SEM observation
reveals that magnetic particles in soils exist in irregular-shaped
particles and spherule. Results reveal that heavy metals from
industrially derived and traffic emissions coexist with coarse-grained
magnetic phases.Conclusions It is concluded that the magnetic
measurement could be regarded as a proxy tool to detect the level of
heavy metal pollution and identify the source of heavy metals in urban
soils. Magnetic properties provide a fast and inexpensive method to map
the spatial distribution of long-term pollution from steel industrial
origin on region scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-global-distribution-and-dynamics-of-surface-soil-moisture&quot;&gt;The global distribution and dynamics of surface soil moisture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
McColl, KA; Alemohammad, SH; Akbar, R; Konings, AG; Yueh, S; Entekhabi,
D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;NATURE GEOSCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, 10 (2):100-+; FEB 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Surface soil moisture has a direct impact on food security, human health
and ecosystem function. It also plays a key role in the climate system,
and the development and persistence of extreme weather events such as
droughts, floods and heatwaves. However, sparse and uneven observations
have made it difficult to quantify the global distribution and dynamics
of surface soil moisture. Here we introduce a metric of soil moisture
memory and use a full year of global observations from NASA’s Soil
Moisture Active Passive mission to show that surface soil moisture-a
storage believed to make up less than 0.001% of the global freshwater
budget by volume, and equivalent to an, on average, 8-mm thin layer of
water covering all land surfaces-plays a significant role in the water
cycle. Specifically, we find that surface soil moisture retains a median
14% of precipitation falling on land after three days. Furthermore, the
retained fraction of the surface soil moisture storage after three days
is highest over arid regions, and in regions where drainage to
groundwater storage is lowest. We conclude that lower groundwater
storage in these regions is due not only to lower precipitation, but
also to the complex partitioning of the water cycle by the surface soil
moisture storage layer at the land surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-survey-pedotransfer-function-of-linear-extensibility-percent-for-soils-of-the-united-states&quot;&gt;Soil Survey: Pedotransfer Function of Linear Extensibility Percent for Soils of the United States&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.lww.com/soilsci/Abstract/2017/01000/Soil_Survey___Pedotransfer_Function_of_Linear.1.aspx&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Seybold, CA; Libohova, Z&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;SOIL SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, 182 (1):1-8; JAN 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Soil survey is an ongoing process from initial soil mapping through soil
survey updates. A national model of linear extensibility percent (LEP)
is needed to improve this process. The objective of this work was to
develop and validate models for estimating LEP using general linear
models and readily available soil survey properties. Measured data from
the Kellogg National Soil Survey Laboratory database (Lincoln, Nebraska)
were used to develop the prediction models. Twenty LEP prediction
equations were developed based on pH and major mineralogy classes.
Noncarbonate clay and, depending on the soil pH, either cation-exchange
capacity or effective cation-exchange capacity explained between 42% and
86% of the total variation in LEP. Model equations using cation-exchange
capacity as a predictive variable collectively produced a prediction
root mean square error (RMSEp) of 1.44% and mean error (ME) of -0.16%.
For low pH soils, the model equations using effective cation-exchange
capacity as a predictive variable collectively produced an RMSEp of
1.29% and ME of -0.034%. The small negative MEs indicate an overall
underestimation of LEP. Breaking down the validation results further
among the different mineralogy groups produced a range of RMSEp from
0.42% to 1.80%. The smectitic group had the largest and the siliceous
group had the lowest RMSEp. The prediction accuracy is considered
adequate for soil survey purposes, and it is expected that LEP estimates
will ultimately enhance soil survey interpretations. The models will be
added to the soil survey database for soil scientists to use when
measured data are not available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;land-management-data-availability-and-process-understanding-for-global-change-studies&quot;&gt;Land management: data availability and process understanding for global change studies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/gcb.13443/full&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Erb, KH; Luyssaert, S; Meyfroidt, P; Pongratz, J; Don, A; Kloster, S;
Kuemmerle, T; Fetzel, T; Fuchs, R; Herold, M; Haberl, H; Jones, CD;
Marin-Spiotta, E; McCallum, I; Robertson, E; Seufert, V; Fritz, S;
Valade, A; Wiltshire, A; Dolman, AJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 23 (2):512-533; FEB 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
In the light of daunting global sustainability challenges such as
climate change, biodiversity loss and food security, improving our
understanding of the complex dynamics of the Earth system is crucial.
However, large knowledge gaps related to the effects of land management
persist, in particular those human-induced changes in terrestrial
ecosystems that do not result in land-cover conversions. Here, we review
the current state of knowledge of ten common land management activities
for their biogeochemical and biophysical impacts, the level of process
understanding and data availability. Our review shows that ca. one-tenth
of the ice-free land surface is under intense human management, half
under medium and one-fifth under extensive management. Based on our
review, we cluster these ten management activities into three groups:
(i) management activities for which data sets are available, and for
which a good knowledge base exists (cropland harvest and irrigation);
(ii) management activities for which sufficient knowledge on
biogeochemical and biophysical effects exists but robust global data
sets are lacking (forest harvest, tree species selection, grazing and
mowing harvest, N fertilization); and (iii) land management practices
with severe data gaps concomitant with an unsatisfactory level of
process understanding (crop species selection, artificial wetland
drainage, tillage and fire management and crop residue management, an
element of crop harvest). Although we identify multiple impediments to
progress, we conclude that the current status of process understanding
and data availability is sufficient to advance with incorporating
management in, for example, Earth system or dynamic vegetation models in
order to provide a systematic assessment of their role in the Earth
system. This review contributes to a strategic prioritization of
research efforts across multiple disciplines, including land system
research, ecological research and Earth system modelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;assessing-uncertainties-in-land-cover-projections&quot;&gt;Assessing uncertainties in land cover projections&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/gcb.13447/full&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Alexander, P; Prestele, R; Verburg, PH; Arneth, A; Baranzelli, C; Silva,
FBE; Brown, C; Butler, A; Calvin, K; Dendoncker, N; Doelman, JC;
Dunford, R; Engstrom, K; Eitelberg, D; Fujimori, S; Harrison, PA;
Hasegawa, T; Havlik, P; Holzhauer, S; Humpenoder, F; Jacobs-Crisioni, C;
Jain, AK; Krisztin, T; Kyle, P; Lavalle, C; Lenton, T; Liu, JY;
Meiyappan, P; Popp, A; Powell, T; Sands, RD; Schaldach, R; Stehfest, E;
Steinbuks, J; Tabeau, A; van Meijl, H; Wise, MA; Rounsevell, MDA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 23 (2):767-781; FEB 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Understanding uncertainties in land cover projections is critical to
investigating land-based climate mitigation policies, assessing the
potential of climate adaptation strategies and quantifying the impacts
of land cover change on the climate system. Here, we identify and
quantify uncertainties in global and European land cover projections
over a diverse range of model types and scenarios, extending the
analysis beyond the agro-economic models included in previous
comparisons. The results from 75 simulations over 18 models are analysed
and show a large range in land cover area projections, with the highest
variability occurring in future cropland areas. We demonstrate
systematic differences in land cover areas associated with the
characteristics of the modelling approach, which is at least as great as
the differences attributed to the scenario variations. The results lead
us to conclude that a higher degree of uncertainty exists in land use
projections than currently included in climate or earth system
projections. To account for land use uncertainty, it is recommended to
use a diverse set of models and approaches when assessing the potential
impacts of land cover change on future climate. Additionally, further
work is needed to better understand the assumptions driving land use
model results and reveal the causes of uncertainty in more depth, to
help reduce model uncertainty and improve the projections of land cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;land-use-contrasts-reveal-instability-of-subsoil-organic-carbon&quot;&gt;Land-use contrasts reveal instability of subsoil organic carbon&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/gcb.13379/full&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Hobley, E; Baldock, J; Hua, Q; Wilson, B&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 23 (2):955-965; FEB 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Subsoils contain large amounts of organic carbon which is generally
believed to be highly stable when compared with surface soils. We
investigated subsurface organic carbon storage and dynamics by analysing
organic carbon concentrations, fractions and isotopic values in 78
samples from 12 sites under different land-uses and climates in eastern
Australia. Despite radiocarbon ages of several millennia in subsoils,
contrasting native systems with agriculturally managed systems revealed
that subsurface organic carbon is reactive on decadal timeframes to
land-use change, which leads to large losses of young carbon down the
entire soil profile. Our results indicate that organic carbon storage in
soils is input driven down the whole profile, challenging the concept of
subsoils as a repository of stable organic carbon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;application-of-spectroscopic-techniques-for-monitoring-microbial-diversity-and-bioremediation&quot;&gt;Application of spectroscopic techniques for monitoring microbial diversity and bioremediation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/05704928.2016.1199028&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microbes are the most fascinating group, with huge diversity devising myriad functional applications in the field of medicine, pharmaceuticals, environmental remediation, and industries. Quantitative and qualitative determination of biomolecules and microbial assisted phenomena by spectroscopy is a pioneer approach. It facilitates the study of atomic and molecular geometries, energy levels, chemical bonds, and interactions between molecules and microbes. It produces fingerprints of the microbial species serving to characterize, differentiate, and identify microorganisms, in both the environment and at single-cell level. Spectroscopy-based bioremediation techniques like Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy, mass spectroscopy, force spectroscopy, Raman spectroscopy, photoemission spectroscopy, and laser-induced breakdown spectroscopy have been very well represented and linked with the microbial applications. This review summarizes the traditional spectroscopic techniques used for the study of microbes and microbial-assisted products as well as illustrates its application in the field of microbial diversity and remediation. This will provide an outlook for the intricate characterization and dimension of microbes to be used for effective application in bioremediation.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/03/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on March 28, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/03/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2017/03/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2017-03-16T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-03-16T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2017-8&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2017 #8&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;combining-biodiversity-resurveys-across-regions-to-advance-global-change-research&quot;&gt;Combining Biodiversity Resurveys across Regions to Advance Global Change Research&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/bioscience/article-abstract/67/1/73/2661833/Combining-Biodiversity-Resurveys-across-Regions-to?rss=1&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Verheyen, K; De Frenne, P; Baeten, L; Waller, DM; Hedl, R; Perring, MP;
Blondeel, H; Brunet, J; Chudomelova, M; Decocq, G; De Lombaerde, E;
Depauw, L; Dirnbock, T; Durak, T; Eriksson, O; Gilliam, FS; Heinken, T;
Heinrichs, S; Hermy, M; Jaroszewicz, B; Jenkins, MA; Johnson, SE; Kirby,
KJ; Kopecky, M; Landuyt, D; Lenoir, J; Li, DJ; Macek, M; Maes, SL;
Malis, F; Mitchell, FJG; Naaf, T; Peterken, G; Petrik, P; Reczynska, K;
Rogers, DA; Schei, FH; Schmidt, W; Standovar, T; Swierkosz, K; Ujhazy,
K; Van Calster, H; Vellend, M; Vild, O; Woods, K; Wulf, M;
Bernhardt-Romermann, M&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;BIOSCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, 67 (1):72-82; JAN 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
More and more ecologists have started to resurvey communities sampled in
earlier decades to determine long-term shifts in community composition
and infer the likely drivers of the ecological changes observed.
However, to assess the relative importance of and interactions among
multiple drivers, joint analyses of resurvey data from many regions
spanning large environmental gradients are needed. In this article, we
illustrate how combining resurvey data from multiple regions can
increase the likelihood of driver orthogonality within the design and
show that repeatedly surveying across multiple regions provides higher
representativeness and comprehensiveness, allowing us to answer more
completely a broader range of questions. We provide general guidelines
to aid the implementation of multiregion resurvey databases. In so
doing, we aim to encourage resurvey database development across other
community types and biomes to advance global environmental change
research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-novel-principal-component-analysis-for-spatially-misaligned-multivariate-air-pollution-data&quot;&gt;A novel principal component analysis for spatially misaligned multivariate air pollution data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1509.01171&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Jandarov, RA; Sheppard, LA; Sampson, PD; Szpiro, AA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF THE ROYAL STATISTICAL SOCIETY SERIES C-APPLIED STATISTICS&lt;/em&gt;, 66 (1):3-28; JAN 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
We propose novel methods for predictive (sparse) principal component
analysis with spatially misaligned data. These methods identify
principal component loading vectors that explain as much variability in
the observed data as possible, while also ensuring that the
corresponding principal component scores can be predicted accurately by
means of spatial statistics at locations where air pollution
measurements are not available. This will make it possible to identify
important mixtures of air pollutants and to quantify their health
effects in cohort studies, where currently available methods cannot be
used. We demonstrate the utility of predictive (sparse) principal
component analysis in simulated data and apply the approach to annual
averages of particulate matter speciation data from national
Environmental Protection Agency regulatory monitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-adaptive-spatiotemporal-smoothing-model-for-estimating-trends-and-step-changes-in-disease-risk&quot;&gt;An adaptive spatiotemporal smoothing model for estimating trends and step changes in disease risk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/rssc.12155/abstract&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Rushworth, A; Lee, D; Sarran, C&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF THE ROYAL STATISTICAL SOCIETY SERIES C-APPLIED STATISTICS&lt;/em&gt;, 66 (1):141-157; JAN 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Statistical models used to estimate the spatiotemporal pattern in
disease risk from areal unit data represent the risk surface for each
time period with known covariates and a set of spatially smooth random
effects. The latter act as a proxy for unmeasured spatial confounding,
whose spatial structure is often characterized by a spatially smooth
evolution between some pairs of adjacent areal units whereas other pairs
exhibit large step changes. This spatial heterogeneity is not consistent
with existing global smoothing models, in which partial correlation
exists between all pairs of adjacent spatial random effects. Therefore
we propose a novel space-time disease model with an adaptive spatial
smoothing specification that can identify step changes. The model is
motivated by a new study of respiratory and circulatory disease risk
across the set of local authorities in England and is rigorously tested
by simulation to assess its efficacy. Results from the England study
show that the two diseases have similar spatial patterns in risk and
exhibit some common step changes in the unmeasured component of risk
between neighbouring local authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;humans-have-already-increased-the-risk-of-major-disruptions-to-pacific-rainfall&quot;&gt;Humans have already increased the risk of major disruptions to Pacific rainfall&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms14368&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Power, SB; Delage, FPD; Chung, CTY; Ye, H; Murphy, BF&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;NATURE COMMUNICATIONS&lt;/em&gt;, 8 14368-14368; FEB 8 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Intermittent disruptions to rainfall patterns and intensity over the
Pacific Ocean lasting up to similar to 1 year have major impacts on
severe weather, agricultural production, ecosystems, and disease within
the Pacific, and in many countries beyond. The frequency with which
major disruptions to Pacific rainfall occur has been projected to
increase over the 21st century, in response to global warming caused by
large 21st century greenhouse gas emissions. Here we use the latest
generation of climate models to show that humans may have contributed to
the major disruption that occurred in the real world during the late
20th century. We demonstrate that although marked and sustained
reductions in 21st century anthropogenic greenhouse gas emissions can
greatly moderate the likelihood of major disruption, elevated risk of
occurrence appears locked in now, and for at least the remainder of the
21st century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;implementation-of-a-sigmoid-depth-function-to-describe-change-of-soil-ph-with-depth&quot;&gt;Implementation of a sigmoid depth function to describe change of soil pH with depth&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0016706116308230&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Zhang, YK; Biswas, A; Adamchuk, VI&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GEODERMA&lt;/em&gt;, 289 1-10; MAR 1 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Soil pH controls the availability of the majority of plant nutrients, if
not all, and determines the growth environment for plant roots. Profile
depth functions have been used to represent the vertical distribution of
soil attributes and to predict them at continuous depths. This paper
proposes a new model to predict pH for a whole soil profile. Soil
properties including pH are often similar within the plow layer from
mixing during tillage and other agricultural operations. Similarly, soil
pH below the root zone tends to be uniform due to low disturbance,
leaving a transition zone from the bottom of the tillage layer to the
bottom of the root zone due to depth-dependent root density and related
soil processes. Keeping this physical description of agricultural field
soil profile in mind, a closed form equation (model) was developed
similar to a sigmoid curve. The model has 4 parameters including 1) soil
pH at the top of a soil profile, 2) soil pH at the bottom of a soil
profile, 3) hillslope parameter representing steepness of the curve that
is determined by the length of the root zone, and 4) inflection point
representing almost the midpoint of the transition zone or root zone. A
total of 32 soil cores down to about 1.1 m depths were collected from an
agricultural field of Macdonald farm, McGill University. The sub-samples
were taken at every 10 cm and analyzed for soil pH in soil: water
suspension in the laboratory. The measured pH was used to test the
fitting performance of the sigmoid model. Additionally, a global dataset
with 432 profiles with various soil classes, drainage types, land use,
and altitude was also used to test the generality of the new model. The
performance of this model was compared with the results of the commonly
used 3rd order polynomial regression function and the equal-area
quadratic spline function. Good performance of the sigmoid model with
explicit physical explanation showed promise in predicting soil pH at
depths. The spline function had the highest accuracy but lacked a
general trend in its shape and parameters. The polynomial function had
good accuracy and displayed a non-monotonic trend, which can also be
used as a substitute for some profiles with complex variability. (C)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-nitrogen-cycle-a-review-of-isotope-effects-and-isotope-modeling-approaches&quot;&gt;The nitrogen cycle: A review of isotope effects and isotope modeling approaches&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0038071716305946&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Denk, TRA; Mohn, J; Decock, C; Lewicka-Szczebak, D; Harris, E;
Butterbach-Bahl, K; Kiese, R; Wolf, B&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;SOIL BIOLOGY &amp;amp; BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, 105 121-137; FEB 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The nitrogen (N) cycle involves a set of N compounds transformed by
plants and microbes. Some of these N compounds, such as nitrous oxide
(N2O) or nitrate (No-3(-)), are environmental pollutants jeopardizing
biodiversity, human health or the global climate. The natural abundances
of the common (N-14) and rare (N-15) stable N isotopes in a given
compound, i.e. the isotopic composition, depend on individual production
and consumption processes. As each process has an individual preference
for the common or rare isotope (isotope effect) the measurement of the
isotopic composition has been identified as a powerful tool for improved
process understanding and source process identification. Both are key
requirements for the development of strategies aiming at mitigating the
release of environmental harmful N compounds. However, up to now, no
comprehensive compilation of N cycle isotope effects is available.A
compilation of isotope effects is also in high demand for testing
biogeochemical models as such models are increasingly used to study N
cycling in ecosystems and across landscapes and regions. Biogeochemical
models are usually calibrated and validated only with single, easily
accessible quantities. The isotopic composition of N compounds has a
high potential to be used as additional, integrative parameter for a
more thorough assessment of simulation results. For instance, the
isotopic composition of soil N is determined by fractionation of the
most relevant processes and, thus, integrates several N cycle processes,
some of which cannot be accessed easily by direct measurement. To
implement isotopic fractionation in ecosystem models and to utilize
those for model validation, the magnitude of the isotope effects
associated with individual transformations in the N cycle need to be
assessed.This review summarizes the available methods to determine N
isotope effects of various key ecosystem processes, thereby
systematically comparing isotope effects for different experimental
conditions and processes, exploring the accuracy of theoretical
calculations of isotope effects and finally, addressing concepts to
implement isotope effects into biogeochemical modeling.Our review shows
that published isotope effects for N processes in soil incubations seem
to be stronger as compared to those in water saturated systems. In
addition to the choice of isotope effects adequate for the respective
ecosystem, the challenge for modeling approaches is the sequential
calculation of isotopic compositions. Associated numerical inaccuracies
can be minimized by controlling the share of reacted substrates, i.e.
the time step. The criterion to determine the time step needs to
consider the strongest isotope effect, required accuracy of the
calculations and the share of substrate consumed from or provided to the
compound pool.The combination of biogeochemical models with delta N-15
methods and novel measures like site preference (SP) of N2O is a
promising approach for improving process understanding at various
spatial and temporal scales. Nevertheless, the compilation of isotope
effects in this review may not only be of benefit for modelers, but also
for experimentalists, as measurement and modeling of isotope effects may
eventually help to test and validate our current process understanding
of the N cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-elusive-role-of-soil-quality-in-nutrient-cycling-a-review&quot;&gt;The elusive role of soil quality in nutrient cycling: a review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/sum.12288/full&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Schroder, JJ; Schulte, RPO; Creamer, RE; Delgado, A; van Leeuwen, J;
Lehtinen, T; Rutgers, M; Spiegel, H; Staes, J; Toth, G; Wall, DP&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;SOIL USE AND MANAGEMENT&lt;/em&gt;, 32 (4):476-486; DEC 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Cycling of nutrients, including nitrogen and phosphorus, is one of the
ecosystem services we expect agricultural soils to deliver. Nutrient
cycling incorporates the reuse of agricultural, industrial and municipal
organic residues that, misleadingly, are often referred to as ‘wastes’.
The present review disentangles the processes underlying the cycling of
nutrients to better understand which soil properties determine the
performance of that function. Four processes are identified (i) the
capacity to receive nutrients, (ii) the capacity to make and keep
nutrients available to crops, (iii) the capacity to support the uptake
of nutrients by crops and (iv) the capacity to support their successful
removal in harvested crop. Soil properties matter but it is imperative
that, as constituents of ‘soil quality’, they should be evaluated in the
context of management options and climate and not as ends in their own
right. The effect of a soil property may vary depending on the
prevailing climatic and hydrologic conditions and on other soil
properties. We recognize that individual soil properties may be
enhancing one of the processes underlying the cycling of nutrients but
simultaneously weakening others. Competing demands on soil properties
are even more obvious when considering other soil functions such as
primary production, purification and flow regulation of water, climate
modification and habitat provision, as shown by examples. Consequently,
evaluations of soil properties and management actions need to be
site-specific, taking account of local aspects of their suitability and
potential challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-characterize-good-and-greening-in-the-eu-common-agricultural-policy-cap-the-case-of-clay-soils-in-the-netherlands&quot;&gt;How to characterize ‘good’ and ‘greening’ in the EU Common Agricultural Policy (CAP): the case of clay soils in the Netherlands&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/sum.12289/abstract&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Bouma, J; Wosten, JHM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;SOIL USE AND MANAGEMENT&lt;/em&gt;, 32 (4):546-552; DEC 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The change in the Common Agricultural Policy (CAP) of the European Union
from product to producer support, including requirements for ‘good
agricultural and environmental conditions’ and ‘greening’, is excellent.
However, these requirements are now defined in rather general terms.
Questions can be raised about suitable indicators, and there is a
recognized need for effective management recommendations to support
farmers in achieving the required ‘good’ conditions. These
recommendations are bound to be quite different for different soils in
different countries. A study of Dutch clay soils was based on a
storyline describing current problems and management options for
improvement, which were quantified using a soil-water-crop simulation
model. Indicators were defined for agricultural conditions and
suggestions made for the use of the model in a predictive mode to help
farmers improve their soil management. Environmental conditions were
judged by current environmental guidelines for water and air. When
modelling, implicit assumptions that soils are homogeneous were shown to
be unrealistic for these clay soils, requiring development of innovative
methods and procedures, presenting a challenge for soil research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-review-of-visual-soil-evaluation-techniques-for-soil-structure&quot;&gt;A review of visual soil evaluation techniques for soil structure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/sum.12300/abstract&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Emmet-Booth, JP; Forristal, PD; Fenton, O; Ball, BC; Holden, NM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;SOIL USE AND MANAGEMENT&lt;/em&gt;, 32 (4):623-634; DEC 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Soil structure forms a key component of soil quality, and its assessment
by semi-quantitative visual soil evaluation (VSE) techniques can help
scientists, advisors and farmers make decisions regarding sampling and
soil management. VSE techniques require inexpensive equipment and
generate immediate results that correlate well with quantitative
measurements of physical and biochemical properties, highlighting their
potential utility. We reviewed published VSE techniques and found that
soils of certain textures present problems and a lack of research into
the influence of soil moisture content on VSE criteria. Generally,
profile methods evaluate process interactions at specific locations
within a field, exploring both intrinsic aspects and anthropogenic
impacts. Spade methods focus on anthropogenic characteristics, providing
rapid synopses of soil structure over wider areas. Despite a focus on
structural form, some methods include criteria related to stability and
resiliency. Further work is needed to improve existing methods regarding
texture influences, on-farm sampling procedures and more holistic
assessments of soil structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pedotransfer-functions-to-predict-atterberg-limits-for-south-african-soils-using-measured-and-morphological-properties&quot;&gt;Pedotransfer functions to predict Atterberg limits for South African soils using measured and morphological properties&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/sum.12303/abstract&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
van Tol, JJ; Dzene, AR; Le Roux, PAL; Schall, R&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;SOIL USE AND MANAGEMENT&lt;/em&gt;, 32 (4):635-643; DEC 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Atterberg limits and indices, for example liquid limit (LL), plastic
limit (PL), linear shrinkage (LS) and plasticity index (PI), are
important soil properties in engineering and land evaluation for
predicting soil mechanical behaviour. This study was conducted to
develop and evaluate pedotransfer functions (PTFs) to predict Atterberg
limits using measured and morphological soil properties from a large
data set in South Africa covering a vast range of soils, geologies and
climates. Five PTFs were developed; the first four using measured
properties from 2330 soil horizons including extractable Fe, Al, Mn, Na,
K, Mg and Ca; organic carbon (OC); pH (H2O); cation exchange capacity
(CEC); and sand, silt and clay fractions to predict LL, PL, LS and PI.
Morphological descriptors such as colour, structure (grade, size and
type), consistency, occurrence of slickensides and cutans and abundance
of roots were included in the second PTF using data from 717 horizons to
predict PI. For all PTFs, two-thirds of the data were randomly selected
and used for model development and the remainder for validation.
Prediction accuracies of R-2 between 0.49 and 0.77 comparable to other
studies on large data sets but underperformed when compared to localized
data sets. For engineering purposes, sitespecific PTFs for prediction of
Atterberg limits should be developed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-digital-morphometric-approach-for-quantifying-ped-shape&quot;&gt;A Digital Morphometric Approach for Quantifying Ped Shape&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.sciencesocieties.org/node/512/view&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Mohammed, AK; Hirmas, DR; Gimenez, D; Mandel, RD; Miller, JR&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;SOIL SCIENCE SOCIETY OF AMERICA JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, 80 (6):1604-1618; NOV-DEC 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Ped shape is an important property with considerable influence over soil
processes, such as root penetration, water infiltration, and solute
transport. Despite the host of methods employed to quantify other soil
morphological properties, ped shape quantification remains elusive.
Existing methods attempting to quantify soil structure utilize
laboratory techniques that have limitations on sample size and
resolution. Our goal was to overcome these limitations by developing an
approach to quantify ped shape using morphometrics created from
published digital photographs of soil profiles and structure specimens.
In addition, ped shapes from heuristic diagrams and three-dimensional
(3-D) scans of peds were examined. The heuristic diagrams were
quantified to assess ped shapes derived from common conceptualizations
of soil structure, while the 3-D scans were quantified to assess the
effect of ped orientation on shape measurements. Ped shape was
quantified by manually outlining distinct examples of soil peds from
high-resolution photographs and heuristic diagrams and calculating
several morphometrics from the resulting silhouettes using image
analysis software. A survey was designed to poll expert judgment to
properly classify the shape of these peds. Using this method, we were
able to transform typical categorical and subjective descriptions of
peds into continuous quantitative shape data. The shape metrics,
circularity and width to height ratio, exemplify the type of continuous
variables that allow significant differences between ped shapes to be
detected. This approach opens the door to analyzing soil structure at
regional and continental scales through the analysis of existing
photographs without the need to resample.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-bibliometric-and-visual-analysis-of-global-geo-ontology-research&quot;&gt;A bibliometric and visual analysis of global geo-ontology research&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0098300416305659&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Li, L; Liu, Y; Zhu, HH; Ying, S; Luo, QY; Luo, H; Kuai, X; Xia, H; Shen,
H&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;COMPUTERS &amp;amp; GEOSCIENCES&lt;/em&gt;, 99 1-8; FEB 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
In this paper, the results of a bibliometric and visual analysis of
geo-ontology research articles collected from the Web of Science (WOS)
database between 1999 and 2014 are presented. The numbers of national
institutions and published papers are visualized and a global research
heat map is drawn, illustrating an overview of global geo-ontology
research. In addition, we present a chord diagram of countries and
perform a visual cluster analysis of a knowledge co-citation network of
references, disclosing potential academic communities and identifying
key points, main research areas, and future research trends. The
International Journal of Geographical Information Science, Progress in
Human Geography, and Computers &amp;amp; Geosciences are the most active
journals. The USA makes the largest contributions to geo-ontology
research by virtue of its highest numbers of independent and
collaborative papers, and its dominance was also confirmed in the
country chord diagram. The majority of institutions are in the USA,
Western Europe, and Eastern Asia. Wuhan University, University of
Munster, and the Chinese Academy of Sciences are notable geo-ontology
institutions. Keywords such as “Semantic Web,” “GIS,” and “space” have
attracted a great deal of attention. “Semantic granularity in
ontology-driven geographic information systems, “Ontologies in support
of activities in geographical space” and “A translation approach to
portable ontology specifications” have the highest cited centrality.
Geographical space, computer-human interaction, and ontology cognition
are the three main research areas of geo-ontology. The semantic mismatch
between the producers and users of ontology data as well as error
propagation in interdisciplinary and cross-linguistic data reuse needs
to be solved. In addition, the development of geoontology modeling
primitives based on OWL (Web Ontology Language) and finding methods to
automatically rework data in Semantic Web are needed. Furthermore, the
topological relations between geographical entities still require
further study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;information-measures-for-terrain-visualization&quot;&gt;Information measures for terrain visualization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0098300416305660&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Bonaventura, X; Sima, AA; Feixas, M; Buckley, SJ; Sbert, M; Howell, JA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;COMPUTERS &amp;amp; GEOSCIENCES&lt;/em&gt;, 99 9-18; FEB 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Many quantitative and qualitative studies in geoscience research are
based on digital elevation models (DEMs) and 3D surfaces to aid
understanding of natural and anthropogenically-influenced topography. As
well as their quantitative uses, the visual representation of DEMs can
add valuable information for identifying and interpreting topographic
features. However, choice of viewpoints and rendering styles may not
always be intuitive, especially when terrain data are augmented with
digital image texture. In this paper, an information theoretic framework
for object understanding is applied to terrain visualisation and terrain
view selection. From a visibility channel between a set of viewpoints
and the component polygons of a 3D terrain model, we obtain three
polygonal information measures. These measures are used to visualize the
information associated with each polygon of the terrain model. In order
to enhance the perception of the terrain’s shape, we explore the effect
of combining the calculated information measures with the supplementary
digital image texture. From polygonal information, we also introduce a
method to select a set of representative views of the terrain model.
Finally, we evaluate the behaviour of the proposed techniques using
example datasets. A publicly available framework for both the
visualization and the view selection of a terrain has been created in
order to provide the possibility to analyse any terrain model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-intelligent-system-for-mineral-identification-in-thin-sections-based-on-a-cascade-approach&quot;&gt;An intelligent system for mineral identification in thin sections based on a cascade approach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0098300416305702&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Izadi, H; Sadri, J; Bayati, M&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;COMPUTERS &amp;amp; GEOSCIENCES&lt;/em&gt;, 99 37-49; FEB 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
In this study, an intelligent system for mineral identification in thin
sections is proposed based on RGB and HSI color spaces and texture
features in plane and cross polarized light. The proposed system has two
phases for mineral identification. In phase#1, which is the segmentation
phase, 12 color components are extracted for each pixel, and using an
incremental clustering algorithm, several mineral clusters including
index mineral are produced. Afterwards, in phase#2 which is the
identification phase, the produced mineral clusters are identified based
on a cascade classification approach. The first level of the cascade
includes a set of artificial neural networks (ANNs) corresponding to the
number of input minerals which are trained based on color components. In
the first level, those minerals exhibiting different colors in plane or
cross polarized light are identified. The second level of the cascade
includes one ANN which is trained based on texture features in plane and
cross polarized light images. In the second level, those minerals which
are indistinguishable based on color components in both plane and cross
polarized light are identified (are rejected in the first level of the
cascade). The final output of the system is the name and number of
minerals, boundary and percentage of each mineral in thin section, and
eventually the name of probable target rock. The proposed system is able
to recognize 23 test igneous minerals with the overall accuracy of
93.81%. The proposed system can be applied in important applications
which require a real time segmentation and identification map such as
petrography, and NASA Mars Explorations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;climate-change-reduces-extent-of-temperate-drylands-and-intensifies-drought-in-deep-soils&quot;&gt;Climate change reduces extent of temperate drylands and intensifies drought in deep soils&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms14196&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Schlaepfer, DR; Bradford, JB; Lauenroth, WK; Munson, SM; Tietjen, B;
Hall, SA; Wilson, SD; Duniway, MC; Jia, G; Pyke, DA; Lkhagva, A;
Jamiyansharav, K&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;NATURE COMMUNICATIONS&lt;/em&gt;, 8 14196-14196; JAN 31 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Drylands cover 40% of the global terrestrial surface and provide
important ecosystem services. While drylands as a whole are expected to
increase in extent and aridity in coming decades, temperature and
precipitation forecasts vary by latitude and geographic region
suggesting different trajectories for tropical, subtropical, and
temperate drylands. Uncertainty in the future of tropical and
subtropical drylands is well constrained, whereas soil moisture and
ecological droughts, which drive vegetation productivity and
composition, remain poorly understood in temperate drylands. Here we
show that, over the twenty first century, temperate drylands may
contract by a third, primarily converting to subtropical drylands, and
that deep soil layers could be increasingly dry during the growing
season. These changes imply major shifts in vegetation and ecosystem
service delivery. Our results illustrate the importance of appropriate
drought measures and, as a global study that focuses on temperate
drylands, highlight a distinct fate for these highly populated areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;progressive-and-regressive-soil-evolution-phases-in-the-anthropocene&quot;&gt;Progressive and regressive soil evolution phases in the Anthropocene&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0341816216304416&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;
Authors:
Bajard, M; Poulenard, J; Sabatier, P; Develle, AL; Giguet-Covex, C;
Jacob, J; Crouzet, C; David, F; Pignol, C; Arnaud, F&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;CATENA&lt;/em&gt;, 150 39-52; MAR 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Soils have a substantial role in the environment because they provide
several ecosystem services such as food supply or carbon storage.
Agricultural practices can modify soil properties and soil evolution
processes, hence threatening these services. These modifications are
poorly studied, and the resilience/adaptation times of soils to
disruptions are unknown. Here, we study the evolution of pedogenetic
processes and soil evolution phases (progressive or regressive) in
response to human-induced erosion from a 4000-year lake sediment
sequence (Lake La Thuile, French Alps). Erosion in this small lake
catchment in the montane area is quantified from the terrigenous
sediments that were trapped in the lake and compared to the soil
formation rate. To access this quantification, soil processes evolution
are deciphered from soil and sediment geochemistry comparison. Over the
last 4000 years, first impacts on soils are recorded at approximately
1600 yr cal. BP, with the erosion of surface horizons exceeding 10
t.km(-2).yr(-1). Increasingly deep horizons were eroded with erosion
accentuation during the Higher Middle Ages (1400-850 yr cal. BP),
reaching 1000 t.km(-2).yr(-1), and leading to the remobilization of
carbonated and poorly weathered material, hence rejuvenating soil
development. Erosion exceeded the soil formation rate and constituted a
regression in the development of soils. The tolerable erosion limit is
thus defined for erosion from 25 to 30 t.km(-2).yr(-1). Beyond this
limit, the sustainability of the agroecosystem is limited and ecosystem
services decrease. Afterwards, pedogenesis evolved again from
progressive (700-300 yr cal. BP) to regressive (300 yr cal. BP-today)
phases. Erosion was less important during the last 700 years than during
the Middle Ages but with the same weathering stages, indicating that
soils were deeply affected during the Middle-Age and have yet not
recovered. Our results highlight the importance of the human factor in
the pedogenesis over last millennia and suggest that the studied
agro-ecosystem entered the Anthropocene 1400 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;landslide-monitoring-for-risk-mitigation-by-using-corner-reflector-and-satellite-sar-interferometry-the-large-landslide-of-carlantino-italy&quot;&gt;Landslide monitoring for risk mitigation by using corner reflector and satellite SAR interferometry: The large landslide of Carlantino (Italy)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Bovenga, F; Pasquariello, G; Pellicani, R; Refice, A; Spilotro, G&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;CATENA&lt;/em&gt;, 151 49-62; APR 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The use of satellite Synthetic Aperture Radar Interferometry (InSAR) for
monitoring ground instability due to landslide events, although
advantageous over large spatial scales, still poses challenges related
to the recurrently complex kinematics of the phenomena or to the
unfavorable settings of the examined areas with respect to steep
topography and vegetated land cover.This paper presents results obtained
by using Multi-temporal InSAR techniques with high resolution TerraSARX
(TSX) data for monitoring the Carlantino landslide, located in the
Daunian Subapennine (Apulia regioh, southern Italy) on a slope
overlooking a water reservoir, and subjected to several investigations
and consolidation works. The targets detected by using Persistent
Scatterer Interferometry (PSI) correspond to urban structures or pen
urban walls and guard rails, while the landslide body is almost
completely devoid of stable targets, due to the widespread vegetation
and variable land cover. To allow stability monitoring, a network of six
Corner Reflectors (CR) was designed and deployed over the landslide test
site. The TSX images were analyzed by using both the PSI processing and
a procedure, based on the double difference analysis of InSAR phase
values on the CR pixels. Despite residual noise and the loss of 2 CRs
due to vandalism, the processing allowed verifying the stability of the
upper and central part of the landslide body, and relating indirectly
the movements at the toe of the landslide to the water level
fluctuations of the reservoir. Finally, this experiment suggests some
recommendations and guidelines in planning CR deployment in complex
landslide sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;modelling-long-term-soil-organic-carbon-dynamics-under-the-impact-of-land-cover-change-and-soil-redistribution&quot;&gt;Modelling long-term soil organic carbon dynamics under the impact of land cover change and soil redistribution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Bouchoms, S; Wang, ZG; Vanacker, V; Doetterl, S; Van Oost, K&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;CATENA&lt;/em&gt;, 151 63-73; APR 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
During the last millennia, anthropogenic land cover change has caused a
significant release of carbon from soils while also accelerating rates
of soil erosion by one to two orders of magnitude. However, mechanistic
frameworks that explicitly link land cover change, erosion and soil
organic carbon (SOC) cycling and, in addition, can be applied to longer
timescales are currently lacking. This study presents a 4D
soil-landscape model coupling sediment fluxes and carbon dynamics in
response to continuous land cover change over a period of 1000 years. We
applied the model to a well-studied catchment of 591 km(2) in Central
Belgium. The model evaluation showed that the simulated magnitude and
spatial patterns of soil redistribution and SOC stocks are in good
agreement with field observations. At the catchment scale, land cover
change over the last 1000 years decreased the SOC stock of the top 1 m
of soil by 33.1 tC.ha(-1) (32% loss compared to the initial SOC stock)
while in contrast erosion resulted in an uptake of 31.9 tC.ha(-1) from
the atmosphere (29% gain compared to theinitial SOC stock). As a result,
the combined effect is a small source of c. 1.2 tC.ha(-1) over the last
1000 years. While the SOC released from the soil to the atmosphere
quickly responded to land conversion, the erosion induced sink operated
at a much lower intensity but with a longer duration. These transient
simulations show that the soil carbon budget is highly variable in both
space and time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;predictive-performance-of-mobile-vis-near-infrared-spectroscopy-for-key-soil-properties-at-different-geographical-scales-by-using-spiking-and-data-mining-techniques&quot;&gt;Predictive performance of mobile vis-near infrared spectroscopy for key soil properties at different geographical scales by using spiking and data mining techniques&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Nawar, S; Mouazen, AM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;CATENA&lt;/em&gt;, 151 118-129; APR 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The development of accurate visible and near infrared (vis-NIR)
spectroscopy calibration models for selected soil properties based on
mobile measurements is essential for site specific soil management at
fine sampling scale. The objective of the present study was to compare
the mobile and laboratory prediction performance of vis-NIR spectroscopy
for total nitrogen (TN), total carbon (TC) and soil moisture content
(MC) of field soil samples based on single field (SFD), two-field
dataset (TFD), UK national dataset (UND) and European continental
dataset (ECD) calibration models developed with linear and nonlinear
data mining techniques including spiking. Fresh soil samples collected
from fields in the UK, Czech Republic, Germany, Denmark and the
Netherlands were scanned with a fibre-type vis-NIR spectrophotometer
(tec5 Technology for Spectroscopy, Germany), with a spectral range of
305-2200 nm. After dividing spectra into calibration (75%) and
validation (25%) sets, spectra in the calibration set were subjected to
three multivariate calibration models, including the partial least
squares regression (PLSR), multivariate adaptive regression splines
(MARS) and support vector machines (SVM), with leave-one-out
cross-validation to establish calibration models of TN, TC and MC.
Results showed that the best model performance in cross-validation was
obtained with MARS methods for the majority of dataset scales used,
whereas the lowest model performance was obtained with the SFD. The
effect of spiking was significant and the best model performance in
general term was obtained when local samples collected from two target
fields in the UK were spiked with the ECD, with coefficients of
determination (R-2) values of 0.96,0.98 and 0.93, root mean square error
(RMSE) of 0.01, 0.1 and 1.75, and ratio of performance to interquartile
distance (RPIQ) of 7.46, 6.57 and 3.98, for TC, TN and MC, respectively.
Therefore, these results suggest that ECD vis-NIR MARS calibration
models can be successfully used to predict TN, TC and MC under both
laboratory and mobile measurement conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;microbial-diversity-and-soil-functions&quot;&gt;Microbial diversity and soil functions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/ejss.4_12398/full&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors
P. Nannipieri, J. Ascher, M. T. Ceccherini, L. Landi, G. Pietramellara, G. Renella&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summary
Soil is a complex and dynamic biological system, and still in 2003 it is difficult to determine the composition of microbial communities in soil. We are also limited in the determination of microbially mediated reactions because present assays for determining the overall rate of entire metabolic processes (such as respiration) or specific enzyme activities (such as urease, protease and phosphomonoesterase activity) do not allow any identification of the microbial species directly involved in the measured processes. The central problem posed by the link between microbial diversity and soil function is to understand the relations between genetic diversity and community structure and between community structure and function. A better understanding of the relations between microbial diversity and soil functions requires not only the use of more accurate assays for taxonomically and functionally characterizing DNA and RNA extracted from soil, but also high-resolution techniques with which to detect inactive and active microbial cells in the soil matrix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil seems to be characterized by a redundancy of functions; for example, no relationship has been shown to exist between microbial diversity and decomposition of organic matter. Generally, a reduction in any group of species has little effect on overall processes in soil because other microorganisms can take on its function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The determination of the composition of microbial communities in soil is not necessary for a better quantification of nutrient transformations. The holistic approach, based on the division of the systems in pools and the measurement of fluxes linking these pools, is the most efficient. The determination of microbial C, N, P and S contents by fumigation techniques has allowed a better quantification of nutrient dynamics in soil. However, further advances require determining new pools, such as active microbial biomass, also with molecular techniques. Recently investigators have separated 13C- and 12C-DNA, both extracted from soil treated with a 13C source, by density-gradient centrifugation. This technique should allow us to calculate the active microbial C pool by multiplying the ratio between labelled and total DNA by the microbial biomass C content of soil. In addition, the taxonomic and functional characterization of 13C-DNA allows us to understand more precisely the changes in the composition of microbial communities affected by the C-substrate added to soil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;climate-driven-thresholds-for-chemical-weathering-in-postglacial-soils-of-new-zealand&quot;&gt;Climate-driven thresholds for chemical weathering in postglacial soils of New Zealand&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/2016JF003864/full&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors
Jean L. Dixon, Oliver A. Chadwick, Peter M. Vitousek&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Chemical weathering in soils dissolves and alters minerals, mobilizes metals, liberates nutrients to terrestrial and aquatic ecosystems, and may modulate Earth’s climate over geologic time scales. Climate-weathering relationships are often considered fundamental controls on the evolution of Earth’s surface and biogeochemical cycles. However, surprisingly little consensus has emerged on if and how climate controls chemical weathering, and models and data from published literature often give contrasting correlations and predictions for how weathering rates and climate variables such as temperature or moisture are related. Here we combine insights gained from the different approaches, methods, and theory of the soil science, biogeochemistry, and geomorphology communities to tackle the fundamental question of how rainfall influences soil chemical properties. We explore climate-driven variations in weathering and soil development in young, postglacial soils of New Zealand, measuring soil elemental geochemistry along a large precipitation gradient (400-4700???mm/yr) across the Waitaki basin on Te Waipounamu, the South Island. Our data show a strong climate imprint on chemical weathering in these young soils. This climate control is evidenced by rapid nonlinear changes along the gradient in total and exchangeable cations in soils and in the increased movement and redistribution of metals with rainfall. The nonlinear behavior provides insight into why climate-weathering relationships may be elusive in some landscapes. These weathering thresholds also have significant implications for how climate may influence landscape evolution and the release of rock-derived nutrients to ecosystems, as landscapes that transition to wetter climates across this threshold may weather and deplete rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/03/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on March 16, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/03/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2017/03/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2017-02-14T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-03-01T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2017-7&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2017 #7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spatial-extent-and-temporal-variability-of-greenland-firn-aquifers-detected-by-ground-and-airborne-radars&quot;&gt;Spatial extent and temporal variability of Greenland firn aquifers detected by ground and airborne radars&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/2016JF003869/full&quot;&gt;online link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Miege, C; Forster, RR; Brucker, L; Koenig, LS; Solomon, DK; Paden, JD;
Box, JE; Burgess, EW; Miller, JZ; McNerney, L; Brautigam, N; Fausto, RS;
Gogineni, S&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF GEOPHYSICAL RESEARCH-EARTH SURFACE&lt;/em&gt;, 121 (12):2381-2398; DEC 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
We document the existence of widespread firn aquifers in an elevation
range of similar to 1200-2000 m, in the high snow-accumulation regions
of the Greenland ice sheet. We use NASA Operation IceBridge accumulation
radar data from five campaigns (2010-2014) to estimate a firn-aquifer
total extent of 21,900 km(2). We investigate two locations in Southeast
Greenland, where repeated radar profiles allow mapping of aquifer-extent
and water table variations. In the upper part of Helheim Glacier the
water table rises in spring following above-average summer melt, showing
the direct firn-aquifer response to surface meltwater production
changes. After spring 2012, a drainage of the firn-aquifer lower margin
(5 km) is inferred from both 750 MHz accumulation radar and 195 MHz
multicoherent radar depth sounder data. For 2011-2014, we use a
ground-penetrating radar profile located at our Ridgeline field site and
find a spatially stable aquifer with a water table fluctuating less than
2.5 m vertically. When combining radar data with surface topography, we
find that the upper elevation edge of firn aquifers is located directly
downstream of locally high surface slopes. Using a steady state 2-D
groundwater flow model, water is simulated to flow laterally in an
unconfined aquifer, topographically driven by ice sheet surface
undulations until the water encounters crevasses. Simulations suggest
that local flow cells form within the Helheim aquifer, allowing water to
discharge in the firn at the steep-to-flat transitions of surface
topography. Supported by visible imagery, we infer that water drains
into crevasses, but its volume and rate remain unconstrained.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/03/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on March 01, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Soil science teaching at Nowley]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/02/Nowley" />
  <id>/2017/02/Nowley</id>
  <updated>2017-03-29T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-02-20T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Towards the end of February of this year I was in the Liverpool Plains for a soil science and field school experience that is for students enrolled in the SOIL3009 unit of study that is offered at the University of Sydney. The field school was based at ‘Nowley’, which is a university owned mixed farming enterprise of about 1500ha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nowley&quot;&gt;Nowley&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/20171902nowley/NowleyHomestead.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Nowley Homestead.&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 1. Aerial photo of the Nowley farm homestead and surrounding cropping fields. Mt Coolanbilla in the background. &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nowley”, more formally known as The Holtsbaum Research Station was a gift from Mr E.J. Holtsbaum to the University of Sydney. Mr Holtsbaum, whose family owned Nowley since 1964, made the gift with the view that the farm would continue to prosper under the University’s stewardship, and serve as a center on the Liverpool Plains for the creation and dissemination of innovative technology for agricultural production and natural resource management. Surplus profits from the operation of Nowley are to be allocated for scholarships to help students fund their studies, and to encourage in recipients a sense of giving something back to the land through their degree, should they have the opportunity to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowley is located in one of the most versatile and reliable winter and summer dry land cropping regions of Australia, in the Spring Ridge district on the central/north west slopes of NSW. The property is run as a successful mixed farming enterprise centered around crops of wheat, barley and canola in winter, sorghum and sunflower in summer, and a cattle herd of breeders, replacement heifers and bulls. Nowley has mostly fertile basaltic soils, an average annual rainfall of about 600 mm with a relatively even summer and winter distribution, and is close to good regional infrastructure. The variation in soil types and parent materials, and the proximity of a large, natural water body (Lake Goran), means that the property offers unique opportunities to study the impacts of parent material and topography on soil type, and consequently on agricultural opportunities. Nowley will give students a strong sense of the interaction of landscape and agriculture. Stands of remnant native forest on sections of the property will provide invaluable undisturbed reference sites for comparative studies of agricultural and native ecosystems, and the influence of human impacts. &lt;a href=&quot;http://sydney.edu.au/agriculture/about_us/facilities_locations/holtsbaum_agricultural_research_institute.shtml&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; for more information about Nowley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;climate-and-soil-water-monitoring&quot;&gt;Climate and soil (water) monitoring&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent development at Nowley has been the installation of a soil and weather monitoring system. This is just a small scale set up that includes 3 weather stations and 8 soil moisture monitoring sites. The soil moisture monitoring is currently set up in one particular field of the farm along a straight line transect. We have 4 different types of moisture sensors in operation at each site at a depth of about 20cm. We are interested in monitoring soil moisture of course and developing predictive models around forecasting, but this initial set up is intended to help us figure out what the most reliable sensor might be to use in the long term. Some preliminary data suggests that there is substantial variability between the different sensors. The sensors we are trialing are: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.decagon.com/en/soils/volumetric-water-content-sensors/gs1/&quot;&gt;Decogon GS1&lt;/a&gt; soil moisture sensors, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decagon.com/en/soils/volumetric-water-content-sensors/10hs-large-volume-vwc/&quot;&gt;10HS&lt;/a&gt; soil moisture sensor, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vegetronix.com/Products/VH400/&quot;&gt;Vegetronix VH400&lt;/a&gt; soil moisture sensors, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ictinternational.com/products/mp306/mp306-moisture-probe/&quot;&gt;MP306&lt;/a&gt; soil moisture sensors. The weather stations obviously collect a little more detailed information than the soil moisture sensors. There is soil moisture, temperature and conductivity sensing at 3 depths (5cm, 20cm and 60cm) which is measured with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.decagon.com/en/soils/volumetric-water-content-sensors/gs3-vwc-temp-ec/&quot;&gt;Decagon GS3 sensors&lt;/a&gt;, as well as the usual air temperature, rainfall, humidity and wind speed observations being recorded too. Every 15 minutes, observations are being logged, then transmitted to a local hub which then transmits this over the internet for real time viewing and analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently there is much excitement and activity around soil sensing and IoT stuff, and we are taking a calm approach to it by testing what setup is best. In the future we will likely delve into the modeling and forecasting side of things. A useful thing about these monitoring set ups is that the equipment can be easily re-located to other sites. I think into the future the optimal placement of this equipment will feature heavily. Given the costs of setting it all up though, the possibility of acquiring more sensors is not very high, so optimal placement of sensors is going to be the best solution in the meantime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/20171902nowley/nowley_weather.png&quot; alt=&quot;Nowley weather&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 2. Soil moisture and weather monitoring at Nowley. Top left is one of the three weather stations. Top right are the soil moisture sensors (GS3) installed at the same weather station. Bottom right is some logged data showing rainfall and volumetric water content. Bottom left is the soil sensor configuration installed for one of the eight soil moisture sensing locations. &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-student-experience&quot;&gt;The Student Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-brief&quot;&gt;The brief&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The field trip revolved around two key activities. The first was a problem-based one, and the second was soil profile description. For the first activity we had given the students a problem to solve. This problem was one of low yielding cropping within a field that would otherwise appear to be uniform. The figure below shows a wheat yield map from 2012 which illustrates quite distinct areas of low and high yields. We wanted the students to figure out why this might be the case. To help them, a data gathering exercise was initiated to collect as much information as we could about the physical and chemical properties of the soils. At the disposal for the data gathering exercise was some soil sampling equipment and proximal soil sensing equipment that included a gamma spectrometer, electromagnetic induction equipment, plus portable vis-NIR and x-ray fluorescence instrumentation. In addition to these, various soil physical measurements were conducted at select locations in the field and included water infiltration experiments, soil moisture reading and soil penetration resistance testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most students had some level of soil science teaching at this particular stage of their undergraduate teaching. In order to push their learning to a new level, the problem-based learning exercise brought some of those fundamental learning experiences to a real world situation, but also introduced them to new concepts and techniques such as proximal soil sensing and rapid soil assessment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/20171902nowley/nowley_yield.png&quot; alt=&quot;Nowley yield&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 3. Aerial shot of the field under investigation and associated map of wheat yield from 2012. &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To break up the intensive activities associated with the problem-based exercise, the students were re-exposed (from earlier soil science units of study) to soil description. Nowley is an good case study for soil description because the property has some quite distinct soil types.  Initially students familiarize themselves with description on a practice pit, but are then pitted against each other both individually and in teams to see who is the best individual and team. With this experience, students get the necessary skill in soil pit description and soil interpretation, but the competition environment brings another level of desire to do well. It has assessment marks attached to it, and it also brings out the competitive streak in most people too.  It is a nice concept for teaching and learning. For the potential winners, the hanging carrot was an invitation to attend an Australian inter-collegiate soil judging competition to be held later in the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;proximal-soil-sensing&quot;&gt;Proximal soil sensing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proximal soil sensing is a relatively cheap and non invasive way of acquiring a lot information about the soil. By a lot I mean high sampling rate across large spatial extents. Proximal soil sensing entailed the acquisition of bulk soil electrical conductivity and gamma radiometric data as well as associated positional and height information acquired via differential GPS device. The two proximal sensors we used in this part of the project were a &lt;a href=&quot;https://georesults.com.au/product/radiation-solutions-rs-700-rs701-rsx1-gamma-ray-spectrometer/&quot;&gt;RSX-1&lt;/a&gt; gamma radiometric detector consisting of a 4L Sodium-Iodine crystal (Radiation Solutions Inc., Mississauga, Ontario, Canada), and a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dualem.com/products.html&quot;&gt;Geonics DUALEM-21S&lt;/a&gt; electromagnetic induction instrument (Geonics Ltd, Mississauga, ON, Canada).  Data from these instruments were logged continuously with measurements being taken approximately every 1m given an average speed of 5 km h-1. Each logged measurement was tagged with a spatial reference coordinate using a digital GPS receiver (SMART6-L GNSS; NovAtel, Canada).  All three instruments were attached to a John Deer ATV and driven on average to a parallel line spacing of approximately 15m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/20171902nowley/nowley_pss.png&quot; alt=&quot;Nowley proximal sensing&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 4. Setting up the proximal sensing instruments and then field data collection. &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some theoretical background,  the gamma-ray spectrometer records the amount of radioactive isotopes in the soil (top 30-50cm) based on the principle that each gamma ray photon relates to a discrete energy window which is characteristic of the source isotope. Gamma radiometrics is a passive sensing technique the detects the varying amounts of naturally occurring radioisotopes of potassium (40K), uranium (238U-series) and thorium (232Th-series) from soil as they produce high-energy gamma-rays with sufficient intensities to be picked up by the detector . Additionally, a total count gamma-ray measurement can be taken over the entire spectrum range too. Measurements were recorded in counts per second (cps).  The reason for the interest in collecting this data for latter soil inference is that the radioisotopic signature of soils has previously been linked to soil physical, chemical and geochemical properties including soil texture and carbon, among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of the electromagnetic induction, the sensors measure bulk soil electrical conductivity. From these data, other soil properties of interest may be inferred using EM data like soil moisture, pH and texture.  The DUALEM-21S (Dualem, Milton, ON, Canada) sensor used has dual-geometry (horizontal and vertical) receivers at separations of 1- and 2-m from the transmitter. This configuration provides four simultaneous depths of conductivity sounding or depth of exploration, that correspond to integrated conductivity measurements in mS/m for depths of 0-0.5m, 0-1m, 0-1.6m and 0-3.2m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/20171902nowley/nowley_pss2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Nowley proximal sensing interpolation&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 5. Drive lines showing data collection points from the proximal sensors and GPS. The bottom two maps show the interpolate maps of the gamma radiometrics corresponding to total count and potassium. The maps on the right are interpolated soil conductivity maps corresponding to 0-0.5m and 0-3.2m depths. We used a local kriging interpolator to create these maps from the collected point observations. &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;soil-sampling-and-soil-physical-measurments&quot;&gt;Soil sampling and soil physical measurments&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the 2012 yield map we created three clusters based on the quantiles of the values. This essentially created three zones: low, medium and high yielding areas. From each cluster we took 10 soil cores (selected at random) for description and further analysis. At around four sites within each cluster some soil physical measurements were undertaken. Some of the data collected included steady state water infiltration rate, soil moisture measurements and soil penetration resistance measurements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/20171902nowley/nowley_sampling.png&quot; alt=&quot;Nowley soil sampling&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 6. Taking soil cores in the field and a snapshot of what some of them look like. The bottom photo shows students working hard in the field collecting their soil physical measurements. &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;soil-spectral-inference&quot;&gt;Soil spectral inference&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the soil cores that were collected in the field we wanted to rapidly make some measurements of key soil properties including texture, soil pH, and carbon and others. So in addition to making some general soil descriptions such as color, horizon designation and aggregate stability we also used our portable visible-near infrared and x-ray florescence spectrometers. Once calibrated these instruments can measure very quickly a number of different soil attributes. For example soil spectral models fitted using vis-NIR spectra and observed soil information can be applied to collected spectra in order to estimate the same attributes. A detailed review of infrared spectroscopy for soil science can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/05704928.2013.811081&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The key for success in regards to soil spectral inference is to have existing spectral libraries that are similar to the soil spectra that is collected in the field. The other consideration is to have a work flow in place to deal with soils in their field condition, rather than their dried ground state which is the usual state in which models are calibrated with. This is an area of research that is not fully developed yet and we continue to investigate how best to use such proximal soil sensing instruments in the field to measure soils in their field state. New developments in this space will make soil measurement much more efficiently and timely. Some key questions that need to be addressed include how to deal with water, which is known to attenuate the spectral signal of soil, and how to deal with the matrix properties of soils i.e. particle size and aggregates etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With regards to the portable XRF, these instruments can relatively quickly estimate the elemental concentrations of soils. This is important for evaluating the soil geochemistry which can give insights about micro nutrient levels, and can even give some clues about likely soil pedogenesis. The pXRF does not need to be calibrated in the same way as the vis-NIR as the response spectral peaks are directly related to elemental species and their concentration. A detailed review of using pXRF for soil science can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.sciencesocieties.org/publications/msa/abstracts/1/1/methods-soil.2015.0033&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;soil-judging&quot;&gt;Soil judging&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the field trip all the students were pitted against each other for the individual soil judging contest. The competition was organised by &lt;a href=&quot;http://sydney.edu.au/agriculture/academic_staff/stephen.cattle.php&quot;&gt;Assoc. Prof. Stephen Cattle&lt;/a&gt;. The competition is run under a strict sequenced routine that involves timed visualizations of the soil pit. The carrot for the top students was a chance to be involved in a National Soil Judging competition to be held in Toowoomba later on in the year, in addition to top marks for their unit of study assessment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/20171902nowley/nowley_soilJudging.png&quot; alt=&quot;Nowley soil judging&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 7. Students in action for the individual soil judging contest held near Spring Ridge. &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my understanding, the students need to describe to key features of the soil and classify the soil with respect to the Australian Soil Classification System. Then some agronomic interpretations of the data ensue. The competition soil pit was a steep stream bank adjacent to an agricultural field a little away from Nowley near the township of Spring Ridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thats-a-wrap&quot;&gt;Thats a wrap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/20171902nowley/Nowley_teaching.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Nowley teaching&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 8. Intensive learning was on offer for both students and staff at Nowley. Here we have (top photo) a teaching in soil geostatistics, and in the background are students getting busy with soil spectral analysis. Bottom photo is a group staff and student SOIL3009 cohort outside the Nowley shearing shed.  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We collected a lot of data on the field trip that is to be used throughout the course of the semester in labs, and to compliment lectures in soil physics, chemistry and pedology. Incorporating the problem-based learning into the unit of study provides context and a good opportunity for self learning. With units of study like this, both the staff and students learn together, as the solution to the problem is not known at the outset. Instead, students and staff are actively learning together through the stages of data collection, compilation and analyses. With this type of experience, everyone is learning together, which I think is highly effective for all parties. Also, I think with this unit of study, the students get exposed to the new technology that is now available to do soil science, which I think is important too.  It was a good week had by all despite the rather warm weather we had.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/02/Nowley&quot;&gt;Soil science teaching at Nowley&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on February 20, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/02/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2017/02/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2017-02-14T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-02-17T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2017-6&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2017 #6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;climate-driven-thresholds-for-chemical-weathering-in-postglacial-soils-of-new-zealand&quot;&gt;Climate-driven thresholds for chemical weathering in postglacial soils of New Zealand&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Dixon, JL; Chadwick, OA; Vitousek, PM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF GEOPHYSICAL RESEARCH-EARTH SURFACE&lt;/em&gt;, 121 (9):1619-1634; SEP 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Chemical weathering in soils dissolves and alters minerals, mobilizes
metals, liberates nutrients to terrestrial and aquatic ecosystems, and
may modulate Earth’s climate over geologic time scales.
Climate-weathering relationships are often considered fundamental
controls on the evolution of Earth’s surface and biogeochemical cycles.
However, surprisingly little consensus has emerged on if and how climate
controls chemical weathering, and models and data from published
literature often give contrasting correlations and predictions for how
weathering rates and climate variables such as temperature or moisture
are related. Here we combine insights gained from the different
approaches, methods, and theory of the soil science, biogeochemistry,
and geomorphology communities to tackle the fundamental question of how
rainfall influences soil chemical properties. We explore climate-driven
variations in weathering and soil development in young, postglacial
soils of New Zealand, measuring soil elemental geochemistry along a
large precipitation gradient (400-4700 mm/yr) across the Waitaki basin
on Te Waipounamu, the South Island. Our data show a strong climate
imprint on chemical weathering in these young soils. This climate
control is evidenced by rapid nonlinear changes along the gradient in
total and exchangeable cations in soils and in the increased movement
and redistribution of metals with rainfall. The nonlinear behavior
provides insight into why climate-weathering relationships may be
elusive in some landscapes. These weathering thresholds also have
significant implications for how climate may influence landscape
evolution and the release of rock-derived nutrients to ecosystems, as
landscapes that transition to wetter climates across this threshold may
weather and deplete rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/02/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on February 17, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/02/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2017/02/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2017-02-14T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-02-14T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2017-5&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2017 #5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;consistent-negative-response-of-us-crops-to-high-temperatures-in-observations-and-crop-models&quot;&gt;Consistent negative response of US crops to high temperatures in observations and crop models&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms13931&quot;&gt;online link&lt;/a&gt;
Authors:
Schauberger, B; Archontoulis, S; Arneth, A; Balkovic, J; Ciais, P;
Deryng, D; Elliott, J; Folberth, C; Khabarov, N; Muller, C; Pugh, TAM;
Rolinski, S; Schaphoff, S; Schmid, E; Wang, XH; Schlenker, W; Frieler, K&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;NATURE COMMUNICATIONS&lt;/em&gt;, 8 NIL_1-NIL_9; JAN 19 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
High temperatures are detrimental to crop yields and could lead to
global warming-driven reductions in agricultural productivity. To assess
future threats, the majority of studies used process-based crop models,
but their ability to represent effects of high temperature has been
questioned. Here we show that an ensemble of nine crop models reproduces
the observed average temperature responses of US maize, soybean and
wheat yields. Each day &amp;gt;30 degrees C diminishes maize and soybean yields
by up to 6% under rainfed conditions. Declines observed in irrigated
areas, or simulated assuming full irrigation, are weak. This supports
the hypothesis that water stress induced by high temperatures causes the
decline. For wheat a negative response to high temperature is neither
observed nor simulated under historical conditions, since critical
temperatures are rarely exceeded during the growing season. In the
future, yields are modelled to decline for all three crops at
temperatures &amp;gt;30 degrees C. Elevated CO2 can only weakly reduce these
yield losses, in contrast to irrigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;effects-of-soil-composition-and-preparation-on-the-prediction-of-particle-size-distribution-using-mid-infrared-spectroscopy-and-partial-least-squares-regression&quot;&gt;Effects of soil composition and preparation on the prediction of particle size distribution using mid-infrared spectroscopy and partial least-squares regression&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.publish.csiro.au/SR/pdf/SR16011&quot;&gt;online link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Janik, LJ; Soriano-Disla, JM; Forrester, ST; McLaughlin, MJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;SOIL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, 54 (8):889-904; 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Soil composition and preparation can affect prediction accuracy using
diffuse reflectance mid-infrared Fourier transform spectroscopy
(DRIFTS). In the present study, we evaluated the effect of soil
composition, preparation and carbonate content on the accuracy of
particle size distribution (PSD) predictions in four contrasting sets of
soils, including calcareous soils, using partial least-squares
regression (PLSR). The soils were scanned as &amp;lt;2- and &amp;lt;0.1-mm fine-ground
samples. Regression calibrations were derived for individual soil sets,
as well as a composite of the four sets. Predictions for clay and sand
for the &amp;lt;2-mm composite calibration resulted in good accuracy
(coefficient of determination R-2 = 0.78; ratio of the standard
deviation of reference values to the prediction error (RPD) = 2.2), but
were less accurate for clay in the calcareous soils (R-2 = 0.70-0.78;
RPD = 1.8-1.1) and similarly accurate for sand (R-2 = 0.68-0.80; RPD =
1.7-2.2). Predictions for silt were poor. Accuracies improved by fine
grinding (R-2 = 0.88, RPD = 2.9 for clay; R-2 = 0.84, RPD = 2.9 for
sand). It was concluded that single, large and highly variable sets
rather than site-specific calibrations could be used for the PSD
predictions of specific soil sets. Changes in the PLSR loading weights,
resulting from grinding, could be linked to an improved access of the
infrared beam to the soil matrix by removal or dilution of surface
coatings, resulting in a reduction of inter-and intraparticulate
heterogeneity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;multifractal-analysis-of-soil-hydraulic-properties-in-arid-areas&quot;&gt;Multifractal analysis of soil hydraulic properties in arid areas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.publish.csiro.au/sr/SR15284&quot;&gt;online link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Pahlevan, N; Yazdani, MR; Zolfaghari, AA; Ghodrati, M&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;SOIL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, 54 (8):914-925; 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Physical and hydraulic properties of soil are variable at different
spatial scales. This indicates the necessity of understanding spatial
patterns of soil properties. Scaling analysis, such as multifractal
analysis, has been used to determine the spatial variability of soil
properties. There are however limited numbers of studies concerning the
applications of multifractal techniques applied to characterise spatial
variability of soil properties in arid lands. The objective of this
study was to quantify the scaling patterns of soil properties measured
across a transect and to apply multifractal analysis in arid land areas.
A transect with a length of 4.80 km was selected, and soil properties
were measured at 0-20 cm depth every 145m along the transect. The soil
properties analysed were: texture (sand, silt, clay), pH, electrical
conductivity (EC), bulk density (BD), soil hydraulic properties
(saturated hydraulic conductivity K-s and the van Genuchten soil
water-retention equation’s parameters n(v) and alpha(v)), saturated
water content (theta(s)), and the slope of the soil water-retention
curve at its inflection point (S). Results showed that the variability
of pH and BD was characterised by quasi-monofractal behaviour. Results
showed that soil hydraulic properties such as K-s, alpha(n), n(v), S,
and theta(s) were characterised by higher multifractal indices in the
transects. EC showed the highest tendency to a multifractal type of
scaling or the higher degree of multifractality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mineralogy-of-volcanically-derived-alluvial-soils-at-moshi-tanzania&quot;&gt;Mineralogy of volcanically derived alluvial soils at Moshi, Tanzania&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.publish.csiro.au/SR/SR15252&quot;&gt;online link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Taylor, TS; Hughes, JC; Titshall, LW&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;SOIL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, 54 (8):926-936; 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Despite intensive commercial agriculture in the rift zone of Tanzania,
mineralogical studies on the soils influenced by volcanic parent
materials are scarce. A mineralogical investigation of the soils and two
buried ash layers from an irrigated sugar estate was undertaken using
X-ray diffraction, transmission electron microscopy and measurements of
extractable iron, aluminium and silicon and the specific surface area
(SSA) of the clay fraction. The dominant mineral in the sand and silt
fractions was sanidine. The clay fractions contained mainly high-defect
kaolin, illite and K-feldspar, with small amounts of calcite, talc and
gibbsite in some samples. Electron microscopy revealed the presence of
tubular and spheroidal halloysite and &amp;lt;0.5 mu m kaolinite crystals, as
well as nanocrystalline material, probably allophane, and volcanic
glass. The amounts of ferrihydrite (0.34-1.84%) and allophane
(0.52-6.84%) were low in the soils but higher in the buried ash layers.
The surface areas of the clay fractions were high (up to 145 m(2) g(-1))
and it was calculated that 5% allophane constituted 22% of the total
SSA. Although all soils were dominated by halloysite and small kaolinite
particles, it is likely that the small amounts of allophane with high
SSA has a strong effect on their physical and chemical properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-alternative-index-to-the-exchangeable-sodium-percentage-for-an-explanation-of-dispersion-occurring-in-soils&quot;&gt;An alternative index to the exchangeable sodium percentage for an explanation of dispersion occurring in soils&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.publish.csiro.au/SR/SR15281&quot;&gt;online link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Bennett, JM; Marchuk, A; Marchuk, S&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;SOIL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, 54 (8):949-957; 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
With the introduction of the cation ratio of soil stability (CROSS) to
replace the sodium adsorption ratio (SAR) on the basis of differential
effects of K and Mg to Na and Ca, respectively, there is a requirement
for a similar index involving these cations to replace the exchangeable
sodium percentage (ESP). The exchangeable dispersive percentage (EDP) is
derived and proposed to replace ESP. This paper uses two datasets, one
where exchangeable K concentration is relatively high and exchangeable
Na low, and a further dataset where Mg dominates the cation exchange
capacity. EDP is validated against these datasets and further
mathematical investigation of the contribution of Mg to dispersion is
undertaken. Mineralogy appears to affect turbidity results at a given
dispersive index, and an improved criterion for assessment of Mg effect
on dispersivity is presented.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/02/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on February 14, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intensive Digital Soil Mapping Workshop. Vancouver, Canada]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/02/vancouver" />
  <id>/2017/02/vancouver</id>
  <updated>2017-02-14T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-02-08T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Between January 24-27, 2017 the Sydney Soil Schools team were situated in Vancouver, Canada providing an intensive hands on workshop in digital soil mapping. The team consisted of Prof. Alex McBratney, Prof. Budiman Minansy and Dr. Brendan Malone. They were invited by the Canadian Government whom recently have embarked on a national project of the digital mapping the countries’ soil resource, and with a particular interest in mapping soil carbon stocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/20171302vancouver/vancouver1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Vancouver sites&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 1. Intensive digital soil mapping workshop was held in Vancouver, Canada. Beautiful city and wonderful hosts.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants of the workshop included scientists from Agri-Food Canada in addition to scientists from each of the provincial governments of Canada. Other participants included researchers and students (undergraduate and post graduate) from the universities: University of British Columbia, Simon Fraser University, University of New Brunswick, and the University of Saskatchewan. In total 28 bright and motivated people came for 4 days of all things digital soil mapping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/20171302vancouver/vancouver2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Workshop participants&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 2. Keen participants of the digital soil mapping workshop which was held at the Downtown Campus of Simon Fraser University.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course included a short lecture series about the fundamentals of digital soil mapping, and common methods and practices of digital soil mapping. A lecture describing the global efforts of creating a digital soil map of the world (under the auspices of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.globalsoilmap.net/specifications&quot;&gt;GlobalSoilMap&lt;/a&gt; project) was of particular keen interest to the Canadian participants. More importantly, the course covered a curriculum of learning that is necessary to understand how to do digital soil mapping. The course materials were recently published in the book, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.springer.com/gp/book/9783319443256&quot;&gt;Using R for Digital Soil Mapping&lt;/a&gt; which was authored by the Sydney Soils School team. These course materials cover the very basics of programmatic scripting, to GIS applications, then to the more complex materials about the data science that underpins the production digital soil maps and their associated uncertainties, among other interesting digital soil related topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/20171302vancouver/vancouver3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Workshop participants&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 3. The digital soil mapping workshop was all about getting the participants an experiential program of doing it for real and developing a workflow that can be applied for their own applications.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all, the 4 day training program and jam packed with learning and importantly, heaps of discussion. From feedback, the course was hugely successful that we believe will provide the necessary starting point for Canada to achieve their aspirational goal of developing a digital soil information system for the country. Despite the cool and sometimes snowing weather conditions, our Canadian hosts were wonderfully warm and keen to learn what the Sydney Soil School had to share.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/02/vancouver&quot;&gt;Intensive Digital Soil Mapping Workshop. Vancouver, Canada&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on February 08, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/02/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2017/02/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2017-02-08T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-02-08T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2017-4&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2017 #4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exploring-the-biophysical-option-space-for-feeding-the-world-without-deforestation&quot;&gt;Exploring the biophysical option space for feeding the world without deforestation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms11382&quot;&gt;online link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Erb, KH; Lauk, C; Kastner, T; Mayer, A; Theurl, MC; Haberl, H&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;NATURE COMMUNICATIONS&lt;/em&gt;, 7 11382-11382; APR 19 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Safeguarding the world’s remaining forests is a high-priority goal. We
assess the biophysical option space for feeding the world in 2050 in a
hypothetical zero-deforestation world. We systematically combine
realistic assumptions on future yields, agricultural areas, livestock
feed and human diets. For each scenario, we determine whether the supply
of crop products meets the demand and whether the grazing intensity
stays within plausible limits. We find that many options exist to meet
the global food supply in 2050 without deforestation, even at low
crop-yield levels. Within the option space, individual scenarios differ
greatly in terms of biomass harvest, cropland demand and grazing
intensity, depending primarily on the quantitative and qualitative
aspects of human diets. Grazing constraints strongly limit the option
space. Without the option to encroach into natural or semi-natural land,
trade volumes will rise in scenarios with globally converging diets,
thereby decreasing the food self-sufficiency of many developing regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hydropedology-and-the-societal-challenge-of-realizing-the-2015-united-nations-sustainable-development-goals&quot;&gt;Hydropedology and the Societal Challenge of Realizing the 2015 United Nations Sustainable Development Goals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vzj.geoscienceworld.org/content/15/12/vzj2016.09.0080&quot;&gt;online link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Bouma, J&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;VADOSE ZONE JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, 15 (12):NIL_57-NIL_63; DEC 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The UN Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) offer a major challenge for
both society and the science community. Hydropedology, combining the
expertise of soil physicists and pedologists, plays a key role in
realizing goals focused on food, water, climate, and ecology, requiring
interdisciplinary research. This update explores emerging trends and
future work, focusing on examples of contributions by pedology to
measuring and modeling in hydropedological studies. Many soil types
create heterogeneous flow patterns that are difficult to characterize
using current soil databases and physical flow models. The clear
potential of hydropedology to produce better modeling results than those
obtained from separate contributions by the two subdisciplines can,
however, only be established by field validation of modeling results
using different types of data and models. Overall soil input in
interdisciplinary SDG-oriented research includes chemical and biological
aspects that become more representative by considering hydropedological
conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;processes-and-modeling-of-initial-soil-and-landscape-development-a-review&quot;&gt;Processes and Modeling of Initial Soil and Landscape Development: A Review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vzj.geoscienceworld.org/content/15/12/vzj2016.05.0048&quot;&gt;online link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Maurer, T; Gerke, HH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;VADOSE ZONE JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, 15 (12):NIL_3-NIL_30; DEC 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The development pathway of a landscape depends to a degree on the
initial spatial distributions of mineral and organic components. The
interaction between structures and ecohydrological processes during the
critical initial development period is scarcely understood and often
difficult to observe. While viable modeling approaches exist for most
aspects of initial development (e.g., landscape evolution, vegetation
succession), a deeper understanding of the prevailing feedback
mechanisms requires a comprehensive, integrated modeling approach. We
present a review of the current literature regarding the description of
initial structures, the state-of-the-art of research on
structure-forming processes and their interaction with existing and
newly emerging structures, as well as the corresponding modeling
efforts. The most relevant aspects are (i) sediment translocation
processes and initial evolution of topography, (ii) surface crusting,
(iii) vegetation succession, and (iv) the evolution of the soil pore
space. Based on existing conceptions for integrated modeling of the
coevolution of structures and ecohydrological behavior, we outline an
integrative modeling framework that is based on a three-dimensional
spatial structural model of initial sediment distributions, which can be
used to: (i) analyze the spatiotemporal development dynamics depending
on initial structures; and (ii) relate the simulated structural
development to available observations of initial ecohydrological
development. We discuss possible validation and generalization
strategies of modeling results, and propose to define three-dimensional
spatial functional catchment units (process domains) characterized by
specific structural dynamics and the dominant ecohydrological processes.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/02/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on February 08, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/01/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2017/01/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2017-01-26T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-01-26T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2017-3&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2017 #3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hybrid-integration-of-multilayer-perceptron-neural-networks-and-machine-learning-ensembles-for-landslide-susceptibility-assessment-at-himalayan-area-india-using-gis&quot;&gt;Hybrid integration of Multilayer Perceptron Neural Networks and machine learning ensembles for landslide susceptibility assessment at Himalayan area (India) using GIS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S034181621630368X&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Pham, BT; Bui, DT; Prakash, I; Dholakia, MB&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;CATENA&lt;/em&gt;, 149 52-63; 1 FEB 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The main objective of this study is to evaluate and compare the
performance of landslide models using machine learning ensemble
technique for landslide susceptibility assessment. This technique is a
combination of ensemble methods (AdaBoost, Bagging, Dagging, MultiBoost,
Rotation Forest, and Random SubSpace) and the base classifier of
Multiple Perceptron Neural Networks (MLP Neural Nets). Ensemble
techniques have been widely applied in other fields; however, their
application is still rare in the assessment of landslide problems.
Meanwhile, MLP Neural Nets, which is known as an artificial neural
network, has been applied widely and efficiently in landslide problems.
In the present study, landslide models of part Himalayan area (India)
have been constructed and validated. For the evaluation and comparison
of these models, receiver operating characteristic curve and Chi Square
test methods have been applied. Overall, all landslide models performed
well in landslide susuceptibility assessment but the performance of the
MultiBoost model is the highest (AUC = 0.886), followed by Dagging model
(AUC = 0.885), the Rotation Forest model (AUC = 0.882), the Bagging and
Random SubSpace models (AUC = 0.881), and the AdaBoost model (AUC =
0.876), respectively. Moreover, machine learning ensemble models have
improved significantly the performance of the base classifier of MLP
Neural Nets (AUC = 0.874). Analysis of results indicates that landslide
models using machine learning ensemble frameworks are promising methods
which can be used as alternatives of individual base classifiers for
landslide susceptibility assessment of other prone areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ecosystem-responses-to-land-abandonment-in-western-mediterranean-mountains&quot;&gt;Ecosystem responses to land abandonment in Western Mediterranean Mountains&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0341816216303241&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Romero-Diaz, A; Ruiz-Sinoga, JD; Robledano-Aymerich, F; Brevik, EC;
Cerda, A&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;CATENA&lt;/em&gt;, 149 824-835; SI 3 FEB 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Agricultural expansion in the Mediterranean resulted in plant and soil
degradation due to the intensive use, climate conditions, and rugged
terrain. After abandonment, the recovery of vegetation contributed to
improvement in soil quality from a hydrological, pedological and
geomorphological point of view. This paper shows three examples of
ecosystem evolution in abandoned fields in Valencia, Murcia and
Andalucia and the application of different methodological approaches
that resulted in similar findings. In Valencia, the main responses were
the recovery of vegetation after land abandonment and an increase in
organic matter and infiltration capacity of soils. In Murcia, with the
exception of some terraced areas on marls, where erosion processes
following abandonment were important, land abandonment resulted in
vegetation recovery, improved soil properties, and reduced surface wash
and soil losses. In Andalucia, research along climatological gradients
showed the relationship between vegetation patterns and soil moisture
and the control that climate exerts on hydrological and erosive
behaviour. The experimental research conducted in three different
regions in Western Mediterranean demonstrated that abandonment can
result in recovery of the geo-ecosystem as vegetation and soil quality
improvements were shown. The marls areas in Murcia were the exception
with low soil quality and low vegetation cover, and as a consequence
showed evidence of high erosion rates after abandonment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hydropedology-and-the-societal-challenge-of-realizing-the-2015-united-nations-sustainable-development-goals&quot;&gt;Hydropedology and the Societal Challenge of Realizing the 2015 United Nations Sustainable Development Goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vzj.geoscienceworld.org/content/15/12/vzj2016.09.0080&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Bouma, J&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;VADOSE ZONE JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, 15 (12):NIL_57-NIL_63; DEC 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The UN Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) offer a major challenge for
both society and the science community. Hydropedology, combining the
expertise of soil physicists and pedologists, plays a key role in
realizing goals focused on food, water, climate, and ecology, requiring
interdisciplinary research. This update explores emerging trends and
future work, focusing on examples of contributions by pedology to
measuring and modeling in hydropedological studies. Many soil types
create heterogeneous flow patterns that are difficult to characterize
using current soil databases and physical flow models. The clear
potential of hydropedology to produce better modeling results than those
obtained from separate contributions by the two subdisciplines can,
however, only be established by field validation of modeling results
using different types of data and models. Overall soil input in
interdisciplinary SDG-oriented research includes chemical and biological
aspects that become more representative by considering hydropedological
conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;processes-and-modeling-of-initial-soil-and-landscape-development-a-review&quot;&gt;Processes and Modeling of Initial Soil and Landscape Development: A Review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vzj.geoscienceworld.org/content/15/12/vzj2016.05.0048&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Maurer, T; Gerke, HH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;VADOSE ZONE JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, 15 (12):NIL_3-NIL_30; DEC 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The development pathway of a landscape depends to a degree on the
initial spatial distributions of mineral and organic components. The
interaction between structures and ecohydrological processes during the
critical initial development period is scarcely understood and often
difficult to observe. While viable modeling approaches exist for most
aspects of initial development (e.g., landscape evolution, vegetation
succession), a deeper understanding of the prevailing feedback
mechanisms requires a comprehensive, integrated modeling approach. We
present a review of the current literature regarding the description of
initial structures, the state-of-the-art of research on
structure-forming processes and their interaction with existing and
newly emerging structures, as well as the corresponding modeling
efforts. The most relevant aspects are (i) sediment translocation
processes and initial evolution of topography, (ii) surface crusting,
(iii) vegetation succession, and (iv) the evolution of the soil pore
space. Based on existing conceptions for integrated modeling of the
coevolution of structures and ecohydrological behavior, we outline an
integrative modeling framework that is based on a three-dimensional
spatial structural model of initial sediment distributions, which can be
used to: (i) analyze the spatiotemporal development dynamics depending
on initial structures; and (ii) relate the simulated structural
development to available observations of initial ecohydrological
development. We discuss possible validation and generalization
strategies of modeling results, and propose to define three-dimensional
spatial functional catchment units (process domains) characterized by
specific structural dynamics and the dominant ecohydrological processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;from-robustness-to-resilience-a-network-price-identity-approach&quot;&gt;From robustness to resilience: A network Price identity approach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1476945X16300794&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Dragicevic, AZ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;ECOLOGICAL COMPLEXITY&lt;/em&gt;, 28 47-53; DEC 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
We model a closed-loop network of agents distributed among subnetworks
and study the sustainability of network structures in presence of random
perturbations. The model outcomes show that the stability of
compartmentalized networks built on uniform operators depends on
perturbations on between-subnetwork coupling, while the stability of
networks built on mutation operators depends on their assimilation
capacity. Through the study of eigenvalues of the Laplacian, we succeed
in measuring the degree of network robustness and resilience. Our
results also permit to situate the Price theorem, both in its standard
and expanded forms, in the context of network evolutionary variational
identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fuzzy-based-energy-efficient-sensor-network-protocol-for-precision-agriculture&quot;&gt;Fuzzy based energy efficient sensor network protocol for precision agriculture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0168169916308250&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Maurya, S; Jain, VK&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;COMPUTERS AND ELECTRONICS IN AGRICULTURE&lt;/em&gt;, 130 20-37; NOV 15 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Today’s, wireless sensor network have become a more emerging technology
in precision agriculture. This paper proposes a novel approach based on
sensor network technology to control the irrigation in agricultural
field automatically. All sensor nodes deployed in the field,
continuously sense soil temperature, soil moisture and air humidity of
the agricultural field and transmit this information to base station
only when the user defined periodic timer or sensed attributes values
exceed desired threshold. In the proposed routing protocol, region-based
static clustering approach is used to provide efficient coverage over
entire agricultural area and threshold sensitive hybrid routing is used
for transmitting sensed data to base station. The proposed protocol uses
fuzzy logic technique to select the best cluster head among other sensor
nodes in a particular round which minimizes the energy consumption of
nodes in every data transmission period. The proposed energy-efficient
protocol is compared with existing benchmark EEHC, DEEC, DDEEC and RBHR
routing protocols. The analysis and experimental results show a
significant decrement in data transmission rate due to user-defined
transmission thresholds. The balanced use of fuzzy logic technique,
static clustering and hybrid routing approach efficiently reduce energy
consumption of sensor nodes in every data transmission round and
prolongs the overall network lifetime by 173.16%, 149.22%, 99.49% and
4739% as compared to EEHC, DEEC, DDEEC and RBHR protocol respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mapping-almond-orchard-canopy-volume-flowers-fruit-and-yield-using-lidar-and-vision-sensors&quot;&gt;Mapping almond orchard canopy volume, flowers, fruit and yield using lidar and vision sensors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0168169916308249&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Underwood, JP; Hung, C; Whelan, B; Sukkarieh, S&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;COMPUTERS AND ELECTRONICS IN AGRICULTURE&lt;/em&gt;, 130 83-96; NOV 15 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
This paper present a mobile terrestrial scanning system for almond
orchards, that is able to efficiently map flower and fruit distributions
and to estimate and predict yield for individual trees. A mobile robotic
ground vehicle scans the orchard while logging data from on-board lidar
and camera sensors. An automated software pipeline processes the data
offline, to produce a 3D map of the orchard and to automatically detect
each tree within that map, including correct associations for the same
trees seen on prior occasions. Colour images are also associated to each
tree, leading to a database of images and canopy models, at different
times throughout the season and spanning multiple years. A canopy volume
measure is derived from the 3D models, and classification is performed
on the images to estimate flower and fruit density. These measures were
compared to individual tree harvest weights to assess the relationship
to yield. A block of approximately 580 trees was scanned at peak bloom,
fruit-set and just before harvest for two subsequent years, with up to
50 trees individually harvested for comparison. Lidar canopy volume had
the strongest linear relationship to yield with R-2 = 0.77 for 39 tree
samples spanning two years. An additional experiment was performed using
hand-held photography and image processing to measure fruit density,
which exhibited similar performance (R-2 = 0.71). Flower density
measurements were not strongly related to yield, however, the maps show
clear differentiation between almond varieties and may be useful for
other studies&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/01/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on January 26, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[NEW PAPER! Rapid assessment of petroleum-contaminated soils with infrared spectroscopy]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/01/rapidassess" />
  <id>/2017/01/rapidassess</id>
  <updated>2017-01-25T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-01-25T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;rapid-assessment-of-petroleum-contaminated-soils-with-infrared-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Rapid assessment of petroleum-contaminated soils with infrared spectroscopy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Published in Geoderma 289 (2017) 150-160.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first paper from our new PhD student in the Soil Security Laboratory, Wartini Ng. Soil sensing using infrared spectroscopy has been proposed as an alternative to conventional soil analysis to detect soil contamination. &lt;a href=&quot;/downloads/journal/malone2017_1.pdf&quot;&gt;This study&lt;/a&gt; evaluated the use of field portable and laboratory bench top infrared spectrometers in both the near infrared (NIR) and mid infrared (MIR) region for rapid, non-destructive assessment of petroleum contaminated soils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A laboratory study of soils spiked with petroleum products showed that several
factors can affect the infrared absorbance. These include soil texture, organic matter content, and the types and
concentrations of contaminants. Despite these factors, infrared regions that are affected by hydrocarbon contamination
can be readily found in 2990-2810 cm???1 in the MIR range, and 2300-2340 nm in the NIR range. Using
continuum-removed spectra, the effects of soil and contaminant factors on the absorbance peaks were isolated.
This study also created statistical models to predict total recoverable petroleum hydrocarbons concentration in
soils by utilizing the absorption features found in the mid-infrared region spectra. Subsequently, three different
approaches were tested for the prediction of Total Recoverable Hydrocarbon (TRH) concentration on 72 field
contaminated samples: (i) linear regression using only 1 infrared region, (ii) multiple linear regression (MLR)
using 4 regions in the MIR, and (iii) partial least square regression (PLSR) which use the whole spectra. The
model created using MLR approach for portable MIR spectrometer outperformed the bench top MIR spectrometer
with a coefficient of determination (R2) of 0.71 and 0.53 respectively.While PLSR model for portable spectrometer
show a better prediction for TRH prediction (R2 = 0.75), the MLR can also achieve a similar performance
(R2 = 0.71) by using only 4 regions in the MIR spectra as predictors.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/01/rapidassess&quot;&gt;NEW PAPER! Rapid assessment of petroleum-contaminated soils with infrared spectroscopy&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on January 25, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[NEW PAPER! Digital soil mapping of soil carbon at the farm scale. A spatial downscaling approach in consideration of measured and uncertain data]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/01/downscale" />
  <id>/2017/01/downscale</id>
  <updated>2017-01-24T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-01-24T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;digital-soil-mapping-of-soil-carbon-at-the-farm-scale-a-spatial-downscaling-approach-in-consideration-of-measured-and-uncertain-data&quot;&gt;Digital soil mapping of soil carbon at the farm scale: A spatial downscaling approach in consideration of measured and uncertain data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Published in Geoderma 290 (2017) 91-99.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initiated during 2015, Quentin Styc was a visiting intern student from France to our soil security laboratory for 3 months. I had this idea of spatial downscaling and trying to include observational data into the scheme. Quentin was happy to work on this little problem, and actually presented some preliminary results on this at the 2015 Pedometrics Conference. At the beginning of 2016, i was troubled by the fact that we were not taking into account the uncertainties of the map to be downscaled. Then Budiman Minansy suggested we should use a sequential Gaussian simulation approach, which more-or-less became generating random fields with some predefined spatial structure to add some deviation about the mean. Doing simulations of these random fields with followed up with spatial downscaling, and incorporation of observational data. Overall &lt;a href=&quot;/downloads/journal/malone2017_2.pdf&quot;&gt;this paper&lt;/a&gt; represents a team effort, and a training opportunity for an up and coming soil scientists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read on for the journal abstract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this paper a spatial downscaling method is explored for generating appropriate farm scale digital soil maps. The digital soil map product to be downscaled is an Australian national extent soil carbon map (100 m grid resolution). Taking into account the associated prediction uncertainties of this map, we used a simulation approach based on Gaussian random fields to generate plausible mapping realizations that were in turn downscaled to 10 m resolution for a farm in North-western NSW, Australia. We were able to derive both a downscaled map of soil carbon and associated prediction variance with this approach. Building further upon this development, we then incorporated a bias correction step into the spatial downscaling procedure which permits the inclusion
of field observations as a way to moderate the downscaling results to better reflect actual conditions on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on an independent validation dataset, it was found that incorporating field observations increase the concordance correlation coefficient to 0.8 from 0.2. This relatively lower correlation achieved using spatial downscaling alone was due to the national scale mapping for the study area being positively biased in the area
of interest. It was found that downscaling that incorporates observational data was marginally better if not comparable to using a point-based digital soil mapping approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advantage of spatial downscaling is that it can be implemented in situations of data scarcity. This will be ideal for on farm soil monitoring in situations where
detailed soil mapping is initially not available. For example, soil carbon auditing schemes requiring prior soil information for implementation of design-based soil sampling could potentially be universally applied with such a
spatial downscaling approach.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/01/downscale&quot;&gt;NEW PAPER! Digital soil mapping of soil carbon at the farm scale. A spatial downscaling approach in consideration of measured and uncertain data&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on January 24, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[NEW PAPER! Soil carbon 4 per mille]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/01/4permille" />
  <id>/2017/01/4permille</id>
  <updated>2017-01-24T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-01-24T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;soil-carbon-4-per-mille&quot;&gt;Soil carbon 4 per mille&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Published in Geoderma 292 (2017) 59-86.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ‘4 per mille Soils for Food Security and Climate’ was launched at the COP21 with an aspiration to increase global soil organic matter stocks by 4 per 1000 (or 0.4 %) per year as a compensation for the global emissions of greenhouse gases by anthropogenic sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/downloads/journal/malone2017_3.pdf&quot;&gt;This paper&lt;/a&gt; surveyed the soil organic carbon (SOC) stock estimates and sequestration potentials from 20 regions in the world: New Zealand, Chile, South Africa, Australia, Tanzania,
Indonesia, Kenya, Nigeria, India, China Taiwan, South Korea, China Mainland, United States of America, France, Canada, Belgium, England &amp;amp; Wales, Ireland, Scotland, and Russia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we asked whether the 4 per mille initiative is feasible for the region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outcomes highlight region specific efforts and scopes for soil carbon sequestration. Reported soil C sequestration rates globally show that under best management practices, 4 per mille or even higher sequestration rates can be accomplished. High C sequestration rates (up to 10 per mille) can be achieved for soils with low initial SOC stock (topsoil less than 30 t C ha???1), and at the first twenty years after implementation of best management practices. Additionally, areas which have reached equilibrium will not be able to further increase their sequestration. it was found that most studies on SOC sequestration only consider topsoil (up to 0.3m
depth) as it is considered to be most affected by management techniques. The 4 per mille number was based on a blanket calculation of the whole global soil profile C stock, however the potential to increase SOC is mostly on managed agricultural lands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If we consider 4 per mille in the top 1m of global agricultural soils, SOC sequestration
is between 2-3 Gt C per year, which effectively offset 20-35% of global anthropogenic greenhouse gas emissions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a strategy for climate change mitigation, soil carbon sequestration buys time over the next ten to twenty years while other effective sequestration and low carbon technologies become viable. The challenge for cropping farmers is to find disruptive technologies that will further improve soil condition and deliver increased soil carbon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Progress in 4 per mille requires collaboration and communication between scientists, farmers, policy makers, and marketeers.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/01/4permille&quot;&gt;NEW PAPER! Soil carbon 4 per mille&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on January 24, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/01/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2017/01/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2017-01-16T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-01-16T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2017-2&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2017 #2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rearranging-agricultural-landscapes-towards-habitat-quality-optimisation-in-silico-application-to-pest-regulation&quot;&gt;Rearranging agricultural landscapes towards habitat quality optimisation: In silico application to pest regulation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1476945X16300538&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Parisey, N; Bourhis, Y; Roques, L; Soubeyrand, S; Ricci, B; Poggi, S&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;ECOLOGICAL COMPLEXITY&lt;/em&gt;, 28 113-122; DEC 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1476945X16300538&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Modern agriculture suffers from its dependence on chemical inputs and
subsequent impacts on health and environment. Alternatively, protecting
crops against pests can be achieved through the reinforcement of
regulation ecological services. Our work propounds a data-driven
methodological framework to derive relevant agricultural landscape
rearrangements enhancing populations of beneficial organisms regulating
pests.Building on spatialised entomological and geographic data, we
developed a parsimonious reaction diffusion model describing the
population dynamics of beneficial organisms. Parameter estimation was
carried out in a Bayesian framework accounting for uncertainty in the
measurement.Thousands of agricultural landscapes were generated under
agronomic specifications dealt with as constraint satisfaction problems.
Population dynamics was simulated on each landscape with the fitted
reaction-diffusion model mentioned above, and two metrics of abundances
allowed the assessment of the regulation performance of the landscape
spatial arrangements. One metric is a mean field performance criterion
assessing the regulation performance from the landscape composition
only, the other is a spatial performance metric assessing the
performance resulting from the whole landscape spatial configuration.
The former is computed with a non-spatialised form of the population
dynamics model, the latter results from the reaction-diffusion model of
the population dynamics. Comparing these metrics enabled to quantify the
impact of spatial arrangements, hence allowing arrangements
proposals.This framework was applied to the case study of a ground
beetle species involved in the biological regulation of weeds. The
arrangement proposals abides by the productive agronomic constraint that
is the landscape composition, while they allow for significant habitat
quality enhancement (or deterioration) for the beneficial organism (or a
pest). Minor adaptations of our integrated data-driven approach would
suit numerous situations ranging from the provision of enhanced
ecosystem services to land management for conservation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;toward-mapping-crop-progress-at-field-scales-through-fusion-of-landsat-and-modis-imagery&quot;&gt;Toward mapping crop progress at field scales through fusion of Landsat and MODIS imagery&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0034425716304369&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Gao, F; Anderson, MC; Zhang, XY; Yang, ZW; Alfieri, JG; Kustas, WP;
Mueller, R; Johnson, DM; Prueger, JH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT&lt;/em&gt;, 188 9-25; JAN 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The ability to regionally monitor crop progress and condition through
the growing season benefits both crop management and yield estimation.
In the United States, these metrics are reported weekly at state or
district (multiple counties) levels by the U.S. Department of
Agriculture (USDA) National Agricultural Statistics Service (NASS) using
field observations provided by trained local reporters. However, the
ground data collection process supporting this effort is time consuming
and subjective. Furthermore, operational crop management and yield
estimation efforts require information with more granularity than at the
state or district level. This paper evaluates remote sensing approaches
for mapping crop phenology using vegetation index time-series generated
by fusing Landsat and MODIS (Moderate Resolution Imaging
Spectroradiometer) surface reflectance imagery to improve temporal
sampling over that provided by Landsat alone. The case study focuses on
an agricultural region in central Iowa from 2001 to 2014. Our objectives
are 1) to assess Landsat-MODIS data fusion results over cropland; 2) to
map crop phenology at 30 m resolution using fused surface reflectance
data; and 3) to identify the relationships between remotely sensed crop
phenology metrics and the crop progress stages reported by NASS. The
results show that detailed spatial and temporal variability in
vegetation development across this landscape can be identified using the
fused Landsat-MODIS data. The mean difference (bias) in Normalized
Difference Vegetation Index (NDVI) between actual Landsat observations
and the fused Landsat-MODIS data, generated for Landsat overpass dates,
is in the range of 0.011 to 0.028 for every year. The derived
phenological metrics show distinct features for different crops and
natural vegetation at field scales. Strong correlations are observed
between remotely sensed phenological stages, based on NDVI curve
inflection points, and the observed crop physiological growth stages
from the NASS Crop Progress (CP) reports. The green-up dates detected
from remote sensing data typically occurred during crop vegetative
stages when 2-4 leaves were developed for both corn and soybeans, or
about 1-3 weeks after the reported emergence dates when the plant were
first visible to ground based observers. Despite being a lagging
indicator, remotely sensed green-up can be used effectively to backcast
emergence, e.g. as input to spatially distributed crop models. The
differences in green-up date between corn and soybean were 8-10 days,
consistent with the offset in emergence dates reported by NASS at
district level. The reported harvest dates were typically about 2-3
weeks after the dormancy stage was detected via remote sensing for corn
and about 1-2 weeks for soybeans. This suggests that probable harvest
times for individual fields may be predicted 1-3 weeks ahead using
remote sensing data. The results suggest that crop phenology and certain
growth stages at field scales (30 m spatial resolution) can be linked
and mapped by integrating imagery from multiple remote sensing
platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;landslide-mapping-from-aerial-photographs-using-change-detection-based-markov-random-field&quot;&gt;Landslide mapping from aerial photographs using change detection-based Markov random field&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0034425716303807&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Li, ZB; Shi, WZ; Lu, P; Yan, L; Wang, QM; Miao, ZL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT&lt;/em&gt;, 187 76-90; DEC 15 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Landslide mapping (LM) is essential for hazard prevention, mitigation,
and vulnerability assessment. Despite the great efforts over the past
few years, there is room for improvement in its accuracy and efficiency.
Existing LM is primarily achieved using field surveys or visual
interpretation of remote sensing images. However, such methods are
highly labor-intensive and time-consuming, particularly over large
areas. Thus, in this paper a change detection-based Markov random field
(CDMRF) method is proposed for near-automatic LM from aerial
orthophotos. The proposed CDMRF is applied to a landslide-prone site
with an area of approximately 40 km2 on Lantau Island, Hong Kong.
Compared with the existing region-based level set evolution (RLSE), it
has three main advantages: 1) it employs a more robust threshold method
to generate the training samples; 2) it can identify landslides more
accurately as it takes advantages of both the spectral and spatial
contextual information of landslides; and 3) it needs little parameter
tuning. Quantitative evaluation shows that it outperforms RLSE in the
whole study area by almost 5.5% in Correctness and by 4% in Quality. To
our knowledge, it is the first time CDMRF is used to LM from bitemporal
aerial photographs. It is highly generic and has great potential for
operational LM applications in large areas and also can be adapted for
other sources of imagery data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;does-amsr2-produce-better-soil-moisture-retrievals-than-amsr-e-over-australia&quot;&gt;Does AMSR2 produce better soil moisture retrievals than AMSR-E over Australia?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S003442571630428X&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Cho, ES; Su, CH; Ryu, D; Kim, H; Choi, M&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT&lt;/em&gt;, 188 95-105; JAN 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The Advanced Microwave Scanning Radiometer 2 (AMSR2), a follow-up
microwave sensor to the AMSR for Earth Observing System (AMSR-E), was
launched on the Global Change Observation Mission 1- Water (GCOM-W1)
satellite in May 2012. It is as yet unclear if instrumental improvements
in AMSR2 over AMSR-E have led to better soil moisture (SM) estimates,
especially since there is no overlapping period of data between the
sensors. This study focuses on comparing the results of AMSR2 and AMSR-E
SM over Australia, distinguishing four Koppen climate zones to determine
if AMSR2 is better than AMSR-E. This is achieved by selecting two
year-long comparative time periods from the operating periods of AMSR-E
and AMSR2, based on their statistical similarities in modeled SM as a
proxy, using Modem Era Retrospective-analysis for Research and
Applications-Land (MERRAL). The AMSR2 and AMSR-E C- and X-band SM
derived from the Land Parameter Retrieval Model (LPRM) was evaluated.
Both AMSR2 C- and X-band SM products were found to show similar temporal
patterns and spatial agreement with AMSR-E C- and X-band SM, supported
by unbiased root mean square difference (ubRMSD) and R-values with
MERRA-L SM, respectively. Using lag-based instrumental variable analysis
to estimate the random error component of SM retrievals, the
noise-to-signal ratios in AMSR2 X-band SM were found to be slightly
higher than their AMSR-E counterparts. The improvements in AMSR2, such
as the superior radiometric sensitivity and spatial resolution, have
therefore not led to statistically significant differences in
performance for LPRM retrievals at 1/2 degrees x 1/2 degrees grid
resolution, when compared with AMSR-E. However, similarities in the
metrics for AMSR2 and AMSR-E SM suggest that AMSR2 provides a valuable
continuation to AMSR-E.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-moisture-prediction-of-bare-soil-profiles-using-diffuse-spectral-reflectance-information-and-vadose-zone-flow-modeling&quot;&gt;Soil moisture prediction of bare soil profiles using diffuse spectral reflectance information and vadose zone flow modeling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0034425716304011&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Babaeian, E; Homaee, M; Montzka, C; Vereecken, H; Norouzi, AA; van
Genuchten, MT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT&lt;/em&gt;, 187 218-229; DEC 15 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Soil hydraulic property information of the vadose zone is key to
quantifying the temporal and spatial variability of soil moisture, and
for modeling water flow and contaminant transport processes in the near
surface. This study deals with exploring the feasibility of using
diffuse soil spectral information in the visible, near-infrared and
shortwave infrared range (350-2500 nm) to estimate coarse-scale soil
hydraulic parameters and predict soil moisture profiles using a
topography-based aggregation scheme in conjunction with a 1D mechanistic
water flow model. Three different types of parametric transfer functions
(so-called spectrotransfer functions, STFs; pedotransfer functions,
PTFs; and spectral pedotransfer functions, SPTF5) were aggregated from
the point scale to 1 km(2) pixel size. to provide coarse scale estimates
of van Genuchten-Mualem (VGM) hydraulic parameters. The coarse scale
hydraulic parameters were evaluated by simulating soil water dynamics of
the 1 km(2) pixels across the Zanjanrood River sub-watershed (ZRS) in
northwest Iran. Resultant soil water states were compared with
ground-truth measurements and advanced synthetic aperture radar (ASAR)
estimates of soil water content. The topography-based aggregation scheme
was found to provide effective values of the VGM hydraulic parameters
across the ZRS study site. The coarse scale STFs performed best in terms
of simulating surface, near-surface and subsurface soil water dynamics,
followed by the coarse scale SPTFs and PM, which performed similarly.
The average simulated soil water contents of the surface layer closely
correlated with ASAR estimates during relatively wet periods. Simulated
subsurface soil water dynamics matched well with the ground-truth
measurements. These findings indicate the feasibility of using spectral
data to predict VGM hydraulic parameters and, ultimately, to predict
soil water dynamics at the larger scales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;on-the-performance-of-remote-sensing-time-series-reconstruction-methods---a-spatial-comparison&quot;&gt;On the performance of remote sensing time series reconstruction methods - A spatial comparison&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0034425716303972&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Zhou, J; Jia, L; Menenti, M; Gorte, B&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT&lt;/em&gt;, 187 367-384; DEC 15 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The satellite observed Normalized Difference Vegetation Index (NDVI)
time series, which describe the temporal and spatial variability of
global terrestrial vegetation, are inevitably contaminated by clouds,
aerosol, snow and ice cover. In general all these conditions yield
negative deviations in the time series of NDVI. Many time series
reconstruction models have been developed to eliminate effect of the
negative deviations and most of them perform differently in different
applications and regions. The Harmonic Analysis (HA), Double logistic
(DL), Asymmetric Gaussian (AG), Whittaker smoother (WS) and
Savitzky-Golay filter (SG) are five of the most widely used time series
reconstruction models owing to their simplicity of implementation or the
capability to extract phenological metrics from the time series. The
performance of these models varies with the NDVI signal and the noise
distribution, however, and until now there is no consensus on which
method outperforms all others under all situations. Since the NDVI
signal and the noise distribution are highly dependent on regional
climate and land cover, the reconstruction performance is expected to be
spatially variable. Thus this study compared the five reconstruction
models at pixel scale to provide practical and biome- specific
recommendations for future time series reconstruction applications.
Specifically, the 14 years raw daily reflectance data and ancillary
Quality Assessment (QA) information from the MODIS sensor were used to
generate pixel reference series and noisy series. Then the five
candidate models were applied to both reference series and noisy series
and three reconstruction performance metrics i.e. Overall Reconstruction
Error (ORE), Fitting Related Error (FRE), and Normalized Noise Related
Error (NNRE), were calculated. Finally, the performance of the five
candidate reconstruction models was evaluated by applying the three
metrics. The preliminary results showed that when considering ORE only,
the Asymmetric Gaussian model outperforms other models over most areas
of high latitude boreal region, while the Savitzky-Golay model gives the
best reconstruction performance in tropical and subtropical regions. The
FRE and the NNRE helped to reveal the main error sources in the
reconstruction in different regions. The comparison method developed and
applied in this study led to suggest adaptive selection of the best
reconstruction model for specific NDVI signals and noise distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;scale-and-scaling-in-soils&quot;&gt;Scale and scaling in soils&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0016706116303640&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Pachepsky, Y; Hill, RL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GEODERMA&lt;/em&gt;, 287 4-30; SI FEB 1 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Scale is recognized as a central concept in the description of the
hierarchical organization of our world. Pressing environmental and
societal problems require an understanding of how processes operate at
different scales, and how they can be linked across scales. Soil science
as many other disciplines obtain the bulk of their empirical information
at fine scales, whereas results of environmental diagnostics,
monitoring, and predictions are needed to make important policy
decisions at much larger scales. It becomes imperative to relate the
information that is available and produced at different scales. The
objective of this work is to present an overview of concepts that are
currently used to define and relate scales in soil studies. The paper is
not intended to be a compendium, but rather should be viewed as material
for discussion, reference, and critique. It discusses definitions and
terminology, including general approaches of scale problems in
environmental studies that are applicable to soils, including
hierarchies, measurement metrics, similitude, non-geometric scale
metrics, and notions of upscaling and downscaling. Concepts of general
scaling methods and theories are dimensional analysis, power law
scaling, space and time dependent scaling. A section on spatiotemporal
patterns introduces scaling ideas that were used in soil studies such as
empirical orthogonal functions, data assimilation, and cumulative
distribution function matching. Reviewed scaling methods developed
specifically to soil studies include geometric similitude of pore
spaces, scaling with Richards equation, scale dependencies of water and
solute flux model parameters, scaling based on temporal stability,
overland flow and sediment transport as the scaling phenomenon, and the
relevance of scaling to pedotransfer functions. An outlook for scaling
research in soils is presented that shows the needs of additional
research and the feasibility of using scaling to enrich and advance soil
research to help face the grand challenges of modern times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-unified-expression-for-grain-size-distribution-of-soils&quot;&gt;A unified expression for grain size distribution of soils&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0016706116307649&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Li, Y; Huang, CM; Wang, BL; Tian, XF; Liu, JJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GEODERMA&lt;/em&gt;, 288 105-119; FEB 15 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Grain size distribution (GSD) is fundamental for soils and usually
described by a set of graphic parameters (e.g., median size, kurtosis,
skewness, uniform and curvature coefficient). Some probability
distributions (e.g., lognormal and Weibull distribution) are used for
special cases, but no general expression is available. In this paper we
propose a general distribution form of P(D) = CD(-mu)exp(-D/Dc) for
various soil materials, with P(D) the exceedance percentage and C,mu and
D-c are parameters determined by the grain size frequency data. The
power-law and exponential part of this expression respectively responds
to the self-similar and random processes of grain fragmentation and
accumulation in soil generation and evolution. The GSD parameters are
distinct in soils and their variation reflects the changes in grain
composition, such as the grain migration and segregation in landslides,
avalanches, debris flows and sedimentary deposits. In addition, the GSD
also fits the pore size of granular materials, confirming the grain-pore
duality and suggesting an important role of the GSD expression in
dynamics of soils and granular media in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;does-organic-farming-accumulate-carbon-in-deeper-soil-profiles-in-the-long-term&quot;&gt;Does organic farming accumulate carbon in deeper soil profiles in the long term?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0016706116305109&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Blanco-Canqui, H; Francis, CA; Galusha, TD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GEODERMA&lt;/em&gt;, 288 213-221; FEB 15 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Organic farming systems provide the opportunity to deliver more soil
ecosystem services than conventional practices. One such service could
be soil organic C (SOC) accumulation, but recent debates suggest that
this is unclear. Furthermore, organic farming potential to accumulate
SOC for the entire soil profile is not well known. We quantified the
cumulative SOC stocks, aggregate-associated SOC, and particulate organic
matter (POM) concentrations for the 0-100 cm depth of the soil profile
in a comparative crop rotation experiment in eastern Nebraska after &amp;gt;20
yr of management. We studied: 1) conventional farming, 2) conventional
farming with diversified rotation, 3) organic rotation with alfalfa
(Medicago sativa L) as green manure, and 4) organic rotation receiving
37 Mg ha(-1) yr(-1) cattle manure. All the treatments had been managed
for 40 yr except the organic rotation with green manure, which had been
in place for 20 yr. Organic farming increased SOC stock, aggregate
associated SOC, and POM concentrations but only in the 0-15 cm soil
depth. The SOC stock under organic cattle manure system was 19% greater
than under conventional farming (33.1 Mg ha(-1)) and 13% greater than
under conventional farming with diversified rotation (34.8 Mg ha(-1)).
The SOC stock under organic rotation with green manure (36.6 Mg ha(-1))
was 10% greater than in conventional farming. Results suggest that
organic cropping systems accumulated SOC at 0.16 Mg C ha(-1) yr(-1) with
cattle manure and 0.18 Mg C ha(-1) yr(-1) with green manure. Growing
alfalfa for only two years in the 4-yr organic rotation probably limited
its potential to increase SOC for the whole soil profile. Overall, in
the long term, organic farming increases SOC stock but only in the upper
15 cm of the soil profile&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/01/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on January 16, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>
