<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Smart Digital Agriculture</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2021-07-08T10:15:48+10:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/07/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/07/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-07-07T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-07-07T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-21&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #21&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil organic carbon estimation using VNIR-SWIR spectroscopy: The effect of multiple sensors and scanning conditions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using ground-penetrating radar to investigate the thickness of mollic epipedons developed from loessial parent material&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evaluating validation strategies on the performance of soil property prediction from regional to continental spectral data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Digital soil maps can perform as well as large-scale conventional soil maps for the prediction of catchment baseflows&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimation of root zone soil moisture from ground and remotely sensed soil information with multisensor data fusion and automated machine learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-organic-carbon-estimation-using-vnir-swir-spectroscopy-the-effect-of-multiple-sensors-and-scanning-conditions&quot;&gt;Soil organic carbon estimation using VNIR-SWIR spectroscopy: The effect of multiple sensors and scanning conditions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visible-near infrared-shortwave infrared (VNIR-SWIR) spectroscopy is being increasingly used for soil organic carbon (SOC) assessment. Common practice consists of scanning soil samples using a single spectrometer. Considerations have rarely been documented of the effects of using multiple instruments and scanning conditions on SOC model calibration that occur when merging soil spectral libraries (SSLs), particularly in soils with low SOC concentration and using both field spectroradiometers and laboratory fixed spectrometers. To address this gap, we scanned 143 low-SOC-content soil samples using three spectrometers (ASD FieldSpec 3, ASD FieldSpec 4, and FOSS XDS) and four setup features - FOSS, contact probe (CP), dark-box (DB), and open laboratory (LAB) - at three laboratories. The application of an internal soil standard (ISS) to align one laboratory spectrum with another for spectral correction and spectral merging of various SSLs was examined. SOC models were developed using i) data from each single spectrometer - single laboratory separately and ii) merged data from multiple spectrometers - different laboratories, applying the 1st derivatives of spectra and random forest (RF) regression. The results indicate that the spectral shape and wavelength position of key features obtained from all spectrometers and setups did not show any noticeable differences, though spectra based on FOSS setup, particularly on low-SOC samples, demonstrated greater range in absolute derivative values regardless of ISS application. The derivative ISS-corrected spectra showed less variation among different spectrometers compared to their uncorrected raw reflectance spectra. All single spectrometer models predicted SOC reasonably well. However, the spectra acquired by the FOSS setup predicted SOC more accurately (R2 = 0.77, RPIQ = 3.30, RMSE = 0.22 %, and SD = 0.04) than the spectra acquired by the other setups. The models derived from merged uncorrected raw reflectance spectra yielded poor results (R2 = 0.48, RPIQ = 2.33, RMSE = 0.33 %, and SD = 0.10); nevertheless, assessment of SOC using the 1st derivative ISS-corrected merged SSLs considerably improved the prediction accuracy (R2 = 0.70, RPIQ = 3.10, RMSE = 0.25 %, and SD = 0.06). Hence, the derivative spectra coupled with the ISS correction improved the accuracy of SOC prediction models obtained from the merged soil spectra collected in different environments using different instruments. We therefore recommend application of the ISS spectral alignment method linked to the 1st derivative approach to enhance the compilation of SSLs at the regional and global scales for SOC assessment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-ground-penetrating-radar-to-investigate-the-thickness-of-mollic-epipedons-developed-from-loessial-parent-material&quot;&gt;Using ground-penetrating radar to investigate the thickness of mollic epipedons developed from loessial parent material&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The information of mollic epipedon (ME) thickness was essential for evaluation and protection of Mollisol resource. However, the traditional methods including the soil profile method, soil probes, and the drilling method, are low efficient and accurate for large area survey of soil thickness. In this study, the ground penetrating radar (GPR) was employed to detect the thickness of ME with underlying loessial parent material (LPM) along three slopes in straight, convex, and concave shapes in northeast China. The accuracy of GPR for measuring the ME thickness was verified by using excavation profile and pre-buried iron pipes. The effects of soil moisture and bulk density on soil permittivity were also investigated based on indoor experiments. The results indicated that the soil permittivity increased and decreased with the increase of bulk density and soil moisture, respectively. The relationships among soil moisture, bulk density and permittivity of both Mollisol and LPM could be described by two fitted equations, and the errors of the prediction equations was in the range of 0.32 %-5.10 %. The errors of GPR to measure the ME thickness was in the range of 3.72 %-10.64 %. The spatial distribution of the ME thickness along the three slopes varied, and the concave slope had a thicker ME than the convex and straight slope. Meanwhile, similar trends were shown that the sedimentation at the slope foot led to the thickest ME, while soil erosion at the slope shoulder and back resulted in the thinnest ME. This study could provide an efficient and accurate method to investigate soil thickness for further evaluation and protection of soil resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evaluating-validation-strategies-on-the-performance-of-soil-property-prediction-from-regional-to-continental-spectral-data&quot;&gt;Evaluating validation strategies on the performance of soil property prediction from regional to continental spectral data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visible-near infrared (vis-NIR) spectroscopy has been widely used to characterize soil information from field to global scales. Before applying a calibrated spectral predictive model to acquire soil information, either independent validation or k-fold cross validation is used to evaluate model performance. However, there is no consensus on which validation strategy is more suitable and robust when evaluating model performance for the studies in different scales. The objective of this study is to evaluate and compare the model performance of two validation strategies coupling different calibration sizes (a ratio of calibration to validation of 2:1, 4:1 and 9:1) and calibration sampling strategies (random sampling (RS), rank, Kennard-Stone (KS), rank-Kennard-Stone (RKS) and conditioned Latin hypercube sampling (cLHS)) across scales. A total of 17,272 vis-NIR spectra of mineral soils from LUCAS data (continental scale) and their soil organic carbon (SOC) and clay contents were used in this study, and the dataset was further split into national (2761 samples in France) and five regional datasets (110 to 248 samples from five French administrative regions). To eliminate the effect of changing validation set on the model performance, a consistent test set (20% of total samples at each scale) was split to evaluate all the combinations involved in two validation strategies. The Lin’s concordance correlation coefficient (CCC) of the cubist model were stable for both SOC and clay for different calibration sizes, calibration sampling and validation strategies for a large calibration size (&amp;gt;1400) at the national and continental scales. A larger calibration size can potentially improve model performance for a small dataset (&amp;lt;300) at the regional scale, and a wider calibration range would result in better model performance. No silver bullet was found among the different calibration sampling strategies at the regional scale. For five French regions (small data set), we found a high variation (95th percentile minus the 5th percentile) in the CCC among the models built from 50 repeated RS (0.10-0.44 for SOC, 0.16-0.52 for clay) and cLHS (0.08-0.40 for SOC, 0.12-0.36 for clay). This finding indicates that a one-time RS or cLHS for selecting the calibration set has high uncertainty in model evaluation for a small dataset and therefore should be used with caution. Therefore, we suggest the following: (1) for a large data set (thousands), either one-time random sampling for independent validation or k-fold cross validation would be appropriate; (2) for a small data set (dozens to hundreds), k-fold cross validation and/or repeated random sampling for independent validation would be more robust for spectral predictive model evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;digital-soil-maps-can-perform-as-well-as-large-scale-conventional-soil-maps-for-the-prediction-of-catchment-baseflows&quot;&gt;Digital soil maps can perform as well as large-scale conventional soil maps for the prediction of catchment baseflows&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rapid advance of digital soil mapping (DSM) has resulted in the generation of fine resolution soils spatial datasets with associated uncertainty that can be as accurate but more cost-effective and faster to produce than conventional soil maps. There is documented and increasing interest by policy makers and end-users in moving from conventional soil mapping to DSM; however, the wider operational use of DSM depends on demonstrating the effectiveness of DSM in fulfilling user needs and requirements along with providing DSM products that can be easily used by non-specialists. In this study we used the Hydrology of Soil Types (HOST) classification scheme, which was devised to predict flows in ungauged catchments and is used by both the research and policy maker communities in the UK, as the exemplar for comparing the efficiency of HOST class maps produced using both DSM and conventional soil map approaches for predicting catchment hydrological response. The performance for hydrological predictions of a detailed (1:25,000 scale) polygon HOST class map and a HOST-DSM class map produced via spatial disaggregation was assessed by comparing Base Flow Index (BFI) calculated using HOST class proportions from both maps with BFI calculated using flow data from gauges in 39 selected catchments. Results showed that the disaggregated HOST-DSM class map gave similar or even better BFI predictions than the conventional polygon-based HOST class map, while also providing a better insight on spatial soil variability within map units and its effect on hydrological predictions. This study demonstrates the potential of DSM to produce soil hydrological maps that provide comparable or better baseflow predictions than maps produced using detailed and intensive soil surveying. The study results also suggest that translating DSM of classes to more easily interpretable mapping datasets and incorporating prediction uncertainty in the final DSM product, as in the case of BFI maps based on HOST-DSM classes, could help with facilitating the transition towards a wider operational use of DSM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;estimation-of-root-zone-soil-moisture-from-ground-and-remotely-sensed-soil-information-with-multisensor-data-fusion-and-automated-machine-learning&quot;&gt;Estimation of root zone soil moisture from ground and remotely sensed soil information with multisensor data fusion and automated machine learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Root zone soil moisture (RZSM) estimation and monitoring based on high spatial resolution remote sensing information such as obtained with an Unmanned Aerial System (UAS) is of significant interest for field-scale precision irrigation management, particularly in water-limited regions of the world. To date, there is no accurate and widely accepted model that relies on UAS optical surface reflectance observations for RZSM estimation at high spatial resolution. This study is aimed at the development of a new approach for RZSM estimation based on the fusion of high spatial resolution optical reflectance UAS observations with physical and hydraulic soil information integrated into Automated Machine Learning (AutoML). The H2O AutoML platform includes a number of advanced machine learning algorithms that efficiently perform feature selection and automatically identify complex relationships between inputs and outputs. Twelve models combining UAS optical observations with various soil properties were developed in a hierarchical manner and fed into AutoML to estimate surface, near-surface, and root zone soil moisture. The addition of independently measured surface and near-surface soil moisture information to the hierarchical models to improve RZSM estimation was investigated. The accuracy of soil moisture estimates was evaluated based on a comparison with Time Domain Reflectometry (TDR) sensors that were deployed to monitor surface, near-surface and root zone soil moisture dynamics. The obtained results indicate that the consideration of physical and hydraulic soil properties together with UAS optical observations improves soil moisture estimation, especially for the root zone with a RMSE of about 0.04 cm3 cm-3. Accurate RZSM estimates were obtained when measured surface and near-surface soil moisture data was added to the hierarchical models, yielding RMSE values below 0.02 cm3 cm-3 and R and NSE values above 0.90. The generated high spatial resolution RZSM maps clearly capture the spatial variability of soil moisture at the field scale. The presented framework can aid farm scale precision irrigation management via improving the crop water use efficiency and reducing the risk of groundwater contamination.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/07/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on July 07, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/07/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/07/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-07-01T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-07-01T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-22&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #22&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Responses of soil carbon and nitrogen cycles to the physical influences of rock fragment in soils&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A review on the possible factors influencing soil inorganic carbon under elevated CO2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Development of functions to predict soil hydraulic properties that account for solution sodicity and salinity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identification of minerals in subtropical soils with different textural classes by VIS-NIR-SWIR reflectance spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A rapid qualitative methodology for ecological integrity assessment across a Mediterranean island’s landscapes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A framework for ecosystem service assessment using GIS interoperability standards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;responses-of-soil-carbon-and-nitrogen-cycles-to-the-physical-influences-of-rock-fragment-in-soils&quot;&gt;Responses of soil carbon and nitrogen cycles to the physical influences of rock fragment in soils&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rock fragments (RFs, mineral particles with diameter &amp;gt; 2 mm) can substantially influence soil carbon (C) and nitrogen (N) cycles through different physical mechanisms. These physical mechanisms include changing soil hydraulic parameters (vSH) by reducing fine earth bulk density (vSHBD) and volume (vSHVo), and affecting soil C and N stocks (vCN) by reducing fine earth bulk density (vCNBD) and volume (vCNVo), and increasing fine earth C and N concentrations (vCNCo). In this study, based on soil and climate data in a typical hilly area of China, we construct scenarios by considering these physical mechanisms to investigate the responses of key soil C and N outputs (carbon dioxide or CO2, and nitrous oxide or N2O emissions, and N leaching) to RF content (RFC) in DNDC and DayCent models. Results showed that when considering vSH and vCN, parabolic relationships were observed between these soil C and N outputs and RFC, with maximum in RFC = 0.3-0.6 g g(-1). The vCN dominated the responses of soil CO2 emission to RFC, while vSH exerted comparative contributions to the responses of soil N2O emission and N leaching. When only considering vSH, opposite contributions of vSHBD and vSHVo were observed in DNDC model, and contributions of vSHBD overwhelmed those of vSHVo. However, vSHVo dominated these responses in DayCent model. When only considering vCN, the vCNCo dominated these responses, though considerable superimposed influences of vCNBD and vCNVo appeared under high RFC. The discrepancies between these responses to RFC in DNDC and DayCent models might be due to the different model complexities in simulating soil hydrology, biogeochemistry, and the role of bulk density in these models. Relatively, more distinct responses were achieved in DNDC model. These findings can extend our understandings of RFs and soil C and N cycles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-review-on-the-possible-factors-influencing-soil-inorganic-carbon-under-elevated-co2&quot;&gt;A review on the possible factors influencing soil inorganic carbon under elevated CO2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil inorganic carbon (SIC) is the largest pool (approximate to 950 Pg of soil carbonate + 1404 Pg of bicarbonate in groundwater; i.e., 1 Pg = 10(15) g = 1 gigaton) of the global carbon cycle at a 100 cm depth, and it might be a significant carbon source and sink in arid and semi-arid regions. The knowledge of the impacts of changing climatic conditions on this important soil structural component is minimal. This review paper provides an inclusive compilation of the available information on potential natural and anthropogenic factors triggering soil acidification and weathering mechanisms under elevated CO2. Furthermore, the consequences of elevated atmospheric CO2 on the SIC pool, soil quality, and compromised ecosystem services have been explored. Soil water content and precipitation are critical factors that influence the effects of elevated CO2 in the SIC pool. Soil microbiological properties, respiration, depth, weathering, precipitation, acidity, and fertilization are emphasized here owing to the high degree of interrelationship between these factors on influencing overall soil quality. These phenomena are then outlined together with comments about possible short and long-term consequences in SIC stock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;development-of-functions-to-predict-soil-hydraulic-properties-that-account-for-solution-sodicity-and-salinity&quot;&gt;Development of functions to predict soil hydraulic properties that account for solution sodicity and salinity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturated soil hydraulic conductivity (K-sat) and the soil water characteristic curve have been predicted from soil texture, bulk density, and other soil physical properties. These previous functions do not account for soil clay mineralogy or soil solution composition. The objectives of this study were to: (1) analyze the performance of previously developed pedotransfer functions (PTFs) on saline and sodic soils, (2) predict hydraulic properties of saline and sodic soils with a range of clay mineralogy, and (3) develop PTFs that account for clay mineralogy and solution composition. Most PTFs do not perform well on soils with smectitic clay mineralogy and usually overestimate K-sat and under-estimate soil water characteristic on smectite clay dominant soils. Accounting for soil cation exchange capacity (CEC) as an indicator of soil clay types and solution composition improved the prediction of K-sat which had a geometric root mean squared error of 3.28 cm day(-1) compared to 6.04 cm day(-1) for the best performing PTF from the literature. A PTF we developed to predict soil water characteristic curve was able to predict soil water characteristic curve with a root mean squared error of 0.032 g g(-1) compared to 0.082 g g(-1) for the best performing previously published PTF. The PTFs developed in this study improved prediction of soil hydraulic properties on salt affected soils by using soil CEC to account for soil clay behavior and responsiveness to the soil solution composition. The PTFs reported here can easily be used to predict the K-sat and the soil water characteristic curve of soils in response to changes in irrigation water quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;identification-of-minerals-in-subtropical-soils-with-different-textural-classes-by-vis-nir-swir-reflectance-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Identification of minerals in subtropical soils with different textural classes by VIS-NIR-SWIR reflectance spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The physical and chemical attributes of soils are strongly influenced by the nature of the minerals they contain and their concentration. Thus, soil texture is directly dependent on the content in clayey minerals, which influences a number of characteristics such as water dynamics. Although the mineralogical composition of soil is usually determined by X-ray diffraction spectroscopy, this technique is expensive and time-consuming, and uses toxic materials, all of which makes it impractical for obtaining large data sets. Also, available methods for acquiring, interpreting and examining visible-near infrared-shortwave infrared (VIS-NIR-SWIR) spectra are largely ineffective with tropical soils. The aim of this work was to ascertain whether VIS-NIR-SWIR reflectance spectroscopy (350-2500 nm) is useful for identifying minerals in subtropical soils as classified by textural class. For this purpose, soil samples were collected at 66 points at three different soil depths (0-20, 20-40 and 40-60 cm) over a study area located in the State of Rio Grande do Sul (Brazil). The soil texture were determined with the pipette method, and soil spectra were recorded on a FieldSpec Pro VIS-NIR-SWIR laboratory spectrophotometer. Soil minerals were identified, and their proportions determined, from the second-derivative of the Kubelka-Munk (KM) function for the spectra. Five main minerals were thus identified from their spectral signatures, namely: hematite, goethite, kaolinite, chlorite and illite. Identification of the minerals was facilitated by classifying the samples according to texture. The higher the clay content was, the higher was the spectral amplitude of the minerals identified. Those textural classes with the highest clay contents exhibited the greatest proportions of iron oxides and of clay minerals such as kaolinite. These relationships allowed more comprehensive analysis of the soils and expeditious characterization of the study area in terms of texture and mineralogy with a view to facilitating decision-making agricultural support policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-rapid-qualitative-methodology-for-ecological-integrity-assessment-across-a-mediterranean-islands-landscapes&quot;&gt;A rapid qualitative methodology for ecological integrity assessment across a Mediterranean island’s landscapes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rapid qualitative field methods can be used to evaluate ecological integrity (EI) at a landscape level. This study evaluates the EI of 63 landscape types (LCTs) in Cyprus derived from Landscape Character Mapping. Following a stratified sampling, LCTs were evaluated using 209 Land Description Units (LDUs) i.e., homogeneous map entities, sharing a similar pattern of natural and cultural elements. In every LDU, six ecological integrity (EI) indicators were visually assessed consistently namely naturalness, habitat continuity, number of habitats, dominant habitat type, management intensity and scale. TwoStep Cluster Analysis was employed to identify EI categories, and Categorical Principal Components Analysis (CATPCA) to associate the individual indicators with overall EI in the LDUs. Linear regressions were used to predict EI based on the most important indicators. Forested and shrubland landscapes have consistently good EI with low variation, while urbanized and agricultural landscapes have lower EI. There is great variation in the number of agricultural landscape types and their EI. There are significant linear relationships between EI and naturalness, habitat continuity and intensity. The novelty of this work lies with the fact that it provides the first island-wide study in the Mediterranean assessing EI spatially through a small number of indicators. Results indicate that LCA can be an appropriate consistent and inexpensive spatial framework for assessing EI, which can be directly associated with management intervention to maintain or improve EI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-framework-for-ecosystem-service-assessment-using-gis-interoperability-standards&quot;&gt;A framework for ecosystem service assessment using GIS interoperability standards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ecosystem Services Web Services (ESWS) are new web-based approaches to quantifying the benefits that humans derive from nature. Specifically, ESWS are the application of open web standards to ecosystem service assessment to facilitate creation, iteration, and dissemination in a seamless way. This integration streamlines collaboration, automation, and curation, while providing an open interface through which novel advances can be incorporated. The approach creates a new level of interoperability through data provenance whereby each transition between processing steps employs standards that ensure cohesive workflows across models and platforms. This imparts a modularity that can be examined and extended at every step.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/07/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on July 01, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/06/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/06/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-06-24T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-06-24T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-20&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #20&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One size does not fit all: Toward regional conservation practice guidance to reduce phosphorus loss risk in the Lake Erie watershed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Regional ensemble modeling reduces uncertainty for digital soil mapping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Concept, Practice, Application and Results of Locally Based Monitoring of the Environment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connecting Top-Down and Bottom-Up Approaches in Environmental Observing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Use of Digital Platforms for Community-Based Monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amalgamation and harmonization of soil survey reports into a multi-purpose database&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multisensor fusion of remotely sensed vegetation indices using space-time dynamic linear models&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do soil health tests match farmer experience? Assessing biological, physical, and chemical indicators in the Upper Midwest United States&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evaluating three calibration transfer methods for predictions of soil properties using mid-infrared spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continuous in situ soil nitrate sensors: The importance of high-resolution measurements across time and a comparison with salt extraction-based methods&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bayesian-based time-varying multivariate drought risk and its dynamics in a changing environment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transferring Hydrologic Data Across Continents - Leveraging Data-Rich Regions to Improve Hydrologic Prediction in Data-Sparse Regions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;one-size-does-not-fit-all-toward-regional-conservation-practice-guidance-to-reduce-phosphorus-loss-risk-in-the-lake-erie-watershed&quot;&gt;One size does not fit all: Toward regional conservation practice guidance to reduce phosphorus loss risk in the Lake Erie watershed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agricultural phosphorus (P) losses to surface water bodies remain a global eutrophication concern, despite the application of conservation practices on farm fields. Although it is generally agreed upon that the use of multiple conservation practices (“stacking”) will lead to greater improvements to water quality, this may not be cost effective to farmers, reducing the likelihood of adoption. At present, wholesale recommendations of conservation practices are given; however, the application of specific conservation practices in certain environments (e.g., no-till with surface application, cover crops) may not be effective and can even lead to unintended consequences. In this paper, we present the Lake Erie watershed as a case study. The Lake Erie watershed contains regions with unique physical geographies that include differences in climate, soil, topography, and land use, which have implications for both P transport from agricultural fields and the efficacy of conservation practices in mitigating P losses. We define major regions within the Lake Erie watershed where common strategies for conservation practice implementation are appropriate, and we propose a five-step plan for bringing regionally tailored, adaptive, and cost-conscious conservation practice into watershed planning. Although this paper is specific to the Lake Erie watershed, our framework can be transferred across broader geographic regions to provide guidance for watershed planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;regional-ensemble-modeling-reduces-uncertainty-for-digital-soil-mapping&quot;&gt;Regional ensemble modeling reduces uncertainty for digital soil mapping&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent country and continental-scale digital soil mapping efforts have used a single model to predict soil properties across large regions. However, different ecophysiographic regions within large-extent areas are likely to have different soil-landscape relationships so models built specifically for these regions may more accurately capture these relationships relative to a ‘global’ model. We ask the question: Is a single ‘global’ model sufficient or are regionally-specific models useful for accurate digital soil mapping? We test this question by modeling soil depth classes across the 432,000 km(2) upper Colorado River Basin in the Western USA using a single global model, multiple ecophysiographic models, and ensembles of the ecophysiographic models.
Effective soil depth class observations (n = 12,194) were derived from multiple soil databases. Fifty-seven environmental covariates were derived from a 30 m digital elevation model, climate data, satellite imagery, and aeroradiometric data. Three independent land classifications were used to stratify the area. Two expert-derived land classifications, USDA Major Land Resource Areas (MLRA) and US-EPA Level III ecoregions, divided the study area into multiple ecophysiographic regions based on vegetation and broad-scale physiographic differences. The third land classification divided the study area into broad landforms.
Soil depth observations were split into separate training (n = 10,470) and validation (n = 1,724) datasets. First, a ‘global’ random forest model was used to model soil depth classes using all training observations and covariates. ‘Global’ denotes a model built with all training data across the extent of the area, not a model at world extent. Second, the land classifications were used to subset the observations into ecophysiographic sub-datasets and random forest models were refit for each region. Models fit by ecophysiographic region are referred to as regional models. Thirdly, predictions from each regional model were fused into regional-ensemble models. Accuracy, Brier scores, and Shannon’s entropy were used to compare model accuracy and uncertainty. Regional ecophysiographic models were also compared to models built for geographic areas that were defined solely to be approximately equal in area. Training dataset density and the imbalance ratio were investigated to determine if data characteristics influenced regional accuracy/uncertainty metrics.
Accuracy for the global model using the validation set was 62.8%. Regional model accuracies ranged between 56.1% and 75.0%. We found: 1) useful inter-regional differences in global model accuracy were revealed when the global model was validated by region, 2) no consistent relationship between training observation density and accuracy/uncertainty metrics, 3) no meaningful differences in accuracy and uncertainty metrics between physiographic and geographic regions, 4) ensembles of regionally-specific models were approximately as accurate as global models, and 5) both region-specific models and ensembles of regional models were less uncertain than the global model. Overall, we recommend the use of soil depth class predictions made from MLRA regional ensemble models because this prediction had higher accuracy than the ecoregion ensemble model prediction, but lower uncertainty than both the global model and the landform ensemble model predictions. We answer our question: Ensembles of regionally-specific models are approximately as accurate as global models, but result in less uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-concept-practice-application-and-results-of-locally-based-monitoring-of-the-environment&quot;&gt;The Concept, Practice, Application and Results of Locally Based Monitoring of the Environment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Locally based monitoring is typically undertaken in areas in which communities have a close attachment to their natural resource base. We present a summary of work to develop a theoretical and practical understanding of locally based monitoring and we outline tests of this approach in research and practice over the past 20 years. Our tests show that locally based monitoring delivers credible data at local scale independent of external experts and can be used to inform local and national decision making within a short time frame. We believe that monitoring conducted by and anchored in communities will gain in importance where scientist-led monitoring is sparse or too expensive to sustain and for ecosystem attributes in cases in which remote sensing cannot provide credible data. The spread of smartphone technology and online portals will further enhance the importance and usefulness of this discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;connecting-top-down-and-bottom-up-approaches-in-environmental-observing&quot;&gt;Connecting Top-Down and Bottom-Up Approaches in Environmental Observing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Effective responses to rapid environmental change rely on observations to inform planning and decision-making. Reviewing literature from 124 programs across the globe and analyzing survey data for 30 Arctic community-based monitoring programs, we compare top-down, large-scale program driven approaches with bottom-up approaches initiated and steered at the community level. Connecting these two approaches and linking to Indigenous and local knowledge yields benefits including improved information products and enhanced observing program efficiency and sustainability. We identify core principles central to such improved links: matching observing program aims, scales, and ability to act on information; matching observing program and community priorities; fostering compatibility in observing methodology and data management; respect of Indigenous intellectual property rights and the implementation of free, prior, and informed consent; creating sufficient organizational support structures; and ensuring sustained community members’ commitment. Interventions to overcome challenges in adhering to these principles are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-use-of-digital-platforms-for-community-based-monitoring&quot;&gt;The Use of Digital Platforms for Community-Based Monitoring&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Environmental observing programs that are based on Indigenous and local knowledge increasingly use digital technologies. Digital platforms may improve data management in community-based monitoring (CBM) programs, but little is known about how their use translates into tangible results. Drawing on published literature and a survey of 18 platforms, we examine why and how digital platforms are used in CBM programs and illuminate potential challenges and opportunities. Digital platforms make it easy to collect, archive, and share CBM data, facilitate data use, and support understanding larger-scale environmental patterns through interlinking with other platforms. Digital platforms, however, also introduce new challenges, with implications for the sustainability of CBM programs and communities’ abilities to maintain control of their own data. We expect that increased data access and strengthened technical capacity will create further demand within many communities for ethically developed platforms that aid in both local and larger-scale decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;amalgamation-and-harmonization-of-soil-survey-reports-into-a-multi-purpose-database&quot;&gt;Amalgamation and harmonization of soil survey reports into a multi-purpose database&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a growing demand for standardized, easily accessible, and detailed information pertaining to soil and its variability across the landscape. Typically, this information is only available for selected areas in the form of local or regional soil surveys reports which are difficult, and costly, to develop. Additionally, soil surveying protocols have changed with time, resulting in inconsistencies between surveys conducted over different periods. This article describes systematic procedures applied to generate an aspatial, terminologically, and unit-consistent, database for forest soils from county-based soil survey reports for the province of New Brunswick, Canada. The procedures involved (i) amalgamating data from individual soil surveys following a hierarchical framework, (ii) summarizing and grouping soil information by soil associations, (iii) assigning correct soil associates to each association, with each soil associate distinguished by drainage classification, (iv) assigning pedologically correct horizon sequences, as identified in the original soil surveys, to each soil associate, (v) assigning horizon descriptors and measured soil properties to each horizon, as outlined by the Canadian System of Soil Classification, and (vi) harmonizing units of measurement for individual soil properties. Identification and summarization of all soil associations (and corresponding soil associates) was completed with reference to the principal soil-forming factors, namely soil parent material, topographic surface expressions, soil drainage, and dominant vegetation type(s). This procedure, utilizing 17 soil surveys, resulted in an amalgamated database containing 106 soil associations, 243 soil associates, and 522 soil horizon sequences summarizing the variability of forest soil conditions across New Brunswick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;multisensor-fusion-of-remotely-sensed-vegetation-indices-using-space-time-dynamic-linear-models&quot;&gt;Multisensor fusion of remotely sensed vegetation indices using space-time dynamic linear models&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High spatiotemporal resolution maps of surface vegetation from remote sensing data are desirable for vegetation and disturbance monitoring. However, due to the current limitations of imaging spectrometers, remote sensing datasets of vegetation with high temporal frequency of measurements have lower spatial resolution, and vice versa. In this research, we propose a space-time dynamic linear model to fuse high temporal frequency data (MODIS) with high spatial resolution data (Landsat) to create high spatiotemporal resolution data products of a vegetation greenness index. The model incorporates the spatial misalignment of the data and models dependence within and across land cover types with a latent multivariate Matern process. To handle the large size of the data, we introduce a fast estimation procedure and a moving window Kalman smoother to produce a daily, 30-m resolution data product with associated uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-soil-health-tests-match-farmer-experience-assessing-biological-physical-and-chemical-indicators-in-the-upper-midwest-united-states&quot;&gt;Do soil health tests match farmer experience? Assessing biological, physical, and chemical indicators in the Upper Midwest United States&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil health testing provides an integrated assessment of biological, physical, and chemical attributes to inform the sustainable management of farm fields. However, it is unclear how tests reflect farmers’ own assessments of soil quality and agronomic performance, which may disproportionately influence farm management practices. We asked farmers in three regions of Michigan to identify three fields to compare their own assessments against soil health tests: a “best,” a “worst,” and a “non-row crop” reference field. Each field was tested for soil aggregate stability, available water capacity, soil organic matter (SOM), mineralizable carbon (MinC), permanganate oxidizable carbon (POXC), pH, P, and K. We evaluated soil health scores using paired t tests to compare results from contrasting fields with farmers’ assessments of each field. Across all farms, the overall soil health test score for cropped fields was significantly higher on fields farmers rated as “Best.” This result was driven solely by physical and biological (including C) parameters; inorganic chemical tests did not distinguish among field types. On reference fields in all regions, biological parameters were consistently higher, but inorganic chemical and physical measures were not. The performance of soil C measures was inconsistent: SOM and MinC consistently detected significant differences between “Best” and “Worst” cropped fields, but POXC did not. Our results suggest that common soil health assays for physical and biological attributes generally align well with farmers’ assessments of their fields. That soil health tests match farmer experience reinforces the value of these tests as a meaningful guide for soil management decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evaluating-three-calibration-transfer-methods-for-predictions-of-soil-properties-using-mid-infrared-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Evaluating three calibration transfer methods for predictions of soil properties using mid-infrared spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mid-infrared (MIR) spectroscopy models have been developed for rapid assessment of soils but are often soil and instrument specific because of differences in laboratory conditions and sensor setup. Calibration transfer is required to apply a spectral model such as partial least squares (PLS) regression developed from a primary instrument to a spectral dataset measured by a secondary instrument with statistically retained accuracy and precision. The study aimed to compare the performance of three transfer methods (i.e., direct standardization [DS], piecewise direct standardization [PDS], and spectral space transfer [SST]) and investigate the effects of transfer sample size and sample selection methods. The transfer methods were developed for predicting total C, clay, silt, and sand contents, cation exchange capacity (CEC), pH in water (pH(W)) and CaCl2, CaCO3 equivalent, and -1,500-kPa water retention using spectral measurements of a secondary instrument. Calibration transfer methods of three PLS models for estimating soil properties with a high (total C), intermediate (clay content), and low (pH(W)) predictability were discussed. The effect of sample size required for the development of the calibration transfer and the selection method of the transferred samples were investigated. It was found that SST was most favorable for a relatively small sample size used in calibration transfer (&amp;lt;= 12 samples). The performance of transfer methods was optimal when the transfer samples accounted for the variability of MIR spectra from the secondary instrument. We conclude that SST and PDS have the potential to be applied in spectroscopy for predicting soil properties using secondary instruments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;continuous-in-situ-soil-nitrate-sensors-the-importance-of-high-resolution-measurements-across-time-and-a-comparison-with-salt-extraction-based-methods&quot;&gt;Continuous in situ soil nitrate sensors: The importance of high-resolution measurements across time and a comparison with salt extraction-based methods&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil NO3- affects microbial processes, plant productivity, and environmental N losses. However, the ability to measure soil NO3- is limited by labor-intensive sampling and laboratory analyses. Hence, temporal variation in soil solution NO3- concentration is poorly understood. We evaluated a new potentiometric sensor that continuously measures soil solution NO3- concentration with unprecedented specificity due to a novel membrane that serves as a barrier to interfering anions. First, we compared sensor and salt extraction-based measurements of soil NO3- in well-controlled laboratory conditions. Second, using 60 d of in situ soil NO3- measurements every 10 s, we quantified temporal variation and the effect of sampling frequency on field estimations of mean daily NO3- concentration both within and across days. In the laboratory, sensors measured soil NO3- concentration without significant difference from theoretical adjusted soil NO3- concentration or conventional salt extraction-based methods. In the field, the sensors demonstrated no within-day pattern in soil NO3- concentration, although individual measurements within a day differed by as much as 20% from the daily mean. Across days, when soil solution NO3- was dynamic (early spring) and sampling frequency was &amp;gt;5 d, estimates of mean daily NO3- concentration were &amp;gt;20% from the actual mean daily concentration. In situ soil sensors offer potential to improve fundamental and applied sciences. However, in most situations, sensors will measure soil properties in a different manner than conventional salt-extract soil sampling-based approaches. Research will be required to interpret sensor measurements and optimize sensor deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bayesian-based-time-varying-multivariate-drought-risk-and-its-dynamics-in-a-changing-environment&quot;&gt;Bayesian-based time-varying multivariate drought risk and its dynamics in a changing environment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drought is one of the most damaging but least understood environmental disasters. The time-varying multi variate drought risk and its dynamics have remained unresolved in a changing environment. To this end, a Bayesian framework with time in its location parameter as a covariate was introduced in this study to conduct time-varying distributions of duration and severity. Besides, the joint distribution of precipitation and runoff was developed by bivariate non-parameter density kernel estimation for multivariate drought index NKMSDI (Nonparametric Kernel Multivariate Standardized Drought Index) and Expected Waiting Time (EWT)-based return period was used to estimate drought risk. Finally, the time-varying risk trends were explored and verified via correlations between drought risk and Normalized Difference Vegetation Index series. Results indicate that: (1) bivariate return period is more accurate than univariate return period for drought risk assessment and return periods under non-stationary assumption are more reasonable than those under stationary assumption; (2) the multivariate drought risks present obviously increasing trends and the western basin shows the highest increasing rate; and (3) the increasing drought risks exhibit strong association with sunspot activities and local vegetation dynamics. In general, this study provides new insights into drought risk and its dynamics under the time-varying drought properties condition, which is highly important for robust and effective management practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;transferring-hydrologic-data-across-continents---leveraging-data-rich-regions-to-improve-hydrologic-prediction-in-data-sparse-regions&quot;&gt;Transferring Hydrologic Data Across Continents - Leveraging Data-Rich Regions to Improve Hydrologic Prediction in Data-Sparse Regions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a drastic geographic imbalance in available global streamflow gauge and catchment property data, with additional large variations in data characteristics. As a result, models calibrated in one region cannot normally be migrated to another without significant modifications. Currently in these regions, non-transferable machine learning models are habitually trained over small local data sets. Here we show that transfer learning (TL), in the senses of weight initialization and weight freezing, allows long short-term memory (LSTM) streamflow models that were pretrained over the conterminous United States (CONUS, the source data set) to be transferred to catchments on other continents (the target regions), without the need for extensive catchment attributes available at the target location. We demonstrate this possibility for regions where data are dense (664 basins in Great Britain), moderately dense (49 basins in central Chile), and scarce with only remotely sensed attributes available (5 basins in China). In both China and Chile, the TL models showed significantly elevated performance compared to locally trained models using all basins. The benefits of TL increased with the amount of available data in the source data set, and seemed to be more pronounced with greater physiographic diversity. The benefits from TL were greater than from pretraining LSTM using the outputs from an uncalibrated hydrologic model. These results suggest hydrologic data around the world have commonalities which could be leveraged by deep learning, and synergies can be had with a simple modification of the current workflows, greatly expanding the reach of existing big data. Finally, this work diversified existing global streamflow benchmarks.
Plain Language Summary We introduced a method to utilize available big data to better start and warm up a machine learning streamflow model that is later fine-tuned for prediction in basins on other continents (Asia, South America and Europe). This procedure noticeably improved streamflow volume prediction for different scenarios with varying amounts of data in the target basins (in terms of time period, length of collected data, and number of basins having data). This allows thousands of basins across the world with only a few years’ worth of streamflow observations to benefit from improved modeling and accuracy resulting from the use of deep learning.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/06/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on June 24, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/06/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/06/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-06-16T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-06-16T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-19&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #19&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evaluating the benefits of chlorophyll fluorescence for in-season crop productivity forecasting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Different climate sensitivity of particulate and mineral-associated soil organic matter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Effect of missing data on short time series and their application in the characterization of surface temperature by detrended fluctuation analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decomposition of multivariate spatial data into latent factors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prediction of various soil properties for a national spatial dataset of Scottish soils based on four different chemometric approaches: A comparison of near infrared and mid-infrared spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evaluating-the-benefits-of-chlorophyll-fluorescence-for-in-season-crop-productivity-forecasting&quot;&gt;Evaluating the benefits of chlorophyll fluorescence for in-season crop productivity forecasting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remote sensing of solar-induced chlorophyll fluorescence (SIF) shows promise for monitoring the productivity of global agricultural systems. SIF-based primary productivity metrics have demonstrated higher fidelity to largescale patterns of crop productivity than reflectance-based vegetation indices when averaged across the growing season. In-season crop yield forecasting typically relies upon reflectance-based vegetation indices, raising the question of whether in-season monitoring could be improved by utilizing SIF. Here, we analyze patterns of US agricultural productivity from USDA surveys and their in-season relationships with coarse-resolution GOME-2 SIF, high-resolution downscaled SIF, SIF-based primary productivity metrics, MODIS NDVI, and MODIS GPP. We find that coarse-resolution SIF-based metrics and NDVI exhibit similar out-of-sample in-season (April-July and April-August) predictive ability, even when spatially filtering higher-resolution NDVI data to cropland areas. The downscaled SIF product performed more poorly than the coarse-resolution SIF, and MODIS GPP performed more poorly than MODIS NDVI. All forecasts are improved by incorporating county fixed effects to control for crosssectional differences between counties. NDVI-based metrics allow for significantly better yield predictions during drought conditions than SIF-based metrics, suggesting limited added value of SIF for early warning of drought impacts. The benefits of SIF for crop monitoring should be continually evaluated as the frequency and quality of SIF measurements continue to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;different-climate-sensitivity-of-particulate-and-mineral-associated-soil-organic-matter&quot;&gt;Different climate sensitivity of particulate and mineral-associated soil organic matter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil carbon sequestration is seen as an effective means to draw down atmospheric CO2, but at the same time warming may accelerate the loss of extant soil carbon, so an accurate estimation of soil carbon stocks and their vulnerability to climate change is required. Here we demonstrate how separating soil carbon into particulate and mineral-associated organic matter (POM and MAOM, respectively) aids in the understanding of its vulnerability to climate change and identification of carbon sequestration strategies. By coupling European-wide databases with soil organic matter physical fractionation, we assessed the current geographical distribution of mineral topsoil carbon in POM and MAOM by land cover using a machine-learning approach. Further, using observed climate relationships, we projected the vulnerability of carbon in POM and MAOM to future climate change. Arable and coniferous forest soils contain the largest and most vulnerable carbon stocks when cumulated at the European scale. Although we show a lower carbon loss from mineral topsoils with climate change (2.5 +/- 1.2 PgC by 2080) than those in some previous predictions, we urge the implementation of coniferous forest management practices that increase plant inputs to soils to offset POM losses, and the adoption of best management practices to avert the loss of and to build up both POM and MAOM in arable soils.
Particulate and mineral-associated soil organic carbon have different climate sensitivity and distributions in Europe, according to analyses of measurements of soil carbon fractions from 352 topsoils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;effect-of-missing-data-on-short-time-series-and-their-application-in-the-characterization-of-surface-temperature-by-detrended-fluctuation-analysis&quot;&gt;Effect of missing data on short time series and their application in the characterization of surface temperature by detrended fluctuation analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Climate change is deeply impacting the society on different scales. Decision making becomes a complex task when, in adverse weather conditions, the meteorological records show missing data due to failures of measuring instruments. Several investigations have proposed optimized regression methods, K-nearest-neighbor imputation, and multiple imputations for the treatment of missing data; however, there is less information about the application of imputation methods for the treatment of missing data on short meteorological records. Therefore, the expected confidence in the results requires using robust analysis methods that depend the least as possible on the length of the records and the number of missing data. In this research, the performance of detrended fluctuation analysis applied on temperature short record was studied when K-nearest-neighbor and neural networks are used as imputation techniques, and compared with the performance without data imputation. The results showed the robustness when it is applied to a short time series with missing data and without data imputation. In this aspect, the DFA method only requires removing the seasonality from the temperature records to get good performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;decomposition-of-multivariate-spatial-data-into-latent-factors&quot;&gt;Decomposition of multivariate spatial data into latent factors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simulating spatial Gaussian realizations is one of the core components of geostatistics and numerous other fields involving uncertainty, risk, and reliability. The use of decorrelation methods and truncated Gaussian algorithms further promotes the use of Gaussian realizations. In multivariate cases, geological variables may represent different scales and exhibit different spatial structures and anisotropy that complicates decorrelation methods. For cases where spatial dependencies cannot be removed using techniques such as the projection pursuit multivariate transform coupled with maximum autocorrelation factors, cokriging is advocated and requires a model of coregionalization. However, blind source separation represents the original multivariate problem as a linear combination of latent source variables, each one having a spatial structure from the linear model of coregionalization (LMC). The latent source variables or factors are independent and follow a standard normal distribution facilitating the use of Gaussian simulation algorithms. Moreover, different algorithms may be utilized for each variable given that some are more efficient at generating realizations for different spatial covariance functions. Recovering the original variables afterwards is straightforward. The theory for this decomposition is presented. A small numerical example is used to explain the theory and the proposed approach is illustrated through a case study with geochemical sample data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prediction-of-various-soil-properties-for-a-national-spatial-dataset-of-scottish-soils-based-on-four-different-chemometric-approaches-a-comparison-of-near-infrared-and-mid-infrared-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Prediction of various soil properties for a national spatial dataset of Scottish soils based on four different chemometric approaches: A comparison of near infrared and mid-infrared spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Infrared spectroscopic techniques, in combination with chemometric approaches, have been widely used to estimate different physical and chemical properties in soil samples. This study aims to assess the performance of diffuse reflectance spectroscopy in the near-infrared (NIR) region and Attenuated Total Reflection Fourier Transform infrared spectroscopy (ATR-FTIR) in the mid-infrared (MIR) region to predict nine different soil properties: total carbon, total nitrogen, bulk density, clay, sand, silt, pH (in H2O), exchangeable Mg and exchangeable K using chemometric approaches. The predictive performance of four different regression methods i.e., Partial least square (PLS), support vector regression (SVR), Cubist and convolutional neural network (CNN) in combination with different pre-processing approaches were investigated. For CNN, the FTIR/NIR spectra were converted to spectrograms and fed into the CNN to examine the prediction accuracy of two-dimensional convolutional neural network (CNN-2D) and to compare its performance with one-dimensional convolutional neural networks (CNN-1D, spectral data as input). To achieve these objectives, we used a spectral library of 650 samples from National Soils Inventory of Scotland (NSIS) dataset collected in a 20 km grid throughout Scotland between 2007 and 2009. The FTIR and NIR data were both split into calibration (n(c) = 520) and validation (n(v) = 130) sets. Our results show that the regression models with FTIR data have better predictive performance than those created using NIR data for all the studied soil properties (improvement in root mean square error of prediction (RMSEP) of 3-61%), except for pH. Comparing the different chemometric approaches, for both the NIR and FTIR, the results indicated that the CNN-1D models performs better than PLS, SVR and CNN-2D for all the studied soil components in terms of RMSEP. We found that the CNN-1D models created using the NIR spectral dataset were superior (lower RMSEP values) to those developed using the Cubist approach for total carbon, total nitrogen, clay, silt, pH and exchangeable K, whereas the Cubist models for sand and exchangeable Mg performed slightly better than CNN-1D. For the FTIR data, Cubist models for total carbon and silt performed best (with lowest RMSEP and highest Residual Prediction Deviation (RPD) values), while for the rest of the components, CNN-1D outperformed the PLS, SVR, Cubist and CNN-2D. We also calculated the impact of the NIR and FTIR variables used by the Cubist and CNN-1D models in predicting different soil properties. We used the Shapley Additive Explanation (SHAP) values, a game theoretic approach, to interpret the output of the CNN-1D models.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/06/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on June 16, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/06/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/06/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-06-08T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-06-08T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-18&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #18&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simultaneously estimating surface soil moisture and roughness of bare soils by combining optical and radar data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The economics of liming in arable crop rotations: analysis of the 35-year Rothamsted and Woburn liming experiments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An integrated spatial econometric approach in valuing soil conservation using contingent valuation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Governing climate risks in the face of normative uncertainties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;simultaneously-estimating-surface-soil-moisture-and-roughness-of-bare-soils-by-combining-optical-and-radar-data&quot;&gt;Simultaneously estimating surface soil moisture and roughness of bare soils by combining optical and radar data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both radar and optical signals are sensitive to the change of surface soil moisture (SSM) and surface roughness properties (such as root mean squared height- RMSH), and the accuracy of retrieved SSM from single radar and optical remote sensing data is influenced by the spatiotemporal change of surface roughness. Here, we attempt to explore a method to simultaneously estimate SSM and RMSH of bare soil by combining optical and radar data, so as to weaken the effect of surface roughness on SSM inversion results. To achieve this goal, two satellite synchronous ground experiments were carried out, collecting 88 sampling plots each with an area of 50 m × 50 m. Radar backscattering coefficient and spectral reflectance are uniformly corrected to a fixed observation direction and solar incident direction respectively, which can eliminate the difference of satellite signal resulted from various sun-satellite geometry. Combining radar backscattering and optical reflectance model, Sentinel-1 and Sentinel-2 data are used to simultaneously retrieve SSM and RMSH of bared soils, and some conclusions are given as below: 1) a strong correlation is observed for (radar and optical) satellite signals and soil surface parameters (SSM and RMSH); 2) a higher accuracy was obtained by the combined use of optical and radar data, indicated by the decreased root mean squared error of retrieved SSM (~0.045 cm3/cm3) and RMSH (~0.8 cm); 3) the further improvement of retrieved SSM and RMSH was achieved by introducing their initial values, revealing that the prior knowledge of soil properties is also beneficial to improve the retrieval accuracy. This study proposed an framework for simultaneous estimation of SSM and RMSH by combining optical and radar data, and its feasibility is verified by experimental data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-economics-of-liming-in-arable-crop-rotations-analysis-of-the-35-year-rothamsted-and-woburn-liming-experiments&quot;&gt;The economics of liming in arable crop rotations: analysis of the 35-year Rothamsted and Woburn liming experiments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liming is a common management practice, but there exists uncertainty about the economic benefits. An economic analysis of the costs and profitability of liming arable crops was undertaken using data from the long-term liming experiment at Rothamsted and Woburn. There was a strong liming effect on gross margins, but large differences in the economic benefit between crops. For some crops (such as spring barley), liming greatly improved the gross margin, while for spring oats liming provided very little increase. Most economic benefit was achieved with the high lime treatment, but the cumulative discounted cash flow indicated that it took approximately 20 years before a distinct difference developed between the lime treatments. Therefore, lime should be considered a capital investment and economic evaluation undertaken over a long period. Liming rate increased the net present value expressed as an annual equivalent (NPVa). An additional £436 ha−1 year−1 at Rothamsted and £208 ha−1 year−1 at Woburn of profit was gained from the adoption of the most profitable liming treatments over not liming. Sensitivity analysis indicated that total liming costs had a weak effect on NPVa, but crop price had a strong effect. The economic performance of liming differed between sites and was higher at Rothamsted than at Woburn, mostly because of soil differences. Liming greatly improves economic returns of most arable crops, but the magnitude of the long-term economic benefit depends upon the sequence of crops within a given rotation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-integrated-spatial-econometric-approach-in-valuing-soil-conservation-using-contingent-valuation&quot;&gt;An integrated spatial econometric approach in valuing soil conservation using contingent valuation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The integration of soil value in agronomic micro-level decision-making and macro-scale policy development has grown immensely in recent years. Major threats to soil resources and their impact on human well-being require a comprehensive estimation of soil’s economic worth, highlighting the need for sustainable and pragmatic conservation strategies. However, the absence of formal markets for numerous soil amenities, coupled with the heterogeneity of stakeholder cognition and spatio-environmental factors, obfuscates the valuation process for soil and similar public goods. This paper aims to address such concerns by evaluating stakeholders’ willingness to pay (WTP) for soil conservation as a proxy indicator for its explicit value. Two contingent valuation method (CVM) formats, the payment card (PC) and the dichotomous choice (DC), were used to analyse WTP in Norzagaray, Philippines. Results suggest farmers’ income, education, land tenure type, level of environmental consciousness and proximity to amenities influence their inclination to spend on soil conservation measures. Econometric analyses indicate a compensating surplus corresponding to the mean WTP estimate of ₱79.98 (PC-CVM) and a Turnbull WTP estimate of ₱99.47 (DC-CVM). Estimated WTP values can be used in future benefit-transfer studies, and the findings of the econometric models can be used in developing strategies that would promote greater stakeholder acceptance and participation. The approach presented here provides another step towards a more comprehensive characterization of soil value that integrates environmental valuation and econometric modelling with geospatial data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;governing-climate-risks-in-the-face-of-normative-uncertainties&quot;&gt;Governing climate risks in the face of normative uncertainties&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Governing risks is not only a technical matter, but also a matter of ethical and societal considerations. In this article, we argue that in addition to scientific and technical uncertainties, we need to also address normative uncertainties of risk decisions. We define normative uncertainties as situations where there are different partially morally defensible – but incompatible – options or courses of action, or ones in which there is no fully morally defensible option. We conceptualize normative uncertainties, distinguishing between the four categories of evolutionary, theoretical, conceptual, and epistemic normative uncertainties. We will show different instances of normative uncertainties in climate adaptation strategies. We finally present two methods for identifying and dealing with normative uncertainties, namely, the Wide Reflective Equilibrium and adaptive planning. Situations of normative uncertainties have always been and will continue to be present in risk decisions and they have often been dealt with in an implicit manner. In this article, we make them explicit, which could lead to better morally informed and justified decisions about climate risks.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/06/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on June 08, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/06/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/06/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-06-03T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-06-03T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-17&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #17&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Comparison of soil organic matter composition under different land uses by DRIFT spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Role of Soils in Land Degradation Assessment: A Review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rapid soil and vegetation changes at regional scale in continental Antarctica&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compaction induced soil structural degradation affects productivity and environmental outcomes: A review and New Zealand case study&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ecosystem services of urban soils: A review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Potential benefits of liming to acid soils on climate change mitigation and food security&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Current carbon prices do not stack up to much land use change, despite bundled ecosystem service co-benefits&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reducing climate impacts of beef production: A synthesis of life cycle assessments across management systems and global regions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comparison-of-soil-organic-matter-composition-under-different-land-uses-by-drift-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Comparison of soil organic matter composition under different land uses by DRIFT spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study aimed to estimate and characterise soil organic matter under different land uses (cropland, grassland, and forest) and soil depths. The soil organic matter composition of the soil was assessed by diffuse reflectance infrared spectroscopy (DRIFT). Humic and fulvic acids (HAs, FAs) were extracted from soils and their compositions were evaluated by DRIFT. Low molecular mass organic acids content was also measured. Our result revealed that the largest differences of the spectra in the composition of organic matter were observed in the upper parts of the soil profile. The forest soil spectra had more intense aliphatic bands, carboxylic, and CH bands than spectra of grassland and cropland soils. The difference of HAs spectra was at 3 010 to 2 800/cm where the most intensive aliphatic bands were in forest soil HAs, followed by grassland and cropland soil HAs. The grassland topsoil FAs spectrum differs most from the other land uses. It has lower peaks around 1 660-1 600/cm and 1 200/cm than cropland and forest. The concentration of low molecular mass organic acid (LMMOA) was the highest in the forest soil and the most abundant acid was citrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-role-of-soils-in-land-degradation-assessment-a-review&quot;&gt;The Role of Soils in Land Degradation Assessment: A Review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the framework of the existing concepts of land degradation assessment, the main ideas about its causes and consequences are formulated, methodological provisions for studying the intensity of degradation processes are defined, and specific methods for assessing the economic component of degradation are developed. The problem of economic assessment of land degradation is complicated by differences in understanding of the nature of degradation processes and the role of soils in them. Soil indicators play the most significant role in the economic assessment of damage from land degradation. However, this methodology does not actually involve the use of modern concepts of ecosystem services. On the contrary, the methodology of land degradation economics, which uses a wide range of ecosystem services, largely ignores the need to take into account the dynamics of soil properties. The development of a unified methodology will solve many problems, among which an important place is occupied by the need to avoid legally regulated formulaic assessments of degradation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rapid-soil-and-vegetation-changes-at-regional-scale-in-continental-antarctica&quot;&gt;Rapid soil and vegetation changes at regional scale in continental Antarctica&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antarctica is the last pristine environment on Earth, its biota being adapted to the harsh and extreme polar climate. Until now, soil formation and vegetation development in continental Antarctica were considered very slow due to the extreme conditions of this polar desert. Since the austral summer 2002/2003, a long-term monitoring network of the terrestrial ecosystems (soils, vegetation, active layer thickness) has been established at Victoria Land (VL) across a &amp;gt; 500 km latitudinal gradient of coastal sites (73 degrees -77 degrees S). In only one decade large ecosystem changes were detected. Climate was characterized by a significant increase of thawing degree days in northern VL and of autumn air temperature. No extreme climatic events (such as hot spells) where detected in the study period. Soil chemistry suffered large quantitative changes, clearly indicating rapid pedogenetic processes. In most soils the upper layers exhibited a strong alkalinization (pH increases up to 3 units) and increases in conductivity, anions and cations (in particular of SO4 and Na). The largest changes were observed in soils with low vegetation cover. Statistically significant differences in soil chemistry were detected between soils with high and low vegetation cover, the former showing lower pH, conductivity, Na and Cl. Most plots exhibited changes of total cover, species richness and floristic composition, with vegetation expansion in soils with low vegetation cover and the largest increase recorded at Apostrophe Island (northern VL). Principal Component Analysis (PCA) identified the main trend of vegetation change, with a shift from lower to higher cover and a secondary trend of change associated with a gradient of water availability, consistent with an increase in water instead of snow. Redundancy analysis (RDA) identified the trend of change in soil chemistry with increases in pH, conductivity, anions and cations associated with the concomitant decrease in C, N, NO3, PO4. The RDA confirmed that soil changes were associated with a gradient of vegetation change (from low to high cover) as well as of water availability, as already indirectly outlined by the PCA. Field manipulation experiments carried out at five locations of the network between 73 degrees S and 77 degrees S, simulating increases of precipitation from snow or water additions didn’t induce changes in soil pH, indicating that pulse events of snow accumulation or melting could not trigger persistent soil pH changes. These data allow hypothesize the occurrence of a main ecosystem change occurring at regional scale at Victoria Land. The slight air warming and its consequences on soil chemistry and vegetation, further highlight the sensitivity of the fragile Antarctic ecosystems to the consequences of even small changes in climate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;compaction-induced-soil-structural-degradation-affects-productivity-and-environmental-outcomes-a-review-and-new-zealand-case-study&quot;&gt;Compaction induced soil structural degradation affects productivity and environmental outcomes: A review and New Zealand case study&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agricultural intensification has enhanced productivity, but has also negatively affected soil structure and environmental outcomes. Agriculture is among New Zealand (NZ)’s largest industries. Like other countries, significant land use intensification over the last 20-30 years has occurred in NZ, resulting in undesirable side-effect of soil structural degradation (SSD) (e.g., soil compaction, aggregate fragmentation). Using NZ as a case study, we reviewed and, where possible, quantified the extent of SSD in NZ and its impacts and implications on production, contaminant losses via drainage and runoff, and N2O emissions. Knowledge gaps were identified that will help guide future research both in NZ and internationally. Our review revealed that SSD is common in many regions and under different land uses in NZ. At the national scale, 44% of sites monitored between 2014 and 2017 were below the national target for macroporosity (pore diameter &amp;gt; 30 mu m). The occurrence of SSD was greater under more intensive land uses such as dairying and continuous cropping. Soil structural degradation from compaction is typically associated with reduced pasture and crop production. In NZ, pasture production was estimated to decrease by an average of 2.5% for every 1.0% (0.01 cm(3) cm (3)) decrease in macroporosity (0-10 cm soil). Compaction from livestock treading and wheel traffic has been shown to increase N2O emissions by 51-814% and 19-1300%, respectively, with no significant evidence that this increase is related to N loading. Effects of compaction on contaminant losses via runoff and drainage, and in particular via preferential flow, are less well researched and findings were less consistent and dependent on many factors including the degree of compaction. Important knowledge gaps include a lack of quantitative relationships between degree of SSD and soil hydraulic properties and processes (e.g., water movement and contaminant losses), and poor knowledge of critical thresholds or optimum ranges of soil physical indicators in relation to critical ecosystem services (e.g., pasture yield, gas and water regulation in soils). We also found few estimates of SSD-induced costs related to production and environmental outcomes (e.g., contaminant losses and N2O emissions) at either farm system, regional or national scales. More data are needed to better determine the true costs and implications for farm production and environmental effects associated with SSD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-ecosystem-services-of-urban-soils-a-review&quot;&gt;The ecosystem services of urban soils: A review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The expansion of urban areas worldwide is increasing the anthropogenic impact upon soil and highlights the important role of urban areas in supporting a sustainable future. As such, urban soils are becoming more important in the delivery of a broad range of ecosystem services (ESs), including carbon storage and climate regulation, biomass provision for food and water flow regulation, and recreational benefits. In this review, we aim to support the development of this emerging research area and, subsequently, support the improved treatment and management of urban soil and ES delivery. We present a systematic review of which ESs have been studied and examine trends in research using a co-occurrence analysis of key terms. We then provide a summary review of current knowledge on ESs and identify the gaps in knowledge. Our review highlights that this is a young, but growing, field of research, with a marked increase in publications since 2014. We found that supporting processes and regulating services were most commonly studied, with 88% and 71% of the papers relating to quantitative studies addressing these, respectively. Cultural, provisioning and water-related ESs were relatively understudied, suggesting key gaps for future research. However, this may be attributable to a disconnection between academic communities rather than a lack of knowledge. Fewer than 20% of quantitative studies addressed more than two ESs simultaneously, leading us to suggest that urban soil multifunctionality is a key area for future research, and highlighting the need to integrate understanding of urban soil ESs across disciplines and professions. In addition to this overarching suggestion, we propose six research gaps and opportunities: further research into biomass provision for food, water-related ESs and cultural ESs; greater geographical representation; further interconnection between research and practitioner communities; and a focus on the future drivers of soil change in urban environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;potential-benefits-of-liming-to-acid-soils-on-climate-change-mitigation-and-food-security&quot;&gt;Potential benefits of liming to acid soils on climate change mitigation and food security&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Globally, about 50% of all arable soils are classified as acidic. As crop and plant growth are significantly hampered under acidic soil conditions, many farmers, but increasingly as well forest managers, apply lime to raise the soil pH. Besides its direct effect on soil pH, liming also affects soil C and nutrient cycles and associated greenhouse gas (GHG) fluxes. In this meta-analysis, we reviewed 1570 observations reported in 121 field-based studies worldwide, to assess liming effects on soil GHG fluxes and plant productivity. We found that liming significantly increases crop yield by 36.3%. Also, soil organic C (SOC) stocks were found to increase by 4.51% annually, though soil respiration is stimulated too (7.57%). Moreover, liming was found to reduce soil N2O emission by 21.3%, yield-scaled N2O emission by 21.5%, and CH4 emission and yield-scaled CH4 emission from rice paddies by 19.0% and 12.4%, respectively. Assuming that all acid agricultural soils are limed periodically, liming results in a total GHG balance benefit of 633-749 Tg CO2-eq year(-1) due to reductions in soil N2O emissions (0.60-0.67 Tg N2O-N year(-1)) and paddy soil CH4 emissions (1.75-2.21 Tg CH4 year(-1)) and increases in SOC stocks (65.7-110 Tg C year(-1)). However, this comes at the cost of an additional CO2 release (c. 624-656 Tg CO2 year(-1)) deriving from lime mining, transport and application, and lime dissolution, so that the overall GHG balance is likely neutral. Nevertheless, liming of acid agricultural soils will increase yields by at least 6.64 x 10(8) Mg year(-1), covering the food supply of 876 million people. Overall, our study shows for the first time that a general strategy of liming of acid agricultural soils is likely to result in an increasing sustainability of global agricultural production, indicating the potential benefit of liming acid soils for climate change mitigation and food security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;current-carbon-prices-do-not-stack-up-to-much-land-use-change-despite-bundled-ecosystem-service-co-benefits&quot;&gt;Current carbon prices do not stack up to much land use change, despite bundled ecosystem service co-benefits&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biological sources of carbon sequestration such as revegetation have been highlighted as important avenues to combat climate change and meet global targets by the global community including the Paris Climate Agreement. However, current and projected carbon prices present a considerable barrier to broad-scale adoption of tree planting as a key mitigation strategy. One avenue to provide additional economic and environmental incentives to encourage wider adoption of revegetation is the bundling or stacking of additional co-beneficial ecosystem services that can be realized from tree planting. Using the World’s largest land-based carbon credit trading scheme, the Australian Emissions Reduction Scheme (ERF), we examine the potential for three pairs of ecosystem services, where the carbon sequestration value of land use change is paired with an additional co-benefit with strong prospects for local tangible benefits to land owners/providers. Two cases consider agricultural provisioning values that can be realized by the landowners in higher returns: increased pollination services and reduced lamb mortality. The third case examined payments for tree plantings along riparian buffers, with payments to farmers by a water utility who realizes the benefit from reduced treatment cost due to water quality improvements. Economic incentives from these co-benefit case studies were found to be mixed, with avoided treatment costs from water quality paired with carbon payments the most promising, while pollination and reduced lamb mortality paired with carbon payments were unable to bridge the economic gap except under the most optimistic assumptions. We conclude that the economics case for significant land use change are likely to be geographically dispersed and only viable in relatively niche landscape positions in high establishment, high opportunity cost areas even when carbon payments are augmented with the value of co-benefits classified as providing direct and local benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reducing-climate-impacts-of-beef-production-a-synthesis-of-life-cycle-assessments-across-management-systems-and-global-regions&quot;&gt;Reducing climate impacts of beef production: A synthesis of life cycle assessments across management systems and global regions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The global demand for beef is rapidly increasing (FAO, 2019), raising concern about climate change impacts (Clark et al., 2020; Leip et al., 2015; Springmann et al., 2018). Beef and dairy contribute over 70% of livestock greenhouse gas emissions (GHG), which collectively contribute similar to 6.3 Gt CO2-eq/year (Gerber et al., 2013; Herrero et al., 2016) and account for 14%-18% of human GHG emissions (Friedlingstein et al., 2019; Gerber et al., 2013). The utility of beef GHG mitigation strategies, such as land-based carbon (C) sequestration and increased production efficiency, are actively debated (Garnett et al., 2017). We compiled 292 local comparisons of “improved” versus “conventional” beef production systems across global regions, assessing net GHG emission data from Life Cycle Assessment (LCA) studies. Our results indicate that net beef GHG emissions could be reduced substantially via changes in management. Overall, a 46 % reduction in net GHG emissions per unit of beef was achieved at sites using carbon (C) sequestration management strategies on grazed lands, and an 8% reduction in net GHGs was achieved at sites using growth efficiency strategies. However, net-zero emissions were only achieved in 2% of studies. Among regions, studies from Brazil had the greatest improvement, with management strategies for C sequestration and efficiency reducing beef GHG emissions by 57%. In the United States, C sequestration strategies reduced beef GHG emissions by over 100% (net-zero emissions) in a few grazing systems, whereas efficiency strategies were not successful at reducing GHGs, possibly because of high baseline efficiency in the region. This meta-analysis offers insight into pathways to substantially reduce beef production’s global GHG emissions. Nonetheless, even if these improved land-based and efficiency management strategies could be fully applied globally, the trajectory of growth in beef demand will likely more than offset GHG emissions reductions and lead to further warming unless there is also reduced beef consumption.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/06/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on June 03, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/05/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/05/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-05-26T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-05-26T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-16&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #16&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil carbon dynamics during drying vs. rewetting: Importance of antecedent moisture conditions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Air-drying and long time preservation of soil do not significantly impact microbial community composition and structure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organic carbon pools and organic matter chemical composition in response to different land uses in southern Brazil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introducing digital twins to agriculture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A review of geostatistical simulation models applied to satellite remote sensing: Methods and applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-carbon-dynamics-during-drying-vs-rewetting-importance-of-antecedent-moisture-conditions&quot;&gt;Soil carbon dynamics during drying vs. rewetting: Importance of antecedent moisture conditions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil moisture influences soil carbon dynamics, including microbial growth and respiration. The response of such ‘soil respiration’ to moisture changes is generally assumed to be linear and reversible, i.e. to depend only on the current moisture state. Current models thus do not account for antecedent soil moisture conditions when determining soil respiration or the available substrate pool. We conducted a laboratory incubation to determine how the antecedent conditions of drought and flood influenced soil organic matter (SOM) chemistry, bioavailability, and respiration. We sampled soils from an upland coastal forest, Beaver Creek, WA USA, and subjected them to drying and rewetting treatments. For the drying treatment, field moist soils were saturated and then dried to 75, 50, 35, and 5% saturation. In the rewetting treatment, field moist soils were air-dried and then rewet to 35, 50, 75, and 100% saturation. We measured respiration and water extractable organic carbon (WEOC) concentrations and used H-1-NMR and FT-ICR-MS to characterize the WEOC pool across the treatments. The drying vs. wetting treatment strongly influenced SOM bioavailability, as rewet soils (with antecedent drought) had greater WEOC concentrations and respiration fluxes compared to the drying soils (with antecedent flood). In addition, air-dry soils had the highest WEOC concentrations, and the NMR-resolved peaks showed a strong contribution of protein groups in these soils. Both NMR and FT-ICR-MS analyses indicated increased contribution of complex aromatic groups/molecules in the rewet soils, compared to the drying soils. We suggest that drying introduced organic matter into the WEOC pool via desorption of aromatic molecules and/or by microbial cell lysis, and this stimulated microbial mineralization rates. Our work indicates that even short-term shifts in antecedent moisture conditions can strongly influence soil C dynamics at the core scale. The predictive uncertainties in current soil models may be reduced by a more accurate representation of soil water and C persistence that includes a mechanistic and quantitative understanding of the impact of antecedent moisture conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;air-drying-and-long-time-preservation-of-soil-do-not-significantly-impact-microbial-community-composition-and-structure&quot;&gt;Air-drying and long time preservation of soil do not significantly impact microbial community composition and structure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To determine whether archived air-dried soils can be potentially used to explore microbial information upon sampling, we examined microbial community dynamics during soil air-drying and long time preserving. Fresh soils from five long-term fertilization treatments were sampled, air-dried, and preserved. Soil microbial community was characterized at specific intervals (from 0 h to 8192 h) by Illumina sequencing. The results showed that both prokaryotic and fungal community profiles did not substantially change during air-drying and long time preserving. The fertilization effects on microbial community structure could still be identified using the airdried soils. These findings suggest that air-drying and preserving exerts an almost negligible impact on soil microbial community profiles, laying the foundation for utilizing worldwide archived soils to investigate microbial community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;organic-carbon-pools-and-organic-matter-chemical-composition-in-response-to-different-land-uses-in-southern-brazil&quot;&gt;Organic carbon pools and organic matter chemical composition in response to different land uses in southern Brazil&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The adoption of conservation agriculture (e.g., no-till system) has been recognized as pivotal to maintaining soil functions, but the potential of this system to enhance organic carbon (OC) quantity and quality and how this OC is stabilized in soils are not well established. In this study, we evaluated the effects of land-use types (native vegetation (NV) vs. no-till system (NT)) on OC stocks and on the chemical composition of organic matter (OM), and sought to understand the mechanisms that govern OC protection in the studied highly weathered soils. To achieve these objectives, we used an OC fractionation scheme in a combination of solid-state C-13 nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) spectroscopic analyses in soils from six farms in southern Brazil. Our results showed smaller OC stocks (whole soil) under NT than under NV in four of the six sites. In addition, the OC stock differences between land-use types were larger in coarser textured soils and in those where conventional tillage was used before the adoption of NT. Among fractions, particulate organic carbon (POC) represented only 8% of the whole OC stock but was the fraction most affected by land-use type. In contrast, the humus organic carbon (HOC) fraction contributed 78% of the whole OC stock and was little altered by land-use type. Resistant organic carbon (ROC) represented 14% of the whole OC stock and it was altered by land-use type, demonstrating that this fraction is not as inert as previously thought. Overall, OM chemical composition was quite similar between land uses, with O-alkyl-C being the predominant C type. This labile component was further highly correlated with OC stock and silt + clay contents, indicating that the accumulation of OC in these highly weathered soils is mainly a response to the association between labile C compounds and minerals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-review-of-geostatistical-simulation-models-applied-to-satellite-remote-sensing-methods-and-applications&quot;&gt;A review of geostatistical simulation models applied to satellite remote sensing: Methods and applications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite an ever-increasing number of spaceborne, airborne, and ground-based data acquisition platforms, remote sensing data are still often spatially incomplete or temporally irregular. While deterministic interpolation techniques are often used, they tend to create unrealistic spatial patterns and generally do not provide uncertainty quantification. Geostatistical simulation models are effective in generating an ensemble of realistic and equally probable realizations of an unmeasured phenomenon, allowing data uncertainty to be propagated. These models are commonly used in several fields of earth science, and in recent years, they have been applied widely to remotely sensed data. This study provides the first review of the applications of geostatistical simulation to remote sensing data. We review recent geostatistical simulation models relevant to satellite remote sensing data and discuss the characteristics and advantages of each approach. Finally, the applications of each geostatistical simulation model are categorized in different domains of natural sciences, including soil, vegetation, topography, and atmospheric science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;introducing-digital-twins-to-agriculture&quot;&gt;Introducing digital twins to agriculture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital twins are being adopted by increasingly more industries, transforming them and bringing new opportunities. Digital twins provide previously unheard levels of control over physical entities and help to manage complex systems by integrating an array of technologies. Recently, agriculture has seen several technological advancements, but it is still unclear if this community is making an effort to adopt digital twins in its operations. In this work, we employ a mixed-method approach to investigate the added-value of digital twins for agriculture. We examine the extent of digital twin adoption in agriculture, shed light on the concept and the benefits it brings, and provide an application-based roadmap for a more extended adoption. We report a literature review of digital twins in agriculture, covering years 2017-2020. We identify 28 use cases, and compare them with use cases in other disciplines. We compare reported benefits, service categories, and technology readiness levels to assess the level of digital twin adoption in agriculture. We distill the digital twin characteristics that can provide addedvalue to agriculture from the examined digital twin applications in agriculture and in other disciplines. Then, inspired by digital twin applications in other disciplines, we propose a roadmap for digital twins in agriculture, consisting of examples of growing complexity. We conclude this paper by identifying the distinctive characteristics of agricultural digital twins.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/05/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on May 26, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/05/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/05/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-05-25T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-05-25T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-15&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #15&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stochastic and deterministic interpretation of pool models&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Classifying human influences on terrestrial ecosystems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feasibility of the 4 per 1000 aspirational target for soil carbon: A case study for France&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Environmental covariates improve the spectral predictions of organic carbon in subtropical soils in southern Brazil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using autoencoders to compress soil VNIR-SWIR spectra for more robust prediction of soil properties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;classifying-human-influences-on-terrestrial-ecosystems&quot;&gt;Classifying human influences on terrestrial ecosystems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human activity is affecting every ecosystem on Earth, with terrestrial biodiversity decreasing rapidly. Human influences materialize in the form of numerous, jointly acting factors, yet the experimental study of such joint impacts is not well developed. We identify the absence of a systematic ordering system of factors according to their properties (traits) as an impediment to progress and offer an a priori trait-based factor classification to illustrate this point, starting at the coarsest level with the physical, biological or chemical nature of factors. Such factor classifications can serve in communication of science, but also can be used as heuristic tools to develop questions and formulate new hypotheses, or as predictors of effects, which we explore here. We hope that classifications such as the one proposed here can help shift the spotlight on the multitude of anthropogenic changes affecting ecosystems, and that such classifications can be used to help unravel joint impacts of a great number of factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stochastic-and-deterministic-interpretation-of-pool-models&quot;&gt;Stochastic and deterministic interpretation of pool models&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carbon and element cycling models can be expressed in terms of the dynamics of individual particles or collection of them in aggregated pools. In both cases, the models represent the same dynamics and provide similar predictions. The time required for individual particles to pass through a system, that is, the transit time, can be obtained from both approaches. Pool models can be analyzed from a stochastic or a deterministic point of view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;feasibility-of-the-4-per-1000-aspirational-target-for-soil-carbon-a-case-study-for-france&quot;&gt;Feasibility of the 4 per 1000 aspirational target for soil carbon: A case study for France&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Increasing soil organic carbon (SOC) stocks is a promising way to mitigate the increase in atmospheric CO2 concentration. Based on a simple ratio between CO2 anthropogenic emissions and SOC stocks worldwide, it has been suggested that a 0.4% (4 per 1000) yearly increase in SOC stocks could compensate for current anthropogenic CO2 emissions. Here, we used a reverse RothC modelling approach to estimate the amount of C inputs to soils required to sustain current SOC stocks and to increase them by 4 parts per thousand per year over a period of 30 years. We assessed the feasibility of this aspirational target first by comparing the required C input with net primary productivity (NPP) flowing to the soil, and second by considering the SOC saturation concept. Calculations were performed for mainland France, at a 1 km grid cell resolution. Results showed that a 30%-40% increase in C inputs to soil would be needed to obtain a 4 parts per thousand increase per year over a 30-year period. 88.4% of cropland areas were considered unsaturated in terms of mineral-associated SOC, but characterized by a below target C balance, that is, less NPP available than required to reach the 4 parts per thousand aspirational target. Conversely, 90.4% of unimproved grasslands were characterized by an above target C balance, that is, enough NPP to reach the 4 parts per thousand objective, but 59.1% were also saturated. The situation of improved grasslands and forests was more evenly distributed among the four categories (saturated vs. unsaturated and above vs below target C balance). Future data from soil monitoring networks should enable to validate these results. Overall, our results suggest that, for mainland France, priorities should be (1) to increase NPP returns in cropland soils that are unsaturated and have a below target carbon balance and (2) to preserve SOC stocks in other land uses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;environmental-covariates-improve-the-spectral-predictions-of-organic-carbon-in-subtropical-soils-in-southern-brazil&quot;&gt;Environmental covariates improve the spectral predictions of organic carbon in subtropical soils in southern Brazil&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Including environmental covariates, when available, can be a valuable strategy for achieving higher soil predictive performance, but it is still unknown whether environmental data should be used either as covariates, combined with Vis-NIR spectra, to predict soil organic carbon (SOC) or as criteria to stratify a soil spectral library (SSL). We hypothesized that the performance of Vis-NIR spectroscopy in predicting SOC could be improved by the inclusion of auxiliary environmental data as covariates in Cubist models and thereby overcome the data stratification limitations. To test this, we evaluated six covariate sets, in which the following covariates were combined: spectral data, spectral classes, pedological data, and environmental data calibrated using Cubist models. An SSL composed of 2,461 samples from southern Brazil was used to calibrate models considering different sets of covariates. Model 1 included Vis-NIR reflectance (350-2500 nm), and Model 2 included Vis-NIR reflectance and spectral class. Model 3 included physiographic region, land-use/land-cover (LULC), climate, parent material, elevation, and clay content, while Model 4 included the parameters from Model 3 with the addition of Vis-NIR reflectance. Model 5 included Vis-NIR reflectance, spectral class, physiographic region, LULC, and soil textural class, while Model 6 included Vis-NIR reflectance, spectral class, physiographic region, LULC, climate, parent material, elevation, and clay content. The inclusion of environmental data as covariates along with Vis-NIR improved the predictive performance for SOC. Among the six covariate sets tested, the set including all covariates (Model 6) showed the best performance, improving the accuracy in prediction by 12% and reducing the prediction error (RMSE) by 22% compared to Model 1. Model 6 was the most accurate, and the input of environmental data as covariates is a promising strategy to achieve more accurate SOC predictions. Thus, covariates (e.g. elevation, clay content) that correlate with SOC improved the prediction accuracy of VisNIR spectroscopy models. The Cubist model was able to achieve similar accuracy and overcome the limitations presented by the stratification strategy documented in the literature by preventing the reduction of the sample size in the calibration of the models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-autoencoders-to-compress-soil-vnir-swir-spectra-for-more-robust-prediction-of-soil-properties&quot;&gt;Using autoencoders to compress soil VNIR-SWIR spectra for more robust prediction of soil properties&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past two decades, research efforts have focused on using near infrared diffuse reflectance spectroscopy (350-2500 nm) as a rapid and cost-effective method for soil analysis. Given the multi-faceted importance of the soil ecosystem, and considering the increasing pressures exerted upon it due to climate change, degradation and urbanization, the advantages of soil spectroscopy are significant. Large soil spectral libraries have been developed to this end throughout the world. The soil matrix is however complex, posing a challenge in the determination of key soil properties from the spectra. To tackle this challenge, two methodologies are generally used: a) the use of spectral pre-processing techniques to transfer the spectra into a new space in which the association between spectrum and soil property is supposed to be more clear, and b) the use of more sophisticated machine learning models (e.g. deep learning). In this paper, we propose a novel methodology using stacked autoencoders to transform the initially recorded spectra in a new compressed (i.e. latent) space which can help the chemometric models enhance the accuracy of prediction. This is an unsupervised learning approach which only depends on the input data (i.e. the spectra). Following the significant results obtained in the literature using combinations of different spectra pre-processing techniques and the simultaneous prediction of multiple soil properties, the proposed methodology is extended to facilitate these approaches. We demonstrate this capacity by applying it in the mineral samples of the LUCAS 2009 topsoil database, and simultaneously predicting eight properties (the particle size distribution, pH, CEC, organic carbon, calcium carbonate, and total nitrogen) using an artificial neural network. Compared to standard pre-processing techniques and other transformations such as the principal components space, the proposed methodology using only one spectral source as input decreases the RMSE on average by 8.4% and by 3.5%, respectively. With respect to the current state-of-the-art and in particular a multi-input convolutional neural network which was recently proposed and outperformed the compared methodologies, the results of our multi-input methodology exhibit an average RMSE decrease of 9.9%. The interpretability aspect of the transformed feature space and the compressed spectra was also examined to identify how the compressed information encodes the input data and enables better associations between input and output.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/05/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on May 25, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/05/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/05/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-05-10T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-05-10T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-14&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #14&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time, Hydrologic Landscape, and the Long-Term Storage of Peatland Carbon in Sedimentary Basins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Predicting soil organic matter nitrogen mineralization&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A regional soil classification framework to improve soil health diagnosis and management&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two centuries of water-level records at Lake George, NSW&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Production of global daily seamless data cubes and quantification of global land cover change from 1985 to 2020-iMap World 1.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;time-hydrologic-landscape-and-the-long-term-storage-of-peatland-carbon-in-sedimentary-basins&quot;&gt;Time, Hydrologic Landscape, and the Long-Term Storage of Peatland Carbon in Sedimentary Basins&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peatland carbon may enter long-term storage in sedimentary basins preserved as either coal or lignite. The time required to account for the carbon in 1-10 m thick coal seams must represent 10(5)-10(6) years, an order of magnitude more than previously assumed. To understand the process by which this happens requires extrapolation of our understanding of peatland carbon accumulation over timescales that greatly exceed those of Holocene peat. We analyze the consequences of extrapolating peat growth to periods of 10(6) years. We deduce that that key to sustained peat growth are hydrologic landscapes that can maintain a saturated peat body above the level of clastic deposition. Contrary to current stratigraphic frameworks, we conclude that the generation of accommodation space at low rates of 0.1-0.2 mm/yr can adequately accommodate thick peat accumulation over periods &amp;gt;10(5) years. However, generation of accommodation space at rates &amp;gt;0.5 mm/yr cannot. The low rates that permit accommodation of thick peat are typical of the rates of subsidence in specific tectonic settings, particularly foreland basins, and this has implications for our understanding of the links between terrestrial carbon burial, tectonics and the carbon cycle. The long-term stability of extensive peatland required to form coal also requires sediment bypass, modifying basin wide sediment transport and deposition. Limits to peatland growth under very low accommodation rates must exist but the relative importance of the limiting process is not understood. Finally, we discuss the consequences of these factors for predicting the future of the peatland carbon reservoir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;predicting-soil-organic-matter-nitrogen-mineralization&quot;&gt;Predicting soil organic matter nitrogen mineralization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objectives of this study were to develop a model for soil organic matter (SOM) N mineralization that required minimal inputs, to test the model using independent datasets, and to determine if the results could be used in adjusting commercial N fertilizer recommendations. A first-order model was adjusted monthly for differences in soil temperature and moisture. A daily time step was used to allow N mineralization estimates from one date to another. Simulations began in the month where temperature exceeded 10 degrees C. Model predictions were compared with those in published studies in northern California and Illinois. In the first California study, model predictions were near observed values in four of five locations. In the second California study, model predictions were within the 95% confidence interval of those based on laboratory incubation corrected for field temperature and moisture regimes. In a third study, unfertilized corn (Zea mays L.) yields were compared with seasonal N mineralization predictions plus N from the prior crop for 15 Illinois soils. The result was 32.0 kg corn kg(-1) seasonal available N as compared with the typical value of 67.5 kg corn kg(-1) commercial N fertilizer. Nitrogen mineralization predictions for Illinois soils were related to total N, suggesting that an equation could replace simulation modeling for a given soil-location combination. It is proposed that the N mineralization model, which has readily obtainable inputs (total N, bulk density, monthly weather), could be used in conjunction with field studies to refine commercial N fertilizer recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-regional-soil-classification-framework-to-improve-soil-health-diagnosis-and-management&quot;&gt;A regional soil classification framework to improve soil health diagnosis and management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil health research has developed soil tests to validate management strategies for creating healthier soils, such as cover crops, compost, and reduced tillage. Missing in this research agenda are soil health management strategies and diagnostics tailored to the systematic variation of soils. The Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database offers comprehensive estimates for many properties linked to soil health indicators. This research uses unsupervised classification of soil surface (0-30 cm) properties and root restrictive horizons in an internationally important agricultural region, the Central and Coastal Valleys of California, covering 5.6 million ha of mostly cropland. K-means clustering of 10 soil properties derived from SSURGO revealed groups distinct from USDA-NRCS Soil Taxonomy. Clustering metrics, data visualization, and validation tests justified a seven-region soil health conceptual model that divided the landscape into two broad classes-those with and without performance limitations. Results revealed three pedogenic conditions limiting soil performance: (a) root restrictive horizons that impede root growth into deeper soil; (b) salinity and alkalinity harmful to crops; and (c) shrink-swell properties making soils challenging to cultivate. Soils without performance limitations, soils with restrictive horizons, and salt-affected soils are further divided by texture and/or organic matter for a total of seven soil health regions. In reality, variation in soil properties is often continuous across the landscape and sometimes fractal in nature, but this research establishes a testable framework for evaluating soil health diagnostics according to geographically coherent differences in soil properties, demonstrating potential for how soil health management and interpretation can be tailor-made to the landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;two-centuries-of-water-level-records-at-lake-george-nsw&quot;&gt;Two centuries of water-level records at Lake George, NSW&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year 2020 marked the 200th anniversary of European settlers first encountering the ‘noble expanse of water’ of Lake George in New South Wales. Since 1820, unofficial observations and official measurements of the lake’s water-level have been recorded almost continuously by various individuals, research teams, government departments and private companies. The lake’s recent hydrographic history has been characterised by periods of flood and drought, which correspond with the prevailing climate conditions of SE Australia. This is the longest water-level record of its sort in the Southern Hemisphere and hence of great scientific and historic value. Here, we have compiled all available historic water-level data for Lake George, referenced them to common datums and presented a methodology for continuing the record using satellite imagery in lieu of on-site measurements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;production-of-global-daily-seamless-data-cubes-and-quantification-of-global-land-cover-change-from-1985-to-2020-imap-world-10&quot;&gt;Production of global daily seamless data cubes and quantification of global land cover change from 1985 to 2020-iMap World 1.0&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Longer time high-resolution, high-frequency, consistent, and more detailed land cover data are urgently needed in order to achieve sustainable development goals on food security, high-quality habitat construction, biodiversity conservation and planetary health, and for the understanding, simulation and management of the Earth system. However, due to technological constraints, it is difficult to provide simultaneously high spatial resolution, high temporal frequency, and high quality observation data. Existing mapping solutions are limited by traditional remotely sensed data, that have shorter observation periods, poor spatio-temporal consistency and comparability. Therefore, a new mapping paradigm is needed. This paper develops a framework for intelligent mapping (iMap) of land cover based on state-of-the-art technologies such as cloud computing, artificial intelligence, virtual constellations, and spatio-temporal reconstruction and fusion. Under this framework, we built an automated, serverless, end-to-end data production chain and parallel mapping system based on Amazon Web Services (AWS) and produced the first 30 m global daily seamless data cubes (SDC), and annual to seasonal land cover maps for 1985?2020. The SDC was produced through a multi-source spatio-temporal data reconstruction and fusion workflow based on Landsat, MODIS, and AVHRR virtual constellations. Independent validation results show that the relative mean error of the SDC is less than 2.14%. As analysis ready data (ARD), it can lay a foundation for high-precision quantitative remote sensing information extraction. From this SDC, we produced 36-year long, 30 m resolution global land cover map data set by combining strategies of sample migration, machine learning, and spatio-temporal adjustment. The average overall accuracy of our annual land cover maps over multiple periods of time is 80% for level 1 classification and over 73% for level 2 classification (29 and 33 classes). Based on an objective validation sample consisting of FLUXNET sites, our map accuracy is 10% higher than that of existing global land cover datasets including Globeland30. Our results show that the average global land cover change rate is 0.36%/yr. Global forest decreased by 1.47 million km2 from 38.44 million km2, cropland increased by 0.84 million km2 from 12.49 million km2 and impervious surface increased by 0.48 million km2 from 0.57 million km2 during 1985? 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/05/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on May 10, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/04/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/04/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-04-26T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-04-26T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-13&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #13&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multi-sensor remote sensing for drought characterization: current status, opportunities and a roadmap for the future&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimation of soil water retention in conservation agriculture using published and new pedotransfer functions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the interpretation of surprisingly high variation of soil map diversity in country-wide study of flood-affected agroecosystems using the legacy data in the Czech Republic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Building a resilient and sustainable food system in a changing world -&amp;amp; nbsp;A case for climate-smart and nutrient dense crops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;multi-sensor-remote-sensing-for-drought-characterization-current-status-opportunities-and-a-roadmap-for-the-future&quot;&gt;Multi-sensor remote sensing for drought characterization: current status, opportunities and a roadmap for the future&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satellite based remote sensing offers one of the few approaches able to monitor the spatial and temporal development of regional to continental scale droughts. A unique element of remote sensing platforms is their multi-sensor capability, which enhances the capacity for characterizing drought from a variety of perspectives. Such aspects include monitoring drought influences on vegetation and hydrological responses, as well as assessing sectoral impacts (e.g., agriculture). With advances in remote sensing systems along with an increasing range of platforms available for analysis, this contribution provides a timely and systematic review of multi sensor remote sensing drought studies, with a particular focus on drought related datasets, drought related phenomena and mechanisms, and drought modeling. To explore this topic, we first present a comprehensive summary of large-scale remote sensing datasets that can be used for multi-sensor drought studies. We then review the role of multi-sensor remote sensing for exploring key drought related phenomena and mechanisms, including vegetation responses to drought, land-atmospheric feedbacks during drought, drought-induced tree mortality, drought-related ecosystem fires, post-drought recovery and legacy effects, flash drought, as well as drought trends under climate change. A summary of recent modeling advances towards developing integrated multi-sensor remote sensing drought indices is also provided. We conclude that leveraging multi-sensor remote sensing provides unique benefits for regional to global drought studies, particularly in: 1) revealing the complex drought impact mechanisms on ecosystem components; 2) providing continuous long-term drought related information at large scales; 3) presenting real-time drought information with high spatiotemporal resolution; 4) providing multiple lines of evidence of drought monitoring to improve modeling and prediction robustness; and 5) improving the accuracy of drought monitoring and assessment efforts. We specifically highlight that more mechanism-oriented drought studies that leverage a combination of sensors and techniques (e.g., optical, microwave, hyperspectral, LiDAR, and constellations) across a range of spatiotemporal scales are needed in order to progress and advance our understanding, characterization and description of drought in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;estimation-of-soil-water-retention-in-conservation-agriculture-using-published-and-new-pedotransfer-functions&quot;&gt;Estimation of soil water retention in conservation agriculture using published and new pedotransfer functions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conservation agriculture has been developed as a means to improve the sustainability of agricultural systems and reduce drawbacks of conventional agricultural practices. Cropping practices can have a large influence on soil properties such as water retention. Proper tools are needed to assess and model effects of conservation agriculture on soil properties. As measuring soil water retention is expensive and time consuming, pedotransfer functions (PTFs) are now commonly used to predict them. The objectives of this study were to (i) present a new dataset of conservation agriculture data, (ii) assess performances of existing PTFs in predicting soil water retention of soils under conservation agriculture and (iii) develop new specific PTFs to predict water retention in conservation agriculture more accurately. We used data collected only in fields under conservation agriculture in France to evaluate several published PTFs with three evaluation criteria (RMSE, prediction bias (ME) and Nash-Sutcliffe Efficiency (EF)). We then developed new PTFs using three methods - multiple linear regression, regression tree and random forest - to predict soil water content at matric heads of -100 (theta(100), field capacity for sandy soils), -330 (theta(330), field capacity for other soils) and -15 000 cm (theta(15) 000, wilting point). Soil tillage, presence of a cover crop, rotation length and previous reduced/no tillage were used as predictors in addition to basic soil properties for regression trees and random forests. The quality of prediction (RMSE, ME and EF) was calculated for each new PTF using a cross-validation procedure. Generally, predictions of wilting point had lower absolute error than those of sandy-soil field capacity (RMSE = 0.044 and 0.066 cm(3)/cm(3), respectively). EF was usually negative for all water contents. The cross-validation performance of the new PTFs was similar for multiple linear regression (RMSE: 0.028, ME: 0.000, EF: 0.34 for theta(100)) and random forest (RMSE: 0.027, ME: 0.000, EF: 0.36 for theta(100)), and generally worse for regression tree (especially EF). Multiple linear regression that did not consider cropping practices performed as well as random forest and thus did not identify any major influence of agricultural management on predicted water content. Future research on developing PTFs should focus on identifying more relevant predictors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;on-the-interpretation-of-surprisingly-high-variation-of-soil-map-diversity-in-country-wide-study-of-flood-affected-agroecosystems-using-the-legacy-data-in-the-czech-republic&quot;&gt;On the interpretation of surprisingly high variation of soil map diversity in country-wide study of flood-affected agroecosystems using the legacy data in the Czech Republic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Legacy soil data have been produced worldwide to provide maps of soil classes or properties. In this study, we joined the legacy results of conventional soil mapping with the application of the pedodiversity concept and compositional data analysis in a comprehensive spatial analysis of the mapped soil diversity within flood-prone agroecosystems in the Czech Republic. After the statistical differences in Shannon’s entropy (conventional and adjusted with taxonomic distances) over different regional inundation areas had been statistically examined, their interpretation was based on Aitchison’s geometry of simplex, rendering an appropriate statistical framework to avoid methodological bias through the use of raw proportions in soil taxa compositions. Working with tailored orthonormal coordinates enabled us to verify the dependency of the soil taxa composition on the multicategory factors of agroecosystem type and flood-periodicity through a conventional linear modelling. The supervised compositional approach improved interpretability of soil information within the Czech legacy soil maps, and hence general patterns of pedodiversity in floodplains might be effectively described in an informative and quantitative manner. The most obvious differences of the soil map diversity proved the regional inundation areas within the catchments with the enhanced complexity of drainage network that might arise from multiple sources (substrate diversity, climatic zonality, man-induced landscape alteration).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;building-a-resilient-and-sustainable-food-system-in-a-changing-world---nbspa-case-for-climate-smart-and-nutrient-dense-crops&quot;&gt;Building a resilient and sustainable food system in a changing world -&amp;amp; nbsp;A case for climate-smart and nutrient dense crops&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current food production and consumption practices have had negative impacts on the environment and are central to global health concerns. Using a mixed-methods review, we examined the nutritional and environmental impacts of our global food systems and addressed the apparent decrease in food sources and crop diversity, and its implication on sustainable and healthy diets. Moreover, we explored the merits of weighing the use of natural capital and agricultural inputs against the output generated in terms of nutrient density. Transforming our food systems to safeguard planetary health will require a shift towards sufficient production of nutrient dense crops that are environmentally sustainable. Such a transformation largely depends on valuing crops for their natural nutrient density and matching them to suitable environments.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/04/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on April 26, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/04/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/04/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-04-25T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-04-25T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-12&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #12&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Direct cell extraction from fresh and stored soil samples: Impact on microbial viability and community compositions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil aggregate size-dependent relationships between microbial functional diversity and multifunctionality&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finding exceedance locations in a large spatial database using nonparametric regression&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Natural and managed soil structure: On the fragile scaffolding for soil functioning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SLAKES and 3D Scans characterize management effects on soil structure in farm fields&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pattern analysis of Australia soil profiles for plant available water capacity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Factors of soil formation in the 21st century&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Information depth of NIR/SWIR soil reflectance spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paying the price for environmentally sustainable and healthy EU diets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The role of nitrogen in achieving sustainable food systems for healthy diets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;paying-the-price-for-environmentally-sustainable-and-healthy-eu-diets&quot;&gt;Paying the price for environmentally sustainable and healthy EU diets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We review consumer-side interventions and their effectiveness to support a transition to healthier and more environmentally sustainable diets and identify taxes/subsidies as relevant instruments. To quantify the scope of necessary tax levels to achieve dietary recommendations on EU average, we apply three established economic models. Our business-as-usual food intake projections stress the need for policy intervention to resolve continued divergence from nutrition guidelines. Our findings suggest that food group specific taxes are effective in reaching nutrition and environmental sustainability targets. However, considerable tax levels are required to achieve the targeted consumption shifts, inducing a discussion about alternative policy designs and current model limitations. A coherent policy package is suggested to approach nutrition and sustainability objectives simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;direct-cell-extraction-from-fresh-and-stored-soil-samples-impact-on-microbial-viability-and-community-compositions&quot;&gt;Direct cell extraction from fresh and stored soil samples: Impact on microbial viability and community compositions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The direct extraction of viable microbes from soil samples is critical for the application of many single-cell related technologies. However, there are many aspects of extraction technologies that can impact the viability and diversity of extractable cells from fresh or stored soil samples. In this study, physical dispersion method, chemical dispersion method, and Nycodenz density gradient medium concentration were optimized with two sequential rounds of cell extraction from four soil samples having diverse physicochemical properties. Cell viability was quantified with fluorescence staining and flow cytometry. The viable microbial community compositions in soil extractable cells and soil samples were assessed after selective removal of DNA from dead cells. Among the four different extraction and purification methods, a protocol that included physical blending, Tween 20 treatment, and centrifugation with 80% Nycodenz, had the highest cell viability and yield. Repeated extraction increased the yield but reduced the cell viability. The over- or under-represented taxa in extractable cells might contribute to the bias of the extractable microbial communities. Using the optimized cell extraction procedure, the effect of soil storage conditions (4 degrees C, -80 degrees C, and air-drying) on yield, viability, and community composition of soil extractable cells were assessed. Cell viability decreased in all stored soil samples, but significant decreases in cell yield was only observed in air-dried soil samples. Microbial community compositions changed significantly in all stored soil samples, with the least changes were observed in soil stored at 4 degrees C, confirming that 4 degrees C short-term storage is suitable for highly efficient viable cell extraction. Taken together, the developed method offers great potential for advancing our analyses and understanding of soil microbial ecology and the role of individual microbes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-aggregate-size-dependent-relationships-between-microbial-functional-diversity-and-multifunctionality&quot;&gt;Soil aggregate size-dependent relationships between microbial functional diversity and multifunctionality&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil stability and aggregates are important drivers of soil fertility and microbial diversity and are highly vulnerable to land degradation. However, the role of soil aggregates in driving the responses of microbial functional diversity and multiple ecosystem services and functions (multifunctionality) to further degradation (e. g., fertilization) remains largely unexplored and poorly understood. In this study, we used soils from long-term experiments involving inorganic and organic fertilization treatments to investigate the role soil aggregates (microscale) play in driving microbial functional gene diversity (via GeoChip) and the activity of multiple extracellular enzymes in an agricultural ecosystem. We found that microbial functional gene diversity has a significant and positive relationship with soil multifunctionality, which is enhanced in soil aggregates by organic fertilizer but is reduced by inorganic fertilizer. We also found that soil aggregate fractions indirectly controlled multiple ecosystem functions via changes in functional diversity. Smaller soil aggregates with higher resource availability (carbon and nitrogen) supported more ecological functions than larger aggregates under contrasting fertilizer management regimes. Soil multifunctionality is regulated by the differences in resource availability and not by microbial functional gene composition, which suggests that microbial functional diversity contributed more to multifunctionality than gene composition. Random forest analysis and structural equation modeling indicated that soil carbon and nitrogen and microbial functional diversity together determined the multifunctionality, whereas soil traits have more standardized total effects than functional diversity. Our study highlights that soil aggregation stratifies soil nutrition and microbial functional diversity, which leads to the differentiation of aggregate ecosystem multifunctionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;finding-exceedance-locations-in-a-large-spatial-database-using-nonparametric-regression&quot;&gt;Finding exceedance locations in a large spatial database using nonparametric regression&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the era of big data analysis, it is of interest to develop diagnostic tools for preliminary scanning of large spatial databases. One problem is identification of locations where certain characteristics exceed a given norm, e.g. timber volume or mean tree diameter exceeding a user-defined threshold. Some of the challenges are, large size of the database, randomness, complex shape of the spatial mean surface, heterogeneity and others. In a step-bystep procedure, we propose a method for achieving this for large spatial data sets. For illustration, we work through a simulated spatial data set as well as a forest inventory data set from Alaska (source: USDA Forest Services). Working within the framework of nonparametric regression modeling, the proposed method can attain a high degree of flexibility regarding the shape of the spatial mean surface. Taking advantage of the large sample size, we also provide asymptotic formulas that are easy to implement in any statistical software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;natural-and-managed-soil-structure-on-the-fragile-scaffolding-for-soil-functioning&quot;&gt;Natural and managed soil structure: On the fragile scaffolding for soil functioning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil structure in natural systems is a product of complex interactions between biological activity, climate and soil minerals that promote aggregation and accumulation of biopores. In arable lands, the management of soil structure often requires the mechanical fragmentation of hardened soil to improve seedbed, control weeds and bury plant residue. Despite difficulties in defining and quantifying soil structure, its critical role is evidenced by loss of productivity when natural structure is perturbed (e.g. compaction) and the long history of tillage in agriculture. To overcome persistent ambiguities among scientific disciplines regarding definition and function of soil structure, we propose a framework for distinguishing managed and natural soil structure based on their different formation processes and functions. Natural soil structure preserves ecological order and legacy that promotes biopore reuse, stabilizes foodwebs and protects soil organic carbon (SOC). The contribution of net primary productivity of natural lands to soil structure forming processes makes it a useful (surrogate) metric of soil structure. The benefits of managed soil structure for crops are quantified indirectly via comparisons with no till farming under similar conditions. The levels and trends of SOC are useful metrics for the status of natural and managed soil structure. The systematic consideration of soil structure state in natural and arable lands using suitable metrics is a prerequisite for rational decisions related to land management and ensuring sustainable functioning of a fragile and central resource such as soil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;slakes-and-3d-scans-characterize-management-effects-on-soil-structure-in-farm-fields&quot;&gt;SLAKES and 3D Scans characterize management effects on soil structure in farm fields&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adoption of no-till (NT) is low in the Lower and Middle Brazos River Watershed of Texas, leaving soil vulnerable to erosion, exacerbating flooding, and contributing to high nutrient and sediment levels in surface waters. To investigate the impact of NT on soil structure and hydraulic function in the region, we measured saturated hydraulic conductivity, organic carbon, bulk density, slaking index of soil aggregates (inversely related to aggregate stability), and soil structure in farm fields under three management systems: conventional tillage (CT), NT, and perennial grass (PG). Soil structure was measured using a novel method for 3D scanning of soil surface horizons - multistripe laser triangulation. Slaking index was measured using a recently developed smartphone application. Exploratory factor analysis combined with a semi-supervised cluster analysis showed that, in general, CT and PG fields were classified into different clusters from one another. Three fields managed with NT for 21, 21, and 7 years were classified in the same cluster as PG fields, while the remaining fields (managed with NT for 21, 21, 18, and 3 years) were classified with CT fields. Organic carbon was significantly higher in NT compared to CT fields. Conventional fields had significantly lower hydraulic conductivity than PG fields and hydraulic conductivity was 1.3 cm h-1 higher in NT than CT fields. Soil structure measured from 10-30 cm depth was significantly improved in NT compared to CT. Improvements in organic carbon and soil hydraulic function are meaningful indicators of improved physical soil health that can be used to promote NT adoption. Improvements in organic carbon and soil hydraulic function also provide ecosystem services to off-site stakeholders who are impacted by erosion and sedimentation resulting from soil tillage. The two novel measurements (a metric derived from scanning of soil structure and slaking index from a smartphone application) were particularly sensitive to management system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pattern-analysis-of-australia-soil-profiles-for-plant-available-water-capacity&quot;&gt;Pattern analysis of Australia soil profiles for plant available water capacity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plant available water capacity (PAWC), defined as the amount of water held in the soil between the drained upper limit (DUL) and crop lower limit (CLL), is a major determinant for crop yield in dryland cropping areas. However, measured soil profile data quantifying the physical soil parameters that determine PAWC are limited. Choosing a ‘representative’ soil profile in order to parameterise a deterministic model is often subjective and may not be appropriate, leading to biased conclusions. To help support these deterministic crop modelling studies, we analysed soil profile data in Australia available in the APSoil database; a database of field and laboratory measured physical soil properties used to parameterise the Agricultural Production Systems sIMulator (APSIM) model. Specifically, we developed typical soil pattern profiles utilizing wheat for CLL using statistical shape analysis and cluster analysis. Our method allows modellers to reduce the number of soil profile parameter choices using a statistically sound basis. We implement our method by grouping the APSoil soil profiles into five clusters, whereby each cluster is represented by a more general soil profile. The representative soil profiles reflect impact of the soil texture on PAWC. The five clusters and representative soil profiles can then be used in future modelling studies to investigate the impact of soil variation on systems performance. In turn, soil scientists will have a plausible and quantifiable collection of soil profiles to choose from for future studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;factors-of-soil-formation-in-the-21st-century&quot;&gt;Factors of soil formation in the 21st century&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year 2021 marks the 80th anniversary of the publication of Factors of Soil Formation. A System of Quantitative Pedology by Hans Jenny. Given the exponential surge in annual citations of the book over the past 30 years, and this important milestone in its history, it is an opportune time to examine what the book presents, and how it is relevant to transdisciplinary research in the 21st Century. The book did not originate the concept of soil forming factors, which were by then already widely accepted in soil science, but instead translated it into a quantitative scientific framework through rigorous definition of the soil system, and the identification and separation of dependent and independent variables. The initial formulation of the theoretical framework was inspired by thermodynamics, but with pedologically-relevant state variables. Subsequent formulations of the model by Jenny articulated the connection and utility to examining energy and mass fluxes through the soil system, a point of departure for recent efforts to bring open system, non-equilibrium thermodynamic methods to bear on soil research. The State Factor theory is a powerful lens to examine a number of academic and societally relevant issues in the 21st century, such as the role of the biotic factor and its interplay with the physical soil environment. However, the most critical, and understudied, state factor is the effect of humans on soil systems. Earth science must embrace the challenge, and obligation to society, to explore the human footprint on the planet, and devise ways to remediate its impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;information-depth-of-nirswir-soil-reflectance-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Information depth of NIR/SWIR soil reflectance spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proximal and remote sensing techniques in the optical domain are cost-effective alternatives to standard soil property characterization methods. However, the extent of light penetration into the soil sample, also termed soil information depth, is not well understood. In this study a new analytical model that links the particle size distribution and soil reflectance in the near infrared (NIR) and shortwave infrared (SWIR) bands of the electromagnetic spectrum is introduced. The model enables the partitioning of measured reflectance spectra into surface and volume (subsurface) contributions, thereby yielding insights about the soil information depth. The model simulations indicate that the surface reflectance contribution to the total reflectance is significantly higher than the volume reflectance contribution for a broad range of soils that vastly differ in texture, mineralogical composition and organic matter contents. The ratio of volume to total reflectance is higher for sandy soils than for clayey soils, especially at longer optical wavelengths, but the ratio rarely exceeds 15%. Therefore, the light reflection from dry soils is predominantly a surface phenomenon and the information depth in most soils rarely exceeds 1 mm. The results of this study reveal an intimate physical relationship between soil reflectance and the particle size distribution in the NIR/SWIR range, which opens a potential new avenue for retrieval of the particle size distribution from remotely sensed reflectance via a universal process-based approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-role-of-nitrogen-in-achieving-sustainable-food-systems-for-healthy-diets&quot;&gt;The role of nitrogen in achieving sustainable food systems for healthy diets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ‘food system’ urgently needs a sustainable transformation. Two major challenges have to be solved: the food system has to provide food security with healthy, accessible, affordable, safe and diverse food for all, and it has to do so within the safe operating space of the planetary boundaries, where the pollution from reactive nitrogen turned out to be the largest bottleneck. Here we argue that thinking strategically about how to balance nitrogen flows throughout the food system will make current food systems more resilient and robust. Looking from a material and a governance perspective on the food system, we highlight major nitrogen losses and policy blind spots originating from a compartmentalization of food system spheres. We conclude that a participatory and integrated approach to manage nitrogen flows throughout the food system is necessary to stay within regional and global nitrogen boundaries, and will additionally provide synergies with a sustainable and healthy diet for all.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/04/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on April 25, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/04/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/04/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-04-14T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-04-14T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-11&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #11&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Progress in recent airborne gamma ray spectrometry measurement technology&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Retrievals of soil moisture and vegetation optical depth using a multi-channel collaborative algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil organic carbon sequestration calculated from depth distribution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;progress-in-recent-airborne-gamma-ray-spectrometry-measurement-technology&quot;&gt;Progress in recent airborne gamma ray spectrometry measurement technology&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the development of deep resource exploration, rapid nuclear emergency response, environmental monitoring, great progress has been made in airborne gamma-ray spectrum (AGS) measurement technology during the past few decades. Its development prospects are closely related to the AGS instruments and data processing technology. The AGS technology can be used to retrieve radionuclide information, which makes it a hot research field to improve the sensitivity, accuracy and detection limit of the AGS detection effectively. This paper focuses on the progress made in the AGS instruments and data processing since 1940s’, deeply reviews the technology characteristics and development status, thoroughly discusses the typical AGS applications, summarizes the current technology trend, and puts forward potential research directions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;retrievals-of-soil-moisture-and-vegetation-optical-depth-using-a-multi-channel-collaborative-algorithm&quot;&gt;Retrievals of soil moisture and vegetation optical depth using a multi-channel collaborative algorithm&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the success of the SMOS (Soil Moisture and Ocean Salinity) and SMAP (Soil Moisture Active Passive) missions, new satellite missions are on the horizon. The current and future missions can benefit from investigations that seek to improve retrieval algorithms that quantitatively map global soil moisture and vegetation optical depth (tau) from Earth’s microwave emissions. In this study, we explore multi-angular and multi-frequency approaches for the retrieval of soil moisture and vegetation tau, considering the payload configurations of current and future satellite missions (such as the Copernicus Imaging Microwave Radiometer, the Water Cycle Observation Mission, and the Terrestrial Water Resources Satellite) using a new set of ground observations. Two ground-based microwave radiometry datasets collected in Inner Mongolia during the Soil Moisture Experiment in the Luan River from July to August 2017 (cropland) and August to September 2018 (grassland) are used for this study. The corn field, which covers an entire growth period, indicated that the degree of information increases linearly as the number of channels (in terms of the incidence angle and frequency) increases, and that the multi-frequency observations contain slightly more independent information than do the multi-angular observations under the same number of channels. The polarization difference in brightness temperature is sensitive to both soil moisture and vegetation water content, especially at L-band due to its penetrating ability. Soil moisture explains most of the variance in frequency differences of brightness temperature at adjacent frequencies (L- &amp;amp; C-bands, C- &amp;amp; X-bands), while the variance in incidence-angle differences of brightness temperature is mostly associated with the vegetation water content. A multi-channel collaborative algorithm (MCCA) is developed based on the two-component version of the omega-tau model, which utilizes information from collaborative channels expressed as an analytical form of brightness temperature at the core channel to rule out the parameters to be retrieved. Results of soil moisture retrieval show that the multi-angular approach used by the MCCA generally has a better performance, unbiased mot mean square difference (ubRMSD) varying from 0.028 cm(3)/cm(3) to 0.037 cm(3)/cm(3), than the multi-frequency approach (ubRMSD from 0.028 cm(3)/cm(3) to 0.089 cm(3)/cm(3)) for the corn field. This is attributed to the dependence of vegetation tau on the frequency being more significant than that on the incidence angle. Except for in the C- &amp;amp; X-band combination, the multi-frequency approach used by the MCCA performs better (ubRMSD from 0.018 cm(3)/cm(3) to 0.023 cm(3)/cm(3)) than the multi-angular version (ubRMSD from 0.026 cm(3)/cm(3) to 0.034 cm(3)/cm(3)) for the grass field due to reduced vegetation effects for this type of cover. It is affirmed that increasing the number of observation channels could make the soil moisture retrieval more robust, but might also limit the retrieval performance, as the probability that the model estimations will not match the observations is increased. This study provides new insights into the design of potential satellite missions to improve soil moisture retrieval. A satellite with simultaneous multi-angular and multi-frequency observation capabilities is highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-organic-carbon-sequestration-calculated-from-depth-distribution&quot;&gt;Soil organic carbon sequestration calculated from depth distribution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract
Sequestration of organic C in agricultural soils is necessary to improve soil health to meet the challenges of climate change, diminishing biodiversity, water quality deterioration, and rising demands for food and fiber production. New assessment approaches are needed to quantify how conservation agriculture might contribute to soil health improvement and soil organic C (SOC) sequestration. In the southeastern United States, conservation management has been repeatedly shown to stratify SOC concentration with depth. Starting immediately below a zone of tillage influence (i.e., 30-cm depth), SOC concentration is rarely affected by management due to low C inputs and high decomposition potential, whereas concentration increases toward the surface in a nonlinear manner, presumably with greater inputs of residue and root inputs and changing temperature and moisture conditions. Using these observations as an ecological foundation, SOC sequestration was calculated as the summation of SOC stock greater than the baseline condition at 30-cm depth. Data from literature sources were mathematically fitted with this new approach as a validation. Two on-farm surveys with different agricultural management practices (5-40 yr) in the southeastern United States yielded preliminary estimates of SOC sequestration. The interquartile range of calculated SOC sequestration was 4.2-9.4 Mg C ha(-1) for conventional-tillage cropland (n = 45 fields), 13.6-29.7 Mg C ha(-1) for no-tillage cropland (n = 97 fields), and 15.9-26.1 Mg C ha(-1) for perennial pasture (n = 29 fields). This new approach will be valuable to estimate SOC sequestration from a greater diversity of conservation agricultural systems practiced on farms within a region and independent of soil type.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/04/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on April 14, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/04/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/04/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-04-05T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-04-05T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-10&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimation of soil water retention curves from soil bulk electrical conductivity and water content measurements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The effect of organic carbon content on soil compression characteristics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A comparison of isometric and amalgamation logratio balances in compositional data analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;estimation-of-soil-water-retention-curves-from-soil-bulk-electrical-conductivity-and-water-content-measurements&quot;&gt;Estimation of soil water retention curves from soil bulk electrical conductivity and water content measurements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Measurement of soil water retention curves (SWRCs) is time consuming, and there is no single laboratory device available to measure a SWRC over an entire range of relevant pressures. The van Genuchten (vG) model is commonly used to characterize the shape of the SWRC. Bulk soil electrical conductivity as a function of water content, sigma(theta), has been used to estimate hydraulic properties of unsaturated soils, thus making it possible to relate sigma(theta) and SWRC. The saturated and residual water content values, theta(s) and theta(r), can be estimated from soil bulk density and particle size distribution. In this study, we present an approach to estimate vG parameters m and alpha from sigma measured at saturated and residual soil water contents, as well as sigma(theta) values measured at intermediate water contents. A thermo-time domain reflectometry (thermo-TDR) sensor is used to measure sigma and theta of the same soil sample volume. SWRCs for three soils (Glassil 530 sand, Tennessee silt loam and Illinois clay loam with bulk densities ranging from 1.52 to 1.67 g cm(-3), 1.05 to 1.25 g cm(-3) and 1.05 to 1.2 g cm(-3), respectively) are estimated from sigma(theta) measurements and compared with direct SWRC measurements obtained with a tension table and pressure plate extractors. Additional comparisons are made using data obtained from the literature. The proposed method to estimate SWRCs performs well when compared to direct SWRC measurements (with an average RMSE and an average bias of 0.041 cm(3) cm(-3) and 0.008 cm(3) cm(-3), respectively). Results indicate that the new sigma(theta) based method accurately estimates SWRCs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-effect-of-organic-carbon-content-on-soil-compression-characteristics&quot;&gt;The effect of organic carbon content on soil compression characteristics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We investigated the effect of soil organic carbon (SOC) on the consolidation behaviour of soil from two long term field experiments at Rothamsted; the Broadbalk Wheat Experiment and Hoosfield Spring Barley. These experiments are located on soil with similar particle size distributions, and include treatments with SOC contents ranging from approximately 1?3.5 g/100 g. Soils taken from plots with contrasting SOC contents were compressed and deformed in a triaxial cell and the normal consolidation and critical state lines were determined. We found that the compression index was independent of SOC, but the void ratio at any given effective stress was highly correlated with organic carbon content. By comparison with uniaxial compression data, the apparent influence of SOC on the compression index is likely to be due to its effect on soil hydraulic properties rather than any intrinsic effects of strength. The plastic limit test appears to be a useful and simple test to allow direct comparison of soil physical behaviour and expected soil density.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-comparison-of-isometric-and-amalgamation-logratio-balances-in-compositional-data-analysis&quot;&gt;A comparison of isometric and amalgamation logratio balances in compositional data analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The isometric logratio transformation, in the form of what has been called a “balance”, has been promoted as a way to contrast two groups of parts in a compositional data set by forming ratios of their respective geometric means. This transformation has attractive theoretical properties and hence provides a useful reference, but geometric means are highly affected by parts with small relative values. When a comparison between two groups of parts is required in practical applications, such as the investigation and construction of models, while making use of substantive domain knowledge, it is demonstrated that the logratio of two amalgamations serves as an alternative, interpretable form of balance. A geochemical data set is considered, which has been analyzed previously by transforming to a set of isometric logratio balances. An alternative approach, using a reduced set of pairwise logratios of parts, optionally involving prescribed amalgamations, is very close to optimal in accounting for the variance in this compositional data set. These simpler transformations also have an exact back transformation to the original parts. This approach highlights for this dataset which compositional parts are driving the data structure, using variables that are easy to interpret and that map well to research-driven objectives.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/04/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on April 05, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/03/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/03/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-03-29T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-03-29T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-9&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rethinking restoration indicators and end-points for post-mining landscapes in light of novel ecosystems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting the message right on nature-based solutions to climate change&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assessment of the interpretability of data mining for the spatial modelling of water erosion using game theory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rethinking-restoration-indicators-and-end-points-for-post-mining-landscapes-in-light-of-novel-ecosystems&quot;&gt;Rethinking restoration indicators and end-points for post-mining landscapes in light of novel ecosystems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Degraded post-mining landscapes exhibit unique biotic and abiotic components and processes relative to predisturbance natural ecosystems. Yet the concept of pre-disturbance reference natural ecosystems and their associated soil quality indicators (SQIs) (e.g., pH, soil organic carbon) are prominently used for assessing restoration of post-mining landscapes. Limited reviews exist on the validity, limitations, opportunities and knowledge gaps associated with the application of the concept and SQIs on post-mining landscapes. Hence, evidence was examined to highlight constraints, opportunities and future research directions pertaining to the concept and SQIs. First, as novel, hybrid or designer ecosystems, severely degraded post-mining landscapes lack reference natural ecosystems. The framing of restoration is multi-dimensional, and dependent on spatial and temporal scales. Therefore, short-term data on SQIs often measured at point scale cannot adequately account for the multi-dimensionality and scales. Moreover, evidence linking SQIs to ecosystem functions, goods, values, services, and benefits on degraded post-mining landscapes remains weak. Potential redundancy exists among SQIs, because soil properties exhibit spatial and temporal correlation. The universality of SQIs remains unconfirmed, because data validating the measurement protocols and interpretation of SQIs across various biomes are scarce. A framework is presented proposing: (1) a shift from the concept of reference natural ecosystems to novel and designer ecosystems in restoration ecology, (2) the development of the next generation of hierarchical or ecosystem cascade indicators, and end-points addressing the multi-dimensionality and scale issues, and (3) a decision matrix for integrating novel, hybrid and designer ecosystems. The potential applications of novel tools such as drones, laser-based cameras, genomics, and big data analytics are highlighted. Such novel tools could unravel the complex linkages among biotic and abiotic components, and ecosystem function and services, which are currently difficult to investigate using conventional techniques. Finally, ten tentative hypotheses are presented on the restoration of degraded post-mining landscapes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-the-message-right-on-nature-based-solutions-to-climate-change&quot;&gt;Getting the message right on nature-based solutions to climate change&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nature-based solutions (NbS)-solutions to societal challenges that involve working with nature-have recently gained popularity as an integrated approach that can address climate change and biodiversity loss, while supporting sustainable development. Although well-designed NbS can deliver multiple benefits for people and nature, much of the recent limelight has been on tree planting for carbon sequestration. There are serious concerns that this is distracting from the need to rapidly phase out use of fossil fuels and protect existing intact ecosystems. There are also concerns that the expansion of forestry framed as a climate change mitigation solution is coming at the cost of carbon rich and biodiverse native ecosystems and local resource rights. Here, we discuss the promise and pitfalls of the NbS framing and its current political traction, and we present recommendations on how to get the message right. We urge policymakers, practitioners and researchers to consider the synergies and trade-offs associated with NbS and to follow four guiding principles to enable NbS to provide sustainable benefits to society: (1) NbS are not a substitute for the rapid phase out of fossil fuels; (2) NbS involve a wide range of ecosystems on land and in the sea, not just forests; (3) NbS are implemented with the full engagement and consent of Indigenous Peoples and local communities in a way that respects their cultural and ecological rights; and (4) NbS should be explicitly designed to provide measurable benefits for biodiversity. Only by following these guidelines will we design robust and resilient NbS that address the urgent challenges of climate change and biodiversity loss, sustaining nature and people together, now and into the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;assessment-of-the-interpretability-of-data-mining-for-the-spatial-modelling-of-water-erosion-using-game-theory&quot;&gt;Assessment of the interpretability of data mining for the spatial modelling of water erosion using game theory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This study undertook a comprehensive application of 15 data mining (DM) models, most of which have, thus far, not been commonly used in environmental sciences, to predict land susceptibility to water erosion hazard in the Kahorestan catchment, southern Iran. The DM models were BGLM, BGAM, Cforest, CITree, GAMS, LRSS, NCPQR, PLS, PLSGLM, QR, RLM, SGB, SVM, BCART and BTR. We identified 18 factors usually considered as key controls for water erosion, comprising 10 factors extracted from a digital elevation model (DEM), three indices extracted from Landsat 8 images, a sediment connectivity index (SCI) and three other intrinsic factors. Three indicators consisting of MAE, MBE, RMSE, and a Taylor diagram were applied to assess model performance and accuracy. Game theory was applied to assess the interpretability of the DM models for predicting water erosion hazard. Among the 15 predictive models, BGAM and PLS respectively returned the best and worst performance in predicting water erosion hazard in the study area. The most accurate model, BGAM predicted that 22%, 8.2%, 9.4% and 60.4% of the total area should be classified as low, moderate, high and very high susceptibility to soil erosion by water, respectively. Based on BGAM and game theory, the factors extracted from the DEM (e.g., DEM, TWI, Slope, TST, TRI, and SPI) were considered the most important ones controlling the predicted severity of soil erosion by water. We conclude that overall, game theory is a valuable technique for assessing the interpretability of predictive models because this theory through SHAP (Shapley additive explanations) and PFIM (permutation feature importance measure) addresses the important concerns regarding the interpretability of more complex DM models.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/03/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on March 29, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/03/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/03/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-03-28T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-03-28T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-8&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #8&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Global Surface Soil Moisture Drydown Patterns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Disentangling the Impact of Catchment Heterogeneity on Nitrate Export Dynamics From Event to Long-Term Time Scales&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mass-balance approach to quantify water distribution in soils based onX-ray computed tomography images&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Land system diversity, scaling laws and polygons map analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Statistical approaches for spatial sample survey: Persistent misconceptions and new&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimation of carbon stocks in boreal cropland soils - methodological considerations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introducing a mechanistic model in digital soil mapping to predict soil organic matter stocks in theCantabrianregion (Spain)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A log -barrier approach for airborne gamma-ray spectrometry inversion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The influence of rock fragments on field capacity water content in stony soils from hard sandstone alluvium&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil quality and grain yield: A win-win combination in clayey tropical oxisols&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;global-surface-soil-moisture-drydown-patterns&quot;&gt;Global Surface Soil Moisture Drydown Patterns&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding the global soil moisture (SM) dynamics and its governing controls beyond the Darcy Scale is critical for various hydrological, meteorological, agricultural, and environmental applications. In this study, we parameterize the pathways of global surface SM (theta(RS)) drydowns using seasonal observation from Soil Moisture Active Passive (SMAP) satellite (between 2015 and 2019) at 36 km resolution. We develop a new data-driven nonparametric approach to identify the canonical forms of theta(RS) drydown, followed by a nonlinear least squares parameterization of the seasonal drydown pathways at each SMAP footprint. The derived parameters provide the effective soil water retention parameters (SWRPeff), land-atmospheric coupling strength and soil hydrologic regimes for SMAP footprint. Depending on the footprint heterogeneity, climate, and season, the characteristics curves comprising different drydown phases are discovered at SMAP footprints. Drydown curves respond to the within-footprint changes in the meteorological drivers, land-surface characteristics, and the soil-vegetative and atmospheric dynamics. Drydown parameters display high interseasonal variability, especially in the grasslands, croplands, and savannah landscapes due to significant changes in the landscape characteristics and moisture patterns at the subgrid-scale. Soil texture exerts influence on the soil water retention and drydown parameters only when the footprint mean theta(RS) is low, specifically in arid and sparsely vegetated regions. The interseasonal variability of the SWRPeff is primarily driven by the landuse and climate of the SMAP footprint. A global understanding of the SM drydown features at SMAP footprint provides a significant step toward a scale-specific, effective soil hydrologic parameterization for various applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;disentangling-the-impact-of-catchment-heterogeneity-on-nitrate-export-dynamics-from-event-to-long-term-time-scales&quot;&gt;Disentangling the Impact of Catchment Heterogeneity on Nitrate Export Dynamics From Event to Long-Term Time Scales&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Defining effective measures to reduce nitrate pollution in heterogeneous mesoscale catchments remains challenging when based on concentration measurements at the outlet only. One reason for this is our limited understanding of the subcatchment contributions to nitrate export and their importance at different time scales. While upstream subcatchments often disproportionally contribute to runoff generation and in turn to nutrient export, agricultural areas (which are typically found in downstream lowlands) are known to be a major source of nitrate pollution. To examine the interplay of different subcatchments, we analyzed seasonal long-term trends and event dynamics of nitrate concentrations, loads, and the concentration-discharge relationship in three nested catchments within the Selke catchment (456 km(2)), Germany. The upstream subcatchments (40.4% of total catchment area, 34.5% of N input) had short transit times and dynamic concentration-discharge relationships with elevated nitrate concentrations during wet seasons and events. Consequently, the upstream subcatchments dominated nitrate export during high flow and disproportionally contributed to overall annual nitrate loads at the outlet (64.2%). The downstream subcatchment was characterized by higher N input, longer transit times, and relatively constant nitrate concentrations between seasons, dominating nitrate export during low-flow periods. Neglecting the disproportional role of upstream subcatchments for temporally elevated nitrate concentrations and net annual loads can lead to an overestimation of the role of agricultural lowlands. Nonetheless, constantly high concentrations from nitrate legacies pose a long-term threat to water quality in agricultural lowlands. This knowledge is crucial for an effective and site-specific water quality management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plain Language Summary To efficiently remove nitrate pollution, we need to understand how it is transported, mobilized, and stored within large and heterogeneous catchments. Previous studies have shown that upstream catchments often have a disproportional impact on nutrient export, while agriculture (a major nitrate source) is often located in downstream lowlands. To understand which parts of a catchment contribute most to nitrate export and when, we analyzed long-term (1983-2016) and high-frequency (2010-2016) data in the Selke catchment (Germany) at three locations. The mountainous upstream part dominated nitrate transport during winter, spring, and rain events. It had a surprisingly high contribution to annual nitrate loads. The agricultural downstream part of the catchment dominated nitrate export during summer and autumn, with relatively constant concentrations between seasons. Here, nitrogen inputs needed more than a decade to travel through the subsurface of the catchment, which causes a time lag between measures to reduce nitrate pollution and their measurable effect. The resulting storage of nitrate in the groundwater threatens drinking water quality for decades to come. While the role of agricultural lowlands for nitrate export can be overestimated if neglecting the disproportional role of upstream subcatchments, their impact poses a long-term threat to water quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mass-balance-approach-to-quantify-water-distribution-in-soils-based-onx-ray-computed-tomography-images&quot;&gt;Mass-balance approach to quantify water distribution in soils based onX-ray computed tomography images&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;X-ray computed tomography (CT) is commonly used in soil science to quantify distributions of pores, water and solids within soil samples. Particularly promising for liquid visualization is dual-energy scanning of samples with added dopant solutions. The approach uses solutions of heavy elements as a proxy for the soil water and utilizes the abrupt increase of the mass attenuation coefficient of heavy elements when crossing an X-ray absorption edge, detectable by dual-energy CT scanning. However, a key step in visualization of the added liquid is image segmentation. In partially saturated soils, the X-ray CT images consist of voxels with the presence of solid, liquid and gaseous phases in different ratios. These ratios are generally ignored by the traditional image segmentation methods, which separate image voxels into groups with either zero or complete saturation by either prevailing phase. The objective of this study was to develop and test a new physically based segmentation approach that accounts for partial saturation of image voxels by liquids. We combined a theoretical equation for detected photon intensity with the mass conservation equation to compute saturation of image voxels by dopant solution applied to the soil. This approach was tested on soil micro-columns with potassium iodide (KI) solutions. The proposed approach outperformed the traditional segmentation methods, particularly at low and intermediate water contents. Tests conducted forKIsolutions in the concentration ranges from 2 to 20% revealed deterioration of the method accuracy with decreasing dopant concentration in the soil. Based on the results of this study we recommend 10 wt% KI solution for quantifying spatial distribution of liquids in soils using dual-energy X-ray microtomography. Highlights
We developed a new approach to quantify soil water distribution based on X-ray CT. This approach accounts for partial saturation of image voxels by liquids. This approach outperforms the standard image segmentation methods. Its application is limited to using dual energy monochromatic X-ray beams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;land-system-diversity-scaling-laws-and-polygons-map-analysis&quot;&gt;Land system diversity, scaling laws and polygons map analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numerous lines of evidence have been presented in the literature that show the patterns of pedodiversity and biodiversity are very similar. One of the most corroborated patterns lies in the fits of the relationships between biodiversity and soil diversity to power laws according to the increase in study area. Several authors have analysed the presence of fractal and multifractal features in pedodiversity and biodiversity analyses. Similarly, it has also been found that valuable information can be extracted from the polygons of soil and vegetation maps, which also have surprising similarities. These approaches concern information on the spatial distribution of natural resources. However, other more artificial but interesting maps and their comparison have been neglected by such studies. Land systems maps and their georeferenced databases fall into this latter category, and they include most of the soil-forming factors. In this paper a georeferenced land system database and map were analysed and the results compared with those obtained in previous pedodiversity and biodiversity studies, primarily the spatial patterns of the polygons. The results showed that the analysed land system map units followed the same patterns that were previously found in pedodiversity and biodiversity studies; that is, the power law concerning richness-area relationships. The same patterns occur with the number of polygons. Some geographers claim there is a “law” that states that there are far more small things/objects than larger ones across several orders of magnitude in geographic space and thus this regularity conforms to scaling laws, independent of the resource involved. The results obtained corroborate this conjecture irrespective of whether natural resources or artificial cartographies were analysed. This paper represents a first test of land use maps; additional work in this area is needed. Highlights
Spatial patterns detected in natural and land system maps seem to be similar Composite GIS maps have the same spatial patterns as their base maps. Soil and land system units conform to long-tail or heavy tail distributions. Soil maps and land system maps conform to power laws, fingerprints of fractal structures There are more small polygons than large ones across several magnitude orders on choropleth maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;statistical-approaches-for-spatial-sample-survey-persistent-misconceptions-and-new&quot;&gt;Statistical approaches for spatial sample survey: Persistent misconceptions and new&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several misconceptions about the design-based approach for sampling and statistical inference, based on classical sampling theory, seem to be quite persistent. These misconceptions are the result of confusion about basic statistical concepts such as independence, expectation, and bias and variance of estimators or predictors. These concepts have a different meaning in the design-based and model-based approach, because they consider different sources of randomness. Also, a population mean is still often confused with a model mean, and a population variance with a model-variance, leading to invalid formulas for the variance of an estimator of the population mean. In this paper the fundamental differences between these two approaches are illustrated with simulations, so that hopefully more pedometricians get a better understanding of this subject. An overview is presented of how in the design-based approach we can make use of knowledge of the spatial structure of the study variable. In the second part, new developments in both the design-based and model-based approach are described that try to combine the strengths of the two approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;estimation-of-carbon-stocks-in-boreal-cropland-soils---methodological-considerations&quot;&gt;Estimation of carbon stocks in boreal cropland soils - methodological considerations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High expectations to harness agricultural soils as sinks for atmospheric carbon (C) necessitate methods for verifying changes in soil organic C (SOC) stocks and improving the accuracy of regional SOC stock estimates specific to various land-use and management types. In this study we used a sample set included in the Finnish national soil monitoring network (n = 125) to determine the SOC stock and its vertical distribution in Finnish agricultural mineral soils using fixed depth (FD) and equivalent soil mass (ESM) methods. Further, we explored the within-field variation in SOC stock and minimum sample size in the context of SOC sequestration. Boreal agricultural mineral soils were found to be rich in SOC. The average SOC stock ranged between 8.4 and 9.8 kg m(-2)in the top 30 cm depending on cropping system and soil type. Cultivation of perennial crops tended to enrich the C close to the soil surface in comparison to dominantly annual crops, which exhibited a less steep C gradient with depth. The commonly used van Bemmelen factor of 1.724 to convert results of loss on ignition to SOC was found to be appropriate for coarse-textured Finnish agricultural soils. However, the results showed that in clay-rich soils, it is critical to take into account the structural water bound in clay particles to avoid overestimation of the SOC content. The study also demonstrated that the minimum sample size required to detect the change of 0.1 kg C m(-2)at field level is typically several hundreds. Therefore empirical soil sampling is not at all cost-effective enough for verifying the changes in SOC stocks with regard to compensation of C sequestration for farmers. Thus, alternative verification methods, such as SOC modelling in combination with field-level data collected, for example, using remote sensing should be developed further. Highlights
Boreal agricultural mineral soils are rich in C Rotations where perennial crops dominated tended to enrich C in the soil surface Soil clay content should be taken into account when converting SOM to SOC The sample size required to verify SOC stock changes for C trading is extremely high&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;introducing-a-mechanistic-model-in-digital-soil-mapping-to-predict-soil-organic-matter-stocks-in-thecantabrianregion-spain&quot;&gt;Introducing a mechanistic model in digital soil mapping to predict soil organic matter stocks in theCantabrianregion (Spain)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital soil mapping (DSM) is an effective mapping technique that supports the increased need for quantitative soil data. In DSM, soil properties are correlated with environmental characteristics using statistical models such as regression. However, many of these relationships are explicitly described in mechanistic simulation models. Therefore, the mechanistic relationships can, in theory, replace the statistical relationships in DSM. This study aims to develop a mechanistic model to predict soil organic matter (SOM) stocks in Natura2000 areas of the Cantabria region (Spain). The mechanistic model is established in four steps: (a) identify major processes that influence SOM stocks, (b) review existing models describing the major processes and the respective environmental data that they require, (c) establish a database with the required input data, and (d) calibrate the model with field observations. The SOM stocks map resulting from the mechanistic model had a mean error (ME) of -2 t SOM ha(-1)and a root mean square error (RMSE) of 66 t SOM ha(-1). The Lin’s concordance correlation coefficient was 0.47 and the amount of variance explained (AVE) was 0.21. The results of the mechanistic model were compared to the results of a statistical model. It turned out that the correlation coefficient between the two SOM stock maps was 0.8. This study illustrated that mechanistic soil models can be used for DSM, which brings new opportunities. Mechanistic models for DSM should be considered for mapping soil characteristics that are difficult to predict by statistical models, and for extrapolation purposes. Highlights
Theoretically, mechanistic models can replace the statistical relationships in digital soil mapping. Mechanistic soil models were used to develop a mechanistic model for digital soil mapping that predicted SOM stocks. The applicability of the mechanistic approach needs to be explored for different soil properties and regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-log--barrier-approach-for-airborne-gamma-ray-spectrometry-inversion&quot;&gt;A log -barrier approach for airborne gamma-ray spectrometry inversion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The standard processing of airborne gamma-ray spectrometry (AGRS) data provides useful preliminary information to interpretation in several contexts, such as environmental studies, geological mapping, and analysis of mineral deposits. For optimal results, the acquisition conditions should be nearly constant, and the flight height should be uniform. However, abrupt changes in flight height (often originated from mountainous terrain) are common and lead to spurious variations and incorrect anomaly interpretation. Moreover, the commonly used corrections applied to radiometric data do not consider the effective sampling area of a survey, especially the overlap between successive fields of view. As a consequence, the concentrations estimates of potassium (K), uranium (eU), and thorium (eTh) are not sharp. A solution to deal with this problem is to compute the concentration from the AGRS data through an inversion algorithm. Inversion of AGRS data has shown to be an effective approach to suppress the significant overlap between successive fields of view. We introduce a logarithmic barrier approach for the radiometric inversion to avoid spurious negative values in the radioelement concentration models. We choose calibration ranges from Brazil and Canada to test the proposed methodology. We produced concentration models for K, eU and eTh and compared the standard approach model with the recovered model from both ranges. The predicted data from inversion of both calibration ranges are mostly consistent with the survey data, not over smoothing the data or fitting noise. The predicted data from inversion showed more consistency with the observed data than the one predicted from the standard procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-influence-of-rock-fragments-on-field-capacity-water-content-in-stony-soils-from-hard-sandstone-alluvium&quot;&gt;The influence of rock fragments on field capacity water content in stony soils from hard sandstone alluvium&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worldwide, rock fragments (RFs) are generally considered inert with respect to bulk soil hydraulic properties, such that all soil water retention properties predicted by national pedotransfer functions (such as S-map) are based on the volumetric fraction of the fine earth (&amp;lt;2 mm fraction) only. Research findings contradict those assumptions, but studies commonly focus on porous RFs, and rely on repacked cores and lab studies, leaving uncertainty as to how low porosity RFs characteristic of common strongly indurated lithologies affect soil in the field. We address this question by examining soil water storage in 52 pits excavated into stony soils on the Canterbury Plains, New Zealand, which are formed in sediment derived from a Mesozoic hard sandstone. The soils at each site were watered to saturation, and then after two days of drainage (a proxy for field capacity), a 30 x 30 cm pit was excavated in 10 cm increments to a depth of 60 cm. From each increment, soil samples were collected and analysed to determine the volumetric size distribution of RFs, the water content of the fine earth and the water content of the RFs themselves. Our results indicated that RFs could influence the fine earth bulk density, porosity, and soil chemistry. RFs could also retain water: 2-20 mm RFs (0.07 m(3) m(-3)) retained twice as much water as &amp;gt;20 mm RFs (0.03 m(3) m(-3)). The water retention of the hard sandstone was low compared to other lithologies, but the volumetric abundance of RFs in the stony soils we sampled meant that they accounted for similar to 10% of the water retained to a depth of 60 cm at field capacity. Our results demonstrate that similar to 13 mm of water retained by RFs at field capacity is not currently considered in water budgets and nutrient leaching predictions, which may be relevant to best practice land management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-quality-and-grain-yield-a-win-win-combination-in-clayey-tropical-oxisols&quot;&gt;Soil quality and grain yield: A win-win combination in clayey tropical oxisols&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relationships between a soil quality index (SQI(FERTBIO)) and soil functions with both relative cumulative grain yields (RCY) and soil organic carbon (SOC), were evaluated in a tropical clayey Cerrado Oxisol. Soil quality (SQ) was quantified integrating chemical (FERT) and biological (BIO) indicators in a weighted-additive soil quality index combining three soil functions and respective indicators: (F1) nutrient cycling (based on the activities of soil enzymes beta-glucosidase and arylsulfatase), (F2) nutrient storage (SOC and cation exchange capacity, CEC) and (F3) nutrient supply (Ca+2, Mg+2, K+, P, pH, H + Al; Al+3, sum of bases (SB) and base saturation (%BS)). The contribution of each indicator for the related soil function was scored using standardized scoring functions (SSF) that transform the indicator value on a scale between 0 and 1. Soil samples (0 to 10 cm depth) were collected in 2013 and 2015 from 21 treatments from three long-term field experiments, with different P fertilizer management strategies. P-fertilization resulted in higher cumulative crop yields that in turn were associated with better SQI(FERTBIO) and soil functions scores. Through linear regression analyses, critical limits (CLs) to interpret the individual scores of the SQI and of the soil functions, based on RCY and SOC were defined. The proposed SQI was positively associated with RCY (p &amp;lt; 0,001; R-2 = 0,95) and SOC (p &amp;lt; 0,001; R-2 = 0,88). Similar significant relationships were found between the three soil functions and RCY or SOC. Overall, the lower and upper limits of the interpretative classes for the SQI(FERTBIO) and soil functions scores (where the index scores are equivalent, respectively, to 40% and 80% of the optimal RCY or SOC) were 0.42 and 0.64. The combination of chemical and biological indicators in different soil functions and in the SQI(FERTBIO) proved to be a simple and useful strategy to assess SQ in tropical Oxisols, linking agronomic management practices to both SQ, yield benefits and SOC. These results will help extensionists, agronomists and soil scientists, when assisting farmers, in soil health assessments, by making easier to explain the importance of SQ for the economic performance of farms.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/03/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on March 28, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/03/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/03/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-03-14T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-03-14T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-7&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A TDR wireless device for volumetric water content sensing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ecotrons: Powerful and versatile ecosystem analysers for ecology, agronomy and environmental science&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Age and origin of the Cumberland (Inner Sydney) Basin of southeast Australia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uncertainty analysis of eleven multisource soil moisture products in the third pole environment based on the three-corned hat method&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A D-vine copula quantile regression approach for soil moisture retrieval from dual polarimetric SAR Sentinel-1 over vegetated terrains&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-tdr-wireless-device-for-volumetric-water-content-sensing&quot;&gt;A TDR wireless device for volumetric water content sensing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time Domain Reflectometry (TDR) is a widely used technique to estimate the soil volumetric water content (theta) and bulk electrical conductivity (sigma). This paper presents TDR-WiFi, a wireless, portable and low cost interface to ease sensing of theta and sigma by connecting TDR cable tester with a smartphone. TDR-WiFi consists of a microprocessor equipped with a WiFi microcontroller (M5Stack unit) and connected to the TDR device through an RS232-TTL adapter. The M5stack firmware is programmed in MicroPython language to act as a server between the user and the TDR device through a web page accessible from any smartphone web browser. TDR-WiFi is compatible with the Campbell TDR100 device and allows storing the TDR waveforms as well as estimating theta and sigma. A complementary web page for subsequent analysis of the TDR waveforms was developed and is publicly available at http://swi.csic.es/tdrwifi/. The system was satisfactorily demonstrated in laboratory and tested in the field. The field trial allowed water content measurements in a steep road slope. TDR-WiFi demonstrated to be operative in the field and it can be satisfactorily used in difficult access areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ecotrons-powerful-and-versatile-ecosystem-analysers-for-ecology-agronomy-and-environmental-science&quot;&gt;Ecotrons: Powerful and versatile ecosystem analysers for ecology, agronomy and environmental science&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ecosystems integrity and services are threatened by anthropogenic global changes. Mitigating and adapting to these changes require knowledge of ecosystem functioning in the expected novel environments, informed in large part through experimentation and modelling. This paper describes 13 advanced controlled environment facilities for experimental ecosystem studies, herein termed ecotrons, open to the international community. Ecotrons enable simulation of a wide range of natural environmental conditions in replicated and independent experimental units while measuring various ecosystem processes. This capacity to realistically control ecosystem environments is used to emulate a variety of climatic scenarios and soil conditions, in natural sunlight or through broad-spectrum lighting. The use of large ecosystem samples, intact or reconstructed, minimizes border effects and increases biological and physical complexity. Measurements of concentrations of greenhouse trace gases as well as their net exchange between the ecosystem and the atmosphere are performed in most ecotrons, often quasi continuously. The flow of matter is often tracked with the use of stable isotope tracers of carbon and other elements. Equipment is available for measurements of soil water status as well as root and canopy growth. The experiments ran so far emphasize the diversity of the hosted research. Half of them concern global changes, often with a manipulation of more than one driver. About a quarter deal with the impact of biodiversity loss on ecosystem functioning and one quarter with ecosystem or plant physiology. We discuss how the methodology for environmental simulation and process measurements, especially in soil, can be improved and stress the need to establish stronger links with modelling in future projects. These developments will enable further improvements in mechanistic understanding and predictive capacity of ecotron research which will play, in complementarity with field experimentation and monitoring, a crucial role in exploring the ecosystem consequences of environmental changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;age-and-origin-of-the-cumberland-inner-sydney-basin-of-southeast-australia&quot;&gt;Age and origin of the Cumberland (Inner Sydney) Basin of southeast Australia&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Cumberland Basin is a structural and topographic low within the sedimentary Sydney Basin of southeast Australia. To the west, the Blue Mountains Plateau was uplifted along the north-south Lapstone Structural Complex after around 90 Ma, with uplift largely completed by middle Miocene to Pliocene times. To the north, upwarping of the Hornsby Plateau preceded the major phase of movement along the Lapstone Structural Complex. To the south, the topography of the Cumberland Basin is closely related to the form of the Camden Syncline. This appears to have been active in the late Permian-Middle Triassic. The western limb of the syncline is truncated by the north-south Lapstone Structural Complex. The southern part of the Cumberland Basin must therefore have taken on its modern form prior to the movements that gave rise to its western margin. The eastern side of the Cumberland Basin forms a broad depression open to the sea. This may be a graben-like structure developed along the Lachlan Transverse Zone. The Botany Basin, which may have begun subsiding at least as far back as the Oligocene, lies within this feature, suggesting that this part of the Cumberland Basin may have already been in existence at this stage. Within the broader Cumberland Basin, the Penrith and Botany basins appear to have begun subsiding early in the Cenozoic, accumulating complex and interrupted records of alluvial sediments in the former and eolian, shallow marine and alluvial sediments in the latter. Over this period, the Penrith and Botany basins seem to have acted as the focus of drainage across the Cumberland Basin, explaining the enigmatic pattern of rivers across the region. The Cumberland Basin’s margins thus formed in different ways and at different times, with the margin-forming processes perhaps associated with the volcanicity and tectonic movements accompanying the uplift of Australia’s Eastern Highlands in the period 80-10 Ma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;uncertainty-analysis-of-eleven-multisource-soil-moisture-products-in-the-third-pole-environment-based-on-the-three-corned-hat-method&quot;&gt;Uncertainty analysis of eleven multisource soil moisture products in the third pole environment based on the three-corned hat method&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil moisture (SM) is a fundamental environmental variable for characterizing climate, land surface and atmosphere. In recent years, several SM products have been developed based on remote sensing (RS), land surface model (LSM) or land data assimilation system (LDAS). However, little knowledge is available in understanding spatial patterns of the uncertainty of different SM products and potential regional drivers over the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau (QTP), a complex environment for accurate SM estimation. This paper investigates the sensitivity of the SM uncertainties based on the three-cornered hat (TCH) method and a generalized additive model (GAM) in terms of underlying surface characteristics (sand fraction, soil organic matter, vegetation, land surface temperature, and topography) and near-ground meteorology (precipitation and air temperature) in the third pole environment over the 2015-2018 period. Eleven SM products are involved in this work, including Soil Moisture Active Passive (SMAP), Soil Moisture Ocean Salinity INRA-CESBIO (SMOS-IC), Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency (JAXA), Land Surface Parameter Model (LPRM), Climate Change Initiative - Active/Combined (CCI_A/CCI_C), Global Land Data Assimilation System (GLDAS), European Centre for Medium-Range Weather Forecasts Interim reanalysis (ERA-Interim), Global Land Evaporation Amsterdam Model product a/b (GLEAM_a/GLEAM_b), and Random Forest Soil Moisture (RFSM). Results show that most of the SM products perform well across QTP, while SMOS-IC is strongly affected by radio-frequency interference in this region, JAXA has a relatively higher noise level over QTP, and LPRM has larger relative uncertainties (RUs) in the southeast of QTP. Nonlinear regression analysis demonstrates that variations of RUs in SMOS-IC and JAXA are driven by topography, while LPRM’s are mainly controlled by vegetation. In addition, two groups of opposite (positive/negative) effects from topography and vegetation, topography and precipitation, and precipitation and land surface temperature affect the spatial variations of RUs in CCI_A, RFSM, and ERA-Interim, respectively. Meanwhile, more complex relationships are found between multiple surface factors and RUs of different products. In general, the underlying surface factors explain on average 39.41% and 28.34% of the variations in RS and LSM/LDAS SM RUs, respectively. Comparatively, the near-ground meteorology factors have a slightly larger effect on LSM/LDAS products than that on RS products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-d-vine-copula-quantile-regression-approach-for-soil-moisture-retrieval-from-dual-polarimetric-sar-sentinel-1-over-vegetated-terrains&quot;&gt;A D-vine copula quantile regression approach for soil moisture retrieval from dual polarimetric SAR Sentinel-1 over vegetated terrains&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil moisture retrieval from Synthetic Aperture Radar (SAR) over vegetated terrains requires an isolation of soil and canopy signals from observed backscatter (sigma degrees). This study develops a probabilistic soil moisture retrieval method from dual polarimetric C-band SAR Sentinel-1 (S-1) with uncertainty quantification at distinct vegetation covers (VCs). Both sigma(VV)degrees and sigma(VH)degrees were used to represent ground and volume scattering due to the high respective sensitivity to soil moisture and vegetation dynamics. A novel D-vine copula quantile regression (DVQR) was adopted to provide the soil moisture estimates based on modelling trivariate dependence of sigma(VV)degrees-sigma(VH)degrees -soil moisture anomalies (VV-VH-Mv), with a support from the innovative cosmic-ray soil moisture as ground-truth data. The feasibility of DVQR was underlined for: (1) multivariate nonlinear dependence structure modelling and (2) soil moisture retrieval with associated uncertainty. An inter-dependence analysis, which assesses the correlations among three major variables, indicated that the dependence between each pair of variables decreased as canopy density increases from herbs to forests, mainly due to the ci degrees attenuated by vegetation effect. The dependence structures simulated from the D-vine copula revealed highly nonlinear and asymmetric shapes with tail dependences occurred in most VCs, which can be well captured by different associated Archimedean copulas. Soil moisture anomaly (Mv) estimated using the DVQR and Multiple linear quantile regression (MLQR) were compared against ground-truth data for both in-sample and out-of-sample predictions. Superior performances of the DVQR in most VCs, with 10% and 16% improved in RMSE at grasslands and broadleaf forests, respectively, demonstrated the robustness of this method for S-1 soil moisture retrieval due to the highly nonlinear dependence structures captured by the D-vine models. Over VCs, better performances were obtained at low-canopy herbaceous regions (grasslands and croplands); whereas extremely dry conditions and complex structures in shrublands and dense forests resulted in inferior performances. A sensitivity analysis was then conducted to evaluate the change in My estimation accuracy given distinct VV and VH quantile levels. Result underlines that VV is the primary factor controlling the retrieval accuracy, but the increase in VH level also contributes to higher errors in soil moisture estimation, especially under wet conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/03/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on March 14, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/03/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/03/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-03-11T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-03-11T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-6&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Three different Fourier-transform mid-infrared sampling techniques to characterize bio-organic samples&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modeling of phosphorus loss from field to watershed: A review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Global Research Alliance N2O chamber methodology guidelines: Introduction, with health and safety considerations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drivers of regional soil water storage memory and persistence&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A profile shape correction to reduce the vertical sensitivity of cosmic-ray neutron sensing of soil moisture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimating coefficient of linear extensibility using Vis-NIR reflectance spectral data: Comparison of model validation approaches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;three-different-fourier-transform-mid-infrared-sampling-techniques-to-characterize-bio-organic-samples&quot;&gt;Three different Fourier-transform mid-infrared sampling techniques to characterize bio-organic samples&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent years, there has been a surge in the number of applications of Fourier-transform mid-infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy for the characterization of environmental samples and prediction of some of their properties whose measurement has traditionally involved time-consuming and costly methods. However, there are several different mid-infrared techniques available, and there is a gap in knowledge regarding the best-suited technique for recording informative spectra of different types of environmental samples. This study compared the three most widespread FTIR techniques using solid and liquid samples. A total of 11 environmental samples belonging to four categories were analyzed with attenuated total reflectance (ATR), photoacoustic (PAS), and diffuse reflectance (DR) FTIR spectroscopy. Overall, PAS-FTIR was the best technique, providing a greater amount of information, especially for opaque samples (i.e., organic waste, biochar, and soil), than ATR-FTIR and DR-FTIR spectroscopy. Attenuated total reflectance FTIR provided the best spectra for soft samples, such as plant materials, probably due to their ability to achieve good optical contact with the ATR crystal. Finally, DR-FTIR performed relatively well for most samples but was found to be more sensitive to moisture in the samples, resulting in noise in specific areas, and was less sensitive in bond vibrations related to Si.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;modeling-of-phosphorus-loss-from-field-to-watershed-a-review&quot;&gt;Modeling of phosphorus loss from field to watershed: A review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract
Phosphorus (P) losses from nonpoint sources into surface water resources through surface runoff and tile drainage play a significant role in eutrophication. Accordingly, the number of studies involving the modeling of agricultural P losses, the uncertainties of such models, and the best management practices (BMPs) supported by the modeling of hypothetical P loss reduction scenarios has increased significantly around the world. Many improvements have been made to these models: separate manure P pools, variable source areas allowing the determination of critical source areas of P loss, analyses of modeling uncertainties, and understanding of legacy P. However, several elements are still missing or have yet to be sufficiently addressed: the incorporation of preferential flow into models, the modification of P sorption-desorption processes considering recent research data (e.g., pedotransfer functions for labile, active, or stable P, along with P sorption coefficients), BMP parameterization, and scale-up issues, as well as stakeholder-scientist and experimentalist-modeler interactions. The accuracy of P loss modeling can be improved by (a) incorporating dynamic P sorption-desorption processes and new P subroutines for direct P loss from manure, fertilizer, and dung, (b) modeling preferential flow, connectivity between field and adjacent water bodies, and P in-stream processes, (c) including an assessment of model uncertainty, (d) integrating field and watershed models for BMP calibration and scaling field results up to larger areas, and (e) building a holistic interaction between stakeholders, experimentalists, and modelers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;global-research-alliance-n2o-chamber-methodology-guidelines-introduction-with-health-and-safety-considerations&quot;&gt;Global Research Alliance N2O chamber methodology guidelines: Introduction, with health and safety considerations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Non-steady-state (NSS) chamber techniques have been used for decades to measure nitrous oxide (N2O) fluxes from agricultural soils. These techniques are widely used because they are relatively inexpensive, easy to adopt, versatile, and adaptable to varying conditions. Much of our current understanding of the drivers of N2O emissions is based on studies using NSS chambers. These chamber techniques require decisions regarding multiplemethodological aspects (e.g., chamber materials and geometry, deployment, sample analysis, and data and statistical analysis), each of which may significantly affect the results. Variation in methodological details can lead to challenges in comparing results between studies and assessment of reliability and uncertainty. Therefore, the New Zealand Government, in support of the objectives of the Livestock Research Group of the Global Research Alliance on Agricultural Greenhouse Gases (GRA), funded two international projects to, first, develop standardized guidelines on the use of NSS chamber techniques and, second, refine them based on the most up to date knowledge and methods. This introductory paper summarizes a collection of papers that represent the revised guidelines. Each article summarizes existing knowledge and provides guidance and minimum requirements on chamber design, deployment, sample collection, storage and analysis, automated chambers, flux calculations, statistical analysis, emission factor estimation and data reporting, modeling, and “gap-filling” approaches. The minimum requirements are not meant to be highly prescriptive but instead provide researchers with clear direction on best practices and factors that need to be considered. Health and safety considerations of NSS chamber techniques are also provided with this introductory paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;drivers-of-regional-soil-water-storage-memory-and-persistence&quot;&gt;Drivers of regional soil water storage memory and persistence&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil water storage dynamics link landscape and climate processes with consequent impacts on hydrologic and biogeochemical cycles, and on ecosystem functions. We explore regional-scale, spatiotemporal dynamics of root-zone soil water storage using spatially explicit, long-term simulations from a land data assimilation system over an area of similar to 2 million km(2) in the U.S. Midwest. We synthesize the dataset to examine spatial patterns of hydroclimatic forcing and soil and vegetation properties to identify the key drivers of soil water storage across the region. To identify differences in temporal hydrologic variability between sites with different soil and vegetation characteristics, we focus on daily data from 10 locations, representative of three major land cover types in the region. We use the concepts of (a) soil water memory to evaluate differences in landscape buffering of rainfall and (b) persistence to evaluate the threshold-crossing properties of statistically defined “wet” and “dry” soil water conditions. Power spectral analyses of soil water storage reveal that regionally consistent patterns emerge in memory at multiple temporal scales. Threshold-crossing analyses reveal corresponding similarity in persistence between sites. The analyses show that stochastic rainfall is the key driver of landscape hydrologic dynamics, with rainfall frequency as the primary determinant of persistence across the region, whereas differences in land cover and soil properties across the region have second-order influence. The synthesis approach we present here is useful for ecological and agricultural risk assessments of climate change impacts, including increasing frequency of extreme events such as droughts and floods, but primarily points to the need for better understanding of future precipitation changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-profile-shape-correction-to-reduce-the-vertical-sensitivity-of-cosmic-ray-neutron-sensing-of-soil-moisture&quot;&gt;A profile shape correction to reduce the vertical sensitivity of cosmic-ray neutron sensing of soil moisture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent years, cosmic-ray neutron sensing (CRNS) has shown a large potential among proximal sensing techniques to monitor soil moisture noninvasively, with high frequency and a large support volume (radius up to 240 m and sensing depth up to 80 cm). This signal is, however, more sensitive to closer distances and shallower depths. Inherently, CRNS-derived soil moisture is a spatially weighted value, different from an average soil moisture as retrieved by a sensor network. In this study, we systematically test a new profile shape correction on CRNS-derived soil moisture, based on additional soil moisture profile measurements and vertical unweighting, which is especially relevant during pronounced wetting or drying fronts. The analyses are conducted with data collected at four contrasting field sites, each equipped with a CRNS probe and a distributed soil moisture sensor network. After applying the profile shape correction on CRNS-derived soil moisture, it is compared with the sensor network average. Results show that the influence of the vertical sensitivity of CRNS on integral soil moisture values is successfully reduced. One to three properly located profile measurements within the CRNS support volume improve the performance. For the four investigated field sites, the RMSE decreased 11-53% when only one profile location was considered. We therefore recommend to install along with a CRNS at least one soil moisture profile in a radial distance &amp;lt;100 m and a measurement depth down to 50 cm. Profile-shape-corrected, CRNS-derived soil moisture is an unweighted integral soil moisture over the support volume, which is easier to interpret and easier to use for further applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;estimating-coefficient-of-linear-extensibility-using-vis-nir-reflectance-spectral-data-comparison-of-model-validation-approaches&quot;&gt;Estimating coefficient of linear extensibility using Vis-NIR reflectance spectral data: Comparison of model validation approaches&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coefficient of linear extensibility (COLE) is used to classify soils according to their swell-shrink potential, and its estimation is crucial for engineering and agronomic applications. The aims of the study were (a) to develop a visible-near-infrared spectroscopy (Vis-NIRS, 400-2,500 nm) calibration model to estimate COLE, (b) to compare two model validation approaches (mixed data and country-wise), and (c) to test if a variable selection method improves the estimation accuracy of the calibration models. For this purpose, partial least square regression (PLSR) was used on the spectra of 53 soil samples from Slovakia and 24 samples from the United States. First, a calibration model based on 70% of the entire dataset (including samples from both locations) was developed and validated with the remaining 30% (mixed data approach). Second, a calibration model based on the Slovakian samples was validated with the U.S. samples (country-wise approach). Higher predictability for COLE with standardized root mean square error (SMRSE) of 0.099 was obtained for the mixed data approach than for the country-wise validation with SRMSE of 0.279. Furthermore, using interval PLSR (iPLSR) as a variable selection method did not improve the estimation accuracy of the mixed data approach (SRMSE of 0.099), and rather resulted in a twofold increase in SRMSE (0.560) for the country-wise validation approach. Overall, the good estimation of COLE from Vis-NIRS was attributed to the high correlation of COLE with clay content and spectrally active clay minerals.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/03/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on March 11, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/03/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/03/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-03-01T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-03-01T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-5&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prediction of available phosphorus in soil: Combined use for crop production and water quality protection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Predicting total petroleum hydrocarbons in field soils with Vis-NIR models developed on laboratory-constructed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Selecting soil properties for assessment of soil aggregation using principal component and clustering analyses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modified self-adaptive model for improving the prediction accuracy of soil organic matter by laser-induced breakdown spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prediction-of-available-phosphorus-in-soil-combined-use-for-crop-production-and-water-quality-protection&quot;&gt;Prediction of available phosphorus in soil: Combined use for crop production and water quality protection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Optimizing phosphorus (P) application to agricultural soils is fundamental to crop production and water quality protection. We sought to relate soil P tests and P sorption characteristics to both crop yield response to P application and environmentally critical soil P status. Barley (Hordeum vulgare L.) was grown in pot experiments with 45 soils of different P status. Half the pots were fertilized at 20 kg P ha(-1), and half received no P. Soils were extracted with ammonium lactate, sodium bicarbonate (Olsen P), dilute salt (0.0025 M CaCl2), and diffusive gradient in thin films. Soil adsorption coefficients were determined using the Freundlich isotherm equation, and the degree of P saturation was determined from both oxalate and ammonium lactate extracted Fe, Al, and P. All soil P analyses showed a nonlinear and significant relationship with yield response to P application, and all analyses manifested a threshold value above which no P response was observed. For the commonly used ammonium lactate test, inclusion of Al and Fe improved prediction of plant-available soil P. The threshold for yield response coincided with the environmentally critical values determined from the degree of P saturation. Results support the conclusion that soil P levels for which no P application is needed also have elevated risk of P loss to runoff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;predicting-total-petroleum-hydrocarbons-in-field-soils-with-vis-nir-models-developed-on-laboratory-constructed&quot;&gt;Predicting total petroleum hydrocarbons in field soils with Vis-NIR models developed on laboratory-constructed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accurate quantification of petroleum hydrocarbons (PHCs) is required for optimizing remedial efforts at oil spill sites. While evaluating total petroleum hydrocarbons (TPH) in soils is often conducted using costly and time-consuming laboratory methods, visible and near-infrared reflectance spectroscopy (Vis-NIR) has been proven to be a rapid and cost-effective field-based method for soil TPH quantification. This study investigated whether Vis-NIR models calibrated from laboratory-constructed PHC soil samples could be used to accurately estimate TPH concentration of field samples. To evaluate this, a laboratory sample set was constructed by mixing crude oil with uncontaminated soil samples, and two field sample sets (F1 and F2) were collected from three PHC-impacted sites. The Vis-NIR TPH models were calibrated with four different techniques (partial least squares regression, random forest, artificial neural network, and support vector regression), and two model improvement methods (spiking and spiking with extra weight) were compared. Results showed that laboratory-based Vis-NIR models could predict TPH in field sample set F1 with moderate accuracy (R-2 &amp;gt; .53) but failed to predict TPH in field sample set F2 (R-2 &amp;lt; .13). Both spiking and spiking with extra weight improved the prediction of TPH in both field sample sets (R-2 ranged from .63 to.88, respectively); the improvement was most pronounced for F2. This study suggests that Vis-NIR models developed from laboratory-constructed PHC soil samples, spiked by a small number of field sample analyses, can be used to estimate TPH concentrations more efficiently and cost effectively compared with generating site-specific calibrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;selecting-soil-properties-for-assessment-of-soil-aggregation-using-principal-component-and-clustering-analyses&quot;&gt;Selecting soil properties for assessment of soil aggregation using principal component and clustering analyses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aggregation is an important factor among physical soil parameters and affects soil quality. In this study, some soil physical (field capacity, wilting point and sand, silt and clay contents), chemical (pH, electrical conductivity, CaCO3, organic matter and exchangeable Na, Ca, Mg and K) and biological properties (CO2 from respiration and urease, dehydrogenase, beta-glucosidase, alkaline phosphatase and acid phosphatase activities) were examined. Some of these properties were eliminated by principal component and clustering analyses to create a minimum dataset. Correlations were evaluated between selected properties and the percentage aggregation of micro (&amp;lt;0.25 mm) and macro aggregates (0.25-4 mm). Sand, Mg, pH, organic matter, urease, dehydrogenase, alkaline phosphatase and beta-glucosidase properties were selected after principal component and clustering analyses. The highest correlation was between the percentage of micro aggregation and urease activity (0.545, P &amp;lt; 0.01). For macro aggregates, the highest correlation was with organic material (0.560, P &amp;lt; 0.01). A negative correlation was observed between macro aggregation percentage and sand content (-0.410, P &amp;lt; 0.01), with a similar relationship for micro aggregation and sand content (-0.450, P &amp;lt; 0.01), but there were positive relationships with other properties. The exchangeable magnesium content showed similar relationships for both aggregate sizes (0.430 and 0.440, P &amp;lt; 0.01). The correlations of aggregation with other enzymes and pH were nonsignificant (P &amp;gt; 0.05). In general, the highest correlation for micro aggregation was with enzyme activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;modified-self-adaptive-model-for-improving-the-prediction-accuracy-of-soil-organic-matter-by-laser-induced-breakdown-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Modified self-adaptive model for improving the prediction accuracy of soil organic matter by laser-induced breakdown spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil organic matter (SOM) significantly influences soil fertility, biology, and the global C cycle. Laser-induced breakdown spectroscopy (LIBS) is attractive, as it can measure SOM accurately and quickly with minimal sample preparation and effective cost. Our earlier self-adaptive (SA) model based on individual distances between LIBS soil spectra coupled with partial least squares (PLS) was favorable for SOM prediction. To optimize this model by including soil identification via the use of a hybrid distance between the spectra, two hybrid distance SA models to enhance SOM predictions from LIBS spectra in 250 Chinese topsoils were built and studied. The models used LIBS soil spectra and SOM content measured by the traditional potassium dichromate oxidation method for calibration. The performance of these models for the validation set was compared with the conventional no-identification PLS model and SA-PLS models. The modified models that used (a) a hybrid of Euclidean distance (ED) and angle cosine (SA(xc)-PLS), and (b) a hybrid of ED and the distance of response y (SA(xy)-PLS) improved SOM predictions , with a R-2 of 0.908, a RMSE of 5.65 g kg(-1), and a residual prediction deviation (RPD) of 2.91 in the validation set for SA(xc)-PLS; and a R-2 of 0.900, a RMSE of 5.49 g kg(-1), and a RPD of 2.99 in the validation set for SA(xy)-PLS. The improved performance mainly resulted from simultaneous consideration of diversity and correlation of the spectra. Therefore, modified SA models hold great potential for SOM prediction, especially for different soils.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/03/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on March 01, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/02/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/02/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-02-16T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-02-22T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-4&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prediction of available phosphorus in soil: Combined use for crop production and water quality protection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Life cycle assessment of wheat production and wheat-based crop rotations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quantifying organic carbon stocks using a stereological profile imaging method to account for rock fragments in stony soils&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How many sampling points are needed to estimate the mean nitrate-N content of agricultural fields? A geostatistical simulation approach with uncertain variograms&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Downscaling digital soil maps using electromagnetic induction and aerial imagery&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In-situ and triple-collocation based evaluations of eight global root zone soil moisture products&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conceptual Links between Landscape Diversity and Diet Diversity: A Roadmap for Transdisciplinary Research&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perspectives on validation in digital soil mapping of continuous attributes-A review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Objective functions from Bayesian optimization to locate additional drillholes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prediction-of-available-phosphorus-in-soil-combined-use-for-crop-production-and-water-quality-protection&quot;&gt;Prediction of available phosphorus in soil: Combined use for crop production and water quality protection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Optimizing phosphorus (P) application to agricultural soils is fundamental to crop production and water quality protection. We sought to relate soil P tests and P sorption characteristics to both crop yield response to P application and environmentally critical soil P status. Barley (Hordeum vulgare L.) was grown in pot experiments with 45 soils of different P status. Half the pots were fertilized at 20 kg P ha(-1), and half received no P. Soils were extracted with ammonium lactate, sodium bicarbonate (Olsen P), dilute salt (0.0025 M CaCl2), and diffusive gradient in thin films. Soil adsorption coefficients were determined using the Freundlich isotherm equation, and the degree of P saturation was determined from both oxalate and ammonium lactate extracted Fe, Al, and P. All soil P analyses showed a nonlinear and significant relationship with yield response to P application, and all analyses manifested a threshold value above which no P response was observed. For the commonly used ammonium lactate test, inclusion of Al and Fe improved prediction of plant-available soil P. The threshold for yield response coincided with the environmentally critical values determined from the degree of P saturation. Results support the conclusion that soil P levels for which no P application is needed also have elevated risk of P loss to runoff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;life-cycle-assessment-of-wheat-production-and-wheat-based-crop-rotations&quot;&gt;Life cycle assessment of wheat production and wheat-based crop rotations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
In the northern Great Plains (NGP), wheat is the primary grain commodity. There is a need for the NGP to have a detailed analysis of environmental impacts for wheat-based agricultural production systems to better understand regional agroecosystems. This article provides a cradle-to-field gate life cycle assessment (LCA) for NGP dryland wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) production. The environmental impacts for winter wheat production using crop rotation and agricultural intensification are quantified. Fourteen no-till crop rotations ranging in duration from 2 to 6 yr were evaluated and compared using data from a historical 13-yr replicated rotation study (&amp;gt;300 observations). Midpoint LCA categories chosen for this comparison are energy, agricultural land use, climate change potential, freshwater eutrophication, and freshwater ecotoxicity due to their direct links with agricultural management practices. The NGP farmers commonly use a fallow period every other year due to moisture limitations. This specific agricultural practice and allocations within rotations are critical considerations within agricultural LCAs. Two aspects of fallow considerations and a sensitivity analysis were also performed. The allocated midpoint impacts between crops in rotational studies averaged 0.31, 0.79, 0.62, and 0.63 kg CO2 eq. per unit of winter wheat when energy, economic, mass, and cereal unit allocations were used, respectively. Economic analysis of the studied experimental crop was performed; results demonstrated that crop insurance policies improved diversification economics by 20%. Agricultural diversification benefits and burdens were better represented by endpoint damage assessments than by midpoint impact analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quantifying-organic-carbon-stocks-using-a-stereological-profile-imaging-method-to-account-for-rock-fragments-in-stony-soils&quot;&gt;Quantifying organic carbon stocks using a stereological profile imaging method to account for rock fragments in stony soils&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accounting for soil organic carbon (SOC) in stony soils is critical for estimating global SOC stocks. However, accurate and cost-effective assessments of SOC stocks in stony soil profiles remain challenging due to the difficulties in accurately determining the rock fragment volume. The objective of this study was to develop a stereological profile imaging method for rock fragment volume fraction estimation and SOC stock assessment in stony soil profiles. Three soil profiles with different rock fragment lithologies, concentrations, and distributions were imaged and quantitatively sampled. The stereological profile imaging method reproduced consistent estimation of the 3-dimensional rock fragment number density distribution and volume fraction compared to the direct measurement. The SOC stocks of the three stony profiles estimated by visual estimation, profile imaging, and stereological profile imaging methods were also assessed and compared to direct measurement. The average difference in total SOC stock between direct measurement and visual estimation, profile imaging, and stereological profile imaging methods was 0.32, 0.17, and 0.09 kg m(-2), respectively. The total profile (0-100 cm) SOC stock for profile 2 differed among the visual estimation and profile imaging methods, but estimated SOC stock from the proposed method did not differ from direct measurement for the three profiles. Results also showed that the differences in SOC stock assessment between rock fragment estimation methods increased with rock fragment concentration. The proposed method was less affected by rock fragment concentration and was more stable compared to the visual and profile imaging methods. The stereological profile imaging method was demonstrated to be a reasonably accurate method for the quantification of rock fragment number density distribution, volume fraction, and SOC stock in stony soil profiles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-many-sampling-points-are-needed-to-estimate-the-mean-nitrate-n-content-of-agricultural-fields-a-geostatistical-simulation-approach-with-uncertain-variograms&quot;&gt;How many sampling points are needed to estimate the mean nitrate-N content of agricultural fields? A geostatistical simulation approach with uncertain variograms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowledge of how many sampling points are needed to estimate the mean content of soil nutrients in agricultural fields, given a precision requirement on the estimated mean, is limited. This paper describes a versatile geo-statistical simulation approach for predicting the variance of the mean nitrate-N (NO3-N) content within an agricultural field estimated by random sampling. In fall of 2016 sixteen agricultural fields were sampled on a square grid to model the spatial variation of NO3-N. On twelve out of sixteen fields NO3-N showed a lognormal distribution rather than a normal distribution. Variograms for (log-transformed) NO3-N are estimated using a Bayesian approach, resulting in 100 vectors with possible variogram parameters per field, obtained by MCMC sampling from the posterior distribution. Each of these variograms is used to simulate 100 maps of NO3-N, resulting in 100 x 100 maps of NO3-N per field. Each map is used to compute the variance of the estimated mean with stratified simple random sampling of 5,10, …, 50 points, with one point per compact geographical stratum. For each sample size (number of sampling points) the mean, median and P90 of the uncertainty distribution are computed. Based on the medians, the sample size required for a maximum expanded measurement uncertainty of 50% varies from &amp;lt; 5 to &amp;gt; 50. This large variation in required sample size shows the large variation among the sixteen fields in variance of NO3-N within a field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;downscaling-digital-soil-maps-using-electromagnetic-induction-and-aerial-imagery&quot;&gt;Downscaling digital soil maps using electromagnetic induction and aerial imagery&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coarse-resolution soil maps at regional to national extents are often inappropriate for mapping intra-field variability. At the same time, sensor data, such as electromagnetic induction measurements and aerial imagery, can be highly useful for mapping soil properties that correlate with electrical conductivity or soil color. However, maps based on these data nearly always require calibration with local samples, as multiple factors can affect the sensor measurements. In this study, we present a downscaling method, which combines coarse-resolution, large extent soil maps with sensor data in order to improve predictions of soil properties. The method modifies values from coarse-resolution soil maps to predict soil properties at a location, using relationships between soil properties and sensor data from other locations. We test this method for predicting clay and soil organic matter contents at five agricultural fields located in Denmark. We test the method for one field at a time, using soil samples from the four other fields to predict soil properties. The maps produced with the method are generally more accurate than the coarse-resolution soil maps, especially for soil organic matter. The method generally overestimates prediction uncertainties, a disadvantage, which will require improvements. Overall, the method is a simple, promising tool for giving a quantitative estimate of soil properties, when no local soil samples are available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-situ-and-triple-collocation-based-evaluations-of-eight-global-root-zone-soil-moisture-products&quot;&gt;In-situ and triple-collocation based evaluations of eight global root zone soil moisture products&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Root zone soil moisture (RZSM) is a vital variable for vegetation growth, drought monitoring and agricultural water management. Satellite remote sensing measures soil moisture at the surface layer, while RZSM is derived usually by model-based simulations. Here, we provide the first comprehensive evaluation of eight RZSM products at a global scale, including GLDAS NOAH, ERA-5, MERRA-2, NCEP R1, NCEP R2, JRA-55, SMAP level 4 and SMOS level 4 datasets. An in-situ validation based on the stations from the International Soil Moisture Network (ISMN) and a triple collocation (TC) evaluation are both conducted to assess the accuracy of these RZSM products. SMAP exhibits the median highest correlation and the median lowest RMSE with in-situ stations over North America. In the TC analysis, MERRA-2 shows the highest median correlation and the median lowest error standard deviation with the unknown truth, followed by GLDAS, SMAP, JRA-55 and ERA-5. A temporal pattern analysis indicates that SMOS has a dry bias relative to other datasets and NCEP R1 has larger seasonal variations relative to other datasets over Asia and North America. The TC analysis indicates that MERRA-2, SMAP, GLDAS, JRA-55, and ERA-5 have better performance relative to other datasets. SMAP is not as good as GLDAS, MERRA-2 and JRA-55 in RZSM estimation over forest areas. The possible factors influencing RZSM performance are discussed, including precipitation forcing, assimilated observations, radio frequency interference issue and validation methods. These results and conclusions may provide new insights for the improvement of model-based RZSM estimation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conceptual-links-between-landscape-diversity-and-diet-diversity-a-roadmap-for-transdisciplinary-research&quot;&gt;Conceptual Links between Landscape Diversity and Diet Diversity: A Roadmap for Transdisciplinary Research&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Malnutrition linked to poor quality diets affects at least 2 billion people. Forests, as well as agricultural systems linked to trees, are key sources of dietary diversity in rural settings. In the present article, we develop conceptual links between diet diversity and forested landscape mosaics within the rural tropics. First, we summarize the state of knowledge regarding diets obtained from forests, trees, and agroforests. We then hypothesize how disturbed secondary forests, edge habitats, forest access, and landscape diversity can function in bolstering dietary diversity. Taken together, these ideas help us build a framework illuminating four pathways (direct, agroecological, energy, and market pathways) connecting forested landscapes to diet diversity. Finally, we offer recommendations to fill remaining knowledge gaps related to diet and forest cover monitoring. We argue that better evaluation of the role of land cover complexity will help avoid overly simplistic views of food security and, instead, uncover nutritional synergies with forest conservation and restoration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;perspectives-on-validation-in-digital-soil-mapping-of-continuous-attributes-a-review&quot;&gt;Perspectives on validation in digital soil mapping of continuous attributes-A review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We performed a systematic mapping of validation methods used in digital soil mapping (DSM), in order to gain an overview of current practices and make recommendations for future publications on DSM studies. A systematic search and screening procedure, largely following the RepOrting standards for Systematic Evidence Syntheses (ROSES) protocol, was carried out. It yielded a database of 188 peer-reviewed DSM studies from the past two decades, all written in English and all presenting a raster map of a continuous soil property. Review of the full-texts showed that most publications (97%) included some type of map validation, while just over one-third (35%) estimated map uncertainty. Most commonly, a combination of multiple (existing) soil sampe datasets was used and the resulting maps were validated by single data-splitting or cross-validation. It was common for essential information to be lacking in method descriptions. This is unfortunate, as lack of information on sampling design (missing in 25% of 188 studies) and sample support (missing in 45% of 188 studies) makes it difficult to interpret what derived validation metrics represent, compromising their usefulness. Therefore, we present a list of method details that should be provided in DSM studies. We also provide a detailed summary of the 28 validation metrics used in published DSM studies, how to interpret the values obtained and whether the metrics can be compared between datasets or soil attributes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;objective-functions-from-bayesian-optimization-to-locate-additional-drillholes&quot;&gt;Objective functions from Bayesian optimization to locate additional drillholes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key available information to choose new locations for drilling are the estimated ore grade values and the corresponding uncertainties at the tentative locations. These pieces of information are combined to generate a single objective function. The mathematical form of the objective function should reflect the effect of these values and their relative importance. Traditional objective function use multiplication of these parameters by different powering values. In this study, we develop two novel objective functions from the Bayesian optimization: the probability of improvement (PI), and the expected improvement (EI). These two objective functions seek new drillholes while considering the effect of the used value and their relative importance. Therefore, they can provide a trade-off between exploration and exploitation. All the objective functions have adjustable parameters. These parameters are typically tuned using expert knowledge or heuristic rules. Here, a statistical method based on cross-validation is proposed to adjust the parameters of the traditional and novel objective functions. The performance of the novel objective functions is validated against other ones using a distance based ranking method, in a phosphate deposit. The obtained results demonstrate the robustness of the EI and PI, the newly introduced objective functions from the Bayesian optimization framework.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/02/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on February 22, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/02/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/02/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-02-16T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-02-16T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-3&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Glomalin - Truths, myths, and the future of this elusive soil glycoprotein&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How microbes can, and cannot, be used to assess soil health&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Analysis of the Informativity of Big Satellite Precision-Farming Data Processing for Correcting Large-Scale Soil Maps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Frontiers in Cultural Ecosystem Services: Toward Greater Equity and Justice in Ecosystem Services Research and Practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;glomalin---truths-myths-and-the-future-of-this-elusive-soil-glycoprotein&quot;&gt;Glomalin - Truths, myths, and the future of this elusive soil glycoprotein&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOIL BIOLOGY &amp;amp; BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term “Glomalin” was originally used to describe a hypothetical gene product of arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi (AMF) that was assumed to be a nearly ubiquitous, thermostable and highly recalcitrant glycoprotein, deposited in soils in large amounts, and deemed to indicate soil health and quality. It was defined operationally as the fraction of soil organic matter (SOM) extractable by a hot citrate buffer and assessed either by Bradford assay or by cross-reactivity with monoclonal antibody MAb32B11. Later, it was recognized that the extracts contained a variety of compounds, including some of non-AMF origin, cross-reactive with both Bradford assay and the monoclonal antibody. This led to re-describing the pertinent (and still only operationally defined) SOM as “glomalin-related soil proteins (GRSP)”, albeit without any substantial change in the underlying concepts. Consequently, a great deal of confusion in this area arose among researchers in soil, plant, and environmental sciences. Glomalin or GRSP (often used interchangeably) has previously been linked to various soil features, including stability of soil aggregates, size of soil C and N pools, sequestration of heavy metals, and alleviation of various plant stresses. GRSP concentrations in soil often, but not always, have been correlated with AMF biomass measured by alternative (mainly microscopic) approaches. GRSP formation, deposition, and/or decomposition in soils seem to be largely dependent on a multitude of interactions among plants, AMF, and other soil microorganisms, including prokaryotes. The chemical structure of GRSP extracted from soil remains unclear and generally complex. That is due to the unspecific mode of its extraction and purification, as well as the great variety of analytical approaches that have been used heretofore to assess it. Future research needs to elucidate the exact composition of this operationally defined SOM fraction, the controls over its production and accumulation in soils, and its exact role in soil ecology generally and soil food webs in particular. Furthermore, novel and independent tools should be established to more specifically (as compared to current glomalin assays) assess AMF biomass and functioning in mots and soil and its involvement in soil processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-microbes-can-and-cannot-be-used-to-assess-soil-health&quot;&gt;How microbes can, and cannot, be used to assess soil health&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOIL BIOLOGY &amp;amp; BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Healthy soils are critical to the health of ecosystems, economies, and human populations. Thus, it is widely acknowledged that soil health is important to quantify, both for assessment and as a tool to help guide management strategies. What is less clear is how soil health should actually be measured, especially considering that soil health is not exclusively a product of soil physical and chemical characteristics. Given their well-established importance to many aspects of soil health, microbes and microbial processes are often used as metrics of soil health with a range of different microbe-based metrics routinely used across the globe. Unfortunately, it is our opinion that many of these pre-existing microbial measurements are not easy to interpret and may not necessarily provide credible inferences about soil health status. Here we review the microbial indices used to assess or monitor soil health and discuss some of the broader issues associated with their use. We provide recommendations to more effectively guide and improve how microbial information could be used to yield relevant and actionable assessments of soil health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;analysis-of-the-informativity-of-big-satellite-precision-farming-data-processing-for-correcting-large-scale-soil-maps&quot;&gt;Analysis of the Informativity of Big Satellite Precision-Farming Data Processing for Correcting Large-Scale Soil Maps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EURASIAN SOIL SCIENCE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Large-scale soil maps produced by research institutes for land management (GIPROZEM) are the main source of soil information on arable land in Russia. These maps date back to the 1960s-1990s. During the time that has passed since the last round of soil surveys, the development of precision farming has greatly increased the requirements for the accuracy of the maps. At present, archival soil maps require correction (verification, updating, detailing, and unification). It is suggested that the maps of stable intrafield heterogeneity (SIFH) of soil fertility based on the analysis of big remote sensing data can find application in modern agriculture. Such maps are created within the framework of the general concept of big data analysis, including big geodata and big agricultural data as its components. Comparative analysis of archival soil maps and the SIFH map for the territory of southern Russia attests to the great potential of SIFH maps for soil mapping. Missing soil polygons have been detected, the location of existing soil polygons has been refined, new soil units not marked on archival soil maps have been identified, and a plan for additional soil surveys within the framework of the data-driven geography concept has been worked out. The accuracy of the soil map has been improved to be applicable to state-of-the-art farming systems, including precision farming. A new source of information on the spatial heterogeneity of the soil cover and its fertility has appeared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;frontiers-in-cultural-ecosystem-services-toward-greater-equity-and-justice-in-ecosystem-services-research-and-practice&quot;&gt;Frontiers in Cultural Ecosystem Services: Toward Greater Equity and Justice in Ecosystem Services Research and Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BIOSCIENCE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cultural ecosystem services (CES) are associated with diverse and profound values, such as spiritual fulfillment, cultural heritage, and identity-related phenomena. Early ecosystem services research often omitted these deep meanings, but they are increasingly explored in recent studies through a range of disciplinary and epistemological perspectives. In the present article, we distill emerging frontiers of CES research. These frontiers help to characterize varied sources of meaning that are central to the CES ethos. They represent both advances in and opportunities for CES research, especially as related to justice and equity. The frontiers are: broadening definitions and conceptualizations of CES; addressing collective aspects of CES and attending to process; acknowledging that CES are reciprocal, relational, and dynamic; embracing narrative; and better connecting CES to biophysical attributes. We focus on the implications of these frontiers for equity and justice and suggest future research that can help ecosystem services work better address both legacies and current manifestations of injustice.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/02/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on February 16, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>
