<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Smart Digital Agriculture</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2020-12-23T11:45:56+11:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/12/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/12/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-23-02T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-12-23T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-21&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #21&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beyond ecosystem modeling: A roadmap to community cyberinfrastructure for ecological data‐model integration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monitoring of wheat crops using the backscattering coefficient and the interferometric coherence derived from Sentinel-1 in semi-arid areas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Synergistic use of SMAP and OCO-2 data in assessing the responses of ecosystem productivity to the 2018 U.S. drought&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;lidR: An R package for analysis of Airborne Laser Scanning (ALS) data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proximally sensed digital data library to predict topsoil clay across multiple sugarcane fields of Australia: Applicability of local and universal support vector machine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hypotheses, machine learning and soil mapping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Predicting soil properties in 3D: Should depth be a covariate?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paper chromatography: An inconsistent tool for assessing soil health&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UAV‐based training for fully fuzzy classification of Sentinel‐2 fluvial scenes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrating portable X-ray fluorescence (pXRF) measurement uncertainty for accurate soil contamination mapping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Bayesian approach toward the use of qualitative information to inform on-farm decision making: The example of soil compaction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Errors induced by spectral measurement positions and instrument noise in soil organic carbon prediction using vis-NIR on intact soil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combination of soil texture with Nix color sensor can improve soil organic carbon prediction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Numerical soil classification supports soil identification by citizen scientists using limited, simple soil observations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beyond x,y,z(t); Navigating New Landscapes of Science in the Science of Landscapes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From pools to flow: The PROMISE framework for new insights on soil carbon cycling in a changing world&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reference state and benchmark concepts for better biodiversity conservation in contemporary ecosystems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;COSORE: A community database for continuous soil respiration and other soil‐atmosphere greenhouse gas flux data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;beyond-ecosystem-modeling-a-roadmap-to-community-cyberinfrastructure-for-ecological-datamodel-integration&quot;&gt;Beyond ecosystem modeling: A roadmap to community cyberinfrastructure for ecological data‐model integration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an era of rapid global change, our ability to understand and predict Earth’s natural systems is lagging behind our ability to monitor and measure changes in the biosphere. Bottlenecks to informing models with observations have reduced our capacity to fully exploit the growing volume and variety of available data. Here, we take a critical look at the information infrastructure that connects ecosystem modeling and measurement efforts, and propose a roadmap to community cyberinfrastructure development that can reduce the divisions between empirical research and modeling and accelerate the pace of discovery. A new era of data‐model integration requires investment in accessible, scalable, and transparent tools that integrate the expertise of the whole community, including both modelers and empiricists. This roadmap focuses on five key opportunities for community tools: the underlying foundations of community cyberinfrastructure; data ingest; calibration of models to data; model‐data benchmarking; and data assimilation and ecological forecasting. This community‐driven approach is a key to meeting the pressing needs of science and society in the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;monitoring-of-wheat-crops-using-the-backscattering-coefficient-and-the-interferometric-coherence-derived-from-sentinel-1-in-semi-arid-areas&quot;&gt;Monitoring of wheat crops using the backscattering coefficient and the interferometric coherence derived from Sentinel-1 in semi-arid areas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radar data at C-band has shown great potential for the monitoring of soil and canopy hydric conditions of wheat crops. In this study, the C-band Sentinel-1 time series including the backscattering coefficients σ0 at VV and VH polarization, the polarization ratio (PR) and the interferometric coherence ρ are first analyzed with the support of experimental data gathered on three plots of irrigated winter wheat located in the Haouz plain in the center of Morocco covering five growing seasons. The results showed that ρ and PR are tightly related to the canopy development. ρ is also sensitive to soil preparation. By contrast, σ0 was found to be widely linked to changes in surface soil moisture (SSM) during the first growth stages when Leaf Area Index remains moderate (&amp;lt;1.5 m2/m2). In addition, drastic changes in the crop geometry associated to heading had a strong impact on the C-band σ0, in particular for VH polarization. The coupled water cloud and Oh models (WCM) were then calibrated and validated on the study sites. The comparison between the predicted and observed σ0 yielded a root mean square error (RMSE) values ranging from 1.50 dB to 2.02 dB for VV and between 1.74 dB to 2.52 dB for VH with significant differences occurring in the second part of the season after heading. Finally, new approaches based on the inversion of the WCM for SSM retrieval over wheat fields were proposed using Sentinel-1 radar data only. To this objective, the dry above-ground biomass (AGB) and the vegetation water content (VWC) were retrieved from the interferometric coherence and the PR. The relationships were then used as the vegetation descriptor in the WCM. The best retrieval results were obtained using the relationship between ρVV and the AGB (R and RMSE of 0.82, 0.05 m3/m3 respectively and no bias). The new retrieval approaches were then applied to a large database covering a rainfed field in Morocco and 18 plots of rainfed and irrigated wheat of the Kairouan plain (Tunisia) and compared to other classical techniques of SSM retrieval including simple linear relationships between SSM and σ0. The method based on the WCM and the ρVV-AGB relationships also provided with slightly better results than the others on the validation database (r = 0.75, RMSE = 0.06 m3/m3 and bias = 0.01 m3/m3 over the 18 plots of Tunisia) but the simple linear relationships performed also reasonably well (r = 0.62, RMSE = 0.07, bias = −0.01 in Tunisia for instance). This study opens perspectives for high resolution soil moisture mapping from Sentinel-1 data over south Mediterranean wheat crops and in fine, for irrigation scheduling and retrieval through the assimilation of these new products in an evapotranspiration model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;synergistic-use-of-smap-and-oco-2-data-in-assessing-the-responses-of-ecosystem-productivity-to-the-2018-us-drought&quot;&gt;Synergistic use of SMAP and OCO-2 data in assessing the responses of ecosystem productivity to the 2018 U.S. drought&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil moisture and gross primary productivity (GPP) estimates from the Soil Moisture Active Passive (SMAP) and solar-induced chlorophyll fluorescence (SIF) from the Orbiting Carbon Observatory-2 (OCO-2) provide new opportunities for understanding the relationship between soil moisture and terrestrial photosynthesis over large regions. Here we explored the potential of the synergistic use of SMAP and OCO-2 based data for monitoring the responses of ecosystem productivity to drought. We used complementary observational information on root-zone soil moisture and GPP (9 km) from SMAP and fine-resolution SIF (0.05°; GOSIF) derived from OCO-2 SIF soundings. We compared the spatial pattern and temporal evolution of anomalies of these variables over the conterminous U.S. during the 2018 drought, and examined to what extent they could characterize the drought-induced variations of flux tower GPP and crop yield data. Our results showed that SMAP GPP and GOSIF, both freely available online, could well capture the spatial extent and dynamics of the impacts of drought indicated by the U.S. Drought Monitor maps and the SMAP root-zone soil moisture deficit. Over the U.S. Southwest, monthly anomalies of soil moisture showed significant positive correlations with those of SMAP GPP (R2 = 0.44, p &amp;lt; 0.001) and GOSIF (R2 = 0.76, p &amp;lt; 0.001), demonstrating strong water availability constraints on plant productivity across dryland ecosystems. We further found that SMAP GPP and GOSIF captured the impact of drought on tower GPP and crop yield. Our results suggest that synergistic use of SMAP and OCO-2 data products can reveal the drought evolution and its impact on ecosystem productivity and carbon uptake at multiple spatial and temporal scales, and demonstrate the value of SMAP and OCO-2 for studying ecosystem function, carbon cycling, and climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lidr-an-r-package-for-analysis-of-airborne-laser-scanning-als-data&quot;&gt;lidR: An R package for analysis of Airborne Laser Scanning (ALS) data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airborne laser scanning (ALS) is a remote sensing technology known for its applicability in natural resources management. By quantifying the three-dimensional structure of vegetation and underlying terrain using laser technology, ALS has been used extensively for enhancing geospatial knowledge in the fields of forestry and ecology. Structural descriptions of vegetation provide a means of estimating a range of ecologically pertinent attributes, such as height, volume, and above-ground biomass. The efficient processing of large, often technically complex datasets requires dedicated algorithms and software. The continued promise of ALS as a tool for improving ecological understanding is often dependent on user-created tools, methods, and approaches. Due to the proliferation of ALS among academic, governmental, and private-sector communities, paired with requirements to address a growing demand for open and accessible data, the ALS community is recognising the importance of free and open-source software (FOSS) and the importance of user-defined workflows. Herein, we describe the philosophy behind the development of the lidR package. Implemented in the R environment with a C/C++ backend, lidR is free, open-source and cross-platform software created to enable simple and creative processing workflows for forestry and ecology communities using ALS data. We review current algorithms used by the research community, and in doing so raise awareness of current successes and challenges associated with parameterisation and common implementation approaches. Through a detailed description of the package, we address the key considerations and the design philosophy that enables users to implement user-defined tools. We also discuss algorithm choices that make the package representative of the ‘state-of-the-art’ and we highlight some internal limitations through examples of processing time discrepancies. We conclude that the development of applications like lidR are of fundamental importance for developing transparent, flexible and open ALS tools to ensure not only reproducible workflows, but also to offer researchers the creative space required for the progress and development of the discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;proximally-sensed-digital-data-library-to-predict-topsoil-clay-across-multiple-sugarcane-fields-of-australia-applicability-of-local-and-universal-support-vector-machine&quot;&gt;Proximally sensed digital data library to predict topsoil clay across multiple sugarcane fields of Australia: Applicability of local and universal support vector machine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowledge about topsoil (0–0.3 m) clay is required to maintain sugarcane profitability in Queensland, Australia. However, laboratory analysis to get this knowledge is tedious and time consuming. To add value to limited clay data, a digital soil map (DSM) can be created by using digital data and mathematical models. At the field level, site-specific linear regression (LR) models are often used along with gamma-ray (γ-ray) spectrometry and electromagnetic induction data (i.e. soil apparent electrical conductivity – ECa). But these LR might not perform well in site-independent calibrations across multiple sites. In this regard, support vector machine (SVM) might be useful. In this research, we first aimed to determine, using a stepwise SVM and calibration dataset, the optimal digital data (i.e. individual or combined) to develop local (for each individual site) and universal (for combined sites) SVM models. Using optimal digital data, our second aim was to predict clay for validation datasets by using local SVM in site-specific approach and universal SVM in site-independent, holdout and spiking approaches. Using these approaches, DSM of predicted clay and associated uncertainty were generated for a representative study site (i.e., Mossman). The third aim was to determine the suitable number of spiking samples and by varying the size of both spiking set and calibration model. Approaches were compared using prediction agreement (Lin’s concordance) and accuracy (ratio of performance to deviation – RPD). We concluded from stepwise SVM that combining digital data resulted in better accuracy (RPD = 2.17) than individual γ-ray (1.79) or ECa (1.49) data. In terms of independent validation, the results of Mossman reflected the general rank order of different approaches with site-specific (3.03) excellent, spiking (1.89) very good, site-independent (1.84) good and holdout (1.18) poor predictions. In case of DSM and uncertainty maps, under-predictions were problematic at field edges and where digital data changed as a function of soil type and or proximity to a prior stream channel. Considering the suitable number of spiking samples, size of spiking set showed linear relationship with improvement in predictions while that of calibration model showed no influence. These results suggest the usefulness of proximally sensed data and universal SVM to effectively predict clay across multiple sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hypotheses-machine-learning-and-soil-mapping&quot;&gt;Hypotheses, machine learning and soil mapping&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hypotheses are of major importance in scientific research. In current applications of machine learning algorithms for soil mapping the hypotheses being tested or developed are often ambiguous or undefined. Mapping soil properties or classes, however, does not tell much about the dynamics and processes that underly soil genesis and evolution. When the interest in the soil map is for applications in a context different than soil science, such as for policy making or baseline production of quantitative soil information, the interpretation should be made in light of this application. If otherwise, we recommend soil scientists to provide hypotheses to accompany their research. The hypothesis is formulated at the beginning of the research and, in some cases, motivates data collection. Here we argue that when applying data-driven techniques such as machine learning, developing hypotheses can be a useful end point of the research. The spatial pattern predicted by the machine learning model and the correlation found among the covariates are an opportunity to develop hypotheses which are likely to require additional analyses and datasets to be tested. Systematically providing scientific hypotheses in digital soil mapping studies will enable the soil science community to build on previous work, and to increase the credibility of data-driven algorithms as a means to accelerate discovery on soil processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;predicting-soil-properties-in-3d-should-depth-be-a-covariate&quot;&gt;Predicting soil properties in 3D: Should depth be a covariate?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil is a three-dimensional volume with property variability in all three dimensions. In Digital Soil Mapping (DSM), the variation of soil properties down a profile is usually harmonised by the use of the equal-area spline depth function approach. Soil observations at various depth intervals are harmonised to pre-determined depth intervals. To create maps of soil at the defined depth intervals, 2.5D model produces maps of individual depth intervals separately. Those maps can be reconstructed to produce a continuous depth function for each predicted location. More recently, several studies propose that soil property at any depth can be mapped using a model incorporating depth along with spatial covariates as predictor variables, creating a ‘3D’ model. The aim of this study is to evaluate the proposition that soil properties can be predicted at any depth. This study compares the 2.5D model and 3D model in two areas. The first test is on a 1500 km2 area in Edgeroi, New South Wales (NSW), Australia, mapping soil organic carbon (SOC, %), carbon storage (kg m−2), pH (H2O), clay content (%), and cation exchange capacity (CEC, mg/kg) based on depth-interval observations. The second study area in the Lower Hunter Valley has SOC observations at every 2 cm increment from a 210 km2 area. 2.5D and 3D models were tested in both study areas using four machine learning techniques: Cubist regression tree, Quantile Regression Forest (QRF), Artificial Neural Network (ANN), and 3D Generalised Additive Model (GAM). Results show that, in terms of R2 and RMSE, 2.5D and 3D models using different machine learning models produce comparable results on the validation of depth interval observations. The 3D tree-based models produce “stepped” prediction of properties with depth. Results on the Hunter Valley area with point observations show that the 3D model cannot replicate field point observations. 3D soil mapping on point depth observation has lower accuracy and larger uncertainty compared to the 2.5D model. For future DSM studies, 3D soil mapping with depth as a covariate requires caution with respect to the prediction method and the requirements of the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;paper-chromatography-an-inconsistent-tool-for-assessing-soil-health&quot;&gt;Paper chromatography: An inconsistent tool for assessing soil health&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although paper chromatography is being promoted as a cost-effective tool for rapid assessment of soil health, few studies have explored the quantitative relationship between chromatogram features and soil health variables, and no studies have investigated the association between chromatogram features and microbial diversity as determined using DNA sequences. We assessed 343 soil samples from varying land uses in southwestern Australia to investigate the relationship between total organic carbon, microbial activity and diversity, salinity and pH levels and 12 chromatogram features. Spearman’s correlations and variance partitioning were used to detect relationships. Although total organic carbon and microbial activity displayed the strongest correlations with chromatogram features, they were not associated with greater development of radial features and median zone radius as expected. This was in contrast to what has been previously reported, implying context dependent responses of chromatogram features to gradients in soil variables. Microbial community structure was found to explain changes in chromatogram features better than the measured soil variables. These results indicate that further studies are necessary before paper chromatography is embraced as a tool for soil health assessment, and raises questions regarding the use of chromatography by community groups as a tool to measure soil health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;uavbased-training-for-fully-fuzzy-classification-of-sentinel2-fluvial-scenes&quot;&gt;UAV‐based training for fully fuzzy classification of Sentinel‐2 fluvial scenes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An estimated 76% of global stream area is occupied by channels with widths above 30 m. Sentinel‐2 imagery with resolutions of 10 m could supply information about the composition of river corridors at national and global scales. Fuzzy classification models that infer sub‐pixel composition could further be used to compensate for small channel widths imaged at 10 m of spatial resolution. A major challenge to this approach is the acquisition of suitable training data useable in machine learning models that can predict land‐cover type information from image radiance values. In this contribution, we present a method which combines unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) and Sentinel‐2 imagery in order to develop a fuzzy classification approach capable of large‐scale investigations. Our approach uses hyperspatial UAV imagery in order to derive high‐resolution class information that can be used to train fuzzy classification models for Sentinel‐2 data where all bands are super‐resolved to a spatial resolution of 10 m. We use a multi‐temporal UAV dataset covering an area of 5.25 km2. Using a novel convolutional neural network (CNN) classifier, we predict sub‐pixel membership for Sentinel‐2 pixels in the fluvial corridor as divided into classes of water, vegetation and dry sediment. Our CNN model can predict fuzzy class memberships with median errors from −5% to +3% and mean absolute errors from 10% to 20%. We also show that our CNN fuzzy predictor can be used to predict crisp classes with accuracies from 95.5% to 99.9%. Finally, we use an example to show how a fuzzy CNN model trained with localized UAV data can be applied to longer channel reaches and detect new vegetation growth. We therefore argue that the novel use of UAVs as field validation tools for freely available satellite data can bridge the scale gap between local and regional fluvial studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;integrating-portable-x-ray-fluorescence-pxrf-measurement-uncertainty-for-accurate-soil-contamination-mapping&quot;&gt;Integrating portable X-ray fluorescence (pXRF) measurement uncertainty for accurate soil contamination mapping&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;significant reduction in the costs associated with contamination assessments can be achieved if traditional soil sampling for contaminated-site characterization is complemented by real-time sampling using proximal soil sensors. Real-time sampling using a portable X-ray fluorescence (pXRF) device is a cheap and fast sampling method to provide more data and reduce the time needed to map soil contamination. The main disadvantage of using pXRF is the degree of uncertainty of these in situ measurements due to the technology’s indirect nature, and its sensitivity to soil heterogeneity and soil moisture content. This study evaluates the potential of using both pXRF and traditional soil sampling measurements to accurately map soil contamination due to the presence of heavy metals. The approach proposed uses geostatistical sequential simulation with local probability distributions to characterize and integrate pXRF uncertainty at each sampling location. The resulting maps agree with the contamination map obtained using traditional laboratory data only, in terms of mapping accuracy and extent of contaminated areas. This study shows that with few collocated pXRF and laboratory analytical data it is possible to identify contaminated areas accurately, thus providing a cost-effective solution to work with pXRF data directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-bayesian-approach-toward-the-use-of-qualitative-information-to-inform-on-farm-decision-making-the-example-of-soil-compaction&quot;&gt;A Bayesian approach toward the use of qualitative information to inform on-farm decision making: The example of soil compaction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the development of predictive tools to aid decision making in agriculture increases, it must be acknowledged that the ability to incorporate management decisions as input data is limited. The data is either not recorded, or highly inadequate in terms of the volume, variety or relevance. Some circumstances are further hampered by the lack of benchmark data for comparison, and soil compaction is an example of this. The premise of this work was to take a probability based approach to decision making, utilising both qualitative and quantitative data to provide a probability distribution of risk against decisions made, in the context of grains production systems as an example of an agricultural enterprise. A Bayesian Belief Network (BBN) was constructed for soil compaction risk, as an exemplar. The BBN conditional probability tables for nodes were populated via a combination of biophysical model output (namely SoilFlex for soil stress distribution, and the APSIM package for soil-water and crop parameters) and expert opinion. Input nodes were parameterised with measured soil data, and the risk of soil compaction, given the soil stress at the wheel of a particular vehicle, was provided as the output. Potential effect on yield was subsequently calculated on the basis of percent change in soil bulk density, which was determined using literature based information (expert opinion). The tool broadly estimated yield impacts due to various agricultural traffic scenarios, providing means to highlight the financial consequences of failing to adopt controlled traffic farming management for a particular agricultural enterprise. Of significance, the BBN approach was determined useful for data limiting environments where empirical models struggle, thus providing a pragmatic and novel approach to on farm decision making incorporating management nuance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;errors-induced-by-spectral-measurement-positions-and-instrument-noise-in-soil-organic-carbon-prediction-using-vis-nir-on-intact-soil&quot;&gt;Errors induced by spectral measurement positions and instrument noise in soil organic carbon prediction using vis-NIR on intact soil&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil spectroscopy potentially would become a routine method for the measurement of soil properties in the field on soil cores. However, many factors could lead to errors in the measurement of spectra from intact soil cores. So far, errors induced by spectral measurement positions and instrument noise have rarely been quantified. The present study evaluated these errors based on 160 intact ring core samples collected from 20 profiles in a forest, southwest China. Each ring sample was scanned using a visible near-infrared (vis-NIR) spectrometer at nine evenly distributed positions at both ends of the ring to characterize within-sample variability. In addition, 10 scans were made at each position to characterize instrument error. A position spectrum was then calculated by averaging the 10 scans at each position, while a sample spectrum was calculated by averaging all 180 scans of each sample. The samples were then tested for soil organic carbon (SOC) content using the wet oxidation method. Based on the sample spectra and SOC content, a partial least squares regression (PLSR) model was calibrated. The modeling error was empirically calculated. Each scan, position spectrum, and sample spectrum was then fed into the calibrated PLSR model to predict SOC content, and the prediction results were evaluated for errors induced by instrument noise and different spectral measurement positions. Results showed that the error induced by different spectral measurement positions was about 75% of the modeling error, while the error induced by instrument noise was small and negligible. These three errors in terms of standard error of prediction (SEP) accounted for 18.6%, 23.8% and 1.46% of the average measured SOC content of the samples, respectively. Besides, the error due to different soil core sampling positions was also considerable. In terms of SEP, this error accounted for 12.5% of the average measured SOC content. These quantified error budgets would help to account for uncertainty in the measurement of soil properties using spectroscopy in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;combination-of-soil-texture-with-nix-color-sensor-can-improve-soil-organic-carbon-prediction&quot;&gt;Combination of soil texture with Nix color sensor can improve soil organic carbon prediction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The optimum ecosystem functioning is reliant on soil organic carbon (SOC) content which is traditionally measured in the laboratory via a cumbersome wet-chemistry method. This preliminary research tested whether a combination of Nix color sensor and portable X-ray fluorescence (PXRF) spectrometer data with soil texture data can improve soil SOC prediction accuracy relative to using them independently. A total of 371 samples representing diverse soil texture and SOC content were collected from three different ecoregions of eastern India: coastal saline zone, red and lateritic zone, and Gangetic alluvial zone. All dried, ground, and sieved samples were scanned via Nix and PXRF and random forest (RF) regression was used to predict soil SOC with different combinations of data. Soils were grouped into nine textural classes while soil SOC content exhibited substantial variability (0.08–2.26%). Comparing soil SOC with texture (sand + silt + clay), satisfactory prediction accuracy was observed (validation R2 = 0.70). Combining Nix extracted color parameters with texture substantially improved the model performance, producing the validation determination coefficient of 0.81. In contrast, PXRF-Rb, as a proxy of soil clay content was unable to achieve satisfactory prediction performance (R2 = 0.24), indicating the heterogeneity in soil mineralogical composition. The RF variable importance plot using Nix alone identified redness (a&lt;em&gt;) and yellowness to blueness (b&lt;/em&gt;) as influential predictors, manifesting the impact of red color from Fe and Al-oxides and their significant negative correlation with soil SOC (r = −0.62 and −0.57 for a* and b*, respectively). These color parameters were again identified by the RF variable importance plot of (Texture + Nix)-model, implying that the SOC prediction improvement may be linked with the Nix sensor’s capability of extracting useful information in the visible range. Summarily, a combination of Nix color variables and texture data was adept at predicting soil SOC in lieu of traditional laboratory analysis. The robustness of the (Texture + Nix)-based SOC prediction model can be augmented by incorporating more soil samples representing all 12 soil textural classes and variable SOC content, showing all possible soil colors in the pedogenic environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;numerical-soil-classification-supports-soil-identification-by-citizen-scientists-using-limited-simple-soil-observations&quot;&gt;Numerical soil classification supports soil identification by citizen scientists using limited, simple soil observations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accurately identifying the soil map unit component at a specific point‐location within a landscape is critical for implementing sustainable soil management. Recent developments in smartphone‐based technologies for characterizing soil profiles, coupled with improved numerical soil classification algorithms, have made it more accessible for non‐soil scientists to sample, characterize, and classify soil profiles. The main objective of this study was to evaluate an operational soil classification framework for identifying the soil component at a sampling‐location based on the numerical similarity of soil property values between the sampled soil profile and the soil components mapped in that area. To evaluate this soil identification framework, we used a subset of the U.S. National Cooperative Soil Survey Soil Characterization Database (NCSS–SCD) as our soil profile test dataset and the U.S. Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database as our reference dataset using profile data of soil components in the area surrounding each test profile. Numerical similarity was tested using soil property data representing different degrees of generalization, both in terms of generalizing depth‐wise variability (i.e., depth‐support) and generalizing across feature space (i.e., soil properties). Three soil property groups (i.e., Novice, Expert, Expert‐Plus) representing different levels of detail and three types of depth‐support (i.e., genetic horizon, depth intervals, and depth functions) were evaluated. Using a simple set of soil property inputs (i.e., Novice: soil texture class, rock fragment volume class, and soil color) resulted in nearly as high identification accuracy (46–53%) as that achieved with an Expert (48–57%) dataset that included more precise determinations (percent sand, silt, clay, and rock fragment volume), and virtually no further improvement with the addition of pH and organic matter in the Expert‐Plus dataset (53–60%). This study also showed minimal effect from the type of depth‐support used to represent depth‐wise variability. Furthermore, we evaluated several measures of soil functional similarity (i.e., ecological sites, land capability, taxonomic distance) which resulted in management relevant accuracies ranging from 65–89%. These findings support the utility of simple soil observations sampled at fixed depths for soil identification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;beyond-xyzt-navigating-new-landscapes-of-science-in-the-science-of-landscapes&quot;&gt;Beyond x,y,z(t); Navigating New Landscapes of Science in the Science of Landscapes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start of its centennial year, AGU’s surface process community revisited G. K. Gilbert’s legacy of landscape description and experimental models of surface processes, as well as his embrace of critique and pragmatism in the practice of landscape science. In the 100 years, since Gilbert and especially since the dawn of the 21st century, we have seen an intensified focus on the acquisition of more and more earth observation data and the numerical modeling of landscapes, alongside widespread use of deterministic and predictive practices to find solutions to the social, economic, and environmental challenges of today. What have we gained and lost in this pursuit? Here we lay out some of the challenges for the discipline in an increasingly data‐rich and complex world in which earth science is also being called to reorient itself towards more societally relevant roles. We ask the community to ponder the following: Is the discipline serving our scientific and societal goals, or is there a need for the science of landscapes to adopt new frameworks of thinking and to question the deterministic approaches that have dominated our discipline to date, in order to attend to the needs of living in the Anthropocene?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;from-pools-to-flow-the-promise-framework-for-new-insights-on-soil-carbon-cycling-in-a-changing-world&quot;&gt;From pools to flow: The PROMISE framework for new insights on soil carbon cycling in a changing world&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soils represent the largest terrestrial reservoir of organic carbon, and the balance between soil organic carbon (SOC) formation and loss will drive powerful carbon‐climate feedbacks over the coming century. To date, efforts to predict SOC dynamics have rested on pool‐based models, which assume classes of SOC with internally homogenous physicochemical properties. However, emerging evidence suggests that soil carbon turnover is not dominantly controlled by the chemistry of carbon inputs, but rather by restrictions on microbial access to organic matter in the spatially heterogeneous soil environment. The dynamic processes that control the physicochemical protection of carbon translate poorly to pool‐based SOC models; as a result, we are challenged to mechanistically predict how environmental change will impact movement of carbon between soils and the atmosphere. Here, we propose a novel conceptual framework to explore controls on belowground carbon cycling: Probabilistic Representation of Organic Matter Interactions within the Soil Environment (PROMISE). In contrast to traditional model frameworks, PROMISE does not attempt to define carbon pools united by common thermodynamic or functional attributes. Rather, the PROMISE concept considers how SOC cycling rates are governed by the stochastic processes that influence the proximity between microbial decomposers and organic matter, with emphasis on their physical location in the soil matrix. We illustrate the applications of this framework with a new biogeochemical simulation model that traces the fate of individual carbon atoms as they interact with their environment, undergoing biochemical transformations and moving through the soil pore space. We also discuss how the PROMISE framework reshapes dialogue around issues related to SOC management in a changing world. We intend the PROMISE framework to spur the development of new hypotheses, analytical tools, and model structures across disciplines that will illuminate mechanistic controls on the flow of carbon between plant, soil, and atmospheric pools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reference-state-and-benchmark-concepts-for-better-biodiversity-conservation-in-contemporary-ecosystems&quot;&gt;Reference state and benchmark concepts for better biodiversity conservation in contemporary ecosystems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Measuring the status and trends of biodiversity is critical for making informed decisions about the conservation, management or restoration of species, habitats and ecosystems. Defining the reference state against which status and change are measured is essential. Typically, reference states describe historical conditions, yet historical conditions are challenging to quantify, may be difficult to falsify, and may no longer be an attainable target in a contemporary ecosystem. We have constructed a conceptual framework to help inform thinking and discussion around the philosophical underpinnings of reference states and guide their application. We characterize currently recognized historical reference states and describe them as Pre‐Human, Indigenous Cultural, Pre‐Intensification and Hybrid‐Historical. We extend the conceptual framework to include contemporary reference states as an alternative theoretical perspective. The contemporary reference state framework is a major conceptual shift that focuses on current ecological patterns and identifies areas with higher biodiversity values relative to other locations within the same ecosystem, regardless of the disturbance history. We acknowledge that past processes play an essential role in driving contemporary patterns of diversity. The specific context for which we design the contemporary conceptual frame is underpinned by an overarching goal—to maximize biodiversity conservation and restoration outcomes in existing ecosystems. The contemporary reference state framework can account for the inherent differences in the diversity of biodiversity values (e.g. native species richness, habitat complexity) across spatial scales, communities and ecosystems. In contrast to historical reference states, contemporary references states are measurable and falsifiable. This ‘road map of reference states’ offers perspective needed to define and assess the status and trends in biodiversity and habitats. We demonstrate the contemporary reference state concept with an example from south‐eastern Australia. Our framework provides a tractable way for policy‐makers and practitioners to navigate biodiversity assessments to maximize conservation and restoration outcomes in contemporary ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cosore-a-community-database-for-continuous-soil-respiration-and-other-soilatmosphere-greenhouse-gas-flux-data&quot;&gt;COSORE: A community database for continuous soil respiration and other soil‐atmosphere greenhouse gas flux data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Globally, soils store two to three times as much carbon as currently resides in the atmosphere, and it is critical to understand how soil greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions and uptake will respond to ongoing climate change. In particular, the soil‐to‐atmosphere CO2 flux, commonly though imprecisely termed soil respiration (RS), is one of the largest carbon fluxes in the Earth system. An increasing number of high‐frequency RS measurements (typically, from an automated system with hourly sampling) have been made over the last two decades; an increasing number of methane measurements are being made with such systems as well. Such high frequency data are an invaluable resource for understanding GHG fluxes, but lack a central database or repository. Here we describe the lightweight, open‐source COSORE (COntinuous SOil REspiration) database and software, that focuses on automated, continuous and long‐term GHG flux datasets, and is intended to serve as a community resource for earth sciences, climate change syntheses and model evaluation. Contributed datasets are mapped to a single, consistent standard, with metadata on contributors, geographic location, measurement conditions and ancillary data. The design emphasizes the importance of reproducibility, scientific transparency and open access to data. While being oriented towards continuously measured RS, the database design accommodates other soil‐atmosphere measurements (e.g. ecosystem respiration, chamber‐measured net ecosystem exchange, methane fluxes) as well as experimental treatments (heterotrophic only, etc.). We give brief examples of the types of analyses possible using this new community resource and describe its accompanying R software package.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/12/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on December 23, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/12/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/12/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-12-02T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-12-02T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-20&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #20&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dynamics of soil penetration resistance in water-controlled environments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New pedotransfer functions for soil water retention curves that better account for bulk density effects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A combined data mining approach for on-line prediction of key soil quality indicators by Vis-NIR spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evaluating the applicability of soil moisture-based metrics for gauging the resiliency of rainfed agricultural systems in the midwestern United States&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Relationship between precipitation and 10Be and impacts on soil dynamics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vis-SWIR spectral prediction model for soil organic matter with different grouping strategies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Landscape-scale spatial variability of kaolinite-gibbsite ratio in tropical soils detected by diffuse reflectance spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Problems of modern soil mapping and ways to solve them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dynamics-of-soil-penetration-resistance-in-water-controlled-environments&quot;&gt;Dynamics of soil penetration resistance in water-controlled environments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In water-controlled environments, because rainfall is one of the primary hydroclimatic forcings, its variability can affect the dynamics of soil water content and other related processes such as soil penetration resistance (PR), plant growth, and food production. The objective of this study was to simulate the relative soil water content (s) and PR year-round considering semi-arid rainfall conditions for different soil classes. An experiment was conducted to obtain relative soil water content (s) and PR data in sandy soil and this information was combined with a data set of four soils from a similar experiment conducted on different soil texture classes. The relative soil water content and PR were simulated at a daily timescale using a stochastic soil water balance model for the five soils. The parameters of the PR-s model can be estimated from the soil texture and bulk density. Under rainfed conditions, there is a short window for tillage (plowing and cultivation) of sandy soils compared with clay soils. During the majority of a typical hydrological year, the PR reaches high values (greater than 5.0MPa) imposing a moderate to high physical limitation for root growth in sandy soils. In the same soils, limiting PR is reached at s levels very close to the field capacity during the drying process. This indicates that an extra input of water through irrigation may be required during the establishment of crops with a well-developed root system in order to prevent impairments to root growth. The daily PR values modeled over the course of a hydrological year followed a beta distribution with shape parameters (α and β) which were strongly correlated with the frequency of rainfall events during the wet season (λwet). The modeling framework presented here for simulating relative soil water content and soil penetration resistance can be applied to agricultural systems in order to prevent physical limitations on crop growth and to plan tillage management schedules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-pedotransfer-functions-for-soil-water-retention-curves-that-better-account-for-bulk-density-effects&quot;&gt;New pedotransfer functions for soil water retention curves that better account for bulk density effects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pedotransfer functions (PTFs) describing soil water retention curves (WRCs) have been widely used in crop, soil, and land surface models. A limitation of the available PTFs is that they fail to account for shape changes in WRCs due to bulk density variations caused by soil tillage, compaction, and other processes. This study develops new PTFs that include bulk density effects on the WRC shape. A new framework is introduced to build the bulk density-associated PTFs based on a widely-used WRC dataset. The new PTFs were validated by comparing the performance with two common PTFs from the literature using two independent datasets. The results show that the newly developed PTFs provide reliable WRC estimates for the validation datasets, with mean RMSE values of 0.055 and 0.059 m3 m-3, respectively. The accuracy of the new PTFs is comparable or in some cases better than the common PTFs. While the literature PTFs investigated do not always properly describe bulk density effects on WRC changes, the new PTFs effectively account for such effects on the WRC shape, thus have the potential to be integrated into crop and soil management models to represent bulk density impacts on WRCs due to anthropogenic (e.g., plowing and compaction) and natural (e.g., wetting/drying) processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-combined-data-mining-approach-for-on-line-prediction-of-key-soil-quality-indicators-by-vis-nir-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;A combined data mining approach for on-line prediction of key soil quality indicators by Vis-NIR spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Successful modelling of visible and near-infrared (vis-NIR) spectra for on-line prediction of key soil quality indicators is crucial for accurate variable rate applications of farm input resources. The aim of this paper is to optimize modelling of on-line collected spectra for the prediction of soil pH, organic carbon (OC), extractable phosphorous (P) and potassium (K) by means of spiking, combined with clustering and/or extra-weighting. A mobile fiber-type vis-NIR spectrophotometer (CompactSpec from Tec5 Technology, Germany), with spectral range of 305−1700 nm was calibrated using 100 samples collected from five different fields, which were merged with 28 samples collected from a target field. The resulting dataset was subjected to spectral pretreatments followed by k-means clustering and 95 % confidence ellipsoid, resulting in three optimal datasets. Partial least squares regression (PLSR) analyses were carried out on the calibration set (75 % of samples) for four calibration strategies: (i) non-clustered and non-weighted (NCNW), (ii) clustered and non-weighted (CNW), (iii) non-clustered but extra-weighted (NCW), and (iv) clustered and extra-weighted (CW). Results showed that the quality of on-line predictions was the best after clustering combined with extra-weighting. Modelling based with CW significantly improved model prediction accuracy to be very good for pH (ratio of prediction deviation (RPD) = 2.32) and P (RPD = 2.05), and good for OC (RPD = 1.90) and K (RPD = 1.80), whereas results of NCNW (standard calibration approach) were the poorest to be fair for P (RPD = 1.74) and OC (RPD = 1.50), and poor for K (RPD = 1.1) and pH (RPD = 1.39). It can be concluded that optimal sample selection with k-mean clustering when combined with extra-weighting will result in accurate PLSR calibration models for on-line prediction of soil pH, P, OC and K using a multi-field diverse dataset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evaluating-the-applicability-of-soil-moisture-based-metrics-for-gauging-the-resiliency-of-rainfed-agricultural-systems-in-the-midwestern-united-states&quot;&gt;Evaluating the applicability of soil moisture-based metrics for gauging the resiliency of rainfed agricultural systems in the midwestern United States&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Measuring and improving resiliency is the key goal of climate risk management in rainfed agriculture. Currently, available metrics are generally used to qualitatively measure the resilience of agricultural systems at broader scales. Moreover, these metrics showed non-linear responses to climate variability, thus often fail to capture the temporal dynamics of resilience at field scales. Our objective for this study is to combine a few soil moisture-based metrics to gauge the resiliency of three promising rainfed agricultural treatments, namely the no-till, organic, and reduced input treatments against the conventional treatment. These treatments have been established at the Kellogg Biological Station Long-Term Ecological Research (KBS-LTER) experiment in a randomized complete block design with six blocks per treatment. All four of these treatments consisted of maize (Zea mays)-soybean (Glycine max)-winter wheat (Triticum aestivum) in rotation. Long-term (1993–2018) soil moisture data from this experiment was collected to compute the soil moisture metrics while the total crop biomass, crop yield, and soil organic carbon data were statistically analyzed to evaluate the robustness of the metrics to gauge the resiliency of these systems. Results have shown that, among the soil moisture metrics, the mean relative difference, the Spearman’s rank correlation coefficient, and soil water deficit index were suitable, while the index of temporal stability was not suitable to gauge the resiliency of different rainfed agricultural systems. The no-till treatment was identified as the most resilient treatment in terms of soil moisture retention, effectiveness for drought mitigation, and crop yields. Meanwhile, the reduced input treatment was the least resilient in terms of soil water conservation and drought recovery. The results of this study can be extended to other Midwest regions of the United States and similar climatological areas around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;relationship-between-precipitation-and-10be-and-impacts-on-soil-dynamics&quot;&gt;Relationship between precipitation and 10Be and impacts on soil dynamics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meteoric beryllium-10 (10Be) is commonly used as a proxy of landscape dynamics (erosion and sedimentation rates) and soil development. Soil represents the first-stage reservoir of meteoric 10Be, and variability in the concentration of the isotope in soils may be affected by soil properties and atmospheric deposition. Although many investigations have targeted this issue, there are still problems in estimating the atmospheric input of the isotope in different soil environments. Here, we used 10Be data measured in soils distributed across China to explore the potential influence of meteorological and pedological conditions on the isotope concentration and related applications. In addition, to determine the mechanisms controlling 10Be concentrations in topsoil on a regional scale, the soil samples were sub-divided into 18 different catchments according to fluvial systems. The results indicated that there were significant negative correlations between precipitation and the soil 10Be concentration in high-precipitation regions (&amp;gt;1200 mm·y−1) and significant positive correlations for soils in low precipitation regions (&amp;lt;1200 mm·y−1). The data also revealed that precipitation is the most important variable controlling the 10Be concentration in soils of China when compared with the effects of soil properties such as grain size, mineralogy, pH, and cation exchange capacity. Land use and soil erosion may have limited impacts on the distribution of 10Be in soils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vis-swir-spectral-prediction-model-for-soil-organic-matter-with-different-grouping-strategies&quot;&gt;Vis-SWIR spectral prediction model for soil organic matter with different grouping strategies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The effect of soil organic matter (SOM) on the spectral characteristics of soil differs among soil samples of different soil types with various mineral contents or mechanical compositions. SOM prediction models with visible and near-infrared and shortwave infrared (Vis-SWIR) spectral variables for grouping soil samples are more accurate than global modeling methods. However, the optimal grouping method must be explored. We measured the Vis-SWIR (400–2500 nm) spectral reflectance of 274 soil samples from the Songnen Plain and applied different grouping strategies, including traditional soil grouping, spectral clustering grouping and decision tree grouping considering both traditional grouping information and spectral information. The original reflectance, continuum removal, and first-derivative reflectance were analyzed with competitive adaptive reweighted sampling (CARS), and the results were used as inputs to establish a random forest model for SOM prediction. The following results were obtained: (1) the decision tree grouping method is the optimal grouping strategy for the SOM prediction model; (2) among different inputs, first-derivative reflectance is optimal; and (3) CARS is an effective way to reduce the number of inputs and improve the prediction accuracy of SOM. This study provides an effective soil grouping methodology for SOM estimation at the soil great group level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;landscape-scale-spatial-variability-of-kaolinite-gibbsite-ratio-in-tropical-soils-detected-by-diffuse-reflectance-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Landscape-scale spatial variability of kaolinite-gibbsite ratio in tropical soils detected by diffuse reflectance spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of diffuse reflectance spectroscopy (DRS) has gained prominence in the quantification of soil attributes due to its ease and practicality of obtaining data. This study aimed to evaluate the potential of different methodologies applied to spectral curves given by DRS to estimate kaolinite (Kt) and gibbsite (Gb), and their spatial variability characterization for the Western Plateau of São Paulo. The Western Plateau of São Paulo has 13 million hectares, 2 million of them covered by basalt and 11 million by sandstones. A total of 600 samples were collected at a depth of 0.0–0.20 m. Calibration curves were constructed with pure minerals for x-ray diffraction (XRD) and DRS techniques. The Kt/(Kt + Gb) ratio and the percentages of Kt and Gb were determined by XRD and using the following three methodologies applied to spectral curves: continuum removal technique (CR), direct ratio of the valley (DRV), and multivariate analysis by partial least squares regression (PLSR). The CR procedure had means similar to those observed by XRD, i.e., 0.90 and 0.92, respectively, while DRV overestimated the ratio, with a mean of 1.32. DRS allowed the estimation of the Kt/(Kt + Gb) ratio for the different geological and landscape compartments of the Western Plateau of São Paulo for the CR and DRV procedures. CR procedure allowed constructing models to be more efficient compared to those obtained by DRV and PLSR. The use of geostatistics to interpolate the data of the ratio Kt/(Kt + Gb) by DRS provided important information to define specific management zones accurately and more economically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;problems-of-modern-soil-mapping-and-ways-to-solve-them&quot;&gt;Problems of modern soil mapping and ways to solve them&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article analyzes the problems of modern soil mapping and offers a new, interdisciplinary approach to overcoming them. Among these problems, the most noticeable are the following: harmonization and thematic content of soil maps, multiscale soil mapping, and global soil map. It is shown that the main reasons of problems in modern soil mapping are the recognition of the priority of the practical purposes of soil mapping over the scientific ones, the lack of understanding of the relationship between soil mapping and the conceptual soil classification, the neglect or misuse of the systems approach and contemporary theories of classification, the lack of a universal soil classification system, and an orientation toward new technological advances. It is emphasized that hopes for a successful solution to the problems of soil mapping using the latest technologies, tools and methods are largely unjustified, since, first of all, a consistent theory of soil mapping is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theoretical foundations and technology for multiscale soil-landscape mapping in a GIS environment are described. Multiscale soil-landscape maps are defined as a system of interconnected maps of all scale ranges, which have a single classification basis and coordinated thematic content. They contain integrated information about soils and landscape systems, which are landscapes, considered from the point of view of the systems approach, and display soils mainly as derived landscape system elements. Another distinctive feature of multiscale soil-landscape maps is that they reflect the relationship between soil properties, on the one hand, and properties of the basic landscape system elements (parent rocks, air, water, and organisms), on the other. The advantages of multiscale soil-landscape mapping in comparison with traditional and digital are shown. From a practical point of view, multiscale soil-landscape maps are considered as the basis for making scientifically sound decisions on sustainable nature management at all levels - from global to local.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/12/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on December 02, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/11/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/11/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-11-15T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-11-15T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-19&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #19&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Operational Bayesian GLS Regression for Regional Hydrologic Analyses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Role of Fire in the Coevolution of Soils and Temperate Forests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Calibration Framework for High‐Resolution Hydrological Models Using a Multiresolution and Heterogeneous Strategy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bootstrap Aggregation and Cross‐Validation Methods to Reduce Overfitting in Reservoir Control Policy Search&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developing pedotransfer functions to harmonize extractable soil phosphorus content measured with different methods: A case study across the mainland of France&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Legacy data-based national-scale digital mapping of key soil properties in India&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimating Atterberg limits of soils from hygroscopic water content&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Characterization of the water retention curves of Everglades wetland soils&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Constant carbon pricing increases support for climate action compared to ramping up costs over time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;operational-bayesian-gls-regression-for-regional-hydrologic-analyses&quot;&gt;Operational Bayesian GLS Regression for Regional Hydrologic Analyses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dirceu S. Reis Jr Andrea G. Veilleux Jonathan R. Lamontagne Jery R. Stedinger Eduardo S. Martins&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;e2019WR026940 First Published:19 February 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key Points&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A comprehensive statistical framework for regional hydrologic regression is presented with spatially correlated flow data and varying record lengths
*Framework correctly attributes variability to sampling errors in computed statistic, variability explained by the model, and model error
*New diagnostics includes Bayesian plausibility value, pseudo adjusted R2, pseudo ANOVA, and Bayesian metrics for leverage and influence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-calibration-framework-for-highresolution-hydrological-models-using-a-multiresolution-and-heterogeneous-strategy&quot;&gt;A Calibration Framework for High‐Resolution Hydrological Models Using a Multiresolution and Heterogeneous Strategy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruochen Sun Felipe Hernández Xu Liang Huiling Yuan
e2019WR026541 First Published:12 June 2020
Key Points&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A novel framework is developed for automatic calibration of computationally demanding hydrological models with a large number of parameters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The framework alleviates equifinality, and calibrated parameters achieve more reasonable values that better correspond to physical reality&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The framework leads to faster improvement and smoother convergence to optimal objective values and is tested with 134 calibration parameters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-role-of-fire-in-the-coevolution-of-soils-and-temperate-forests&quot;&gt;The Role of Fire in the Coevolution of Soils and Temperate Forests&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assaf Inbar Petter Nyman Patrick N. J. Lane Gary J. Sheridan
e2019WR026005 First Published:11 July 2020
Key Points&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wildfire strongly influences forest hydrogeomorphology, yet its net effect on coevolution of soil‐vegetation systems is not yet constrained&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We used a new numerical model to test the hypothesis that fire is central to coevolution of forest‐soil systems in SE Australia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The hypothesis was supported, and the role of fire was found to increase with aridity due to higher fire frequency and less developed soils&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bootstrap-aggregation-and-crossvalidation-methods-to-reduce-overfitting-in-reservoir-control-policy-search&quot;&gt;Bootstrap Aggregation and Cross‐Validation Methods to Reduce Overfitting in Reservoir Control Policy Search&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zachary P. Brodeur Jonathan D. Herman Scott Steinschneider
e2020WR027184 First Published:08 July 2020
Key Points&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We apply machine learning techniques of bootstrap aggregation (bagging) and cross‐validation to improve reservoir control policy search&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Block bootstrapping of historic hydrology based on paleo‐inflows can efficiently generate calibration‐validation‐testing data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Policy selection according to validation performance on bootstrapped data leads to the greatest improvement in out‐of‐sample performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;developing-pedotransfer-functions-to-harmonize-extractable-soil-phosphorus-content-measured-with-different-methods-a-case-study-across-the-mainland-of-france&quot;&gt;Developing pedotransfer functions to harmonize extractable soil phosphorus content measured with different methods: A case study across the mainland of France&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geoderma&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phosphorus (P) is a nutrient essential to living organisms and ecosystems. Accurate information regarding extractable soil P is necessary for agricultural management and environmental quality. Direct measurements of extractable soil P at large scales are usually impeded by considerable time, labour, and economic resources required for implementation. To meet agronomic and environmental monitoring needs, multiple extraction methods have been developed worldwide to estimate the different components of soil P. In France, three extraction methods are used, namely the Dyer method for acidic soils, Joret-Hébert for calcareous soils, and Olsen for all soils. Therefore, it is difficult to compare data obtained nationwide for monitoring purposes. Consequently, it is of significant importance to develop pedotransfer functions (PTFs) to harmonise extractable soil P data obtained from different extraction methods with the assistance of other easily available predictors from soil information systems. In this study, we used an extensive dataset from the French soil-monitoring programme for the calibration and evaluation of PTFs. We implemented the partial least squares regression to relate extractable P measured by the Dyer or Joret-Hébert method to extractable P determined by the Olsen method considering 14 soil properties (total P2O5, pH, cation exchange capacity (CEC), CaCO3, soil texture (clay, silt and sand contents), total organic carbon, and exchangeable Fe, Al, CaO, Mn, MgO, and K2O). We constructed patrimonial models by selecting the most important predictors. According to the results of 10 iterations cross-validation, the average R2, root mean-square error (RMSE), and mean error (ME) of the PTF of calcareous soils were 0.66, 25.81, and −0.11 mg kg−1, whereas those of acidic soils were 0.70, 24.02, and −0.87 mg kg1, respectively. The Joret-Hébert P2O5, silt, pH, total P2O5, CEC, and K were the most important predictors for estimating Olsen P2O5 in calcareous soils, whereas Dyer P2O5, exchangeable Al, K, and pH were the most important predictors for estimating Olsen P2O5 in acidic soils. We observed that the explanatory power of the soil properties was more important in calcareous than in acidic soils. As expected, the proxies of Olsen P2O5, namely, Dyer P2O5 and Joret-Hébert P2O5, were the most important variables in modelling Olsen P2O5 variations. In addition, the relationship between Olsen P2O5 and Dyer P2O5 was much stronger than that between Olsen P2O5 and Joret-Hébert P2O5. The results confirmed the feasibility of estimating extractable P in soil by PTFs that were constructed using statistical methods, such as partial least squares regression. The addition of more predictors that are related to agricultural practices and topography attributes may improve the prediction accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;legacy-data-based-national-scale-digital-mapping-of-key-soil-properties-in-india&quot;&gt;Legacy data-based national-scale digital mapping of key soil properties in India&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Mapping soil resources at a national scale in large countries such as India is a challenge because of limited soil data available and efforts to collect them. Legacy soil information shows promise; but, there are still challenges that need to be addressed. In this study, we deliver the first digital maps of key soil properties down to 2 m depth across India using legacy data and quantified the relationships between mapped soil properties and bioclimatic and terrain attributes. A legacy database containing analytical data for 1,707 soil profiles with 7,337 soil horizons was collated from reports published by the National Bureau of Soil Survey and Land Use Planning and other Indian organizations. 3D regression kriging based on the random forest model was used to map sand and clay contents, pH and soil organic carbon (SOC) contents at depths as per the GlobalSoilMap specifications. Important covariates included mean monthly temperature and precipitation data from the World Climatic Centre and terrain attributes derived from the NASA’s Shuttle Radar Topography Mission (SRTM) digital elevation model. The uncertainty of the model was quantified as the coefficient of variation of the predicted soil properties by repeated random sampling of the profile dataset into calibration and validation samples at a ratio of 75:25. The performance statistics for the surface soil properties were superior to subsurface soils with the highest Lin’s concordance coefficient (LCC) recorded for soil pH. Estimated LCC values in validation datasets ranged from 0.81 to 0.84 for pH, 0.30 to 0.59 for SOC, 0.48 to 0.56 for clay content, and 0.34 to 0.44 for sand content. Elevation, topographic wetness index, high rainfall, and temperature were observed to be the major drivers for the variability of selected soil properties. Prepared digital soil maps across different agroecological regions showed that sandy soils dominated Western Plains while clayey soils were dominant in the central Deccan Plateau. Soils of the North-Eastern hills were acidic in nature while the Western Ghats and Coastal Plains showed high SOC accumulation. Although finer soil fractions are considered as major drivers of SOC stabilization, rainfall during June (onset of monsoon) was a major climatic driver for SOC in Indian soils. The national maps of soil properties may be linked to soil productivity and provisioning of ecosystem services to guide policy makers for creating region-specific soil management plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;estimating-atterberg-limits-of-soils-from-hygroscopic-water-content&quot;&gt;Estimating Atterberg limits of soils from hygroscopic water content&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
A number of environmental, agronomic and engineering applications require knowledge of the Atterberg limits (liquid limit, LL; plastic limit, PL) and the plasticity index, PI of soils. The tedious and costly nature of standard experimental methods, as well as challenges with measurement repeatability motivated the development of regressions as well as more sophisticated techniques to estimate the Atterberg limits from other properties such as clay content, cation exchange capacity (CEC), and soil specific surface area. The amount of water adsorbed to particle surfaces at relative humidity (RH) &amp;lt; 95% is intimately linked to these soil properties, which suggests that hygroscopic water content (wh) may be a better predictor of the Atterberg limits. The present study (i) proposes regression models that estimate the LL, PL, and PI from wh at different relative humidity values ranging from 10 to 90% and considering water sorption hysteresis, and (ii) compares the performance of the models to other models that comprise clay, silt and organic carbon contents and CEC. For model development, wh was measured by water adsorption and desorption for 168 soil samples that varied widely in terms of geographic origin, clay mineralogy, and soil organic carbon content. The LL and PL were determined with the drop cone penetrometer and rolling device, respectively. Regression models were developed for both sorption directions for nine RH values between 10 and 90%. For 44 independent soil samples, the models estimated LL, PL and PI accurately (e.g., for desorption wh measured at 90% RH, RMSE and r2 values were 6.43% &amp;amp; 0.89; 3.95% &amp;amp; 0.83 and 6.69% &amp;amp; 0.79, respectively). There was no clear effect of sorption direction on the estimation accuracy. The wh determined at higher RH tended to better estimate the Atterberg limits compared to that measured at lower RH. The wh models were superior in estimating LL and PL compared to models that were based on clay content and organic carbon or CEC. For the PI, the models based on CEC performed slightly better than the wh models. Thus, a single measure of wh can provide reliable estimates of the Atterberg limits and PI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;characterization-of-the-water-retention-curves-of-everglades-wetland-soils&quot;&gt;Characterization of the water retention curves of Everglades wetland soils&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Alterations to the natural hydrology of wetlands like the Everglades have increased the presence of unsaturated zones in typically inundated soil environments. Understanding soil moisture dynamics through numerical modeling requires a large dataset of soil hydraulic parameters (SHPs) due to the spatially variable nature of hydromorphic soils typically found in wetlands. Furthermore, the application of conventional parameterization models is challenging due to shrinkage with desaturation observed in these organic-rich soils. The objective of this work was to investigate water retention, shrinkage, and the effect of shrinkage on the SHPs of Everglades soils. This study used pressure plate extractors to determine the soil water retention curves (SWRCs) and corresponding shrinkage from triplicates for 53 sites across the Everglades. In addition, the organic content (OC), and fiber content (FC) were measured in the laboratory. An agglomerative clustering method applied to the retention and shrinkage data identified three distinct clusters: marl, mixed marl-peat and peat. Marl had higher volumetric water contents (VWCs) than marl-peat or peat particularly at higher pressures. The susceptibility of peat to shrinkage resulted in lower VWCs compared to the other two soils. When shrinkage was accounted for in the vGM model, a significantly higher  and lower  were observed. In addition, some deviations from typical SWRC behavior, attributed to the collapse of macro-pores, caused poor model fit. Northern marshes with predominantly fibric peat had steeper SWRCs due to the inverse relationship between FC and VWC at higher pressures. Further work is required to determine the influence of vegetation on the SWRC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;constant-carbon-pricing-increases-support-for-climate-action-compared-to-ramping-up-costs-over-time&quot;&gt;Constant carbon pricing increases support for climate action compared to ramping up costs over time&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael M. Bechtel, Kenneth F. Scheve &amp;amp; Elisabeth van Lieshout 
Nature Climate Change volume 10, pages1004–1009(2020)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
The introduction of policies that increase the price of carbon is central to limiting the adverse effects of global warming. Conventional wisdom holds that, of the possible cost paths, gradually raising costs relating to climate action will receive the most public support. Here, we explore mass support for dynamic cost paths in four major economies (France, Germany, the United Kingdom and the United States). We find that, for a given level of average costs, increasing cost paths receive little support whereas constant cost schedules are backed by majorities in all countries irrespective of whether those average costs are low or high. Experimental evidence indicates that constant cost paths significantly reduce opposition to climate action relative to increasing cost paths. Preferences for climate cost paths are related to the time horizons of individuals and their desire to smooth consumption over time.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on November 15, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/11/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/11/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-11-07T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-11-07T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-18&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #18&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Global Cropland Connectivity: A Risk Factor for Invasion and Saturation by Emerging Pathogens and Pests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Land use/land cover recognition in arid zone using A multi-dimensional multi-grained residual Forest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pedotransfer Function for the Brunswick Soil Hydraulic Property Model and Comparison to the van Genuchten‐Mualem Model&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil-based, field-specific fertilizer recommendations are a pipe-dream&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trade-offs in greenhouse gas emissions across a liming-induced gradient of soil pH: Role of microbial structure and functioning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;global-cropland-connectivity-a-risk-factor-for-invasion-and-saturation-by-emerging-pathogens-and-pests&quot;&gt;Global Cropland Connectivity: A Risk Factor for Invasion and Saturation by Emerging Pathogens and Pests&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yanru Xing,  John F Hernandez Nopsa,  Kelsey F Andersen,  Jorge L Andrade-Piedra, Fenton D Beed,  Guy Blomme,  Mónica Carvajal-Yepes,  Danny L Coyne,  Wilmer J Cuellar, Gregory A Forbes
BioScience, Volume 70, Issue 9, September 2020, Pages 744–758, https://doi.org/10.1093/biosci/biaa067
Published: 29 July 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
The geographic pattern of cropland is an important risk factor for invasion and saturation by crop-specific pathogens and arthropods. Understanding cropland networks supports smart pest sampling and mitigation strategies. We evaluate global networks of cropland connectivity for key vegetatively propagated crops (banana and plantain, cassava, potato, sweet potato, and yam) important for food security in the tropics. For each crop, potential movement between geographic location pairs was evaluated using a gravity model, with associated uncertainty quantification. The highly linked hub and bridge locations in cropland connectivity risk maps are likely priorities for surveillance and management, and for tracing intraregion movement of pathogens and pests. Important locations are identified beyond those locations that simply have high crop density. Cropland connectivity risk maps provide a new risk component for integration with other factors—such as climatic suitability, genetic resistance, and global trade routes—to inform pest risk assessment and mitigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;land-useland-cover-recognition-in-arid-zone-using-a-multi-dimensional-multi-grained-residual-forest&quot;&gt;Land use/land cover recognition in arid zone using A multi-dimensional multi-grained residual Forest&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Monitoring arid areas could effectively improve economic, ecological and humanity benefits. It is an effective monitoring approach to recognize the land cover or land use of arid areas through machine learning methods using satellite images. However, there is no public classified dataset for arid areas currently, and hence remote sensing image monitoring in desert areas is restricted. Existing classification methods are not able to fully utilize effective features of satellite images and multi-spectral optical parameters. In this paper, our contributions are as follows: Firstly, we presented a new satellite dataset named the ARID-5 for arid area land cover/land use (LULC) classification, the LULC in arid areas included desert, oasis, Gobi, and water system. Second, we proposed a machine learning algorithm named the multi-dimensional multi-grained residual forest algorithm for LULC recognition on arid areas. In this algorithm, the multi-dimensional multi-grained structure was able to effectively extract image features and spectral information. The residual forest structure mapped probability feature vectors to higher levels for prediction, which effectively improved the reflection of the forest structure on the sample. At the same time, the base estimator was transmitted in cascade layers, and thus the diversity and the accuracy were improved. Experimental results proved that the multi-dimensional multi-grained residual forest showed good classification abilities. Last, we also tested our algorithm on SAT-4 and SAT-6 datasets, which proved the generalization performance of our algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pedotransfer-function-for-the-brunswick-soil-hydraulic-property-model-and-comparison-to-the-van-genuchtenmualem-model&quot;&gt;Pedotransfer Function for the Brunswick Soil Hydraulic Property Model and Comparison to the van Genuchten‐Mualem Model&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tobias K. D. Weber  Michael Finkel  Maria da Conceição Gonçalves  Harry Vereecken  Efstathios Diamantopoulos
First published: 20 June 2020 https://doi.org/10.1029/2019WR026820&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Modeling soil hydraulic properties requires an effective representation of capillary and noncapillary storage and conductivity. This is made possible by using physically comprehensive yet flexible soil hydraulic property models. Such a model (Brunswick [BW] model) was introduced by Weber et al. (2019, https://doi.org/10.1029/2018WR024584), and it overcomes some core deficiencies present in the widely used van Genuchten‐Mualem (VGM) model. We first compared the performance of the BW model to that of the VGM model in its ability to describe water retention and hydraulic conductivity data on a set of measurements of 402 soil samples with textures covering the entire range of classes. Second, we developed a simple transfer function to predict BW parameters based on VGM parameters. Combined with our new function, any existing pedotransfer function for the prediction of the VGM parameters can be extended to predict BW model parameters. Based on information criteria, the smaller variance of the residuals, and a 40% reduction in mean absolute error in the hydraulic conductivity over all samples, the BW model clearly outperforms VGM. This is possible as the BW model explicitly accounts for hydraulic properties of dry soils. With the new pedotransfer function developed in this study, better descriptions of water retention and hydraulic conductivities are possible. We are convinced that this will strengthen the utility of the new model and enable improved field‐scale simulations, climate change impact assessments on water, energy and nutrient fluxes, as well as crop productivity in agroecosystems by soil‐crop and land‐surface modeling. The models and the pedotransfer function are included in an R package spsh (https://cran.r‐project.org/package=spsh).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;trade-offs-in-greenhouse-gas-emissions-across-a-liming-induced-gradient-of-soil-ph-role-of-microbial-structure-and-functioning&quot;&gt;Trade-offs in greenhouse gas emissions across a liming-induced gradient of soil pH: Role of microbial structure and functioning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highlights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two-year data from a field experiment initiated in 1942, with four liming rates.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Liming decreased N2O due to increased N2O reduction and by promoting plant growth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Liming increased ecosystem respiration with no effects on soil organic carbon.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lime application stimulated CH4 oxidation, but high rates decreased CH4 oxidation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liming is a common agricultural practice to improve crop yields by raising soil pH. Liming also modulates the production and consumption of greenhouse gases (GHGs) in soils, but the direction and strength of such effects are largely unknown. Since lime application is not a dichotomous variable (application or not), but rather can be dosed according to crop requirements, a critical research gap is whether liming effects on GHG emissions are linear or follow alternate relationships. Based on two-years of data from a long-term field-liming experiment (initiated in 1942), we show that the relationship between an established soil pH gradient (pH of 3.77, 4.92, 6.39, and 6.84 in 1 M KCl extracts) and the emission of GHGs deviates from linearity. Liming increased carbon dioxide (CO2) fluxes from ecosystem respiration, but there were no differences between limed treatments. The increased respiration was due to higher plant carbon (C) inputs and root respiration, enhanced decomposition activity (β-glucosidase) and increased abundance of specific microbial groups (e.g., cellulose-decomposing bacteria). Liming decreased nitrous oxide (N2O) emissions due to increased N2O reduction via denitrification and by promoting plant growth. Compared with native acidic soil, lime application stimulated methane (CH4) oxidation, but the highest liming rate was least stimulatory. This aligned with the soil CH4 oxidation potential, which was modified by liming-induced changes in soil microbial structure as indicated by phospholipid fatty acid analyses. There were no differences in soil organic C (SOC) content between liming levels, apparently because increased ecosystem respiration rates compensated for higher plant C inputs from limed plots. Overall, our results reveal a fundamental ecological trade-off: applying lime at a rate that maximizes crop yield with low N2O emissions may increase CO2 emissions (not compensated by higher SOC in a sandy soil) and decrease CH4 oxidation compared to liming applications below this level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-based-field-specific-fertilizer-recommendations-are-a-pipe-dream&quot;&gt;Soil-based, field-specific fertilizer recommendations are a pipe-dream&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author links open overlay panelA.G.T.SchutK.E.Giller
https://doi.org/10.1016/j.geoderma.2020.114680&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Laboratory ring-tests showed large coefficients of variation in soil analyses.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimates of soil N, P and K supply for a single field varied strongly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Field-specific recommendations based on a single soil sample were inaccurate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fertilizer with balanced N:P:K content strongly reduced errors in recommendations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Fertilizer recommendations are key for farmers: the investment is relatively large for smallholders and risky with unknown yield responses and variable fertilizer prices. Are agronomists able to provide useful site-specific fertilizer recommendations that reduce these uncertainties? We evaluated the influence of errors introduced due to soil sampling and chemical analysis procedures both within- and among laboratories on fertilizer recommendations. Using what we consider to be conservative estimates of the uncertainty in estimating soil supply of N, P and K in a single composite soil sample, the resulting 90% confidence interval of fertilizer recommendations ranged from 86 to 186, 0–58 and 38–114 kg N, P and K ha−1 respectively. The numerous laboratory services and digital applications providing field-specific recommendations appear to promise more accuracy than soil analysis can realistically deliver. We conclude that a field-specific fertilizer recommendation based on a single composite soil sample is indeed a pipe-dream.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on November 07, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/11/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/11/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-11-03T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-11-03T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-17&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #17&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mapping the effectiveness of nature‐based solutions for climate change adaptation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Diversity‐dependent soil acidification under nitrogen enrichment constrains biomass productivity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mapping-the-effectiveness-of-naturebased-solutions-for-climate-change-adaptation&quot;&gt;Mapping the effectiveness of nature‐based solutions for climate change adaptation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alexandre Chausson Beth Turner Dan Seddon Nicole Chabaneix Cécile A. J. Girardin Valerie Kapos Isabel Key Dilys Roe Alison Smith Stephen Woroniecki Nathalie Seddon
Pages: 6134-6155 First Published: 09 September 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We present the first global systematic map of the effectiveness of nature‐based solutions (NbS) for addressing the impacts of climate change and hydrometeorological hazards on people. We found that most studies on NbS interventions in natural or semi‐natural ecosystems reported reduced climate impacts and that, overall, more synergies than trade‐offs were reported between addressing climate impacts and broader ecological, social and climate change mitigation outcomes. However, to strengthen the evidence base and support the upscaling of NbS, future studies should compare the cost‐effectiveness of NbS with engineered alternatives and consider social and ecological outcomes. More NbS research is also needed in the Global South.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;diversitydependent-soil-acidification-under-nitrogen-enrichment-constrains-biomass-productivity&quot;&gt;Diversity‐dependent soil acidification under nitrogen enrichment constrains biomass productivity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kaitlin Kimmel George N. Furey Sarah E. Hobbie Forest Isbell David Tilman Peter B. Reich
Pages: 6594-6603 First Published: 01 September 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nitrogen enrichment is known to increase plant productivity, while also decreasing species richness and acidifying soils. We show that productivity could have been 14.5% greater on average in monocultures if not for nitrogen‐induced soil acidification and about 28.5% greater on average in 16 species communities if not for nitrogen‐induced species losses in a 20 year planted richness by nitrogen addition grassland plant experiment. Our results suggest that the positive effect of nutrient enrichment on productivity can diminish over time, especially because of soil acidification in low diversity communities and especially because of plant diversity loss in initially high diversity communities.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on November 03, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/10/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/10/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-10-19T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-10-19T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-16&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #16&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Molecular trade-offs in soil organic carbon composition at continental scale&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linear mixed effects models for non‐Gaussian continuous repeated measurement data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Circular regression trees and forests with an application to probabilistic wind direction forecasting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use of diffuse reflectance spectroscopy and Nix pro color sensor in combination for rapid prediction of soil organic carbon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A framework for modelling soil structure dynamics induced by biological activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;molecular-trade-offs-in-soil-organic-carbon-composition-at-continental-scale&quot;&gt;Molecular trade-offs in soil organic carbon composition at continental scale&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-020-0634-x&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The molecular composition of soil organic carbon remains contentious. Microbial-, plant- and fire-derived compounds may each contribute, but whether they vary predictably among ecosystems remains unclear. Here we present carbon functional groups and molecules from a diverse spectrum of North American surface mineral soils, collected primarily from the National Ecological Observatory Network and quantified by nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy and a molecular mixing model. We find that soils vary widely in relative contributions of carbohydrate, lipid, protein, lignin and char-like carbon, but each compound class has similar overall abundance. Ninety percent of the variance in carbon composition can be explained by three principal component axes representing a trade-off between lignin and protein, a trade-off between carbohydrate and char, and lipids. Reactive aluminium, crystalline iron oxides and pH plus overlying organic horizon thickness—predictors that are all related to climate—best explain variation along each respective axis. Together, our data point to continental-scale trade-offs in soil carbon molecular composition that are linked to environmental and geochemical variables known to predict carbon mass concentrations. Controversies regarding the genesis of soil carbon and its potential responses to global change can be partially reconciled by considering diverse ecosystem properties that drive complementary persistence mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;linear-mixed-effects-models-for-nongaussian-continuous-repeated-measurement-data&quot;&gt;Linear mixed effects models for non‐Gaussian continuous repeated measurement data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has an R package&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://rss.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/rssc.12405&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We consider the analysis of continuous repeated measurement outcomes that are collected longitudinally. A standard framework for analysing data of this kind is a linear Gaussian mixed effects model within which the outcome variable can be decomposed into fixed effects, time invariant and time‐varying random effects, and measurement noise. We develop methodology that, for the first time, allows any combination of these stochastic components to be non‐Gaussian, using multivariate normal variance–mean mixtures. To meet the computational challenges that are presented by large data sets, i.e. in the current context, data sets with many subjects and/or many repeated measurements per subject, we propose a novel implementation of maximum likelihood estimation using a computationally efficient subsampling‐based stochastic gradient algorithm. We obtain standard error estimates by inverting the observed Fisher information matrix and obtain the predictive distributions for the random effects in both filtering (conditioning on past and current data) and smoothing (conditioning on all data) contexts. To implement these procedures, we introduce an R package: ngme. We reanalyse two data sets, from cystic fibrosis and nephrology research, that were previously analysed by using Gaussian linear mixed effects models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;circular-regression-trees-and-forests-with-an-application-to-probabilistic-wind-direction-forecasting&quot;&gt;Circular regression trees and forests with an application to probabilistic wind direction forecasting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has an R package&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://rss.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/rssc.12437&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although circular data occur in a wide range of scientific fields, the methodology for distributional modelling and probabilistic forecasting of circular response variables is quite limited. Most of the existing methods are built on generalized linear and additive models, which are often challenging to optimize and interpret. Specifically, capturing abrupt changes or interactions is not straightforward but often relevant, e.g. for modelling wind directions subject to different wind regimes. Additionally, automatic covariate selection is desirable when many predictor variables are available, as is often the case in weather forecasting. To address these challenges we suggest a general distributional approach using regression trees and random forests to obtain probabilistic forecasts for circular responses. Using trees simplifies model estimation as covariates are used only for partitioning the data and subsequently just a simple von Mises distribution is fitted in the resulting subgroups. Circular regression trees are straightforward to interpret, can capture non‐linear effects and interactions, and automatically select covariates affecting location and/or scale in the von Mises distribution. Circular random forests regularize and smooth the effects from an ensemble of trees. The new methods are applied to probabilistic wind direction forecasting at two Austrian airports, considering other common approaches as a benchmark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-of-diffuse-reflectance-spectroscopy-and-nix-pro-color-sensor-in-combination-for-rapid-prediction-of-soil-organic-carbon&quot;&gt;Use of diffuse reflectance spectroscopy and Nix pro color sensor in combination for rapid prediction of soil organic carbon&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contemporary soil characterization is increasingly dependent upon proximal sensor data whereby high sample throughput and low-cost analysis are realized. Recent research studies have shown that combined sensor platforms generally offer greater predictive model stability and increased accuracy than the use of sensors in isolation. In this study, data from an inexpensive ($350 USD) Nix Pro color sensor, which measures the true color of an object by using red, blue, and green filters, was used with diffuse reflectance spectroscopy (DRS) (590–2490 nm) to predict soil organic carbon (OC) content in highly disturbed, landfill soils of India ex-situ. Generalized additive model (GAM) and partial least squares regression (PLSR) were applied to model DRS and Nix Pro data, respectively, both independently and by combining model predictions using a bilinear regression. Results showed that the combined model outperformed either sensor independently where the 30% external test set achieved a validation R2 of 0.95, residual prediction deviation (RPD) of 4.54, and the ratio of performance to interquartile range of 6.25 relative to laboratory-measured OC data. In contrary, the GAM-OC model using Nix Pro data alone and the PLSR-OC model using DRS data alone exhibited validation R2 values of 0.58 and 0.81, respectively. In sum, the addition of the inexpensive Nix Pro sensor substantively improved the prediction of soil OC relative to the use of DRS in isolation. Future studies should evaluate the effectiveness of such an approach on a wider variety of soil types (e.g., colors), its effectiveness in-situ under variable moisture conditions, and in possible combination with other proximal sensing platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-framework-for-modelling-soil-structure-dynamics-induced-by-biological-activity&quot;&gt;A framework for modelling soil structure dynamics induced by biological activity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil degradation is a worsening global phenomenon driven by socio‐economic pressures, poor land management practices and climate change. A deterioration of soil structure at timescales ranging from seconds to centuries is implicated in most forms of soil degradation including the depletion of nutrients and organic matter, erosion and compaction. New soil–crop models that could account for soil structure dynamics at decadal to centennial timescales would provide insights into the relative importance of the various underlying physical (e.g. tillage, traffic compaction, swell/shrink and freeze/thaw) and biological (e.g. plant root growth, soil microbial and faunal activity) mechanisms, their impacts on soil hydrological processes and plant growth, as well as the relevant timescales of soil degradation and recovery. However, the development of such a model remains a challenge due to the enormous complexity of the interactions in the soil–plant system. In this paper, we focus on the impacts of biological processes on soil structure dynamics, especially the growth of plant roots and the activity of soil fauna and microorganisms. We first define what we mean by soil structure and then review current understanding of how these biological agents impact soil structure. We then develop a new framework for modelling soil structure dynamics, which is designed to be compatible with soil–crop models that operate at the soil profile scale and for long temporal scales (i.e. decades, centuries). We illustrate the modelling concept with a case study on the role of root growth and earthworm bioturbation in restoring the structure of a severely compacted soil.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/10/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on October 19, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/08/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/08/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-08-16T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-08-16T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-15&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #15&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Characterising the biophysical, economic and social impacts of soil carbon sequestration as a greenhouse gas removal technology&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adapting smartphone app used in water testing, for soil nutrient analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From sensor data to Munsell color system: Machine learning algorithm applied to tropical soil color classification via Nix™ Pro sensor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Effects of water, organic matter, and iron forms in mid-IR spectra of soils: Assessments from laboratory to satellite-simulated data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quantifying-uncertainty-for-remote-spectroscopy-of-surface-composition&quot;&gt;Quantifying uncertainty for remote spectroscopy of surface composition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Characterising the biophysical, economic and social impacts of soil carbon sequestration as a greenhouse gas removal technology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To limit warming to well below 2°C, most scenario projections rely on greenhouse gas removal technologies (GGRTs); one such GGRT uses soil carbon sequestration (SCS) in agricultural land. In addition to their role in mitigating climate change, SCS practices play a role in delivering agroecosystem resilience, climate change adaptability and food security. Environmental heterogeneity and differences in agricultural practices challenge the practical implementation of SCS, and our analysis addresses the associated knowledge gap. Previous assessments have focused on global potentials, but there is a need among policymakers to operationalise SCS. Here, we assess a range of practices already proposed to deliver SCS, and distil these into a subset of specific measures. We provide a multidisciplinary summary of the barriers and potential incentives towards practical implementation of these measures. First, we identify specific practices with potential for both a positive impact on SCS at farm level and an uptake rate compatible with global impact. These focus on: (a) optimising crop primary productivity (e.g. nutrient optimisation, pH management, irrigation); (b) reducing soil disturbance and managing soil physical properties (e.g. improved rotations, minimum till); (c) minimising deliberate removal of C or lateral transport via erosion processes (e.g. support measures, bare fallow reduction); (d) addition of C produced outside the system (e.g. organic manure amendments, biochar addition); (e) provision of additional C inputs within the cropping system (e.g. agroforestry, cover cropping). We then consider economic and non‐cost barriers and incentives for land managers implementing these measures, along with the potential externalised impacts of implementation. This offers a framework and reference point for holistic assessment of the impacts of SCS. Finally, we summarise and discuss the ability of extant scientific approaches to quantify the technical potential and externalities of SCS measures, and the barriers and incentives to their implementation in global agricultural systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;adapting-smartphone-app-used-in-water-testing-for-soil-nutrient-analysis&quot;&gt;Adapting smartphone app used in water testing, for soil nutrient analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smartphone technology has now penetrated every aspect of modern life. At such high rates of access and utilization, there is today much potential for the development of smartphones as high-performing tools in a number of industries. Traditionally, smartphones have been used as e.g. point-of-care testing devices in developing countries; now a similar approach can be extended to agriculture. This paper assesses the viability of utilizing smartphones in soil analysis. An Android-based smartphone application, in conjunction with commercially available Quantofix® test strips, was employed to analyze 92 soil samples collected across Indonesia. The soils tested encompassed a wide range of different textures (with 13%, 60% and 25% of samples constituting sandy, loamy and clayey soils, respectively), soil organic matter contents (range: 0.8–19.7%) and nutrient concentrations (range for plant-available N: 0.1–137.4 mg kg−1 and P: 1.2 to 64.2 mg kg−1; on dry soil basis). The app utilizes the smartphone as a portable reflectometer, which relates the color of test strips to the concentration of particular nutrients present in the soil medium. Three mobile devices currently available on the market, representing low, mid- and high-end products, were used to test the application. The results obtained via the smartphone were compared against standard methods for determination of extractable nitrate-N and exchangeable phosphorus (Olsen-P) under laboratory conditions. The smartphone-mediated soil analysis was found to have a high degree of agreement with standard methods for nitrate-N determination (87% of samples with nitrate-N differed by less than 10 mg kg−1 from the standard method for the high-end smartphone) but not for phosphorus determination where chemical interferences to test strip colour development were noted. All three mobile devices were shown to be effective as portable reflectometers. However, color perception was found to differ amongst the devices, resulting in a consistent bias between the high-end phone and the remaining appliances. Whereas, it is essential to consider the inter-smartphone variability in readings and environmental factors such as temperature prior to the smartphone-mediated soil analysis, the smartphone-test strip combination might be employed as acceptable screening tool for soil nutrient concentration assessment to enhance crop outcomes, increasing yield, and preventing over-application of inputs, reducing consequent financial and environmental impact. Further enhancements can test the applicability of smartphone-mediated soil analysis in field conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;from-sensor-data-to-munsell-color-system-machine-learning-algorithm-applied-to-tropical-soil-color-classification-via-nix-pro-sensor&quot;&gt;From sensor data to Munsell color system: Machine learning algorithm applied to tropical soil color classification via Nix™ Pro sensor&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil color has historically drawn humans’ attention, although its definition is somewhat subjective. It is correlated with several soil attributes and it allows for inferences about several soil aspects. New proximal sensors, such as the Nix™ Pro color sensor, can determine soil color values, but its correlation with the widely used Munsell soil color chart (MSCC) has yet to be investigated. This work aimed to train machine learning models using the Random Forest (RF) algorithm to predict each notation of MSCC chips from data extracted by the Nix™ Pro sensor, test the model’s accuracy by evaluating whether it can identify MSCC chips using a brand-new and a dirty MSCC, and compare model predictions with soil color classifications made by the human eye. Additionally, MSCC data obtained via Nix™ was compared to Munsell renotation data to assess the color detection accuracy of the sensor. Prediction models were calibrated by scanning every MSCC chip (437 in total) in triplicate. All validation samples were excluded from model calibration. Accuracy of the predictions of MSCC notation reached overall accuracy and Kappa index values of 0.93 for the brand-new MSCC and of 0.70 for the dirty MSCC. Soil color classification by human eye had little agreement with the predicted MSCC notation, as expected due to the variable conditions affecting soil color conventional determination in the field. Color difference was calculated by the Euclidian distance (ΔE&lt;em&gt;ab) between three color stimuli in the CIELAB color space. The mean ΔE&lt;/em&gt;ab between Nix™-provided data and renotation data was 2.9, demonstrating high color detection accuracy. The Nix™ Pro color sensor allows for assessment of accurate color data. When applied together with machine learning algorithms, Nix™ Pro provides a reliable determination of soil color classification equivalent to MSCC in an easily reproducible, rapid, inexpensive and non-subjective way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;effects-of-water-organic-matter-and-iron-forms-in-mid-ir-spectra-of-soils-assessments-from-laboratory-to-satellite-simulated-data&quot;&gt;Effects of water, organic matter, and iron forms in mid-IR spectra of soils: Assessments from laboratory to satellite-simulated data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The soil mineralogical constitution directly influences its chemical, physical and hydraulic characteristics. Although very important, it is still rarely used for decision-making in agriculture, mainly due to the complexity and cost of standard analyzes. In this sense, the middle infrared spectroscopy (mid-IR, 4000 to 400 cm−1) has great potential to obtain soil mineralogical information quickly and accurately. Nevertheless, some soil constituents can severely influence the spectra and produce misinterpretations. In this research, we aim to detect changes in the mid-IR spectra caused by water, iron forms and organic matter (OM), and to relate soil attributes to laboratory spectra and remote sensing simulated spectral bands. The research area is located in São Paulo State, Brazil, where seventeen soil samples were collected. The reflectance intensities, shapes and absorption features of the mid-IR spectra before and after the removal of OM and iron forms and the addition of water were described. Soil attributes, such as kaolinite, gibbsite, 2:1 minerals among others were correlated with the mid-IR spectra and simulated ASTER spectral bands by Pearson’s analysis, to verify its potential on mineralogical evaluation. The description of mid-IR revealed that the removal of the OM from the soil samples decreased the reflectance intensities between 4000 and 2000 cm−1. Iron forms mainly influence the 3250 – 1200 cm−1 spectral range and mask the spectral features of other minerals as well. The addition of water masked several absorption features and decreased the reflectance intensities from 3700 to 2700 cm−1. High correlation coefficients were obtained between soil attributes and ASTER simulated spectral bands, which allowed the selection of potential spectral regions for future satellite sensors: 2760 – 2500 cm−1 (3600 – 4000 nm), 2150 – 1875 cm−1 (4600 – 5300 nm), and 840 – 740 cm−1 (11900 – 3500 nm).&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/08/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on August 16, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/08/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/08/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-08-06T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-08-06T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-14&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #14&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quantifying uncertainty for remote spectroscopy of surface composition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quantifying-uncertainty-for-remote-spectroscopy-of-surface-composition&quot;&gt;Quantifying uncertainty for remote spectroscopy of surface composition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remote Sensing of Environment
Volume 247, 15 September 2020, 111898&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Remote surface measurements by imaging spectrometers play an important role in planetary and Earth science. To make these measurements, investigators calibrate instrument data to absolute units, invert physical models to estimate atmospheric effects, and then determine surface properties from the spectral reflectance. This study quantifies the uncertainty in this process. Global missions demand predictive uncertainty models that can estimate future errors for varied environments and observing conditions. Here we validate uncertainty predictions with remote surface composition retrievals and in situ measurements in a field analogue of Earth and planetary exploration. We consider rover transects at Cuprite, Nevada, and remote observations by NASA’s Next-Generation Airborne Visible Infrared Imaging Spectrometer (AVIRIS-NG). We show that accounting for input uncertainties can benefit mineral detection methods such as constrained spectrum fitting. This suggests that operational uncertainty estimates could improve future NASA missions like the Earth Mineral dust source InvesTigation (EMIT) and the Lunar Trailblazer mission, as well as NASA’s Decadal Surface Biology and Geology (SBG) Investigation.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/08/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on August 06, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/07/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/07/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-07-30T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-07-30T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-13&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #13&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mapping soil profile depth, bulk density and carbon stock in Scotland using remote sensing and spatial covariates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new approach for studying vertical infiltration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increasing the organic carbon stocks in mineral soils sequesters large amounts of phosphorus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Global human influence maps reveal clear opportunities in conserving Earth’s remaining intact terrestrial ecosystems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Distinct controls over the temporal dynamics of soil carbon fractions after land use change&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil as an extended composite phenotype of the microbial metagenome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mapping-soil-profile-depth-bulk-density-and-carbon-stock-in-scotland-using-remote-sensing-and-spatial-covariates&quot;&gt;Mapping soil profile depth, bulk density and carbon stock in Scotland using remote sensing and spatial covariates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt Aitkenhead Malcolm Coull
EJSS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-new-approach-for-studying-vertical-infiltration&quot;&gt;A new approach for studying vertical infiltration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alexander Poulovassilis 0000-0003-1117-1158 and Ioannis Argyrokastritis 0000-0003-0519-2219
pp. 509-518&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The absorption of rain and irrigation water by soils, called the infiltration process, is of vital importance for plant growth. This process is controlled by the permeability properties of soils, and this paper presents new methods for determining these properties and new equations describing the infiltration process more precisely than in previous works. These contributions allow a better understanding of the infiltration process and more precise calculation of water infiltration rates under conditions imposed by both nature and irrigation practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;increasing-the-organic-carbon-stocks-in-mineral-soils-sequesters-large-amounts-of-phosphorus&quot;&gt;Increasing the organic carbon stocks in mineral soils sequesters large amounts of phosphorus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marie Spohn
Global CHange Biology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;global-human-influence-maps-reveal-clear-opportunities-in-conserving-earths-remaining-intact-terrestrial-ecosystems&quot;&gt;Global human influence maps reveal clear opportunities in conserving Earth’s remaining intact terrestrial ecosystems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason Riggio Jonathan E. M. Baillie Steven Brumby Erle Ellis Christina M. Kennedy James R. Oakleaf Alex Tait Therese Tepe David M. Theobald Oscar Venter James E. M. Watson Andrew P. Jacobson
Pages: 4344-4356 First Published: 05 June 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading up to the Convention on Biological Diversity Conference of the Parties 15, there is momentum around setting bold conservation targets. Yet it remains unclear how much of Earth’s land area remains without significant human influence. We compare four recent global maps of human influences (Anthromes, Global Human Modification, Human Footprint, and Low Impact Areas) and find that about half of Earth’s terrestrial surface has relatively low human influence. These findings offer opportunities for proactive conservation actions to retain the last intact ecosystems on the planet, although the relative abundance of ecosystem areas with low human influence varies widely by biome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;distinct-controls-over-the-temporal-dynamics-of-soil-carbon-fractions-after-land-use-change&quot;&gt;Distinct controls over the temporal dynamics of soil carbon fractions after land use change&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zhongkui Luo Raphael A. Viscarra Rossel Zhou Shi
Pages: 4614-4625 First Published: 13 May 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our understanding on the controls over soil organic carbon (SOC) composition, particularly its temporal dynamics, is quite limited, inhibiting reliable prediction of SOC dynamics. By assessing a comprehensive dataset including temporal measurements of three SOC fractions (i.e. particulate, mineral-associated and charred organic carbon) after land use change, we found that environmental factors present distinct effects on the dynamics of the three fractions, and these effects were time-dependent. To reduce uncertainties in SOC predictions in response to global change and land management, the distinct controls over the dynamics of SOC fractions should be properly considered in carbon models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-as-an-extended-composite-phenotype-of-the-microbial-metagenome&quot;&gt;Soil as an extended composite phenotype of the microbial metagenome&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew L. Neal, Aur?lie Bacq-Labreuil, Xiaoxian Zhang, Ian M. Clark, Kevin Coleman, Sacha J. Mooney, Karl Ritz &amp;amp; John W. Crawford&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/07/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on July 30, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/06/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/06/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-06-19T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-06-12T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-12&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #12&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil magnetic susceptibility and its relationship with naturally occurring processes and soil attributes in pedosphere, in a tropical environment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The challenge for the soil science community to contribute to the implementation of the UN Sustainable Development Goals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evaluating a low-cost portable NIR spectrometer for the prediction of soil organic and total carbon using different calibration models&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Dynamics of Soil Microbial Communities on Different Timescales: A Review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Debates: Does Information Theory Provide a New Paradigm for Earth Science? Sharper Predictions Using Occam’s Digital Razor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can Continental Models Convey Useful Seasonal Hydrologic Information at the Catchment Scale?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does Information Theory Provide a New Paradigm for Earth Science? Hypothesis Testing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Climate Adaptation as a Control Problem: Review and Perspectives on Dynamic Water Resources Planning Under Uncertainty&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Debates-Does Information Theory Provide a New Paradigm for Earth Science? Causality, Interaction, and Feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-magnetic-susceptibility-and-its-relationship-with-naturally-occurring-processes-and-soil-attributes-in-pedosphere-in-a-tropical-environment&quot;&gt;Soil magnetic susceptibility and its relationship with naturally occurring processes and soil attributes in pedosphere, in a tropical environment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: de Mello, Danilo Cesar; Dematte, Jose A. M.; Silvero, Nelida E. Q.; et al.
GEODERMA  Volume:  372   Pages:  14364-14364   Published:  AUG 1 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil magnetic susceptibility (kappa) has potential to be used as a pedoenvironmental indicator from which mineralogy, pedogeochemical, pedogeomorphological and pedogenic processes can be inferred. It can be used in pedosphere studies, as an auxiliary information for appropriate and sustainable soil use and management. This research aimed to analyze how pedogenesis and geochemical processes affect the kappa and some of its attributes, as well as its potential use in discriminating soil great groups, following the digital soil mapping approach. The study area is located in Sao Paulo State - Brazil. Soil samples were collected for physical-chemical analysis from 79 locations (0-20 cm depth). At these sites, magnetic susceptibility was measured with a portable field instrument and analyzed in terms of geology, relief and soil class. The results showed that geology strongly affects kappa, mainly in diabase derived soils, followed by metamorphosed siltstone and siltstone. In fluvial sediments, the kappa exhibits different behaviors due to different sediments deposited by the Capivari River. In less evolved soils, such as Cambisols, lithology is a more important contributor to kappa than pedogenesis. In more evolved soils, pedogenesis increases kappa, whereas argilluviation/ferralitization reduces it. The kappa values did not decrease significantly or even increase downslope, due to the presence of diabase on the lower parts. Differences in kappa where observed between diabase bedrock located in different parts of the study area, indicating more of an influence by geomorphic processes rather than lithology. With respect to soil attributes, positive correlations between kappa and base saturation, cation exchange capacity, organic matter, and iron and clay content were found, whereas a negative correlation was found between kappa and sand content. The kappa correlates with changes in lithology and soil class demonstrating its application as a potential tool for the discrimination of soil great groups and digital soil mapping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-challenge-for-the-soil-science-community-to-contribute-to-the-implementation-of-the-un-sustainable-development-goals&quot;&gt;The challenge for the soil science community to contribute to the implementation of the UN Sustainable Development Goals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Bouma, Johan; Montanarella, Luca; Evanylo, Gregory
SOIL USE AND MANAGEMENT  Volume:  35   Issue:  4   Pages:  538-546   Published:  DEC 2019
Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract
Seventeen Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) were adopted by 193 Governments at the General Assembly of the United Nations in 2015 for achievement by 2030. These SDGs present a roadmap to a sustainable future and a challenge to the science community. To guide activities and check progress, targets and indicators have been and are still being defined. The soil science community has published documents that describe the primary importance of soil for SDGs addressing hunger, water quality, climate mitigation and biodiversity preservation, and secondary relevance of soil for addressing several other SDGs. Soil scientists only marginally participated in the SDG discussions and are currently only peripherally engaged in discussions on targets or indicators. Agreement on several soil-related indicators has still not been achieved. Involvement of soil scientists in SDG–based studies is desirable for both developing solutions and increasing the visibility of the soil profession. Inputs into policy decisions should be improved as SDG committee members are appointed by Governments. Possible contributions of soil science in defining indicators for the SDGs are explored in this paper. We advocate the pragmatic use of soil-water-atmosphere-plant simulation models and available soil surveys and soil databases where “representative” soil profiles for mapping units (genetically defined genoforms) are functionally expressed in terms of several phenoforms reflecting effects of different types of soil use and management that strongly affect functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evaluating-a-low-cost-portable-nir-spectrometer-for-the-prediction-of-soil-organic-and-total-carbon-using-different-calibration-models&quot;&gt;Evaluating a low-cost portable NIR spectrometer for the prediction of soil organic and total carbon using different calibration models&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Sharififar, Amin; Singh, Kanika; Jones, Edward; et al.
SOIL USE AND MANAGEMENT  Volume:  35   Issue:  4   Pages:  607-616   Published:  DEC 2019
Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
This study aims to assess the performance of a low-cost, micro-electromechanical system-based, near infrared spectrometer for soil organic carbon (OC) and total carbon (TC) estimation. TC was measured on 151 soil profiles up to the depth of 1 m in NSW, Australia, and from which a subset of 24 soil profiles were measured for OC. Two commercial spectrometers including the AgriSpec(TM) (ASD) and NeoSpectra(TM) (Neospectra) with spectral wavelength ranges of 350-2,500 and 1,300-2,500 nm, respectively, were used to scan the soil samples, according to the standard contact probe protocol. Savitzky-Golay smoothing filter and standard normal variate (SNV) transformation were performed on the spectral data for noise reduction and baseline correction. Three calibration models, including Cubist tree model, partial least squares regression (PLSR) and support vector machine (SVM), were assessed for the prediction of soil OC and TC using spectral data. A 10-fold cross-validation analysis was performed for evaluation of the models and devices accuracies. Results showed that Cubist model predicts OC and TC more accurately than PLSR and SVM. For OC prediction, Cubist showed R-2 = 0.89 (RMSE = 0.12%) and R-2 = 0.78 (RMSE = 0.16%) using ASD and NeoSpectra, respectively. For TC prediction, Cubist produced R-2 = 0.75 (RMSE = 0.45%) and R-2 = 0.70 (RMSE = 0.50%) using ASD and NeoSpectra, respectively. ASD performed better than NeoSpectra. However, the low-cost NeoSpectra predictions were comparable to the ASD. These finding can be helpful for more efficient future spectroscopic prediction of soil OC and TC with less costly devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-dynamics-of-soil-microbial-communities-on-different-timescales-a-review&quot;&gt;The Dynamics of Soil Microbial Communities on Different Timescales: A Review&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Chernov, T. I.; Zhelezova, A. D.
EURASIAN SOIL SCIENCE  Volume:  53   Issue:  5   Pages:  643-652   Published:  MAY 2020
Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Soil microbial communities are subjected to significant changes over time. The most rapid changes caused by temperature and soil moisture alternations or the by the inflow of fresh organic matter occur during the several hours or days. They are mostly related to the soil microbial activity. Seasonal dynamics are caused by annual variations in temperature and precipitation that affect the microbial community directly or indirectly through the regulation of plant life. The microbial biomass and the taxonomic composition of soil microbial communities vary significantly throughout the year, which should be taken into account when sampling for a comparative analysis of different soils. The long-term dynamics of microbial communities during primary or secondary successions lead to an increase in the total microbial biomass and the fungi/bacteria ratio, as well as to changes in the taxonomic composition of microbial communities. The main factors of the long-term dynamics are the accumulation of soil organic matter, plant successions, and changes in pH. The diversity of microbial communities during long-term dynamics can vary in different ways and does not follow a single trend. The longest dynamics of soil microbial communities are associated with changes in bioclimatic conditions. Information about soil microbial communities of the past can be obtained by studying buried and permafrost soils. The study of future changes in soil microbial communities is possible in experiments with artificial changes in climatic parameters. Plants are a significant factor in the dynamics of soil microbial communities on all timescales; in short-term periods, the major role is played by the activity of plants; in the long-term trends, the changes in the vegetation abundance and diversity are the most important factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;debates-does-information-theory-provide-a-new-paradigm-for-earth-science-sharper-predictions-using-occams-digital-razor&quot;&gt;Debates: Does Information Theory Provide a New Paradigm for Earth Science? Sharper Predictions Using Occam’s Digital Razor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Weijs, Steven. V.; Ruddell, Benjamin. L.
WATER RESOURCES RESEARCH  Volume:  56   Issue:  2   Pages:  26471-26471   Published:  FEB 2020
Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract
Occam’s Razor is a bedrock principle of science philosophy, stating that the simplest hypothesis (or model) is preferred, at any given level of model predictive performance. A modern restatement often attributed to Einstein explains, “Everything should be made as simple as possible, but not simpler.” Using principles from (algorithmic) information theory, both model descriptive performance and model complexity can be quantified in bits. This quantification yields a Pareto-style trade-off between model complexity (length of the model program in bits) and model performance (information loss in bits, or the missing information, needed to describe the original observations). Model complexity and performance can be collapsed to one single measure of lossless model size, which, when minimized, leads to optimal model complexity versus loss trade-off for generalization and prediction. Our view puts both simple data-driven and complex physical-process-based models on a continuum, in the sense that both describe patterns in observed data in compressed form, with different degrees of generality, model complexity, and descriptive performance. Information theory-based assessment of compression performance with fair and meaningful accounting for model complexity will enable us to best compare and combine the strengths of physics knowledge and data-driven modeling for a given problem, given the availability of data. “Suppose we draw a set of points on paper in a totally random manner” …“I am saying it is possible to find a geometric line whose notation is constant and uniform, following a certain law, that will pass through all points, and in the sameorder they were drawn.” … “But if that law is strongly composed,the thing that conforms to it should be seen as irregular”Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz, 1686: Discours de metaphysique V, VI (from French)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;can-continental-models-convey-useful-seasonal-hydrologic-information-at-the-catchment-scale&quot;&gt;Can Continental Models Convey Useful Seasonal Hydrologic Information at the Catchment Scale?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Crochemore, L.; Ramos, M. -H.; Pechlivanidis, I. G.
WATER RESOURCES RESEARCH  Volume:  56   Issue:  2   Pages:  25700-25700   Published:  FEB 2020
Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract
The development and availability of climate forecasting systems have allowed the implementation of seasonal hydroclimatic services at the continental scale. User guidance and quality of the forecast information are key components to ensure user engagement and service uptake, yet forecast quality depends on the hydrologic model setup. Here, we address how seasonal forecasts from continental services can be used to address user needs at the catchment scale. We compare a continentally calibrated process-based model (E-HYPE) and a catchment-specific parsimonious model (GR6J) to forecast streamflow in a set of French catchments. Results show that despite expected high performance from the catchment setup against observed streamflow, the continental setup can, in some catchments, match or even outperform the catchment-specific setup for 3-month aggregations and threshold exceedance. Forecast systems can become comparable when looking at statistics relative to model climatology, such as anomalies, and adequate initial conditions are the main source of skill in both systems. We highlight the need for consistency in data used in modeling chains and in tailoring service outputs for use at the catchment scale. Finally, we show that the spread in internal model states varies largely between the two systems, reflecting the differences in their setups and calibration strategies, and highlighting that caution is needed before extracting hydrologic variables other than streamflow. We overall argue that continental hydroclimatic services show potential on addressing needs at the catchment scale, yet guidance is needed to extract, tailor and use the information provided.
Plain Language Summary Climatic variations can have a significant impact on a number of water-related sectors. Managing such variations through accurate predictions is thus crucial. Continental hydroclimate services have recently received attention to address various user needs. However, predictions for months ahead can be limited at catchment scale, highlighting the need for data tailoring. Here, we compare the predictions from two hydrologic setups at catchment scale. One setup (E-HYPE) is used in a European hydroclimate service, whereas the other (GR6J) is used for local water-related risk assessment. Our results show that predictions from the continental setup can be as accurate as the predictions from the local model when predicting streamflow averaged over several months and when looking at changes in streamflow rather than absolute values. A good estimation of the hydrologic states, such as soil moisture or lake levels, prior to the prediction is the most important factor in obtaining accurate streamflow predictions in both setups. However, the differences in the setups can result in different uncertainties for variables other than streamflow, like in the case of soil water content. We argue that useful information is provided by continental services, yet guidance for information extraction can result into tailored information for regional needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;does-information-theory-provide-a-new-paradigm-for-earth-science-hypothesis-testing&quot;&gt;Does Information Theory Provide a New Paradigm for Earth Science? Hypothesis Testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Nearing, Grey S.; Ruddell, Benjamin L.; Bennett, Andrew R.; et al.
WATER RESOURCES RESEARCH  Volume:  56   Issue:  2   Pages:  24918-24918   Published:  FEB 2020
Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract
Model evaluation and hypothesis testing are fundamental to any field of science. We propose here that by changing slightly the way we think and communicate about inference-from being fundamentally a problem of uncertainty quantification to being a problem of information quantification-allows us to avoid certain problems related to testing models as hypotheses. We propose that scientists are typically interested in assessing the information provided by models, not the truth value or likelihood of a model. Information theory allows us to formalize this perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;climate-adaptation-as-a-control-problem-review-and-perspectives-on-dynamic-water-resources-planning-under-uncertainty&quot;&gt;Climate Adaptation as a Control Problem: Review and Perspectives on Dynamic Water Resources Planning Under Uncertainty&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Herman, Jonathan D.; Quinn, Julianne D.; Steinschneider, Scott; et al.
WATER RESOURCES RESEARCH  Volume:  56   Issue:  2   Pages:  24389-24389   Published:  FEB 2020
Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract
Climate change introduces substantial uncertainty to water resources planning and raises the key question: when, or under what conditions, should adaptation occur? A number of recent studies aim to identify policies mapping future observations to actions-in other words, framing climate adaptation as an optimal control problem. This paper uses the control paradigm to review and classify recent dynamic planning studies according to their approaches to uncertainty characterization, policy structure, and solution methods. We propose a set of research gaps and opportunities in this area centered on the challenge of characterizing uncertainty, which prevents the unambiguous application of control methods to this problem. These include exogenous uncertainty in forcing, model structure, and parameters propagated through a chain of climate and hydrologic models; endogenous uncertainty in human-environmental system dynamics across multiple scales; and sampling uncertainty due to the finite length of historical observations and future projections. Recognizing these challenges, several opportunities exist to improve the use of control methods for climate adaptation, namely, how problem context and understanding of climate processes might assist with uncertainty quantification and experimental design, out-of-sample validation and robustness of optimized adaptation policies, and monitoring and data assimilation, including trend detection, Bayesian inference, and indicator variable selection. We conclude with a summary of recommendations for dynamic water resources planning under climate change through the lens of optimal control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;debates-does-information-theory-provide-a-new-paradigm-for-earth-science-causality-interaction-and-feedback&quot;&gt;Debates-Does Information Theory Provide a New Paradigm for Earth Science? Causality, Interaction, and Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Goodwell, Allison E.; Jiang, Peishi; Ruddell, Benjamin L.; et al.
WATER RESOURCES RESEARCH  Volume:  56   Issue:  2   Pages:  24940-24940   Published:  FEB 2020
Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract
The concept of causal interactions between components is an integral part of hydrology and Earth system sciences. Modelers, decision makers, scientists, and other water resources stakeholders all utilize some notion of cause-and-effect to understand processes, make decisions, and infer how systems react to change. However, there are different perspectives on the meaning of causality in complex systems and, further, different frameworks and methodologies with which to detect causal interactions. We propose here that information theory (IT) provides a compelling framework for the detection of causality and discuss approaches for several levels of analyses that capture interactions that range from pairwise to multivariate in nature. We illustrate these types of analyses with an example based on weather station time series variables, in which variables may interact pairwise or jointly and on short to long time scales. In general, many unsolved or even unanticipated questions in the hydrologic sciences could benefit from this perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/06/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on June 12, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/06/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/06/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-06-08T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-06-08T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-11&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #11&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bibliometric analysis of research on soil health from 1999 to 2018&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Climate drives global soil carbon sequestration and crop yield changes under conservation agriculture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marching in step: The importance of matching model complexity to data availability in terrestrial biosphere models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bibliometric-analysis-of-research-on-soil-health-from-1999-to-2018&quot;&gt;Bibliometric analysis of research on soil health from 1999 to 2018&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Liu, Yanan; Wu, Kening; Zhao, Rui&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JOURNAL OF SOILS AND SEDIMENTS Volume:  20 Issue:  3 Pages:  1513-1525 Published:  MAR 2020 Context Sensitive Links Close Abstract Purpose Soil health has been a major focus of research by international scholars because it is an important factor that supports human survival and development. However, few scholars have performed bibliometric analyses of research on soil health. This study investigated the current research status and development characteristics of soil health. Materials and methods We performed a bibliometric analysis of documents on soil health from 1999 to 2018 in the Web of Science Core Collection. The bibliometric analysis tools, CiteSpace and HistCite software, were applied. Results and discussion A total of 1629 documents on soil health in the Web of Science Core Collection were identified. From the research status of soil health, the number of publications will continue to increase. Most of the research institutions examining soil health are located in the USA, and there is little cooperation and communication among countries, neither do research institutions in this field. Each country has its own research labs while lab cooperation within individual countries is relatively close. Most documents on the research of soil health have been published in the journal Applied Soil Ecology. In addition, research directions are expanding from the basic study of soil production, soil health indicators, and soil pollution to the comprehensive study of soil ecosystem. Conclusions Bibliometric analysis tools, CiteSpace and HistCite software, provide a comprehensive approach for making predictions regarding trends in the field. This method was used in this study to identify the hotspots, frontiers, and future development of soil health to provide guidance for future research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;climate-drives-global-soil-carbon-sequestration-and-crop-yield-changes-under-conservation-agriculture&quot;&gt;Climate drives global soil carbon sequestration and crop yield changes under conservation agriculture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Sun, Wenjuan; Canadell, Josep G.; Yu, Lijun; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY Volume:  26 Issue:  6 Pages:  3325-3335 Published:  JUN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Close Abstract Conservation agriculture has been shown to have multiple benefits for soils, crop yield and the environment, and consequently, no-till, the central practice of conservation agriculture, has rapidly expanded. However, studies show that the potential for carbon (C) sequestration in no-till farming sometimes is not realized, let alone the ability to maintain or improve crop yield. Here we present a global analysis of no-till-induced changes of soil C and crop yield based on 260 and 1,970 paired studies; respectively. We show that, relative to local conventional tillage, arid regions can benefit the most from conservation agriculture by achieving a win-win outcome of enhanced C sequestration and increased crop yield. However, more humid regions are more likely to increase SOC only, while some colder regions have yield losses and soil C loss as likely as soil C gains. In addition to site-specific characteristics and management, a careful assessment of the regional climate is needed to determine the potential benefits of adopting conservation agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;marching-in-step-the-importance-of-matching-model-complexity-to-data-availability-in-terrestrial-biosphere-models&quot;&gt;Marching in step: The importance of matching model complexity to data availability in terrestrial biosphere models&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Feng, Xue GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY Volume:  26 Issue:  6 Pages:  3190-3192 Published:  JUN 2020 Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract This is a Commentary on Paschalis et al. Building models to predict ecosystem responses to future rainfall changes requires closely matching model complexity to data availability. A new study by Paschalis et al. (Global Change Biology, 2020) examines opportunities to improve both data availability and model structure in 10 state-of-the-art terrestrial biosphere models.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/06/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on June 08, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/06/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/06/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-06-02T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-06-02T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-10&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data fusion of vis-NIR and PXRF spectra to predict soil physical and chemical properties&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Boundary line models for soil nutrient concentrations and wheat yield in national-scale datasets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Global patterns of soil heterotrophic respiration - A meta-analysis of available dataset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-fusion-of-vis-nir-and-pxrf-spectra-to-predict-soil-physical-and-chemical-properties&quot;&gt;Data fusion of vis-NIR and PXRF spectra to predict soil physical and chemical properties&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Zhang, Yakun; Hartemink, Alfred E.
EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF SOIL SCIENCE  Volume: 71   Issue: 3   Pages: 316-333   Published: MAY 2020
Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
We tested one front-end data fusion method to combine visible near-infrared (vis-NIR) and portable X-ray fluorescence (PXRF) spectra for predicting different soil properties and investigated the contribution of different sensor data. A total of 197 soil samples were collected from 25 Alfisols and Mollisols in south-central Wisconsin, USA. Soils were analysed in the laboratory for clay, sand, silt content, total carbon (TC), total nitrogen (TN) and pH. Air-dried soil samples were scanned with vis-NIR and PXRF spectrometers. A principal component analysis (PCA) was applied to each of the vis-NIR and PXRF spectra to extract the first 10 principal components (PCs), which were used in the Cubist model. Five types of input data were compared for constructing the models using a front-end data fusion approach, including: (a) 10 PCs from vis-NIR spectra, (b) 10 PCs from spectra of PXRF beam 1 (XRF40), (c) 10 PCs from spectra of PXRF beam 2 (XRF10), (d) concatenating 20 PCs from two PXRF spectra (XRF40 + 10), and (e) concatenating 30 PCs from two PXRF spectra and vis-NIR spectra (XRF40 + 10 + NIR). In addition, the performances of the preprocessing methods (four smoothing methods with or without background removal) of PXRF spectra were compared. Multiple linear regression was also used to predict soil properties directly from 11 PXRF-estimated elements. Our results suggest that smoothing should be applied to the PXRF spectra prior to developing predictive models. PXRF spectra and elemental data can predict soil texture with validation R-2 &amp;gt; 0.85, better than using solely vis-NIR spectra, and combining vis-NIR and PXRF spectra improved the prediction. Combining PXRF and vis-NIR can also predict TC and TN moderately well. Soil pH cannot be predicted from vis-NIR or PXRF spectra in this dataset due to its weak correlations with other soil properties and elements. It is concluded that PXRF spectra can be solely used to estimate soil texture, whereas combining vis-NIR and PXRF spectra via PCA should be used to estimate TC and TN. Highlights
The use of front-end data fusion method to combine vis-NIR and PXRF spectra for predicting soil properties. Different preprocessing algorithms were compared systematically for PXRF spectra. Spectral smoothing should be applied to the PXRF spectra prior to developing predictive models. PXRF spectra can be used solely to estimate soil texture, whereas combining vis-NIR and PXRF spectra via PCA should be used to estimate TC and TN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;boundary-line-models-for-soil-nutrient-concentrations-and-wheat-yield-in-national-scale-datasets&quot;&gt;Boundary line models for soil nutrient concentrations and wheat yield in national-scale datasets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Lark, Richard M.; Gillingham, Vincent; Langton, David; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF SOIL SCIENCE  Volume: 71   Issue: 3   Pages: 334-351   Published: MAY 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In boundary line analysis a biological response (e.g., crop yield) is assumed to be a function of a variable (e.g., soil nutrient concentration), which limits the response in only some subset of observations because other limiting factors also apply. The response function is therefore expressed by an upper boundary of the plot of the response against the variable. This model has been used in various branches of soil science. In this paper we apply it to the analysis of some large datasets, originating from commercial farms in England and Wales, on the recorded yield of wheat and measured concentrations of soil nutrients in within-field soil management zones. We considered boundary line models for the effects of potassium (K), phosphorus (P) and magnesium (Mg) on yield, comparing the model with a simple bivariate normal distribution or a bivariate normal censored at a constant maximum yield. We were able to show, using likelihood-based methods, that the boundary line model was preferable in most cases. The boundary line model suggested that the standard RB209 soil nutrient index values (Agriculture and Horticulture Development Board, nutrient management guide (RB209), 2017) are robust and apply at the within-field scale. However, there was evidence that wheat yield could respond to additional Mg at concentrations above index 0, contrary to RB209 guidelines. Furthermore, there was evidence that the boundary line model for yield and P differs between soils at different pH and depth intervals, suggesting that shallow soils with larger pH require a larger target P index than others. Highlights
Boundary line analysis is one way to examine how soil variables influence crop yield in large datasets. We showed that boundary line models could be applied to large datasets on soil nutrients and crop yield. The resulting models are consistent with current practice for P and K, but not for Mg. Models suggest that more refined recommendations for P requirement could be based on soil pH and depth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;global-patterns-of-soil-heterotrophic-respiration---a-meta-analysis-of-available-dataset&quot;&gt;Global patterns of soil heterotrophic respiration - A meta-analysis of available dataset&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Tang, Xiaolu; Du, Jie; Shi, Yuehong; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CATENA  Volume: 191   Pages: 4574-4574   Published: AUG 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil heterotrophic respiration (RH) represents the carbon losses from the decomposition of litter detritus and soil organic matter by microorganisms. Despite conflicting findings on the dominant climatic, soil and vegetation controls on RH from local studies, little is known on the global patterns of RH and the potential drivers behind these patterns. Based on the updated Global Soil Respiration Database, we conducted a meta-analysis to evaluate the direct and indirect effects of climatic, soil and vegetation controls on RH across the globe using structure equation model (SEM). Our results showed that the global weighted mean RH was 457 +/- 139 g C m(-2) a(-1) (mean +/- standard deviation), but RH differed significantly among ecosystem types and positively correlated with gross primary production, highlighting the importance of the vegetation control on RH. Climate was the most important environmental control on RH indicated by SEM. Soil organic carbon (SOC) content had a negative influence on RH at the global scale, challenging the current understanding that SOC leads to a positive effect on RH at site or ecosystem scale, further indicating that SOC quantity may dominate RH at local scales, while SOC quality and availability may dominate RH at regional or global scales. Great differences were found not only between observed and dymanic global vegetation model (DGVM)-based RH, but also among different DGVMs, highlighting a better parameterizing of DGVMs, particularly the model output not validated by field observations, to better understand RH and belowground carbon dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/06/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on June 02, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/06/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/06/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-06-01T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-06-01T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-9&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sub-pixel mapping with point constraints&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An integrated methodology using open soil spectral libraries and Earth Observation data for soil organic carbon estimations in support of soil-related SDGs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Earth observation-based ecosystem services indicators for national and subnational reporting of the sustainable development goals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Validation practices for satellite soil moisture retrievals: What are (the) errors?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agricultural drought mitigating indices derived from the changes in drought characteristics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An optimal design for hierarchical generalized group testing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“sen2r”: An R toolbox for automatically downloading and preprocessing Sentinel-2 satellite data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;atakrig: An R package for multivariate area-to-area and area-to-point kriging predictions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Content search within large environmental datasets using a convolution neural network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sub-pixel-mapping-with-point-constraints&quot;&gt;Sub-pixel mapping with point constraints&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Wang, Qunming; Zhang, Chengyuan; Atkinson, Peter M.
REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT  Volume: 244   Pages: 11817-11817   Published: JUL 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Remote sensing images contain abundant land cover information. Due to the complex nature of land cover, however, mixed pixels exist widely in remote sensing images. Sub-pixel mapping (SPM) is a technique for predicting the spatial distribution of land cover classes within mixed pixels. As an ill-posed inverse problem, the uncertainty of prediction cannot be eliminated and hinders the production of accurate sub-pixel maps. In contrast to conventional methods that use continuous geospatial information (e.g., images) to enhance SPM, in this paper, a SPM method with point constraints into SPM is proposed. The method of fusing point constraints is implemented based on the pixel swapping algorithm (PSA) and utilizes the auxiliary point information to reduce the uncertainty in the SPM process and increase map accuracy. The point data are incorporated into both the initialization and optimization processes of PSA. Experiments were performed on three images to validate the proposed method. The influences of the performances were also investigated under different numbers of point data, different spatial characters of land cover and different zoom factors. The results show that by using the point data, the proposed SPM method can separate more small-sized targets from aggregated artifacts and the accuracies are increased obviously. The proposed method is also more accurate than the advanced radial basis function interpolation-based method. The advantage of using point data is more evident when the point data size and scale factor are large and the spatial autocorrelation of the land cover is small. As the amount of point data increases, however, the increase in accuracy becomes less noticeable. Furthermore, the SPM accuracy can still be increased even if the point data and coarse proportions contain errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-integrated-methodology-using-open-soil-spectral-libraries-and-earth-observation-data-for-soil-organic-carbon-estimations-in-support-of-soil-related-sdgs&quot;&gt;An integrated methodology using open soil spectral libraries and Earth Observation data for soil organic carbon estimations in support of soil-related SDGs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Tziolas, Nikolaos; Tsakiridis, Nikolaos; Ogen, Yaron; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT  Volume: 244   Pages: 11793-11793   Published: JUL 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
There is a growing realization amongst policy-makers that reliable and accurate soil monitoring information is required at scales ranging from regional to global to support ecosystem functions and services in a sustainable manner under the amplifying climate change enabling countries in target setting of the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). In this line, the need of access to and integration of existing regional in situ Earth Observation (EO) data and different sources such as contemporary and forthcoming satellite imagery is highlighted. The current study puts major emphasis on leveraging existing open soil spectral libraries and EO systems and bridging them with memory-based learning algorithms that create more cost-efficient and targeted large scale mapping of soil properties. Relying mostly on contemporary capacities and open resources it can be readily applied to countries with differing capacities and levels of development. To test our methodology, the GEOCRADLE SSL developed in the Balkans, Middle East, and North Africa region and a hyperspectral airborne image were utilized to provide Soil Organic Carbon (SOC) maps of cropland fields over an agricultural region near the city of Netanya, Israel. Furthermore, simulated data of forthcoming space-borne satellite (EnMAP) and current super-spectral mission (Sentinel 2) were explored. The SOC content of the collected in situ soil samples was predicted using a novel local regression approach that combines spatial proximity and spectral similarities. These predictions were subsequently used to develop models using the airborne and simulated satellite spectra, achieving a fair prediction accuracy of R-2 &amp;gt; 0.8 and RPIQ &amp;gt; 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;earth-observation-based-ecosystem-services-indicators-for-national-and-subnational-reporting-of-the-sustainable-development-goals&quot;&gt;Earth observation-based ecosystem services indicators for national and subnational reporting of the sustainable development goals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Cochran, Ferdouz; Daniel, Jessica; Jackson, Laura; et al.
REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT  Volume: 244   Pages: 11796-11796   Published: JUL 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Decision-making that impacts sustainability occurs at national and subnational levels, highlighting the need for multi-scale Earth observations (EO) and geospatial data for assessing the United Nations’ Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). EnviroAtlas, developed by the United States Environmental Protection Agency and partners, provides a collection of web-based, interactive maps of environmental and socio-economic data relevant to the SDGs. EnviroAtlas maps ecosystem services indicators at national, regional, and local extents that can contribute to targets set forth in numerous goals, such as SDG 6 for clean water, SDG 11 for sustainable cities and communities, and SDG 15 for life on land. Examples of EnviroAtlas indicators that provide a way to view spatial inequalities, help fill gaps in environmental indicators, and integrate socio-economic and environmental data for the SDGs are explored herein. Remotely sensed EO data are essential for producing these indicators and informing planning and decision-making for the SDGs at subnational scales. The National Land Cover Dataset is the basis for many EnviroAtlas maps at the national extent, while National Agriculture Imagery Program and Light Detection and Ranging (LiDAR) data are used to classify Meter-scale Urban Land Cover in select US metro areas. These 30 m and 1 m land cover products are combined with demographic and other geospatial data (remotely sensed and otherwise) to produce integrated indicators that can aid in target setting of the SDGs. Though EnviroAtlas was created for the conterminous US, the methods for indicator creation are transferable, and the open-source code for the EnviroAtlas resource may serve as an example for other nations. Achieving the SDGs means assessing targets and decision-making outcomes at local, regional, and national levels using consistent and accurate data. Geospatial resources like EnviroAtlas that provide open access to indicators based on EO data and allow for assessment at multiple extents and resolutions are critical to broadly addressing national to subnational SDG goals and targets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;validation-practices-for-satellite-soil-moisture-retrievals-what-are-the-errors&quot;&gt;Validation practices for satellite soil moisture retrievals: What are (the) errors?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Gruber, A.; De Lannoy, G.; Albergel, C.; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT  Volume: 244   Pages: 11806-11806   Published: JUL 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract
This paper presents a community effort to develop good practice guidelines for the validation of global coarse-scale satellite soil moisture products. We provide theoretical background, a review of state-of-the-art methodologies for estimating errors in soil moisture data sets, practical recommendations on data pre-processing and presentation of statistical results, and a recommended validation protocol that is supplemented with an example validation exercise focused on microwave-based surface soil moisture products. We conclude by identifying research gaps that should be addressed in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;agricultural-drought-mitigating-indices-derived-from-the-changes-in-drought-characteristics&quot;&gt;Agricultural drought mitigating indices derived from the changes in drought characteristics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Wu, Bingfang; Ma, Zonghan; Yan, Nana&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT  Volume: 244   Pages: 11813-11813   Published: JUL 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Droughts can cause tremendous losses to agricultural and economic development; humans have explored many anti-drought measures to mitigate the influence of drought and accordingly altering the characteristics of actual agricultural drought. In this study, a method is proposed to detect the spatiotemporal changes in drought characteristics, which show the effects of anti-drought measures on drought mitigation. Two agricultural drought mitigation evaluation indices are proposed, the agricultural drought frequency change (ADFC) and agricultural drought area change (ADAC), which are calculated by combining the Palmer drought severity index (PDSI) and vegetation health index (VHI), two widely used drought monitoring indices. The PDSI and VHI represent the natural and actual agricultural drought severity under natural and actual conditions respectively, and their differences in drought frequency and affected area reflect the level of anti-drought measures in mitigating agricultural drought. The feasibility of using ADFC and ADAC to quantify the effects of anti-drought measures for agriculture is explored using data from six typical agricultural provinces in the North China Plain and Northeast China. The results show that ADFC and ADAC could reflect both the spatiotemporal changes in agricultural drought characteristics and the influence of anti-drought measures on agricultural drought. The trend of the drought mitigation index is consistent with agricultural activity statistics. These two indices could be further used to evaluate the effects of different anti-drought methods and aid in defeating agricultural drought across many countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-optimal-design-for-hierarchical-generalized-group-testing&quot;&gt;An optimal design for hierarchical generalized group testing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Malinovsky, Yaakov; Haber, Gregory; Albert, Paul S.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JOURNAL OF THE ROYAL STATISTICAL SOCIETY SERIES C-APPLIED STATISTICS  Volume: 69   Issue: 3   Pages: 607-621   Published: JUN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Choosing an optimal strategy for hierarchical group testing is an important problem for practitioners who are interested in disease screening with limited resources. For example, when screening for infectious diseases in large populations, it is important to use algorithms that minimize the cost of potentially expensive assays. Black and co-workers described this as an intractable problem unless the number of individuals to screen is small. They proposed an approximation to an optimal strategy that is difficult to implement for large population sizes. We develop an optimal design with respect to the expected total number of tests that can be obtained by using a novel dynamic programming algorithm. We show that this algorithm is substantially more efficient than the approach that was proposed by Black and co-workers. In addition, we compare the two designs for imperfect tests. R code is provided for practitioners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sen2r-an-r-toolbox-for-automatically-downloading-and-preprocessing-sentinel-2-satellite-data&quot;&gt;“sen2r”: An R toolbox for automatically downloading and preprocessing Sentinel-2 satellite data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Ranghetti, Luigi; Boschetti, Mirco; Nutini, Francesco; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COMPUTERS &amp;amp; GEOSCIENCES  Volume: 139   Pages: 4473-4473   Published: JUN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
sen2r is a scalable and flexible R package to enable downloading and preprocessing of Sentinel-2 satellite imagery via an accessible and easy to install interface. It allows the execution of several preprocessing steps which are commonly performed by Sentinel-2 users: searching the Sentinel-2 archive for datasets available over a spatial area of interest and in a defined time window, downloading them, applying the Sen2Cor atmospheric correction algorithm to compute surface reflectances, merging adjacent files, performing geometric transformations, applying a cloud mask, computing spectral indices and colour images. The package is designed to be accessible to a range of users, from beginners to skilled R users. It comes with a Graphical User Interface, which can be used to set the processing parameters and launch processing operations: this feature makes sen2r accessible also for novices with limited programming experience. High-level R functions, which enable customised image processing workflows and control over intermediate steps, can be useful to experienced remote sensing researchers. Thanks to those functions it is possible to easily schedule automatic processing chains, so to manage massive processing operations. This paper describes the main characteristics, functionalities and performance of the package and highlights its usefulness as the operational back-end of service-oriented architectures, as illustrated by the SATURNO project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;atakrig-an-r-package-for-multivariate-area-to-area-and-area-to-point-kriging-predictions&quot;&gt;atakrig: An R package for multivariate area-to-area and area-to-point kriging predictions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Hu, Maogui; Huang, Yanwei&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COMPUTERS &amp;amp; GEOSCIENCES  Volume: 139   Pages: 4471-4471   Published: JUN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Geostatistical interpolation methods are used in diverse disciplines, such as environmental science, ecology, and hydrology. With the increasing availability of areal spatial data, area-to-area and area-to-point interpolations have great application potential. In this study, based on the variogram deconvolution algorithm proposed by Goovaerts (2008), an open-source area-to-area kriging package atakrig is developed in the R environment. In atakrig, point-scale variogram and cross-variogram can be automatically deconvoluted from spatial areal samples. It provides a general framework for area-to-area and area-to-point ordinary kriging and cokriging. Two applications show that the package works well in river runoff prediction and missing data interpolation for remote sensing aerosol optical depth. The package can be deployed on different operating systems and computer hardware platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;content-search-within-large-environmental-datasets-using-a-convolution-neural-network&quot;&gt;Content search within large environmental datasets using a convolution neural network&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Freeman, J.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COMPUTERS &amp;amp; GEOSCIENCES  Volume: 139   Pages: 4479-4479   Published: JUN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Convolution Neural Networks (CNN) have demonstrated a high level of performance in the areas of image recognition and classification. The training of such networks over large corpora of imagery has facilitated additional applications such as content-based image searching and retrieval. Here we investigate the efficacy of applying a pre-trained deep CNN to the task of content searching within large environmental datasets. It is demonstrated that the learned convolution filters from a pre-trained network provide sufficient fidelity and diversity to accurately perform a content search within a dataset that is unrelated to the CNN training data.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/06/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on June 01, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/04/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/04/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-04-14T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-04-14T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-8&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #8&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;VisNIR integrated multi-sensing penetrometer for in situ high-resolution vertical soil sensing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Classification of soil aggregates: A novel approach based on deep learning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applications of SAR Interferometric Coherence Time Series: Spatiotemporal Dynamics of Geomorphic Transitions in the South-Central Andes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clay content and mineralogy, organic carbon and cation exchange capacity affect water vapour sorption hysteresis of soil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simultaneous measurement of net nitrogen mineralization and denitrification rates in soil using nitrification inhibitor 3,5-dimethylpyrazole&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;visnir-integrated-multi-sensing-penetrometer-for-in-situ-high-resolution-vertical-soil-sensing&quot;&gt;VisNIR integrated multi-sensing penetrometer for in situ high-resolution vertical soil sensing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Wijewardane, Nuwan K.; Hetrick, Sarah; Ackerson, Jason; et al.
SOIL &amp;amp; TILLAGE RESEARCH  Volume: 199   Pages: 4604-4604   Published: MAY 2020
Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract
An in situ penetrometer system that can measure profile soil properties rapidly, cost-effectively, and at high vertical resolution would benefit the soil science and agriculture communities. A visible and near infrared (VisNIR) integrated multi-sensing penetrometer system was developed to automatically measure in situ soil VisNIR reflectance spectra, penetration resistance, and insertion depth along a soil profile. The system was tested in 11 agricultural fields in Nebraska, Illinois, Iowa, and South Dakota of the U.S. An independent soil VisNIR spectral library was used to build calibration models for soil property prediction. External Parameter Orthogonalization (EPO) was used to correct for the field intactness of in situ VisNIR spectra. The results showed that EPO was effective in correcting for the spectral disparity between in situ and dry-ground VisNIR spectra. The EPO correction showed an improvement of prediction accuracy of soil total carbon (R-2 and RMSE improved from 0.29 and 3.06 % to 0.5 and 0.79%, respectively) and total nitrogen (R-2 and RMSE improved from 0.51 and 0.36 % to 0.62 and 0.06 %, respectively). The system also predicted soil bulk density with an RMSE of 0.12 g cm(-3) and R-2 of 0.80. It is concluded that the VisNIR multi-sensing penetrometer, along with the use of external soil spectral libraries and the spectral correction algorithm EPO, can lead to a rapid, robust and cost-effective system for in situ high resolution vertical soil sensing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;classification-of-soil-aggregates-a-novel-approach-based-on-deep-learning&quot;&gt;Classification of soil aggregates: A novel approach based on deep learning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Azizi, Afshin; Gilandeh, Yousef Abbaspour; Mesri-Gundoshmian, Tarahom; et al.
SOIL &amp;amp; TILLAGE RESEARCH  Volume: 199   Pages: 4586-4586   Published: MAY 2020
Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Having a powerful tool and the knowledge to classify soil aggregates, one of the most important factors in evaluating the performance of tillage implements, will result in quick and accurate classification of soil aggregates. By considering them as virtual sieve, a large part of the energy and workforce used in this sector can be reduced. In this regard, computational intelligence tools can play an important and optimal role in the evaluation of tillage quality and its real-time employment. The objective of the present study was to introduce a method known as deep learning to classify aggregates of any size in specific classes. Accordingly, stereo-pair images were used to provide multiple images simultaneously and the proper nutrition of the network. Since stereo-pair images are not dependent on changes in ambient light, imaging was done under conditions of the field with no lighting system. To train the deep models, the images of each lens were separated from each other and entered into the network. Without the extraction of the required features that is done manually in most image and vision-processing algorithms, the presented deep model began to learn to observe and could extract the required features from the lowest level to highly complex features automatically. Among the variety of neural network algorithms in deep learning, a convolutional neural network (CNN) was used in this study for its unique properties in working on images. To train the CNN, VggNet16, ResNet50, and Inception-v4 architects were used. Classification accuracy of these networks was above 95 %, but the highest accuracy achieved with ResNet50 (98.72 %). This accuracy, which was significantly different from previous studies, indicated the good performance of the deep learning method in the classification of aggregates. The results of the current study showed that the estimation of mean weight diameter (MWD) of aggregates without limitations in size and with great precision is completely practical and achievable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;applications-of-sar-interferometric-coherence-time-series-spatiotemporal-dynamics-of-geomorphic-transitions-in-the-south-central-andes&quot;&gt;Applications of SAR Interferometric Coherence Time Series: Spatiotemporal Dynamics of Geomorphic Transitions in the South-Central Andes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Olen, Stephanie; Bookhagen, Bodo
JOURNAL OF GEOPHYSICAL RESEARCH-EARTH SURFACE  Volume: 125   Issue: 3   Pages: 5141-5141   Published: MAR 2020
Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Sediment transport domains in mountain landscapes are characterized by fundamentally different processes and rates depending on several factors, including geology, climate, and biota. Accurately identifying where transitions between transport domains occur is an important step to quantify the past, present, and future contribution of varying erosion and sedimentation processes and enhance our predictive capabilities. We propose a new methodology based on time series of synthetic aperture radar (SAR) interferometric coherence images to map sediment transport regimes across arid and semiarid landscapes. Using 4 years of Sentinel-1 data, we analyze sediment transport regimes for the south-central Andes in northwestern Argentina characterized by steep topographic and climatic gradients. We observe seasonally low coherence during the regional wet season, particularly on hillslopes and in alluvial channels. The spatial distribution of coherence is compared to drainage areas extracted from digital topography to identify two distinct transitions within watersheds: (a) a hillslope-to-fluvial and (b) a fluvial-to-alluvial transition. While transitions within a given basin can be well-constrained, the relative role of each sediment transport domain varies widely over the climatic and topographic gradients. In semiarid regions, we observe larger relative contributions from hillslopes compared to arid regions. Across regional gradients, the range of coherence within basins positively correlates to previously published millennial catchment-wide erosion rates and to topographic metrics used to indicate long-term uplift. Our study suggests that a dense time series of interferometric coherence can be used as a proxy for surface sediment movement and landscape stability in vegetation-free settings at event to decadal timescales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;clay-content-and-mineralogy-organic-carbon-and-cation-exchange-capacity-affect-water-vapour-sorption-hysteresis-of-soil&quot;&gt;Clay content and mineralogy, organic carbon and cation exchange capacity affect water vapour sorption hysteresis of soil&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Arthur, Emmanuel; Tuller, Markus; Moldrup, Per; et al.
EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF SOIL SCIENCE  Volume: 71   Issue: 2   Pages: 204-214   Published: MAR 2020
Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract
The hysteretic behaviour of the dry region (&amp;lt;-1.5 MPa) of the soil water characteristic, which is of the essence for accurate characterization and modelling of bio-physicochemical soil processes under dry conditions, is well documented. However, knowledge about how to best quantify water vapour sorption hysteresis and about the effects of soil properties on dry-region hysteretic behaviour is limited. To overcome this knowledge gap, we proposed a new method for quantifying sorption hysteresis and evaluated its applicability based on measured sorption isotherms of four source clay minerals and 147 soil samples. Furthermore, the effects of clay mineralogy, clay content, soil organic carbon (SOC) and cation exchange capacity (CEC) on the magnitude of sorption hysteresis were investigated. For the clay minerals, kaolinite did not exhibit hysteretic behaviour, illite showed some hysteresis, whereas Na- and Ca-smectite exhibited strong hysteretic behaviour. The average hysteresis, corrected for clay and SOC contents, was strongly reflective of the dominant clay mineralogy of the soil samples. For the soil samples with low SOC content, the average hysteresis significantly increased with increasing clay content (R-2 = 0.92), except for the kaolinite-rich samples (R-2 = 0.35). The SOC-rich samples that exhibited illitic clay mineralogy and similar soil texture showed a significant increase in average hysteresis with increasing organic carbon content (R-2 = 0.93). For all soil samples combined, the CEC was the strongest indicator for the magnitude of water vapour sorption hysteresis.
Highlights
A new index for quantification of soil vapour sorption hysteresis was proposed
Large SOC and clay content increased sorption hysteresis
For soil samples, dominant clay mineralogy controlled the magnitude of hysteresis
Cation exchange capacity was the best predictor of hysteresis for all soil types&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;simultaneous-measurement-of-net-nitrogen-mineralization-and-denitrification-rates-in-soil-using-nitrification-inhibitor-35-dimethylpyrazole&quot;&gt;Simultaneous measurement of net nitrogen mineralization and denitrification rates in soil using nitrification inhibitor 3,5-dimethylpyrazole&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Zebarth, B. J.; Burton, D. L.; Spence, J.; et al.
CANADIAN JOURNAL OF SOIL SCIENCE  Volume: 100   Issue: 1   Pages: 1-10   Published: MAR 2020
Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract
A practical means to quantify the response of the rates of net N mineralization and denitrification over a wide range of soil water contents is generally lacking. This study examined the potential to use a nitrification inhibitor (NI) assay system to simultaneously estimate the rates of net N mineralization and denitrification, and applied the NI assay to assess the effect of water content on net N mineralization and denitrification rates in two soils with contrasting soil texture. The compound 3,5-dimethylpyrazole (DMP) applied at a rate of 200 mg kg(-1) was found to provide essentially complete inhibition of nitrification over the duration of the soil incubation for two soils with contrasting soil texture (clay loam vs. sandy loam) and over a range of soil water contents (35%, 55%, and 85% water-filled pore space). This allowed net N mineralization to be estimated as the accumulation of soil ammonium (NHthorn 4) and of denitrification as the disappearance of added nitrate (NO3-). Addition of DMP resulted in a small increase in soil respiration rate but did not appear to influence the rate of net soil N mineralization. The NI assay provides a practical means to quantify the rates of net N mineralization and denitrification simultaneously over a wide range of soil water contents. The assay can be readily scaled up to routinely test multiple soils in an efficient manner, has limited material costs, and is also relatively simple to perform.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/04/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on April 14, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/04/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/04/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-04-07T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-04-07T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-7&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mapping nature’s contribution to SDG 6 and implications for other SDGs at policy relevant scales&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Comprehensive analysis of alternative downscaled soil moisture products&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The impact of sensitivity and uncertainty of soil physical parameters on the terms of the water balance: Some case studies with default R packages. Part I: Theory, methods and case descriptions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The impact of sensitivity and uncertainty of soil physical parameters on the terms of the water balance: Some case studies with default R packages. Part II: Results and discussion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improving the Predictive Skill of a Distributed Hydrological Model by Calibration on Spatial Patterns With Multiple Satellite Data Sets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The role of climate variability in Australian drought&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mapping-natures-contribution-to-sdg-6-and-implications-for-other-sdgs-at-policy-relevant-scales&quot;&gt;Mapping nature’s contribution to SDG 6 and implications for other SDGs at policy relevant scales&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Mulligan, Mark; van Soesbergen, Arnout; Hole, David G.; et al.
REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT  Volume: 239   Pages: 11671-11671   Published: MAR 15 2020
Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
The natural world has multiple, sometimes conflicting, sometimes synergistic, values to society when viewed through the lens of the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), Spatial mapping of nature’s contributions to the SDGs has the potential to support the implementation of SDG strategies through sustainable land management and conservation of ecosystem services. Such mapping requires a range of spatial data. This paper examines the use of remote sensing and spatial ecosystem service modelling to examine nature’s contribution to targets under SDG 6, also highlighting synergies with other key SDGs and trade-offs with agriculture.
We use a wide range of remotely sensed and globally available datasets (for land cover, climate, soil, population, agriculture) alongside the existing and widely used spatial ecosystem services assessment tool, Co$tingNature. With these we identify priority areas for sustainable management to realise targets under SDG 6 (water) at the country scale for Madagascar and at the basin scale for the Volta basin, though the application developed can be applied to any country or major basin in the world. Within this SDG 6 priority areas footprint, we assess the synergies and trade-offs provided by this land for SDG 15 (biodiversity) and SDG 13 (climate action) as well as SDG 2 (zero hunger).
Results highlight the co-benefits of sustainably managing nature’s contribution to SDG 6, such as the protection of forest cover (for SDG target 15.2), carbon storage as a contribution to the Paris climate agreement and nationally determined contributions (SDG 13) and biodiversity (for SDG target 15.5) but also trade-offs with the zero hunger goal (for SDG 2). Such analyses allow for better understanding of land management requirements for realising multiple SDGs through protection and restoration of green infrastructure. We provide a freely available tool, within the Co$tingNature platform, based on a variety of remotely sensed products, that can be used by SDG practitioners to carry out similar analyses and inform decision-making at national or sub-national levels globally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comprehensive-analysis-of-alternative-downscaled-soil-moisture-products&quot;&gt;Comprehensive analysis of alternative downscaled soil moisture products&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Sabaghy, Sabah; Walker, Jeffrey P.; Renzullo, Luigi J.; et al.
REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT  Volume: 239   Pages: 11586-11586   Published: MAR 15 2020
Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Recent advances in L-band passive microwave remote sensing provide an unprecedented opportunity to monitor soil moisture at similar to 40 km spatial resolution around the globe. Nevertheless, retrieval of the accurate high spatial resolution soil moisture maps that are required to satisfy hydro-meteorological and agricultural applications remains a challenge. Currently, a variety of downscaling, otherwise known as disaggregation techniques have been proposed as the solution to disaggregate the coarse passive microwave soil moisture into high-to-medium resolutions. These techniques take advantage of the strengths of both the passive microwave observations of soil moisture having low spatial resolution and the spatially detailed information on land surface features that either influence or represent soil moisture variability. However, such techniques have typically been developed and tested individually under differing weather and climate conditions, meaning that there is no clear guidance on which technique performs the best. Consequently, this paper presents a quantitative assessment of the existing radar-, optical-, radiometer-, and oversampling-based downscaling techniques using a singular extensive data set collected specifically for that purpose, being the Soil Moisture Active Passive Experiment (SMAPEx)-4 and -5 airborne field campaigns, and the OzNet in situ stations, to determine the relative strengths and weaknesses of their performances. The oversampling-based soil moisture product best captured the temporal and spatial variability of the reference soil moisture overall, though the radar-based products had a better temporal agreement with airborne soil moisture during the short SMAPEx-4 period. Moreover, the difference between temporal analysis of products against in situ and airborne soil moisture reference data sets pointed to the fact that relying on in situ measurements alone is not appropriate for validation of spatially enhanced soil moisture maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-impact-of-sensitivity-and-uncertainty-of-soil-physical-parameters-on-the-terms-of-the-water-balance-some-case-studies-with-default-r-packages-part-i-theory-methods-and-case-descriptions&quot;&gt;The impact of sensitivity and uncertainty of soil physical parameters on the terms of the water balance: Some case studies with default R packages. Part I: Theory, methods and case descriptions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Wesseling, Jan; Kroes, Joop; Oliveira, Thalita Campos; et al.
COMPUTERS AND ELECTRONICS IN AGRICULTURE  Volume: 170   Pages: 5054-5054   Published: MAR 2020
Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract
These papers (part I and part II) emphasize the need for sensitivity and uncertainty analyses. A number of techniques are applied, e.g. latin hypercube sampling, impact response surfaces and Sobol-analyses. Five examples are presented, four of them concerning the numerical model SWAP. The data generation and analysis is performed with standard R packages. Although the computations can be made on any computer, the most time-consuming examples in this paper have been run on a High Performance Computer Cluster. With the relatively simple Impact Response Surface technique it is shown that variation of the saturated hydraulic conductivity has far less impact than changing the moisture content at saturation. Analyses according to the Sobol-Jansen method show that when the soil physical relationships are described according to Damiano, then the parameter b has a very large influence on the results. If the well-known Mualem - Van Genuchten equations are applied, most variation can be explained by the parameter n.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;improving-the-predictive-skill-of-a-distributed-hydrological-model-by-calibration-on-spatial-patterns-with-multiple-satellite-data-sets&quot;&gt;Improving the Predictive Skill of a Distributed Hydrological Model by Calibration on Spatial Patterns With Multiple Satellite Data Sets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Dembele, Moctar; Hrachowitz, Markus; Savenije, Hubert H. G.; et al.
WATER RESOURCES RESEARCH  Volume: 56   Issue: 1   Pages: 26085-26085   Published: JAN 2020
Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Hydrological model calibration combining Earth observations and in situ measurements is a promising solution to overcome the limitations of the traditional streamflow-only calibration. However, combining multiple data sources in model calibration requires a meaningful integration of the data sets, which should harness their most reliable contents to avoid accumulation of their uncertainties and mislead the parameter estimation procedure. This study analyzes the improvement of model parameter selection by using only the spatial patterns of satellite remote sensing data, thereby ignoring their absolute values. Although satellite products are characterized by uncertainties, their most reliable key feature is the representation of spatial patterns, which is a unique and relevant source of information for distributed hydrological models. We propose a novel multivariate calibration framework exploiting spatial patterns and simultaneously incorporating streamflow and three satellite products (i.e., Global Land Evaporation Amsterdam Model [GLEAM] evaporation, European Space Agency Climate Change Initiative [ESA CCI] soil moisture, and Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment [GRACE] terrestrial water storage). The Moderate Resolution Imaging Spectroradiometer (MODIS) land surface temperature data set is used for model evaluation. A bias-insensitive and multicomponent spatial pattern matching metric is developed to formulate a multiobjective function. The proposed multivariate calibration framework is tested with the mesoscale Hydrologic Model (mHM) and applied to the poorly gauged Volta River basin located in a predominantly semiarid climate in West Africa. Results of the multivariate calibration show that the decrease in performance for streamflow (-7%) and terrestrial water storage (-6%) is counterbalanced with an increase in performance for soil moisture (+105%) and evaporation (+26%). These results demonstrate that there are benefits in using satellite data sets, when suitably integrated in a robust model parametrization scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-role-of-climate-variability-in-australian-drought&quot;&gt;The role of climate variability in Australian drought&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: King, Andrew D.; Pitman, Andy J.; Henley, Benjamin J.; et al.
NATURE CLIMATE CHANGE  Volume: 10   Issue: 3   Pages: 177-179   Published: MAR 2020
Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Much of Australia has been in severe drought since at least 2017. Here we link Australian droughts to the absence of Pacific and Indian Ocean mode states that act as key drivers of drought-breaking rains. Predicting the impact of climate change on drought requires accurate modelling of these modes of variability.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/04/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on April 07, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/03/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/03/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-03-29T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-03-29T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-6&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Which practices co-deliver food security, climate change mitigation and adaptation, and combat land degradation and desertification?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Global patterns of terrestrial nitrogen and phosphorus limitation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mapping soil organic carbon and clay using remote sensing to predict soil workability for enhanced climate change adaptation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modelling the spatial extent and severity of extreme European windstorms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;which-practices-co-deliver-food-security-climate-change-mitigation-and-adaptation-and-combat-land-degradation-and-desertification&quot;&gt;Which practices co-deliver food security, climate change mitigation and adaptation, and combat land degradation and desertification?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Smith, P (Smith, Pete)[ 1 ] ; Calvin, K (Calvin, Katherine)[ 2 ] ; Nkem, J (Nkem, Johnson)[ 3 ] ; Campbell, D (Campbell, Donovan)[ 4 ] ; Cherubini, F (Cherubini, Francesco)[ 5 ] ; Grassi, G (Grassi, Giacomo)[ 6 ] ; Korotkov, V (Korotkov, Vladimir)[ 7 ] ; Hoang, AL (Anh Le Hoang)[ 8 ] ; Lwasa, S (Lwasa, Shuaib)[ 9 ] ; McElwee, P (McElwee, Pamela)[ 10 ] …More&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View Web of Science ResearcherID and ORCID
GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pages: NIL_1-NIL_44
Published: DEC 14 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
There is a clear need for transformative change in the land management and food production sectors to address the global land challenges of climate change mitigation, climate change adaptation, combatting land degradation and desertification, and delivering food security (referred to hereafter as “land challenges”). We assess the potential for 40 practices to address these land challenges and find that: Nine options deliver medium to large benefits for all four land challenges. A further two options have no global estimates for adaptation, but have medium to large benefits for all other land challenges. Five options have large mitigation potential (&amp;gt;3 Gt CO(2)eq/year) without adverse impacts on the other land challenges. Five options have moderate mitigation potential, with no adverse impacts on the other land challenges. Sixteen practices have large adaptation potential (&amp;gt;25 million people benefit), without adverse side effects on other land challenges. Most practices can be applied without competing for available land. However, seven options could result in competition for land. A large number of practices do not require dedicated land, including several land management options, all value chain options, and all risk management options. Four options could greatly increase competition for land if applied at a large scale, though the impact is scale and context specific, highlighting the need for safeguards to ensure that expansion of land for mitigation does not impact natural systems and food security. A number of practices, such as increased food productivity, dietary change and reduced food loss and waste, can reduce demand for land conversion, thereby potentially freeing-up land and creating opportunities for enhanced implementation of other practices, making them important components of portfolios of practices to address the combined land challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;global-patterns-of-terrestrial-nitrogen-and-phosphorus-limitation&quot;&gt;Global patterns of terrestrial nitrogen and phosphorus limitation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By:Du, EZ (Du, Enzai)[ 1,2,3 ] ; Terrer, C (Terrer, Cesar)[ 3,4 ] ; Pellegrini, AFA (Pellegrini, Adam F. A.)[ 3 ] ; Ahlstrom, A (Ahlstrom, Anders)[ 3,5,6 ] ; van Lissa, CJ (van Lissa, Caspar J.)[ 7 ] ; Zhao, X (Zhao, Xia)[ 8 ] ; Xia, N (Xia, Nan)[ 2 ] ; Wu, XH (Wu, Xinhui)[ 2 ] ; Jackson, RB (Jackson, Robert B.)[ 3,9,10 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View Web of Science ResearcherID and ORCID
NATURE GEOSCIENCE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 13 Issue: 3 Pages: 221-+
Published: MAR 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Spatial patterns in the phosphorus and nitrogen limitation in natural terrestrial ecosystems are reported from analysis of a global database of the resorption efficiency of nutrients by leaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nitrogen (N) and phosphorus (P) limitation constrains the magnitude of terrestrial carbon uptake in response to elevated carbon dioxide and climate change. However, global maps of nutrient limitation are still lacking. Here we examined global N and P limitation using the ratio of site-averaged leaf N and P resorption efficiencies of the dominant species across 171 sites. We evaluated our predictions using a global database of N- and P-limitation experiments based on nutrient additions at 106 and 53 sites, respectively. Globally, we found a shift from relative P to N limitation for both higher latitudes and precipitation seasonality and lower mean annual temperature, temperature seasonality, mean annual precipitation and soil clay fraction. Excluding cropland, urban and glacial areas, we estimate that 18% of the natural terrestrial land area is significantly limited by N, whereas 43% is relatively P limited. The remaining 39% of the natural terrestrial land area could be co-limited by N and P or weakly limited by either nutrient alone. This work provides both a new framework for testing nutrient limitation and a benchmark of N and P limitation for models to constrain predictions of the terrestrial carbon sink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mapping-soil-organic-carbon-and-clay-using-remote-sensing-to-predict-soil-workability-for-enhanced-climate-change-adaptation&quot;&gt;Mapping soil organic carbon and clay using remote sensing to predict soil workability for enhanced climate change adaptation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Paul, SS (Paul, S. S.)[ 1 ] ; Coops, NC (Coops, N. C.)[ 2 ] ; Johnson, MS (Johnson, M. S.)[ 3 ] ; Krzic, M (Krzic, M.)[ 1,4 ] ; Chandna, A (Chandna, A.)[ 1 ] ; Smukler, SM (Smukler, S. M.)[ 1 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GEODERMA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 363 Pages: 14177-14177
Published: APR 1 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Climate change is presenting sizeable challenges for agricultural production around the world. In some regions, shifting precipitation patterns in the spring and fall are negatively impacting farm operation by reducing the number of “workable days” or the days fields can be worked with heavy equipment without damaging soil structure. This can be particularly problematic for farms on clay soils and/or poor drainage. Approximating a water content threshold at which a soil is not workable due to soil structure destruction can be helpful for planning effective farm operations. In this study, we applied advanced remote sensing and machine learning tools to produce digital maps of soil organic carbon (SOC) and clay (CL) content and used them in existing pedotransfer functions (PTFs) to predict a workability threshold (WT) across a study area in Delta, British Columbia, Canada. We combined field data, soil and vegetation indices derived from multiple Landsat satellite images, topographic indices, and soil survey information to digitally map SOC and CL of the agricultural lands in Delta using random forest (RF) and generalized boosted regression model (GBM). When validated against an independent field dataset, the RF model outperformed GBM for all accuracy measures (coefficient of determination - R-2, concordance correlation coefficient - CCC, and normalized root mean square error - nRMSE). We then spatially applied several PTFs using our digital maps to estimate the plasticity limits of the soil and produce WT map. The WT map was then tested against independent field samples of the soil water content at - 10 kPa and we achieved R-2 of 0.59, CCC of 0.70, and nRMSE of 0.15. Our analysis showed that 40% of the fields in the study area had WT &amp;lt; 30%, a threshold that is already being impacted by reduced workable days. This WT map could be used to improve spatial prioritizations of investments for climate change adaptation at farm to regional scales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;modelling-the-spatial-extent-and-severity-of-extreme-european-windstorms&quot;&gt;Modelling the spatial extent and severity of extreme European windstorms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Sharkey, P (Sharkey, Paul)[ 1 ] ; Tawn, JA (Tawn, Jonathan A.)[ 2 ] ; Brown, SJ (Brown, Simon J.)[ 3 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JOURNAL OF THE ROYAL STATISTICAL SOCIETY SERIES C-APPLIED STATISTICS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 69 Issue: 2 Pages: 223-250
Published: APR 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Windstorms are a primary natural hazard affecting Europe that are commonly linked to substantial property and infrastructural damage and are responsible for the largest spatially aggregated financial losses. Such extreme winds are typically generated by extratropical cyclone systems originating in the North Atlantic and passing over Europe. Previous statistical studies tend to model extreme winds at a given set of sites, corresponding to inference in an Eulerian framework. Such inference cannot incorporate knowledge of the life cycle and progression of extratropical cyclones across the region and is forced to make restrictive assumptions about the extremal dependence structure. We take an entirely different approach which overcomes these limitations by working in a Lagrangian framework. Specifically, we model the development of windstorms over time, preserving the physical characteristics linking the windstorm and the cyclone track, the path of local vorticity maxima, and make a key finding that the spatial extent of extratropical windstorms becomes more localized as its magnitude increases irrespective of the location of the storm track. Our model allows simulation of synthetic windstorm events to derive the joint distributional features over any set of sites giving physically consistent extrapolations to rarer events. From such simulations improved estimates of this hazard can be achieved in terms of both intensity and area affected.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/03/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on March 29, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/03/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/03/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-03-02T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-03-02T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-5&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Model parameterization to represent processes at unresolved scales and changing properties of evolving systems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;R software packages as a tool for evaluating soil physical and hydraulic properties&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrating satellite soil-moisture estimates and hydrological model products over Australia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Process-Guided Deep Learning Predictions of Lake Water Temperature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;model-parameterization-to-represent-processes-at-unresolved-scales-and-changing-properties-of-evolving-systems&quot;&gt;Model parameterization to represent processes at unresolved scales and changing properties of evolving systems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Luo, Yiqi; Schuur, Edward A. G.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY  Pages: NIL_1-NIL_9   Published: JAN 12 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modeling has become an indispensable tool for scientific research. However, models generate great uncertainty when they are used to predict or forecast ecosystem responses to global change. This uncertainty is partly due to parameterization, which is an essential procedure for model specification via defining parameter values for a model. The classic doctrine of parameterization is that a parameter is constant. However, it is commonly known from modeling practice that a model that is well calibrated for its parameters at one site may not simulate well at another site unless its parameters are tuned again. This common practice implies that parameter values have to vary with sites. Indeed, parameter values that are estimated using a statistically rigorous approach, that is, data assimilation, vary with time, space, and treatments in global change experiments. This paper illustrates that varying parameters is to account for both processes at unresolved scales and changing properties of evolving systems. A model, no matter how complex it is, could not represent all the processes of one system at resolved scales. Interactions of processes at unresolved scales with those at resolved scales should be reflected in model parameters. Meanwhile, it is pervasively observed that properties of ecosystems change over time, space, and environmental conditions. Parameters, which represent properties of a system under study, should change as well. Tuning has been practiced for many decades to change parameter values. Yet this activity, unfortunately, did not contribute to our knowledge on model parameterization at all. Data assimilation makes it possible to rigorously estimate parameter values and, consequently, offers an approach to understand which, how, how much, and why parameters vary. To fully understand those issues, extensive research is required. Nonetheless, it is clear that changes in parameter values lead to different model predictions even if the model structure is the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;r-software-packages-as-a-tool-for-evaluating-soil-physical-and-hydraulic-properties&quot;&gt;R software packages as a tool for evaluating soil physical and hydraulic properties&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: de Sousa, Dedola Fernandes; Rodrigues, Sueli; de Lima, Herdjania Veras; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COMPUTERS AND ELECTRONICS IN AGRICULTURE  Volume: 168   Pages: 5077-5077   Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The determination of soil physical properties requires complex analyzes performed by software, which are mostly paid access programs. The advantage of using R software is that it is open access and offers several packages for the analysis of soil physic-hydrical properties data. The objective of this review is to present and to disseminate the tools available in R for studies in soil physics. We briefly describe some packages of the R software for soil physics and analyze their ease of reproduction. From the examples given in the manuals of each package we observed that their reproducibility was not always self-explanatory, as verified for the packages soilwater and SoilHyP. The HydroMe and soilphysics packages were the most comprehensible to be reproduced. The most common determination offered by these packages is related to soil water retention curve models. We hope this will guide the soil science researchers to employ, more often, R codes to analyze their data. The R scripts that were used to exemplify the packages reported in this paper are available at https://github.com/sousaetal/COMPAG_2019_600.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;integrating-satellite-soil-moisture-estimates-and-hydrological-model-products-over-australia&quot;&gt;Integrating satellite soil-moisture estimates and hydrological model products over Australia&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Khaki, M.; Zerihun, A.; Awange, J. L.; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AUSTRALIAN JOURNAL OF EARTH SCIENCES  Volume: 67   Issue: 2   Pages: 265-277   Published: FEB 17 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accurate soil-moisture monitoring is essential for water-resource management and agricultural applications, and is now widely undertaken using satellite remote sensing or terrestrial hydrological models’ products. While both methods have limitations, e.g. the limited soil depth resolution of space-borne data and data deficiencies in models, data-assimilation techniques can provide an alternative approach. Here, we use the recently developed data-driven Kalman-Takens approach to integrate satellite soil-moisture products with those of the Australian Water Resources Assessment system Landscape (AWRA-L) model. This is done to constrain the model’s soil-moisture simulations over Australia with those observed from the Advanced Microwave Scanning Radiometer-Earth Observing System and Soil-Moisture and Ocean Salinity between 2002 and 2017. The main objective is to investigate the ability of the integration framework to improve AWRA-L simulations of soil moisture. The improved estimates are then used to investigate spatiotemporal soil-moisture variations. The results show that the proposed model-satellite data integration approach improves the continental soil-moisture estimates by increasing their correlation to independent in situ measurements (similar to 10% relative to the non-assimilation estimates).
HIGHLIGHTS
Satellite soil-moisture measurements are used to improve model simulation.
A data-driven approach based on Kalman-Takens is applied.
The applied data-integration approach improves soil-moisture estimates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;process-guided-deep-learning-predictions-of-lake-water-temperature&quot;&gt;Process-Guided Deep Learning Predictions of Lake Water Temperature&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Read, Jordan S.; Jia, Xiaowei; Willard, Jared; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WATER RESOURCES RESEARCH  Pages: NIL_1-NIL_18   Published: NOV 16 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rapid growth of data in water resources has created new opportunities to accelerate knowledge discovery with the use of advanced deep learning tools. Hybrid models that integrate theory with state-of-the art empirical techniques have the potential to improve predictions while remaining true to physical laws. This paper evaluates the Process-Guided Deep Learning (PGDL) hybrid modeling framework with a use-case of predicting depth-specific lake water temperatures. The PGDL model has three primary components: a deep learning model with temporal awareness (long short-term memory recurrence), theory-based feedback (model penalties for violating conversation of energy), and model pretraining to initialize the network with synthetic data (water temperature predictions from a process-based model). In situ water temperatures were used to train the PGDL model, a deep learning (DL) model, and a process-based (PB) model. Model performance was evaluated in various conditions, including when training data were sparse and when predictions were made outside of the range in the training data set. The PGDL model performance (as measured by root-mean-square error (RMSE)) was superior to DL and PB for two detailed study lakes, but only when pretraining data included greater variability than the training period. The PGDL model also performed well when extended to 68 lakes, with a median RMSE of 1.65 degrees C during the test period (DL: 1.78 degrees C, PB: 2.03 degrees C; in a small number of lakes PB or DL models were more accurate). This case-study demonstrates that integrating scientific knowledge into deep learning tools shows promise for improving predictions of many important environmental variables.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/03/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on March 02, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/02/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/02/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-02-26T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-02-26T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-4&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quantification of Peat Thickness and Stored Carbon at the Landscape Scale in Tropical Peatlands: A Comparison of Airborne Geophysics and an Empirical Topographic Method&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hydrogeological Modeling and Water Resources Management: Improving the Link Between Data, Prediction, and Decision Making&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quantification-of-peat-thickness-and-stored-carbon-at-the-landscape-scale-in-tropical-peatlands-a-comparison-of-airborne-geophysics-and-an-empirical-topographic-method&quot;&gt;Quantification of Peat Thickness and Stored Carbon at the Landscape Scale in Tropical Peatlands: A Comparison of Airborne Geophysics and an Empirical Topographic Method&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Silvestri, S (Silvestri, Sonia)[ 1,2 ] ; Knight, R (Knight, Rosemary)[ 3 ] ; Viezzoli, A (Viezzoli, Andrea)[ 4 ] ; Richardson, CJ (Richardson, Curtis J.)[ 2 ] ; Anshari, GZ (Anshari, Gusti Z.)[ 5 ] ; Dewar, N (Dewar, Noah)[ 3 ] ; Flanagan, N (Flanagan, Neal)[ 2 ] ; Comas, X (Comas, Xavier)[ 6 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JOURNAL OF GEOPHYSICAL RESEARCH-EARTH SURFACE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 124 Issue: 12 Pages: 3107-3123
Published: DEC 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Peatlands play a key role in the global carbon cycle, sequestering and releasing large amounts of carbon. Despite their importance, a reliable method for the quantification of peatland thickness and volume is still missing, particularly for peat deposits located in the tropics given their limited accessibility, and for scales of measurement representative of peatland environments (i.e., of hundreds of km(2)). This limitation also prevents the accurate quantification of the stored carbon as well as future greenhouse gas emissions due to ongoing peat degradation. Here we present the results obtained using the airborne electromagnetic (AEM) method, a geophysical surveying tool, for peat thickness detection at the landscape scale. Based on a large amount of data collected on an Indonesian peatland, our results show that the AEM method provides a reliable and accurate 3-D model of peatlands, allowing the quantification of their volume and carbon storage. A comparison with the often used empirical topographic approach, which is based on an assumed correlation between peat thickness and surface topography, revealed larger errors across the landscape associated with the empirical approach than the AEM method when predicting the peat thickness. As a result, the AEM method provides higher estimates (22%) of organic carbon pools than the empirical method. We show how in our case study the empirical method tends to underestimate the peat thickness due to its inability to accurately detect the large variability in the elevation of the peat/mineral substrate interface, which is better quantified by the AEM method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hydrogeological-modeling-and-water-resources-management-improving-the-link-between-data-prediction-and-decision-making&quot;&gt;Hydrogeological Modeling and Water Resources Management: Improving the Link Between Data, Prediction, and Decision Making&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Harken, Bradley; Chang, Ching-Fu; Dietrich, Peter; et al.
WATER RESOURCES RESEARCH  Volume: 55   Issue: 12   Pages: 10340-10357   Published: DEC 2019
Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A risk-based decision-making mechanism capable of accounting for uncertainty regarding local conditions is crucial to water resources management, regulation, and policy making. Despite the great potential of hydrogeological models in supporting water resources decisions, challenges remain due to the many sources of uncertainty as well as making and communicating decisions mindful of this uncertainty. This paper presents a framework that utilizes statistical hypothesis testing and an integrated approach to the planning of site characterization, modeling prediction, and decision making. Benefits of this framework include aggregated uncertainty quantification and risk evaluation, simplified communication of risk between stakeholders, and improved defensibility of decisions. The framework acknowledges that obtaining absolute certainty in decision making is impossible; rather, the framework provides a systematic way to make decisions in light of uncertainty and determine the amount of information required. In this manner, quantitative evaluation of a field campaign design is possible before data are collected, beginning from any knowledge state, which can be updated as more information becomes available. We discuss the limitations of this approach by the types of uncertainty that can be recognized and make suggestions for addressing the rest. This paper presents the framework in general and then demonstrates its application in a synthetic case study. Results indicate that the effectiveness of field campaigns depends not only on the environmental performance metric being predicted but also on the threshold value in decision-making processes. The findings also demonstrate that improved parameter estimation does not necessarily lead to better decision making, thus reemphasizing the need for goal-oriented characterization.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/02/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on February 26, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/02/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/02/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-02-12T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-02-12T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-3&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Human fingerprint in global weather&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Changing risks of simultaneous global breadbasket failure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;human-fingerprint-in-global-weather&quot;&gt;Human fingerprint in global weather&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Min, Seung-Ki&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NATURE CLIMATE CHANGE  Volume: 10   Issue: 1   Pages: 15-16   Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An anthropogenic fingerprint has been detected in long-term climate trends, but distinguishing human-induced change from natural variability in day-to-day weather remains a challenge. Research now finds that a human influence is discernible in global patterns of daily temperature and moisture.
&lt;em&gt;Climate change now detectable from any single day of weather at global scale&lt;/em&gt;
Sebastian Sippel, Nicolai Meinshausen, Erich M. Fischer, Enikő Székely &amp;amp; Reto Knutti&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;changing-risks-of-simultaneous-global-breadbasket-failure&quot;&gt;Changing risks of simultaneous global breadbasket failure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Gaupp, Franziska; Hall, Jim; Hochrainer-Stigler, Stefan; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NATURE CLIMATE CHANGE  Volume: 10   Issue: 1   Pages: 54-+   Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The risk of extreme climatic conditions leading to unusually low global agricultural production is exacerbated if more than one global ‘breadbasket’ is exposed at the same time. Such shocks can pose a risk to the global food system, amplifying threats to food security, and could potentially trigger other systemic risks(1,2). While the possibility of climatic extremes hitting more than one breadbasket has been postulated(3,4,) little is known about the actual risk. Here we combine region-specific data on agricultural production with spatial statistics of climatic extremes to quantify the changing risk of low production for the major food-producing regions (breadbaskets) over time. We show an increasing risk of simultaneous failure of wheat, maize and soybean crops across the breadbaskets analysed. For rice, risks of simultaneous adverse climate conditions have decreased in the recent past, mostly owing to solar radiation changes favouring rice growth. Depending on the correlation structure between the breadbaskets, spatial dependence between climatic extremes globally can mitigate or aggravate the risks for the global food production. Our analysis can provide the basis for more efficient allocation of resources to contingency plans and/or strategic crop reserves that would enhance the resilience of the global food system.
The risk of concurrent climate extremes affecting breadbasket regions is increasing with climate change, with wheat, maize and soybean crops at risk of simultaneous failure. Correlation between the regions and climate extremes should be considered to ensure food security in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/02/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on February 12, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/02/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/02/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-02-06T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-02-06T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-2&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimating Soil Hydraulic Conductivity at the Field Scale With a State-Space Approach&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil risk maps - Interpreting soils data for policy makers, agencies and industry&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A review of remote laser-induced breakdown spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to measure, report and verify soil carbon change to realize the potential of soil carbon sequestration for atmospheric greenhouse gas removal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How eddy covariance flux measurements have contributed to our understanding of Global Change Biology&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rethinking sources of nitrogen to cereal crops&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conceptualizing soil organic matter into particulate and mineral-associated forms to address global change in the 21st century&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;estimating-soil-hydraulic-conductivity-at-the-field-scale-with-a-state-space-approach&quot;&gt;Estimating Soil Hydraulic Conductivity at the Field Scale With a State-Space Approach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Zhang, Xi; Wendroth, Ole; Matocha, Christopher; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOIL SCIENCE  Volume: 184   Issue: 3   Pages: 101-111   Published: JUN 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A precise description of saturated (K-s) and near-saturated hydraulic conductivity (K-10) and their spatial variability is important for understanding water/solute transport in the vadose zone. However, it is laborious to measure K directly. Alternatively, K could be predicted from easily measurable soil properties using pedotransfer functions (PTFs). Because PTFs ignore the spatial relationships and covariance between soil variables, they often perform unsatisfactorily when field-scale estimations of K are needed. Therefore, the objective of this study was to improve the estimation of K at field scale through consideration of spatial dependences between soil variables. K was measured at 48 locations in a 71 x 71-m grid within a farmland under no-till. An autoregressive state-space approach was used to quantify the spatial relations between K and soil properties and to analyze the spatial variability of K in the field. In comparison, multiple linear regression (MLR) was used to derive PTFs for K estimation. Using various combinations of variables, state-space analysis outperformed PTFs in estimating spatial K distribution across the field. While state-space approach explained 69%, MLR method explained only 6% of the total variation in K-s. For K-10, the best state-space model included silt, clay, and macroporosity and performed almost perfectly (R-2 &amp;gt;95%) in characterizing the spatial variability of K-10. In that case, the best MLR-type PTF explained only 60% of the variation. The results indicate that, by considering the spatial relations between soil variables, state-space approach is an effective tool for analyzing the spatial variability of K at field scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-risk-maps---interpreting-soils-data-for-policy-makers-agencies-and-industry&quot;&gt;Soil risk maps - Interpreting soils data for policy makers, agencies and industry&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Baggaley, Nikki; Lilly, Allan; Blackstock, Kirsty; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOIL USE AND MANAGEMENT  Volume: 36   Issue: 1   Pages: 19-26   Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surface runoff, erosion, compaction and the leaching of potential pollutants from land can degrade the soil resource and damage the water environment, reducing crop yields, causing loss of valuable nutrients and organic matter, together with increasing flood risk. Increasingly, it is recognized that scientific information must be translated into practical tools to change practices and protect the soil and water resource. Working alongside agencies in Scotland, we applied a suite of simple, transparent, rule-based models to identify areas most at risk of exporting sediment and pollutants that may degrade water quality based on field-scale (1:25,000) soil maps. The maps have been used by Scottish Environment Protection Agency, Scottish Water and Scottish Government to assess soil risks to waters from field to regional scale. The work brought scientists together with policy makers, agencies and the water industry to pool their knowledge to apply these practical tools for decision-making. It highlights the need to apply existing knowledge to answer salient questions. All three examples described show that providing the right type of information, which is based on fundamental soils data, can directly influence the implementation of policies, investment and monitoring decisions and provide evidence in support of government. However, this requires both researchers and agency scientists to develop skills as knowledge brokers and to normalize the use of soil data in everyday agency settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-review-of-remote-laser-induced-breakdown-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;A review of remote laser-induced breakdown spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By:Li, WT (Li, Wanting)[ 1 ] ; Li, XY (Li, Xiangyou)[ 1 ] ; Li, X (Li, Xin)[ 1 ] ; Hao, ZQ (Hao, Zhongqi)[ 1,2 ] ; Lu, YF (Lu, Yongfeng)[ 1 ] ; Zeng, XY (Zeng, Xiaoyan)[ 1 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;APPLIED SPECTROSCOPY REVIEWS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume: 55 Issue: 1 Pages: 1-25
Published: JAN 2 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document Type: Review&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Laser-induced breakdown spectroscopy (LIBS) is well known for its feature of remote detection. In this review, the development of remote detection based on LIBS is presented. Three kinds of remote LIBS configurations and their characteristics have been illustrated. Owing to an inferior efficiency and intensity of spectral signals collected in a remote distance, different methods have been studied to enhance signals. This review briefly summarized the advanced enhancement approaches for remote LIBS, which further improves the capabilities of LIBS for real-time and in situ measurement. Furthermore, the recent development and application of remote LIBS in a variety of fields have been presented. The potential of LIBS in remote detection and its existing problems have also been discussed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-measure-report-and-verify-soil-carbon-change-to-realize-the-potential-of-soil-carbon-sequestration-for-atmospheric-greenhouse-gas-removal&quot;&gt;How to measure, report and verify soil carbon change to realize the potential of soil carbon sequestration for atmospheric greenhouse gas removal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Smith, Pete; Soussana, Jean-Francois; Angers, Denis; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY  Volume: 26   Issue: 1   Pages: 219-241   Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is growing international interest in better managing soils to increase soil organic carbon (SOC) content to contribute to climate change mitigation, to enhance resilience to climate change and to underpin food security, through initiatives such as international ‘4p1000’ initiative and the FAO’s Global assessment of SOC sequestration potential (GSOCseq) programme. Since SOC content of soils cannot be easily measured, a key barrier to implementing programmes to increase SOC at large scale, is the need for credible and reliable measurement/monitoring, reporting and verification (MRV) platforms, both for national reporting and for emissions trading. Without such platforms, investments could be considered risky. In this paper, we review methods and challenges of measuring SOC change directly in soils, before examining some recent novel developments that show promise for quantifying SOC. We describe how repeat soil surveys are used to estimate changes in SOC over time, and how long-term experiments and space-for-time substitution sites can serve as sources of knowledge and can be used to test models, and as potential benchmark sites in global frameworks to estimate SOC change. We briefly consider models that can be used to simulate and project change in SOC and examine the MRV platforms for SOC change already in use in various countries/regions. In the final section, we bring together the various components described in this review, to describe a new vision for a global framework for MRV of SOC change, to support national and international initiatives seeking to effect change in the way we manage our soils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-eddy-covariance-flux-measurements-have-contributed-to-our-understanding-of-global-change-biology&quot;&gt;How eddy covariance flux measurements have contributed to our understanding of Global Change Biology&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Baldocchi, Dennis D.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY  Volume: 26   Issue: 1   Pages: 242-260   Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A global network of long-term carbon and water flux measurements has existed since the late 1990s. With its representative sampling of the terrestrial biosphere’s climate and ecological spaces, this network is providing background information and direct measurements on how ecosystem metabolism responds to environmental and biological forcings and how they may be changing in a warmer world with more carbon dioxide. In this review, I explore how carbon and water fluxes of the world’s ecosystem are responding to a suite of covarying environmental factors, like sunlight, temperature, soil moisture, and carbon dioxide. I also report on how coupled carbon and water fluxes are modulated by biological and ecological factors such as phenology and a suite of structural and functional properties. And, I investigate whether long-term trends in carbon and water fluxes are emerging in various ecological and climate spaces and the degree to which they may be driven by physical and biological forcings. As a growing number of time series extend up to 20 years in duration, we are at the verge of capturing ecosystem scale trends in the breathing of a changing biosphere. Consequently, flux measurements need to continue to report on future conditions and responses and assess the efficacy of natural climate solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rethinking-sources-of-nitrogen-to-cereal-crops&quot;&gt;Rethinking sources of nitrogen to cereal crops&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Yan, Ming; Pan, Genxing; Lavallee, Jocelyn M.; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY  Volume: 26   Issue: 1   Pages: 191-199   Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding how to manage N inputs to identify the practices that maximize N recovery has been an organizing principle of agronomic research. Because growth in N fertilizer inputs is expected to continue in an ongoing effort to boost crop production over coming decades, understanding how to efficiently manage recovery of fertilizer N will be important going forward. Yet synthesis of published data that has traced the fate of N-15-labeled fertilizer shows that less than half of the N taken up by crops is derived from current-year N fertilizer. The source of the majority of N in crops is something other than current-year fertilizer and the sources are not really known. This is true for maize (only 41% of N in crops was from current-year N fertilizer), rice (32%), and small grains (37%). Recovery of organic fertilizer N (manure, green manure, compost, etc.) in crops is low (27%), though N recovery in subsequent years (10%) was greater than that for mineral fertilizers. Thus, while research on efficiency of N fertilizer use through improved rate, type, location, and timing is important, this research fails to directly address management of the majority of the N supplied to crops. It seems likely that the majority of non-fertilizer N found in crops comes from turnover of soil and crop residue N. We encourage the research community to revisit the mental model that fertilizer is a replacement for N supply from turnover of soil organic N (SON) and consider a model in which N fertilizer augments ongoing SON turnover and makes an important longer term contribution to SON maintenance and turnover. Research focused on the efficient recovery of N current-year fertilizer inputs neglects this potential role for building soil N and managing soil N turnover, which seems likely to be the most important source of crop N.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conceptualizing-soil-organic-matter-into-particulate-and-mineral-associated-forms-to-address-global-change-in-the-21st-century&quot;&gt;Conceptualizing soil organic matter into particulate and mineral-associated forms to address global change in the 21st century&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Lavallee, Jocelyn M.; Soong, Jennifer L.; Cotrufo, M. Francesca&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY  Volume: 26   Issue: 1   Pages: 261-273   Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Managing soil organic matter (SOM) stocks to address global change challenges requires well-substantiated knowledge of SOM behavior that can be clearly communicated between scientists, management practitioners, and policy makers. However, SOM is incredibly complex and requires separation into multiple components with contrasting behavior in order to study and predict its dynamics. Numerous diverse SOM separation schemes are currently used, making cross-study comparisons difficult and hindering broad-scale generalizations. Here, we recommend separating SOM into particulate (POM) and mineral-associated (MAOM) forms, two SOM components that are fundamentally different in terms of their formation, persistence, and functioning. We provide evidence of their highly contrasting physical and chemical properties, mean residence times in soil, and responses to land use change, plant litter inputs, warming, CO2 enrichment, and N fertilization. Conceptualizing SOM into POM versus MAOM is a feasible, well-supported, and useful framework that will allow scientists to move beyond studies of bulk SOM, but also use a consistent separation scheme across studies. Ultimately, we propose the POM versus MAOM framework as the best way forward to understand and predict broad-scale SOM dynamics in the context of global change challenges and provide necessary recommendations to managers and policy makers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;interannual-variation-of-terrestrial-carbon-cycle-issues-and-perspectives&quot;&gt;Interannual variation of terrestrial carbon cycle: Issues and perspectives&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Piao, Shilong; Wang, Xuhui; Wang, Kai; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY  Volume: 26   Issue: 1   Pages: 300-318   Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With accumulation of carbon cycle observations and model developments over the past decades, exploring interannual variation (IAV) of terrestrial carbon cycle offers the opportunity to better understand climate-carbon cycle relationships. However, despite growing research interest, uncertainties remain on some fundamental issues, such as the contributions of different regions, constituent fluxes and climatic factors to carbon cycle IAV. Here we overviewed the literature on carbon cycle IAV about current understanding of these issues. Observations and models of the carbon cycle unanimously show the dominance of tropical land ecosystems to the signal of global carbon cycle IAV, where tropical semiarid ecosystems contribute as much as the combination of all other tropical ecosystems. Vegetation photosynthesis contributes more than ecosystem respiration to IAV of the global net land carbon flux, but large uncertainties remain on the contribution of fires and other disturbance fluxes. Climatic variations are the major drivers to the IAV of net land carbon flux. Although debate remains on whether the dominant driver is temperature or moisture variability, their interaction,that is, the dependence of carbon cycle sensitivity to temperature on moisture conditions, is emerging as key regulators of the carbon cycle IAV. On timescales from the interannual to the centennial, global carbon cycle variability will be increasingly contributed by northern land ecosystems and oceans. Therefore, both improving Earth system models (ESMs) with the progressive understanding on the fast processes manifested at interannual timescale and expanding carbon cycle observations at broader spatial and longer temporal scales are critical to better prediction on evolution of the carbon-climate system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;managing-soils-for-resolving-the-conflict-between-agriculture-and-nature-the-hard-talk&quot;&gt;Managing soils for resolving the conflict between agriculture and nature: The hard talk&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Lal, Rattan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF SOIL SCIENCE  Volume: 71   Issue: 1   Pages: 1-9   Published: JAN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among soil-centric options for addressing global issues being intensely debated by soil scientists, ecologists and earth scientists regarding their effectiveness and applicability are: (a) harnessing soil carbon (C) sink capacity for adaptation and mitigation of climate change; (b) reducing soil erosion as a source of greenhouse gases and the need to include it in the global C budget; (c) enhancing use efficiency of inputs to agroecosystems and returning land, water and other resources back to nature; (d) using global drylands, saline culture, halomorphic plants and brackish water for provisioning of ecosystem services; and (e) adopting a system-based conservation agriculture for eco-intensification of agroecosystems as a strategy of “producing more from less”. Not only should agriculture be made a solution for addressing global issues, but it is also essential to reconciling the need for advancing food and nutritional security with the absolute necessity of enhancing the environment, restoring degraded soils and desertified ecosystems, and advancing Sustainable Development Goals or the Agenda 2030. Highlights
Sustainable soil management, degraded soil restoration abridging agronomic yield gap and improving the environment are important to achieve world peace. Sustainable eco-intensification of agro-ecosystems reduces inputs and enhances use efficiency by restoring soil health. Harnessing soil carbon sink capacity includes reducing accelerated soil erosion for adaptation and mitigation of climate change. System-based conservation agriculture sustains agronomic productivity and minimizes soil degradation and environmental pollution.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/02/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on February 06, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>
