<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Smart Digital Agriculture</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2021-11-03T04:46:48+11:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/11/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/11/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-11-04T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-11-04T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-37&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #37&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A transfer function to predict soil surface reflectance from laboratory soil spectral libraries&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using carbonate absorbance peak to select the most suitable regression model before predicting soil inorganic carbon concentration by mid-infrared reflectance spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monitoring soil organic matter on grassland farms: An exploratory analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An integrated approach for the evaluation of quantitative soil maps through Taylor and solar diagrams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Achieving joint calibration of soil Vis-NIR spectra across instruments, soil types and properties by an attention-based spectra encoding-spectra/property decoding architecture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bayesian approach for sample size determination, illustrated with Soil Health Card data of Andhra Pradesh (India)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quantification of soil organic carbon at regional scale: Benefits of fusing vis-NIR and MIR diffuse reflectance data are greater for in situ than for laboratory-based modelling approaches&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The effectiveness of digital soil mapping with temporal variables in modeling soil organic carbon changes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Statistical inference for trends in spatiotemporal data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Predicting Characteristics of the Water Cycle From Scaling Relationships&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil Classification: A New Approach for Grouping Soils Using Unsaturated Hydraulic Conductivity Data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Abuse of Popular Performance Metrics in Hydrologic Modeling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sequestration of soil carbon by burying it deeper within the profile: A theoretical exploration of three possible mechanisms&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How farmers approach soil carbon sequestration? Lessons learned from 105 carbon-farming plans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-farmers-approach-soil-carbon-sequestration-lessons-learned-from-105-carbon-farming-plans&quot;&gt;How farmers approach soil carbon sequestration? Lessons learned from 105 carbon-farming plans&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil carbon sequestration is a recognized climate mitigation method, but it involves changes in the practices of more than 0.5 billion farms worldwide. Regionally customized carbon-farming programs are one way to tailor soil carbon storage to local conditions. We conducted farmer participatory research on 105 Finnish farms to investigate how farmers approach carbon (C) sequestration. We conducted training for farmers in the basics of carbon-farming and instructed them to make a Carbon Farming Plan for one of their fields. The plans were evaluated by a team of experts and through soil C balance calculations. In addition, potential nutrient limitations and the existing C stock were identified from soil tests. Although the existing C stocks were relatively high, an assessment of the plans indicated high potential for additional C storage (median 320 kg C ha(-1)year(-1)). The plans did not show any sensitivity to the existing C stock, with similar C inputs planned for low organic matter (OM) and high OM soils. The farmers either did not know their C stock or were not familiar with the C balance concept. Most soil samples showed considerable nutrient deficiencies (P, S, B and Mn), which can limit C storage. The quality of most plans was adequate for research with minor modifications. The largest C storage potential was estimated for measures with large additions of nutrient-poor amendments or in grazing. Most farmers chose measures with relatively low C storage benefits but high potential benefits for soil structure and productivity (cover crops, nutrient-rich amendments, grassland management). The C gain from some measures (subsoiling, diversity in grasslands) could not be estimated with current methodologies. The magnitude of planned C storage over 5 years on most farms was so small (&amp;lt;0.5% OM), that it is challenging to measure it through soil sampling. This finding supports the earlier conclusions that a combination of modeling and soil sampling is needed to verify the C storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sequestration-of-soil-carbon-by-burying-it-deeper-within-the-profile-a-theoretical-exploration-of-three-possible-mechanisms&quot;&gt;Sequestration of soil carbon by burying it deeper within the profile: A theoretical exploration of three possible mechanisms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subsoil carbon is generally older and decomposes more slowly than topsoil carbon. It has, therefore, been suggested that carbon stocks could be increased by burying carbon-rich topsoil at depth to slow its decomposition. This has been supported by recent experiments that showed that buried topsoil carbon indeed decomposed more slowly, but the mechanisms causing the reduction have not yet been identified. We investigated three theoretical mechanisms that may explain reduced decomposition rates at depth: (1) lower soil-temperature variability, (2) lower oxygen concentrations/redox potential and (3) less priming (biological synergy). Temperature variability decreases with soil depth. As decomposition rates vary non-linearly with temperature, reduced temperature variability should, therefore, reduce annual decomposition rates. However, detailed simulations showed that it changed annual decomposition rates by only a few percent. Maximal decomposition rates also require adequate oxygen, but our simulations showed that oxygen diffusion rates would need to be reduced 1000 to 10 000-fold compared to the topsoil for it to protect buried soil carbon. Oxygen limitation is, therefore, likely to be confined to soils that are water-logged for extended periods. Priming (or biological synergy) is assumed to be the stimulation of decomposition rates by the availability of labile organic carbon. Our simulations showed that lower labile carbon inputs could reduce priming and potentially preserve up to half of buried carbon for centuries. If experimental work can further substantiate the role of this mechanism, carbon burial at depth could become a practical and useful climate-change mitigation option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-abuse-of-popular-performance-metrics-in-hydrologic-modeling&quot;&gt;The Abuse of Popular Performance Metrics in Hydrologic Modeling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this commentary is to critically evaluate the use of popular performance metrics in hydrologic modeling. We focus on the Nash-Sutcliffe Efficiency (NSE) and the Kling-Gupta Efficiency (KGE) metrics, which are both widely used in hydrologic research and practice around the world. Our specific objectives are: (a) to provide tools that quantify the sampling uncertainty in popular performance metrics; (b) to quantify sampling uncertainty in popular performance metrics across a large sample of catchments; and (c) to prescribe the further research that is, needed to improve the estimation, interpretation, and use of popular performance metrics in hydrologic modeling. Our large-sample analysis demonstrates that there is substantial sampling uncertainty in the NSE and KGE estimators. This occurs because the probability distribution of squared errors between model simulations and observations has heavy tails, meaning that performance metrics can be heavily influenced by just a few data points. Our results highlight obvious (yet ignored) abuses of performance metrics that contaminate the conclusions of many hydrologic modeling studies: It is essential to quantify the sampling uncertainty in performance metrics when justifying the use of a model for a specific purpose and when comparing the performance of competing models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-classification-a-new-approach-for-grouping-soils-using-unsaturated-hydraulic-conductivity-data&quot;&gt;Soil Classification: A New Approach for Grouping Soils Using Unsaturated Hydraulic Conductivity Data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grouping soils based on similarities in their textural, taxonomic, and/or structural properties has broad applications to pedology, hydrology, and soil science. In this study, we present a new approach for classifying soils using hydraulic conductivity data. We apply concepts from critical path analysis and calculate critical pore sizes at various water saturations from the unsaturated hydraulic conductivity curves. Soils with similar critical pore size at the same effective water saturation are then grouped into the same class. To demonstrate the practical application of the proposed soil classification method, we use 102 samples including nine soil textures from the UNSODA database. Applying a curve clustering method, we find eight different soil classes within the studied data set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;predicting-characteristics-of-the-water-cycle-from-scaling-relationships&quot;&gt;Predicting Characteristics of the Water Cycle From Scaling Relationships&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over multi-decadal time scales, assuming that changes in subsurface water storage are negligible, the continental precipitative water flux, P, can be divided into two principal components, Q (run-off, including soil infiltration and groundwater recharge) and ET (evapotranspiration). Taking into account a broadly applied Budyko’s phenomenology to describe the relationship of ET/P as a function of PET/P, where PET is the potential evapotranspiration, we propose a theoretical framework for predicting characteristics of the water cycle from scaling relationships. In this framework, the ecosystem net primary productivity is expressed in terms of soil formation and vegetation growth, which is mathematically optimized with respect to the water partitioning, generating directly the value ET/P. The mathematical optimization is based on the general ecological principle that dominant ecosystems tend to be those that, for any given conditions, maximize conversion of atmospheric carbon to biomass. It is shown that application of the results of mathematical optimization to water-limited ecosystems is possible by applying the optimization only to a vegetation covered portion of the surface. For energy-limited ecosystems, the optimization can be applied only to a portion of the precipitation equal to PET, assuming that the remaining P simply runs off. We use theoretical and actual values of plant root fractal dimensionalities, d(f), to predict ranges of ET/P as a function of PET/P for 0 &amp;lt;= PET/P &amp;lt;= 1 and compare with annual and multi-decadal means of ET/P. By comparing the developed approach with a large amount of data collected from the literature, we demonstrate its successful applications to both water- and energy-limited systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-transfer-function-to-predict-soil-surface-reflectance-from-laboratory-soil-spectral-libraries&quot;&gt;A transfer function to predict soil surface reflectance from laboratory soil spectral libraries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spectral-based models extracted from laboratory reflectance in the 400-2500 nm spectral range to predict soil attributes may not be applicable to soil spectra acquired in the field. This is because laboratory sampling procedures disturb the natural soil surface’s status. We investigated this issue by using the soil surface-dependent property of water-infiltration rate (WIR). We created a dataset with 114 samples collected from six fields with varying textures located in three different Mediterranean countries (Israel, Greece, Italy). Using the field and laboratory spectral datasets, we demonstrated that WIR is better predicted by field vs. laboratory measurements (R-2 = 0.92 and 0.56, respectively). We also developed a transfer function (TF) to predict the field spectral measurements from the laboratory spectra. Use of the TF-processed dataset considerably improved the WIR prediction using laboratory information (from R-2 = 0.56 to 0.76). It was concluded that soil surface reflectance values can be estimated based on laboratory spectra using a TF. The generated TF enables exploiting soil spectral libraries for remote-sensing views and for assessing surface-related soil properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-carbonate-absorbance-peak-to-select-the-most-suitable-regression-model-before-predicting-soil-inorganic-carbon-concentration-by-mid-infrared-reflectance-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Using carbonate absorbance peak to select the most suitable regression model before predicting soil inorganic carbon concentration by mid-infrared reflectance spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mid-Infrared reflectance spectroscopy (MIRS, 4000-400 cm(-1)) is being considered to provide accurate estimations of soil inorganic carbon (SIC) contents, based on prediction models when the test dataset is well represented by the calibration set, with similar SIC range and distribution and pedological context. This work addresses the case where the test dataset, here originating from France, is poorly represented by the calibration set, here originating from Tunisia, with different SIC distributions and pedological contexts. It aimed to demonstrate the usefulness of 1) classifying test samples according to SIC level based on the height of the carbonate absorbance peak at 2510 cm(-1), and then 2) selecting a suitable prediction model according to SIC level. Two regression methods were tested: Linear Regression using the height of the carbonate peak at 2510 cm(-)(1), called Peak-LR model; and Partial Least Squares Regression using the entire MIR spectrum, called Full-PLSR model. First, our results showed that Full-PLSR was 1) more accurate than Peak-LR on the Tunisian validation set (R-val(2) = 0.99 vs. 0.86 and RMSEval = 3.0 vs. 9.7 g kg(-1) , respectively), but 2) less accurate than Peak-LR when applied on the French dataset (R-test(2) = 0.70 vs. 0.91 and RMSEtest = 13.7 vs. 4.9 g kg(-1), respectively). Secondly, on the French dataset, predictions on SIC-poor samples tended to be more accurate using Peak-LR, while predictions on SIC-rich samples tended to be more accurate using Full-PLSR. Thirdly, the height of the carbonate absorbance peak at 2510 cm(-1) might be used to discriminate SIC-poor and SIC-rich test samples (&amp;lt;5 vs. &amp;gt; 5 g kg(-1)): when this height was &amp;gt; 0, Full-PLSR was applied; otherwise Peak-LR was applied. Coupling Peak-LR and Full-PLSR models depending on the carbonate peak yielded the best predictions on the French dataset (R-test(2) = 0.95 and RMSEtest = 3.7 g kg(-1)). This study underlined the interest of using a carbonate peak to select suitable regression approach for predicting SIC content in a database with different distribution than the calibration database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;monitoring-soil-organic-matter-on-grassland-farms-an-exploratory-analysis&quot;&gt;Monitoring soil organic matter on grassland farms: An exploratory analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To meet the goals of the Climate Agreement, policy makers consider incentivizing soil carbon sequestration by carbon credits to offset greenhouse gas emissions from agriculture, industry and other sectors. Therefore, the interest in monitoring soil organic matter dynamics is growing rapidly, yet factors affecting the precision of the monitoring results are rarely quantified. We used the rhetorical scheme “The seven circumstances” to structure the methodological aspects of setting up a soil organic matter (SOM) monitoring program. The rhetorical scheme was applied during four years on two grass-based dairy farms in the Netherlands to assess in detail: conversion of SOM weight concentrations to SOM stocks (HOW), the effect of soil depth and the integration of scales field vs. farm (WHERE), and the effect of sampling date and sampling frequency on SOM estimates (WHEN). We found that all three circumstances affect conclusions on SOM stocks or SOM dynamics strongly. Considerable variation was found in the relationship between soil bulk density and SOM weight concentration (i.e. pedotransfer curves) among fields, depth and literature reference equations. Therefore, preferably a site specific pedotransfer curve should be used when comparing SOM stocks based on SOM weight concentrations across sites. Large differences in trends of SOM stock changes over time were found between fields and sampling depths. We conclude that a sampling depth in grassland soils up to 60 cm may be relevant to capture the dynamics in deeper layers. Furthermore, for quantitative underpinning of carbon payment schemes, the whole farm should be monitored rather than a few fields as trends between fields are highly variable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-integrated-approach-for-the-evaluation-of-quantitative-soil-maps-through-taylor-and-solar-diagrams&quot;&gt;An integrated approach for the evaluation of quantitative soil maps through Taylor and solar diagrams&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many decades, soil scientists have produced spatial estimates of soil properties using statistical and non-statistical mapping models. Commonly in soil mapping studies the map quality is assessed through pairwise comparison of observed and predicted values of a soil property, from which statistical indices summarizing the quality of the entire map are computed. Often these indices are based on average error and correlation statistics. In this study, we recommend a more appropriate and effective method of map evaluation by means of Taylor and solar diagrams. Taylor and solar diagrams are summary diagrams exploiting the relationship between statistical indices to visualize differentiable aspects of map quality into a single plot. An important advantage over current map quality evaluation is that map quality can be assessed from the combined effect of a few statistical quantities, not just on the basis of a single index or list of indices. We illustrate the use of common statistical indices and their combination into summary diagrams with a simulation study and two applications on soil data. In the simulation study nine maps with known statistical properties are produced and evaluated with tables and summary diagrams. In the first case study with soil data, change in the quality of a large-scale topsoil organic carbon map is tracked for a number of permutations in the mapping model parameters, whereas in the second case study several maps of topsoil organic carbon content for the same area, made by various statistical and non-statistical models, are compared and evaluated. We consider that in all cases better insights in map quality are obtained with summary diagrams, instead of using a single index or an extensive list of indices. This underpins the importance of using integrated summary graphics to communicate on quantitative map quality so as to avoid excessive trust that a single map quality index may suggest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;achieving-joint-calibration-of-soil-vis-nir-spectra-across-instruments-soil-types-and-properties-by-an-attention-based-spectra-encoding-spectraproperty-decoding-architecture&quot;&gt;Achieving joint calibration of soil Vis-NIR spectra across instruments, soil types and properties by an attention-based spectra encoding-spectra/property decoding architecture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the differences in instruments and measurement methods, soil visible-near infrared (Vis-NIR) spectral data collected worldwide cannot be combined to provide consistent calibration models, reducing the benefit of producing soil spectra libraries. We propose an attention-based spectra encoding-spectra/property decoding model for soil Vis-NIR spectral analysis to solve this problem. By introducing the attention mechanism, the model can use the same parameters to achieve a joint calibration regardless of the length of the input spectral data and the type of soil samples. The model design pays attention to wavelengths combination, which accords to the essence of Vis-NIR analysis. Three datasets, including the LUCAS, Brazilian, and Kenyan datasets, were used to train and test the attention model. An alternative convolution neural network (CNN) encoding architecture that allows joint calibration was also introduced. Comparing with conventional partial least squares regression (PLSR) and CNN encoding model, the present attention model obtained the best results on all three datasets. This is the first time that an attention-based model has been applied to soil Vis-NIR spectra analysis. The model can process spectra data with different sizes and focus on the relation between different wavelengths, providing a joint calibration. It has the potential to become a “one model for all” in soil Vis-NIR spectra research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bayesian-approach-for-sample-size-determination-illustrated-with-soil-health-card-data-of-andhra-pradesh-india&quot;&gt;Bayesian approach for sample size determination, illustrated with Soil Health Card data of Andhra Pradesh (India)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A crucial decision in designing a spatial sample for soil survey is the number of sampling locations required to answer, with sufficient accuracy and precision, the questions posed by decision makers at different levels of geographic aggregation. In the Indian Soil Health Card (SHC) scheme, many thousands of locations are sampled per district. In this paper the SHC data are used to estimate the mean of a soil property within a defined study area, e.g., a district, or the areal fraction of the study area where some condition is satisfied, e.g., exceedence of a critical level. The central question is whether this large sample size is needed for this aim. The sample size required for a given maximum length of a confidence interval can be computed with formulas from classical sampling theory, using a prior estimate of the variance of the property of interest within the study area. Similarly, for the areal fraction a prior estimate of this fraction is required. In practice we are uncertain about these prior estimates, and our uncertainty is not accounted for in classical sample size determination (SSD). This deficiency can be overcome with a Bayesian approach, in which the prior estimate of the variance or areal fraction is replaced by a prior distribution. Once new data from the sample are available, this prior distribution is updated to a posterior distribution using Bayes’ rule. The apparent problem with a Bayesian approach prior to a sampling campaign is that the data are not yet available. This dilemma can be solved by computing, for a given sample size, the predictive distribution of the data, given a prior distribution on the population and design parameter. Thus we do not have a single vector with data values, but a finite or infinite set of possible data vectors. As a consequence, we have as many posterior distribution functions as we have data vectors. This leads to a probability distribution of lengths or coverages of Bayesian credible intervals, from which various criteria for SSD can be derived. Besides the fully Bayesian approach, a mixed Bayesian-likelihood approach for SSD is available. This is of interest when, after the data have been collected, we prefer to estimate the mean from these data only, using the frequentist approach, ignoring the prior distribution. The fully Bayesian and mixed Bayesian-likelihood approach are illustrated for estimating the mean of log-transformed Zn and the areal fraction with Zn-deficiency, defined as Zn concentration &amp;lt;0.9 mg kg(-1), in the thirteen districts of Andhra Pradesh state. The SHC data from 2015-2017 are used to derive prior distributions. For all districts the Bayesian and mixed Bayesian-likelihood sample sizes are much smaller than the current sample sizes. The hyperparameters of the prior distributions have a strong effect on the sample sizes. We discuss methods to deal with this. Even at the mandal (sub-district) level the sample size can almost always be reduced substantially. Clearly SHC over-sampled, and here we show how to reduce the effort while still providing information required for decision-making. R scripts for SSD are provided as supplementary material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quantification-of-soil-organic-carbon-at-regional-scale-benefits-of-fusing-vis-nir-and-mir-diffuse-reflectance-data-are-greater-for-in-situ-than-for-laboratory-based-modelling-approaches&quot;&gt;Quantification of soil organic carbon at regional scale: Benefits of fusing vis-NIR and MIR diffuse reflectance data are greater for in situ than for laboratory-based modelling approaches&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benefits of fusion approaches for visible to near (vis-NIR) and mid-infrared (MIR) chemometric modelling have been studied to some extent for laboratory-based soil studies, but little is known about the usefulness and limitations for in situ studies. Objectives were to compare laboratory-based and in situ vis-NIR and MIR partial least squares (PLS) and bagging-PLS regression approaches and to explore the potentials of combining both types of spectral data for the quantification of soil organic carbon (SOC). We applied different established low-level (spectra concatenation, outer product fusion approach) and high-level (averaging of vis-NIR and MIR modelling results) data fusion methods. The studied set comprised a total of 186 soil samples collected in SaxonyAnhalt and northern Saxony, Central Germany. One subset (Querfurt Plateau) covered 90 finely-textured soils originating from the Chernozem soil region, another (Diiben Heath) with 96 samples was characterized by a wider pedological variety. Vis-NIR and MIR diffuse reflectance spectra were measured in situ on the soil surface and in the laboratory on pre-treated (dried and finely ground) soil material with the ASD FieldSpec 4 and the Agilent 4300 Handheld FTIR instruments. We found a regionally stratified approach to be beneficial for accurate estimations for both laboratory and in situ data. For laboratory spectra, MIR outperformed vis-NIR data in both regions (Querfurt Plateau: r(2) = 0.85 vs. 0.65, RMSE = 0.11 (in % SOC) vs. 0.17; Diiben Heath: 0.77 vs. 0.69 (r(2)) and 0.27 vs. 0.40 (RMSE)). Ranking for in situ data was the same, but accuracies decreased markedly. With MIR, r(2) amounted to 0.58 and RMSE was 0.20 for the Querfurt Plateau (vis-NIR: r(2) = 0.26, RMSE = 0.27); for Diiben Heath, r(2) was 0.60 and RMSE was 0.39 for MIR data, while vis-NIR resulted in an r(2) of 0.53 and an RMSE of 0.43. For the studied samples, which had medium to low water contents (0.68 to 16.8 wt%, median at 5.4 wt%), we found accuracies with both spectral datasets to be similarly affected by in situ conditions. Model ensemble averaging based on bagging-PLS regression was the most efficient approach to improve SOC estimation accuracies with in situ spectral data, whereas model averaging was in general of little effect for laboratory data. Improvements were most marked for the in situ data of the Diiben Heath region, where r(2) increased to a value of 0.77 and RMSE decreased to 0.28. Low-level data fusion methods did not yield any improvements compared to model ensemble averaging. For the latter, we identified averaging with weights derived sample-wise from uncertainties in the bootstrap-based modelling as being most accurate, but with little benefits compared to a simple (unweighted) averaging of vis-NIR and MIR estimates. Our results suggest that already a simple averaging procedure has the potential to advance multi-sensor applications integrating vis-NIR and MIR data for in situ or on-site soil spectroscopy. This applies especially to regions with heterogeneous soil conditions, tied to spectral variablity, as this increases the probability of complementary vis-NIR and MIR information and their prospective fusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-effectiveness-of-digital-soil-mapping-with-temporal-variables-in-modeling-soil-organic-carbon-changes&quot;&gt;The effectiveness of digital soil mapping with temporal variables in modeling soil organic carbon changes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The effectiveness of using changes in environmental conditions to explain the spatiotemporal variability in soil organic carbon (SOC) with digital soil mapping (DSM) requires investigation. In this study, temporal variables representing temporal patterns of climate, vegetation, and land cover factors were explored. Models to predict SOC stocks were developed using a random forest algorithm and data from China during two periods (the 1980s and 2010s). We forecasted and hindcasted the developed models and assessed their temporal projections against temporally independent data. Models were developed for both periods using different sets of variables (with/without temporal variables), and their temporal projections were compared. The important temporal variables were identified by applying the recursive feature elimination algorithm. The results showed that the performances of temporal projections for the 1980s and 2010s were improved by approximately 17% and 47%, respectively, when temporal variables were included in the models. Spatially, the maps of changes in SOC stocks derived from the models that included temporal variables presented stronger associations with temporal changes in climate, vegetation, and land cover than those derived from the models that did not include temporal variables. This work highlights that variation in SOC stocks can be linked to temporal patterns of environmental factors. The findings also provide evidence that the application of temporal patterns of environmental factors to DSM models can be useful for the large-scale prediction of changes in SOC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;statistical-inference-for-trends-in-spatiotemporal-data&quot;&gt;Statistical inference for trends in spatiotemporal data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Global change analyses are facilitated by the growing number of remote-sensing datasets that have both broad spatial extent and repeated observations over decades. These datasets provide unprecedented power to detect patterns of time trends involving information from all pixels on a map. However, rigorously testing for time trends requires a solid statistical foundation to identify underlying patterns and test hypotheses. Appropriate statistical analyses are challenging because environmental data often have temporal and spatial autocorrelation, which can either obscure underlying patterns in the data or suggest false associations between patterns in the data and independent values used to explain them. Existing statistical methods that account for temporal and spatial autocorrelation are not practical for remote-sensing datasets that often contain millions of pixels. Here, we first analyze simulated data to show the need to account for both spatial and temporal autocorrelation in time-trend analyses. Second, we present a new statistical approach, PARTS (Partitioned Autoregressive Time Series), to identify underlying patterns and test hypotheses about time trends using all pixels in large remotesensing datasets. PARTS is flexible and can include, for example, the effects of multiple independent variables, such as land-cover or latitude, on time trends. Third, we use PARTS to analyze global trends in NDVI, focusing on trends in pixels that have not experienced land-cover change. We found that despite the appearance of overall increases in NDVI in all continents, there is little statistical support for these trends except for Asia and Europe, and only in some land-cover classes. Furthermore, we found no overall latitudinal trend in greening for any continent, but some latitude by land-cover class interactions, implying that latitudinal patterns differed among land-cover classes. PARTS makes it possible to identify patterns and test hypotheses that involve the aggregate information from many pixels on a map, thereby increasing the value of existing remote-sensing datasets.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/11/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on November 04, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/11/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/11/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-11-03T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-11-03T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-36&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #36&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Land-use change and biodiversity: Challenges for assembling evidence on the greatest threat to nature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Predicting ecosystem responses by data-driven reciprocal modelling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multi-layer high-resolution soil moisture estimation using machine learning over the United States&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sentinel-1 soil moisture at 1 km resolution: a validation study&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Monitoring Nitrous Oxide Sources (MIN2OS) satellite project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carbon myopia: The urgent need for integrated social, economic and environmental action in the livestock sector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;land-use-change-and-biodiversity-challenges-for-assembling-evidence-on-the-greatest-threat-to-nature&quot;&gt;Land-use change and biodiversity: Challenges for assembling evidence on the greatest threat to nature&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Land-use change is considered the greatest threat to nature, having caused worldwide declines in the abundance, diversity, and health of species and ecosystems. Despite increasing research on this global change driver, there are still challenges to forming an effective synthesis. The estimated impact of land-use change on biodiversity can depend on location, research methods, and taxonomic focus, with recent global meta-analyses reaching disparate conclusions. Here, we critically appraise this research body and our ability to reach a reliable consensus. We employ named entity recognition to analyze more than 4000 abstracts, alongside full reading of 100 randomly selected papers. We highlight the broad range of study designs and methodologies used; the most common being local space-for-time comparisons that classify land use in situ. Species metrics including abundance, distribution, and diversity were measured more frequently than complex responses such as demography, vital rates, and behavior. We identified taxonomic biases, with vertebrates well represented while detritivores were largely missing. Omitting this group may hinder our understanding of how land-use change affects ecosystem feedback. Research was heavily biased toward temperate forested biomes in North America and Europe, with warmer regions being acutely underrepresented despite offering potential insights into the future effects of land-use change under novel climates. Various land-use histories were covered, although more research in understudied regions including Africa and the Middle East is required to capture regional differences in the form of current and historical land-use practices. Failure to address these challenges will impede our global understanding of land-use change impacts on biodiversity, limit the reliability of future projections and have repercussions for the conservation of threatened species. Beyond identifying literature biases, we highlight the research priorities and data gaps that need urgent attention and offer perspectives on how to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;predicting-ecosystem-responses-by-data-driven-reciprocal-modelling&quot;&gt;Predicting ecosystem responses by data-driven reciprocal modelling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Treatment effects are traditionally quantified in controlled experiments. However, experimental control is often achieved at the expense of representativeness. Here, we present a data-driven reciprocal modelling framework to quantify the individual effects of environmental treatments under field conditions. The framework requires a representative survey data set describing the treatment (A or B), its responding target variable and other environmental properties that cause variability of the target within the region or population studied. A machine learning model is trained to predict the target only based on observations in group A. This model is then applied to group B, with predictions restricted to the model’s space of applicability. The resulting residuals represent case-specific effect size estimates and thus provide a quantification of treatment effects. This paper illustrates the new concept of such data-driven reciprocal modelling to estimate spatially explicit effects of land-use change on organic carbon stocks in European agricultural soils. For many environmental treatments, the proposed concept can provide accurate effect size estimates that are more representative than could feasibly ever be achieved with controlled experiments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;multi-layer-high-resolution-soil-moisture-estimation-using-machine-learning-over-the-united-states&quot;&gt;Multi-layer high-resolution soil moisture estimation using machine learning over the United States&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lack of proper understanding of multi-layer soil moisture (SM) profile (signals) remains a persistent challenge in sustainable agricultural water management and food security, especially during drought conditions. We develop a machine-learning algorithm using the concept of learning from patterns to estimate the multi-layer SM information in ungauged locations firmly based on local knowledge of the climatic and landscape controls. The Contiguous United States (CONUS) is clustered into homogeneous regions based on the association between SM and climate and landscape controls. Extreme Gradient Boosting (XGBoost) algorithm is applied to homogenous regions to capture the complex relationship between appropriate predictor variables and in-situ SM at multiple layers over the CONUS. Soil Moisture Active Passive (SMAP) Level 4 (L4) surface (0-5 cm) and rootzone (0-100 cm) SM along with climate and landscape datasets are used as predictor variables. In-situ multi-layer SM recorded by Soil Climate Analysis Network (SCAN), Snow Telemetry (SNOTEL), and U.S. Climate Reference Network (USCRN) networks are utilized as predictands. XGBoost models are then trained region-wise and layer-wise to estimate multi-layer SM information at 5, 10, 20, 50, and 100 cm depths (five layers) at 1-km spatial resolution. Results indicate that the predictor variables have varying levels of influence on SM with changing soil depth, and meteorological variables have the least importance. Validation at 79 independent locations indicates the multi-layer SM estimates successfully capture temporal dynamics of SM, with most locations achieving ubRMSE less than 0.04 m(3)/m(3). The high-resolution SM estimates offer spatial sub-grid heterogeneity compared to SMAP L4 SM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sentinel-1-soil-moisture-at-1-km-resolution-a-validation-study&quot;&gt;Sentinel-1 soil moisture at 1 km resolution: a validation study&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This study presents an assessment of a pre-operational soil moisture product at 1 km resolution derived from satellite data acquired by the European Radar Observatory Sentinel-1 (S-1), representing the first space component of the Copernicus program. The product consists of an estimate of surface soil volumetric water content Theta [m(3)/m(3)] and its uncertainty [m(3)/m(3)], both at 1 km. The retrieval algorithm relies on a time series based Short Term Change Detection (STCD) approach, taking advantage of the frequent revisit of the S-1 constellation that performs C-band Synthetic Aperture Radar (SAR) imaging. The performance of the S-1 Theta product is estimated through a direct comparison between 1068 S-1 Theta images against in situ Theta measurements acquired by 167 ground stations located in Europe, America and Australia, over 4 years between January 2015 and December 2020, depending on the site. The paper develops a method to estimate the spatial representativeness error (SRE) that arises from the mismatch between the S-1 Theta retrieved at 1 km resolution and the in situ point-scale Theta observations. The impact of SRE on standard validation metrics, i.e., root mean square error (RMSE), Pearson correlation (R) and linear regression, is quantified and experimentally assessed using S-1 and ground Theta data collected over a dense hydrologic network (4-5 stations/km(2)) located in the Apulian Tavoliere (Southern Italy). Results show that for the dense hydrological network the RMSE and correlation are similar to 0.06 m(3)/m(3) and 0.71, respectively, whereas for the sparse hydrological networks, i.e., 1 station/km(2), the SRE increases the RMSE by similar to 0.02 m(3)/m(3) (70% Confidence Level). Globally, the S-1 Theta product is characterized by an intrinsic (i.e., with SRE removed) RMSE of similar to 0.07 m(3)/m(3) over the Theta range [0.03, 0.60] m(3)/m(3) and R of 0.54. A breakdown of the RMSE per dry, medium and wet Theta ranges is also derived and its implications for setting realistic requirements for SAR-based Theta retrieval are discussed together with recommendations for the density of in situ Theta observations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-monitoring-nitrous-oxide-sources-min2os-satellite-project&quot;&gt;The Monitoring Nitrous Oxide Sources (MIN2OS) satellite project&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Monitoring Nitrous Oxide Sources (MIN2OS) satellite project aims at monitoring global-scale nitrous oxide (N2O) sources by retrieving N2O surface fluxes from the inversion of space-borne N2O measurements that are sensitive to the lowermost atmospheric layers under favorable conditions. MIN2OS will provide emission estimates of N2O at a horizontal resolution of 1 degrees x 1 degrees on the global scale and 10 x 10 km(2) on the regional scale on a weekly to monthly basis depending on the application (e.g., agriculture, national inventories, policy, scientific research). Our novel approach is based on the development of: 1) a space-borne instrument operating in the Thermal InfraRed domain providing, in clear sky conditions, N2O mixing ratio in the lowermost atmosphere (900 hPa) under favorable conditions (summer daytime) over land and under favorable and unfavorable (winter nighttime) conditions over the ocean and 2) an atmospheric inversion framework to estimate N2O surface fluxes from the atmospheric satellite observations. After studying three N2O spectral bands (B1 at 1240-1350 cm(-1), B2 at 2150-2260 cm(-1) and B3 at 2400-2600 cm(-1)), a new TIR instrument will be developed, centered at 1250-1330 cm(-1), with a resolution of 0.125 cm(-1), a Full Width at Half Maximum of 0.25 cm(-1) and a swath of 300 km. To optimally constrain the retrieval of N2O vertical profiles, the instrument will be on-board a platform at-830 km altitude in a sun-synchronous orbit crossing the Equator in descending node at 09:30 local time in synergy with two other platforms (Metop-SG and Sentinel-2 NG) expected to fly in 2031-32 aiming at detecting surface properties, agricultural information on the field scale and vertical profiles of atmospheric constituents and temperature. The lifetime of the MIN2OS project would be 4-5 years to study the interannual variability of N2O surface fluxes. The spectral noise can be decreased by at least a factor of 5 compared to the lowest noise accessible to date with the Infrared Atmospheric Sounding Interferometer-New Generation (IASI-NG) mission. The N2O total error is expected to be less than similar to 1% (similar to 3 ppbv) along the vertical. The preliminary design of the MIN2OS project results in a small instrument (payload of 90 kg, volume of 1200 x 600 x 300 mm(3)) with, in addition to the spectrometer, a wide field and 1-km resolution imager for cloud detection. The instruments could be hosted on a small platform, the whole satellite being largely compatible with a dual launch on VEGA-C. The MIN2OS project has been submitted to the European Space Agency Earth Explorer 11 mission ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;carbon-myopia-the-urgent-need-for-integrated-social-economic-and-environmental-action-in-the-livestock-sector&quot;&gt;Carbon myopia: The urgent need for integrated social, economic and environmental action in the livestock sector&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Livestock have long been integral to food production systems, often not by choice but by need. While our knowledge of livestock greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions mitigation has evolved, the prevailing focus has been-somewhat myopically-on technology applications associated with mitigation. Here, we (1) examine the global distribution of livestock GHG emissions, (2) explore social, economic and environmental co-benefits and trade-offs associated with mitigation interventions and (3) critique approaches for quantifying GHG emissions. This review uncovered many insights. First, while GHG emissions from ruminant livestock are greatest in low- and middle-income countries (LMIC; globally, 66% of emissions are produced by Latin America and the Caribbean, East and southeast Asia and south Asia), the majority of mitigation strategies are designed for developed countries. This serious concern is heightened by the fact that 80% of growth in global meat production over the next decade will occur in LMIC. Second, few studies concurrently assess social, economic and environmental aspects of mitigation. Of the 54 interventions reviewed, only 16 had triple-bottom line benefit with medium-high mitigation potential. Third, while efforts designed to stimulate the adoption of strategies allowing both emissions reduction (ER) and carbon sequestration (CS) would achieve the greatest net emissions mitigation, CS measures have greater potential mitigation and co-benefits. The scientific community must shift attention away from the prevailing myopic lens on carbon, towards more holistic, systems-based, multi-metric approaches that carefully consider the raison d’etre for livestock systems. Consequential life cycle assessments and systems-aligned ‘socio-economic planetary boundaries’ offer useful starting points that may uncover leverage points and cross-scale emergent properties. The derivation of harmonized, globally reconciled sustainability metrics requires iterative dialogue between stakeholders at all levels. Greater emphasis on the simultaneous characterization of multiple sustainability dimensions would help avoid situations where progress made in one area causes maladaptive outcomes in other areas.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/11/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on November 03, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/11/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/11/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-11-02T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-11-02T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-35&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #35&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The accumulation of microbial necromass carbon from litter to mineral soil and its contribution to soil organic carbon sequestration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spatial variability of soil mineral fractions and bulk density in Northern Ireland: Assessing the influence of topography using different interpolation methods and fractal analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Characterization of soil drainage using electromagnetic induction measurement of soil magnetic susceptibility&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A sensors-based profile heterogeneity index for soil characterization&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transfer functions for phosphorus and potassium soil tests and implications for the QUEFTS model&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To spike or to localize? Strategies to improve the prediction of local soil properties using regional spectral library&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rapid assessment of soil water repellency indices using Vis-NIR spectroscopy and pedo-transfer functions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provoking a Cultural Shift in Data Quality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-accumulation-of-microbial-necromass-carbon-from-litter-to-mineral-soil-and-its-contribution-to-soil-organic-carbon-sequestration&quot;&gt;The accumulation of microbial necromass carbon from litter to mineral soil and its contribution to soil organic carbon sequestration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microbial necromass plays an essential role in soil organic carbon (SOC) accumulation. Nevertheless, how microbial necromass carbon (C) concentrations and their contributions to SOC sequestration change from litter to mineral soil and what factors influence its accumulation remain poorly understood. To address this knowledge gap, we performed a field experiment to investigate the compositional distribution characteristics of microbial necromass C and its contributions to SOC sequestration in an oak forest (Quercus wutaishanica) litter-mineral soil profile of the Chinese Loess Plateau. The present study estimated the microbial necromass C concentrations based on the microbial cell wall’s biomarker amino sugars. Our results demonstrated that microbial necromass C increased from the Oi1 to Oa layers but decreased from the Ah1 to AB horizons. The highest accumulation of microbial necromass C was found at the litter-mineral soil interface (i.e., total microbial necromass in the Oa layer was 39.5 Mg ha(-1), and Ah1 was 22.8 Mg ha(-1)). The contribution of total microbial necromass C to SOC increased from Oi1 to Ah2. Specifically, the total microbial necromass C accounted for 40.7%, 47.7%, and 37.0% of the average bulk SOC in the Ah1, Ah2, and AB horizons of the oak forest mineral soil, respectively. The ratio of fungal to bacterial necromass C decreased from litter to mineral soil, indicating that the relatively higher bacterial necromass C increasingly accumulated in the deeper litter layers and upper mineral soil horizons. Fungal and bacterial necromass C increased with increasing labile organic C, nitrogen (N), and labile inorganic phosphorus (P), suggesting that higher easily accessible soluble nutrients lead to higher microbial biomass levels, which in turn lead to higher microbial necromass accumulation. Overall, our findings suggested that microbial demand for C or N influences the quantity of soluble nutrients and further lead to changes in microbial necromass C decomposition/accumulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spatial-variability-of-soil-mineral-fractions-and-bulk-density-in-northern-ireland-assessing-the-influence-of-topography-using-different-interpolation-methods-and-fractal-analysis&quot;&gt;Spatial variability of soil mineral fractions and bulk density in Northern Ireland: Assessing the influence of topography using different interpolation methods and fractal analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding how topography affects the distribution of soil properties is essential in the management of landscape hydrology and establishment of sustainable soil management practices. This study investigated the impact of topography on the variation in particle size distribution, coarse fragments, and soil bulk density using different interpolation techniques and fractal analysis. It also evaluated the performance of various interpolation techniques in predicting and characterizing the distribution of soil properties. The study was conducted using data from 620 samples extracted from the Tellus and LUCAS databases in Eglinton and Castlederg counties, Northern Ireland. Terrain attributes were obtained at a 30 x 30 m resolution using a global digital elevation model (GDEM) reintroduced to the Universal Transverse Mercator (UTM) projection. Interpolation analyses were conducted using inverse distance weighting (IDW), ordinary kriging (OK), block kriging (BK) and co-kriging (CK). Among the terrain attributes, elevation was the most influential covariate for CK. In addition, fractal analysis was conducted to assess the self-similarity of the soil properties. Prediction accuracy of the interpolation methods was evaluated using the Nash-Sutcliffe efficiency, mean absolute error, index of agreement, and Pearson correlation coefficient. Spatial maps produced from the kriging techniques showed high accuracy in the prediction of soil particle size distribution and bulk density. The use of elevation as an auxiliary variable was successful in producing accurate soil property distribution maps with CK. The fractal parameters showed that the soil properties had short range spatial variability, anti-persistent nature, and strong spatial structure. Additionally, the fractal dimension was strongly correlated with sand, silt and clay contents and bulk density, and weakly correlated with the coarse fragments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;characterization-of-soil-drainage-using-electromagnetic-induction-measurement-of-soil-magnetic-susceptibility&quot;&gt;Characterization of soil drainage using electromagnetic induction measurement of soil magnetic susceptibility&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a physical property of soil, magnetic susceptibility (MS) has been widely used to delineate soil drainage conditions over the past two decades, where all MS values were derived from laboratory measurements. In this paper, the ability of an electromagnetic induction (EMI) instrument, Geonics EM38, in in-field measurements of apparent magnetic susceptibility (MSa or.a) of topsoil was tested on six selected soil profiles having different drainage conditions. The MSa data, measured in both vertical and horizontal coil configurations of EM38, were then inverted using an iterative 1-D inversion procedure to calculate real volume MS of soil layers up to 1 m depth. Moreover, volume and mass-specific MS of the soil profiles were directly measured in laboratory by employing Bartington MS2C and MS2B sensors applied on core and dried soil samples, respectively, collected at the soil profiles. Comparing the results revealed that volume MS profiles derived from inversion of MSa data were positively correlated with MS profiles measured in laboratory, especially at topsoil. It was also found that MS values in poorly drained soil profile were lower than those of a well-drained profile. So, considering that EMI methods are fast, precise and cost-efficient, they would be preferred over conventional methods for delineating soil drainage conditions if using soil MS assessment is considered as soil drainage criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-sensors-based-profile-heterogeneity-index-for-soil-characterization&quot;&gt;A sensors-based profile heterogeneity index for soil characterization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technological and computational development has raised new possibilities for soil scientists to describe and infer about soil-forming processes and functions. Thus, why not to insert the contrasts between soil layers in a profile revealed by proximal sensing? We proposed to study the soil profile heterogeneity by reflectance (Vis-NIR-SWIR), X-ray fluorescence and magnetic susceptibility aiming to quantify it with the proposed “Profile Heterogeneity Index” (PHI) through seven soil sequences in twenty-seven locations over different hillslope positions and parent materials. The study was conducted in a 165-ha farm, at Rio das Pedras municipality, Sao Paulo State, Brazil. The differences between two consecutive soil layers were calculated by subtracting the data to the bottom and the immediately above for each soil profile. The results are depicted as a depth function with proportional colors to highlight the heterogeneity in the soil profiles. This approach provided a new method to identify where the transitions of soil attributes occur exactly and improve the understanding about soil-formation factors and processes. In this study, greater PHI values were mainly related to erosion and redeposition process through the landscape, differences in soil parent materials and also soil-forming processes. The sensors can furnish important and complementary information to the characterization of soil profile heterogeneity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;transfer-functions-for-phosphorus-and-potassium-soil-tests-and-implications-for-the-quefts-model&quot;&gt;Transfer functions for phosphorus and potassium soil tests and implications for the QUEFTS model&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multi-element soil extractions such as Mehlich 3 (M3) have gained popularity in recent years, but comparing outcomes to other soil testing methods is not always straightforward. In this study, extraction mechanisms of M3, Olsen and neutral 1 M ammonium acetate (AA) soil tests were explored and transfer functions were derived between P-Olsen and P-M3 as well as between K-AA and K-M3. Soils from tropical and temperate areas were used to derive these P and K transfer functions and were evaluated separately. The application of these transfer functions for tropical soils was evaluated by using them as input for the Quantitative Evaluation of the Fertility of Tropical Soils (QUEFTS). AA and M3 generally extracted similar amounts of K, but relations between K-AA and K-M3 were different for tropical and temperate soils. For tropical soils, the transfer function did not require additional parameters besides K-M3 to predict K-AA, but for temperate soils inclusion of clay content and pH was needed. This difference between tropical and temperate soils was explained by clay mineralogy. The relation between P-Olsen and P-M3 in tropical soils was found to be dependent on pH, Al-M3, Fe-M3 and Ca-M3. P-Olsen and K-AA values, calculated with their respective transfer functions, were used as input for QUEFTS. The yields predicted with measured P-Olsen and Exch. K were used as benchmark. For 63 out of 81 soil samples, predicted maize yields with transfer functions deviated less than 10% from the benchmark. The largest deviations from the benchmark were found for low P-Olsen and K-AA values, which corresponds to QUEFTS maize yield predictions up to 3000 kg ha(-1). We conclude that a M3 extraction results and soil pH can reliably be transferred to, and thus replace P-Olsen and K-AA determinations with the functions developed for tropical soils. The transfer functions can be used to generate input for the QUEFTS model with minor effects on yield predictions, thus expanding its applicability in cases where only M3 extraction results are available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;to-spike-or-to-localize-strategies-to-improve-the-prediction-of-local-soil-properties-using-regional-spectral-library&quot;&gt;To spike or to localize? Strategies to improve the prediction of local soil properties using regional spectral library&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An increasing number of soil spectral libraries are being developed at larger extents, including at national, continental, and global scales. However, the prediction accuracy of these libraries was often fairly poor when used on local scales. This study evaluates different strategies to improve the model accuracy of a regional spectral library for soil organic carbon prediction in four different local target areas. In total, five strategies using the Partial least squares regression (PLSR) were compared, including the use of local, spiked-regional, spiked-subsetregional and two localized models (memory based learning (MBL) and localized PLSR). MBL derives a new local prediction model based on a subset of the regional spectra similar to the new sample to be predicted. A localized PLSR calibrates a linear regression model using projected scores of the local samples derived from a pre-trained regional PLSR model. Validation results showed that the performances of the spiked models were not much better than those derived from the local and localized models. With &amp;gt;20 local samples, the localized PLSR model performed better than both the local and spiked-regional models. MBL model achieved similar performance to the localized PLSR model. Nevertheless, the accuracy of the models was heavily affected by both the spectral similarity of the data and the statistics of the predictand. Therefore, we recommend localizing the prediction models. Our results also suggest that spiking affected the regression coefficients of the PLSR models but not the loadings, which enabled the compression of spectra data into informative PLS scores. If the local spectra have low similarity to the regional spectral library, building a local spectral library would be more beneficial, assuming the sample size is large enough (&amp;gt;30).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rapid-assessment-of-soil-water-repellency-indices-using-vis-nir-spectroscopy-and-pedo-transfer-functions&quot;&gt;Rapid assessment of soil water repellency indices using Vis-NIR spectroscopy and pedo-transfer functions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil water repellency (SWR) is an important soil physical property that may restrict water infiltration and soil water retention. Common laboratory and field techniques for assessing SWR are laborious, time-consuming, and costly. Meanwhile, Visible-Near-Infrared (Vis-NIR) spectroscopy has been reported as a rapid, cost-effective, and alternative technique to estimate several soil properties. To investigate the efficacy of this technique for predicting SWR indices [soil water repellency index (RI) and soil-water contact angle (beta)] at dry condition, 100 soil samples collected from farmlands, orchards, rangelands and forests of Zrebar lake watershed in Kurdistan province, Iran, were measured by Vis-NIR spectroscopy within the 350-2500 nm range. The Savitzky-Golay first derivative method was applied for denoising the spectral data. The RI and beta were measured by the intrinsic sorptivity method (using water and ethanol as absorbing liquids). The other basic soil properties were also measured by standard laboratory methods. Stepwise multiple linear regression (SMLR) and partial least squares regression (PLSR) were utilized to establish pedo-transfer functions (PTFs) and spectro-transfer functions (STFs) using basic soil properties and spectral absorbance data, respectively, to estimate soil organic matter (SOM) content and SWR indices. We obtained good predictions for SOM with R-2 = 0.67 and RPIQ (the ratio of performance to interquartile range) = 1.92 using the PLSR-based STF. The results also revealed that although the SMLR-based STFs achieved slightly better estimates of the SWR indices (RI and beta) than the SMLR-based PTFs (R-2 values of 0.28 to 0.39 vs. 0.19 to 0.23, respectively); but, overall, none of these transfer functions for estimating these indices showed acceptable predictive capability. However, the PLSR-based STFs could provide a reasonable prediction for the studied SWR indices (R-2 &amp;gt; 0.52 and RPIQ &amp;gt; 2.27). The majority of important adsorption bands in the Vis-NIR PLSR models for the SWR prediction was related to both the quantity and quality of SOM. Overall, the results demonstrated that the Vis-NIR PLSR could be applied to predict SOM and SWR indices rapidly, non-destructively, and with fair accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;provoking-a-cultural-shift-in-data-quality&quot;&gt;Provoking a Cultural Shift in Data Quality&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ecological studies require quality data to describe the nature of ecological processes and to advance understanding of ecosystem change. Increasing access to big data has magnified both the burden and the complexity of ensuring quality data. The costs of errors in ecology include low use of data, increased time spent cleaning data, and poor reproducibility that can result in a misunderstanding of ecosystem processes and dynamics, all of which can erode the efficacy of and trust in ecological research. Although conceptual and technological advances have improved ecological data access and management, a cultural shift is needed to embed data quality as a cultural practice. We present a comprehensive data quality framework to evoke this cultural shift. The data quality framework flexibly supports different collaboration models, supports all types of ecological data, and can be used to describe data quality within both short- and long-term ecological studies.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/11/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on November 02, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/10/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/10/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-10-16T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-10-16T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-34&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #34&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil carbon sequestration potential and the identification of hotspots in the eastern Corn Belt of the United States&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sensitivity and variability of soil health indicators in a California cropping system&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Relating indicators to soil health functions in conventional and organic Mediterranean cropping systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-carbon-sequestration-potential-and-the-identification-of-hotspots-in-the-eastern-corn-belt-of-the-united-states&quot;&gt;Soil carbon sequestration potential and the identification of hotspots in the eastern Corn Belt of the United States&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil C sequestration is a significant CO2 mitigation strategy, but precise assessments of sequestration require spatially explicit modeling of potential changes in soil organic C (SOC) in response to soil, climate, land condition, and management interactions. We assessed the SOC sequestration potential of the eastern Corn Belt (ECB) in the United States (Indiana, Kentucky, Maryland, Michigan, Ohio, Pennsylvania, and West Virginia) in response to the adoption of conservation farming practices and land use change (pasture and forestation) using the SOCRATES model. Input data was provided through an intersection of the State Soil Geographic database, National Land Cover Database, and a PRISM (https://prism.oregonstate.edu) climate surface. At the end of the 20th century, the 15.3 Mha of cropped soils in the ECB contained 632 Tg C, an estimated reduction of 52% since the introduction of agriculture in the mid 1800s. Complete adoption of no-tillage practices on prime cropland would potentially recover 147 Tg SOC over 20 yr, whereas a continuation of conventional tillage would produce a loss of 35 Tg SOC over that period. Sequestration hotspots (&amp;gt;500 Gg increase in SOC) under no-tillage cover 2.3 Mha providing 28 Tg C over 20 yr. The conversion of marginal (nonprime) agricultural lands to forests would yield an additional 13 Tg C in SOC and 381 Tg C in aboveground biomass. The rehabilitation of minelands to forest would yield an additional 4 Tg C in SOC and 42 Tg C in biomass. Opportunities to sequester C in the ECB via tillage and reforestation are substantial and should be incorporated into regional and national climate change mitigation strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sensitivity-and-variability-of-soil-health-indicators-in-a-california-cropping-system&quot;&gt;Sensitivity and variability of soil health indicators in a California cropping system&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An indicator that is used to monitor whether a management practice is improving soil health must be sensitive to management changes. However, it should not be overly influenced by variations in sampling time or location, previous crop, or annual differences in weather or operations timing. In this study, we assessed the sensitivity and variability of several soil health indicators in long-term plots under typical farming practices in a Mediterranean climate. These plots have been conventionally or organically farmed in a corn (Zea mays L.)-processing tomato (Solanum lycopersicum L.) rotation for 25 yr. We sampled in both crop phases prior to planting and midseason for two consecutive years, analyzing subsamples taken from three adjacent locations per plot. Management was the most significant factor differentiating most indicators, particularly indicators of biological processes and C accumulation. Whereas management differences were consistent across sampling times, average indicator values for a management system often varied significantly between dates and years. Crop phases, conversely, were usually similar. Accounting for soil texture increased management sensitivity for aggregate stability and most C accumulation indicators. Sensitive indicators such as mineral N, particulate organic matter C, and mineralizable C had greater subsample variability than indicators measuring large, stable pools, such as total C. Our results show that indicators relating to organic C and biological processes most strongly differentiated the two systems, and underline the importance of using consistent sampling dates. They also suggest that an indicator dataset including both stable and sensitive indicators may be the most reliable to interpret.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;relating-indicators-to-soil-health-functions-in-conventional-and-organic-mediterranean-cropping-systems&quot;&gt;Relating indicators to soil health functions in conventional and organic Mediterranean cropping systems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accurate assessment of the benefits of soil health building practices to soil function and crop performance requires region-specific data and locally relevant indicators. In this study, we used a long-term experiment to measure the effect of 25 yr of differing management on soil health and crop performance indicators in organic and conventionally farmed annual crops in a Mediterranean climate. We measured the strength and consistency of the relationships between several indicators and three functions of a healthy agroecosystem-C storage, net N mineralization, and yields-over two growing seasons and two crop types. Lastly, we used path analysis to test the hypothesis that healthier soils lead to healthier plants and higher yields. Organic plots had greater C stocks and net N mineralization compared with the conventional plots, but lower yields. The path analysis suggested that yields were limited by factors other than N deficiency. The relationships between soil health indicators and soil function were unaffected by crop type but were moderated by yearly changes in weather and operations timing. The indicators most strongly and consistently related to C stocks were permanganate oxidizable C and microbial biomass C, and to N mineralization were CO2 mineralized from rewet soil and fluorescein diacetate hydrolysis. Our results highlight that (a) different indicators are appropriate for assessing different aspects of soil health, (b) using several years of data in developing robust ranges for indicator interpretation is important, and (c) links between soil and crop health must be assessed mechanistically within a given system.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/10/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on October 16, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/10/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/10/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-10-15T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-10-15T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-33&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #33&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Satellite Earth observation to support sustainable rural development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An overview of agriculture 4.0 development: Systematic review of descriptions, technologies, barriers, advantages, and disadvantages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How sustainable is sustainable intensification? Assessing yield gaps at field and farm level across the globe&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Additive effects of organic and inorganic amendments can significantly improve structural stability of a sodic dispersive subsoil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does biochar application alleviate soil compaction? Review and data synthesis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To standardize by mass of soil or organic carbon? A comparison of permanganate oxidizable carbon (POXC) assay methods&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spatial extrapolation of topographic models for mapping soil organic carbon using local samples&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Empirical estimation of soil temperature and its controlling factors in Australia: Implication for interaction between geographic setting and air temperature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;satellite-earth-observation-to-support-sustainable-rural-development&quot;&gt;Satellite Earth observation to support sustainable rural development&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditional survey and census data are not sufficient for measuring poverty and progress towards achieving the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). Satellite Earth Observation (EO) is a novel data source that has considerable potential to augment data for sustainable rural development. To realise the full potential of EO data as a proxy for socioeconomic conditions, end-users - both expert and non-expert - must be able to make the right decisions about what data to use and how to use it. In this review, we present an outline of what needs to be done to operationalise, and increase confidence in, EO data for sustainable rural development and monitoring the socioeconomic targets of the SDGs. We find that most approaches developed so far operate at a single spatial scale, for a single point in time, and proxy only one socioeconomic metric. Moreover, research has been geographically focused across three main regions: West Africa, East Africa, and the Indian Subcontinent, which underscores a need to conduct research into the utility of EO for monitoring poverty across more regions, to identify transferable EO proxies and methods. A variety of data from different EO platforms have been integrated into such analyses, with Landsat and MODIS datasets proving to be the most utilised to-date. Meanwhile, there is an apparent underutilisation of fusion capabilities with disparate datasets, in terms of (i) other EO datasets such as RADAR data, and (ii) non-traditional datasets such as geospatial population layers. We identify five key areas requiring further development to encourage operational uptake of EO for proxying socioeconomic conditions and conclude by linking these with the technical and implementational challenges identified across the review to make explicit recommendations. This review contributes towards developing transparent data systems to assemble the high-quality data required to monitor socioeconomic conditions across rural spaces at fine temporal and spatial scales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-overview-of-agriculture-40-development-systematic-review-of-descriptions-technologies-barriers-advantages-and-disadvantages&quot;&gt;An overview of agriculture 4.0 development: Systematic review of descriptions, technologies, barriers, advantages, and disadvantages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agriculture 4.0 upgrades traditional production methods and world agriculture strategies to an optimized value chain using a range of emerging technologies that enhance disruptive solutions at all stages of the agricultural production chain. Due to the complexity of the changing farm ecosystem, the new technological revolution’s benefits will not be shared evenly. It is necessary to understand the problems and challenges that need to be addressed so that all countries fully benefit from the potential of agriculture 4.0. This study aims to contribute to the development of agriculture 4.0 by identifying descriptions, technologies, barriers, advantages, and disadvantages. Three independent researchers carried out a Systematic Literature Review based on the Protocol of Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses. After applying the inclusion and exclusion criteria pre-established in the Scopus, Science Direct, and Web of Science databases, 50 articles were selected for analysis. As a result, it was possible to identify the descriptions of agriculture 4.0, propose a definition, and present a compilation of approaches related to the term. Technologies of agriculture 4.0, responsible for revolutionizing and impacting how commodities are produced, processed, traded, and consumed, were also surveyed. Moreover, the barriers that hinder the development of agriculture 4.0 and that limit its progress are listed. The barriers were classified into five dimensions: technological, economic, political, social, and environmental. These are issues that need to be resolved in different areas to achieve a larger scale in countries looking to implement agriculture 4.0. Finally, this study’s findings support actors in the agricultural production chain and pave the way for the successful development of agriculture 4.0. Besides, research helps broaden the inclusive debate that can shape the introduction of agriculture 4.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-sustainable-is-sustainable-intensification-assessing-yield-gaps-at-field-and-farm-level-across-the-globe&quot;&gt;How sustainable is sustainable intensification? Assessing yield gaps at field and farm level across the globe&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sustainable intensification has been proposed as a pathway to achieve food security and reduce environmental impacts of agriculture by focusing on narrowing yield gaps on existing agricultural land while improving resource use efficiencies. There is a general consensus that regions with large yield gaps can benefit most from sustainable intensification but it remains unclear how sustainable this is for farmers given their current resource constraints and livelihood strategies. Here, we draw upon three contrasting case studies, for which detailed data at field and farm levels were available for yield gap decomposition, to assess how sustainable intensification of crops (at field level) works out at farm level using environmental and socio-economic indicators. Although there is large potential for future intensification (more output with more input) of cereal production in southern Ethiopia, current input use in these farming systems is not economically and environmentally sustainable at farm level. The same is true for rice production in Central Luzon where sustainable intensification (more output with less input) can help to narrow yield gaps and improve N use efficiency (NUE) but it is not profitable due to the heavy reliance on costly hired labour. Trade-offs between yield gap closure and labour productivity were also observed in the aforementioned farming systems. Arable farms in the Netherlands exhibit small yield gaps as well as higher economic performance, NUE and N surplus compared to those observed in Southern Ethiopia and Central Luzon. For improving environmental sustainability, these farms require increases in resource-use efficiency and a reduction of the environmental impacts through a lower use of inputs (same output with less input). We conclude that public investments conducive for innovation and profitable farming are essential to make technologies accessible and affordable for farmers and to ensure that yield gaps can be narrowed and sustainability objectives served at the farm level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;additive-effects-of-organic-and-inorganic-amendments-can-significantly-improve-structural-stability-of-a-sodic-dispersive-subsoil&quot;&gt;Additive effects of organic and inorganic amendments can significantly improve structural stability of a sodic dispersive subsoil&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sodic dispersive subsoils pose significant constraints to agricultural productivity and sustainability in arid and semiarid regions. Gypsum and organic amendments (OAs) have shown the potential to improve soil structure and fertility and may address constraints associated with these dispersive soils. However, the mechanistic linkages between the quality of OAs, and the dynamics of soil structural stability (i.e., soil aggregates), particularly under the interactive impacts of gypsum and exogenous nutrients, remain elusive. We quantified aggregate stability (i.e., wet mean weight diameter, WMWD) and the accumulation of OA-carbon (C) in different aggregate-classes in a dispersive clay subsoil (delta C-13 -24.5 parts per thousand) with or without the application of OAs (delta C-13 -12.8 to -14.3 parts per thousand), gypsum and/or exogenous nutrients (nitrogen (N) and phosphorus (P)) over the 270 days incubation period. The OAs include sorghum stubble and sugarcane bagasse that were low C quality (e.g., C:N:P ratio of 328:6.2:1 and 850:17.3:1, respectively) and less decomposed (e.g., low alkyl-C/o-alkyl-C ratio), and sugarcane mill mud that was high C quality (C:N:P ratio of 17:1.4:1) and more decomposed status. The results suggest that the quality of OAs is likely to control the dominant mechanisms of soil aggregation: (i) a quick top-down formation of aggregate hierarchy (similar to 31 days) in the low C quality and less decomposed OAs; and (ii) a slow bottom-up formation of aggregate hierarchy (&amp;gt;= 90 days) in the high C-quality and more decomposed OA. Over time, lowering the C-nutrient stoichiometric ratio of OAs (via exogenous nutrients) decreased aggregate stability by 30%, owing to accelerated breakdown/loss of OAs (i.e., by 16%). The exchangeable Ca2+ (from gypsum) was positively correlated to WMWD and water stable aggregates (&amp;gt;0.05 mm), which were not influenced by OAs or nutrients. In this dispersive clay subsoil, a long-term positive effect on soil aggregation occurred when improving either biochemical properties (e.g., microbial biomass and soil organic C) or chemical properties (e.g., soil dispersion, exchangeable sodium percentage, and pH), and an additive effect appeared when both properties were changed. This study provides critical information on the effects of OAs with variable C qualities, gypsum, and nutrients on structural stability with insights into strategies of sodic subsoil amelioration and soil C storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;does-biochar-application-alleviate-soil-compaction-review-and-data-synthesis&quot;&gt;Does biochar application alleviate soil compaction? Review and data synthesis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biochar is considered to enhance numerous soil ecosystem services, but whether it alleviates soil compaction is not well known. This paper: 1) synthesizes the biochar impacts on soil compaction parameters including bulk density, penetration resistance, aggregate tensile strength, Proctor maximum bulk density (soil compactability), and the water content at which the Proctor maximum bulk density occurs (critical water content), 2) discusses potential factors affecting biochar performance, and 3) compares the impacts of biochar on soil compaction with those of other amendments. Literature indicates that biochar generally reduces bulk density, tensile strength, and Proctor maximum bulk density; and increases the critical water content but may or may not reduce penetration resistance. Biochar reduces bulk density from 1% to 20% (-8.8% average), tensile strength from 8 to 72% (-31% average), and Proctor maximum bulk density from 1 to 19% (-9.3% average), whereas it increases the critical water content from 1 to 64% (21% average). The increase in critical water content suggests soils with biochar can be trafficked at higher water content without causing compaction than soils without biochar. An increase in biochar application rate reduces soil compaction and explains 11% to 63% of the variability in compaction parameters, but biochar benefits can be short-lived (&amp;lt;2 yr). It appears that, in general, at least 10 Mg ha 1 of biochar are needed to significantly reduce compaction. Larger application rates (&amp;gt;20 Mg ha 1) can be needed for reducing penetration resistance and Proctor maximum bulk density than for other compaction parameters. Biochar has similar benefits to manure for reducing soil bulk density and can complement other organic amendments for reducing soil compaction. How biochar feedstock, pyrolysis temperature; and companion amendments; and soil texture influence biochar impacts on compaction is still unclear. Overall, biochar has the potential to alleviate soil compaction, but more long-term field data, particularly on penetration resistance, Proctor maximum bulk density, and critical water content for multiple biochar application rates, feedstocks, pyrolysis temperature; and amendments are needed to better elucidate biochar effects, biochar longevity, and optimum levels of biochar application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;to-standardize-by-mass-of-soil-or-organic-carbon-a-comparison-of-permanganate-oxidizable-carbon-poxc-assay-methods&quot;&gt;To standardize by mass of soil or organic carbon? A comparison of permanganate oxidizable carbon (POXC) assay methods&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of permanganate oxidizable carbon (POXC) as a soil health indicator has gained traction due to its low analysis cost and potential for high-throughput analysis. Permanganate (MnO4-) has long been proposed to fractionate soil organic matter. A methodological alteration was proposed to allow for its use as a rapid soil health indicator (POXC) is to allow the MnO4- to reach with a fixed soil mass, rather than a fixed mass of soil organic carbon (SOC). However, this modification may compromise the robustness of the results by altering the consistency of the stoichiometry in the reduction-oxidation reaction (MnO4- : SOC). Here we use a diverse set of 69 U.S. soils to evaluate whether using a fixed soil mass (2.5 g) substantively undermines the theoretical requirement of a fixed amount of SOC (15 or 25 mg SOC per sample) per unit of oxidant (MnO4-). We found that the use of a fixed SOC mass entailed a more consistent reduction of MnO4- than a fixed soil mass and also resulted in a greater range of absolute (mg kg(-1)) and relative POXC values (as a % of SOC) across soils. This broader range of values was not driven by large differences in the amount of MnO4- reduced per unit of SOC analyzed, but rather resulted from normalizing the amount of MnO4- reduced on a soil mass basis. The underlying distribution of MnO4- reduction did not substantively change, suggesting that the interpretation when comparing relative differences in POXC would similarly be unchanged. Unexpectedly, the use of a fixed SOC mass decreased the repeatability of the metric relative to the use of a fixed soil mass. Given the current interpretation of POXC, we see few upsides of using fixed SOC mass and several downsides (i.e. lower throughput and decreased reliability), relative to the current use of a fixed soil mass. To minimize unfounded assumptions, we further propose that POXC values be reported strictly as MnO4- reduced, specifically as mu mol MnO4- reduced kg(-1) soil. Our results further underscore that the results of POXC assays should be cautiously interpreted. Specifically, interpretations should be qualified by the operationally-defined nature of the POXC assay as an indirectly measured, chemically defined fraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spatial-extrapolation-of-topographic-models-for-mapping-soil-organic-carbon-using-local-samples&quot;&gt;Spatial extrapolation of topographic models for mapping soil organic carbon using local samples&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accurate prediction of soil organic carbon (SOC) at fine scales is frequently limited by data availability but finescale maps of soil properties are often of great importance for local agricultural land management and watershed processes assessment. Terrain attributes derived from elevation have been commonly used predictor variables in SOC mapping. The aim of this study is to map SOC density (0-30 cm) using hybrid methods that combine regional topographic models and a residual kriging procedure using local samples from an area of interest and evaluate the effects of different sampling designs for residual kriging on final map quality. The regional topographic model was developed based on light detection and ranging (lidar)-derived topographic covariates using random forest to map SOC density on a cropland site intensively sampled for SOC (n = 224). To test ability to generate a local calibration of this regional model, a second intensively sampled cropland site (n = 225) was used to generate a reference SOC density map where residual kriging was implemented involving different numbers of local samples (n = 10-255) and different sample selection schemes: stratified random sampling (SRS) and spatial coverage sampling with close-pairs inclusions (SCS+). To generate a population of local sample sets, 500 repeats were conducted for each scheme from the reference map. By analyzing the distribution of relative mean error (RME) of the overall map for the second site with repeated selection of local samples, we found a smaller variation in RME for SCS+ than that for SRS for a given sample size. However, the E(RME) estimates for SCS+ slightly varied with number of local samples used while the E(RME) for SRS was stabilized at zero over that range in local sampling intensity. There was negligible difference between the distributions of RME for the two sampling schemes at individual points, except a finding of somewhat lower RME for SCS+ based point estimates. These results indicate that SCS+ can generate smaller variation in overall map quality while SRS can provide unbiased mean estimate for an area of interest. This study demonstrates the utility of extrapolating a regional topographic model by use of a limited number of new samples for local calibration and provides insight for practitioners who are interested in mapping soil carbon distribution in sparsely sampled areas of interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;empirical-estimation-of-soil-temperature-and-its-controlling-factors-in-australia-implication-for-interaction-between-geographic-setting-and-air-temperature&quot;&gt;Empirical estimation of soil temperature and its controlling factors in Australia: Implication for interaction between geographic setting and air temperature&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil temperature is a key parameter affecting changes in the balance among energy flow, water flow, nutrient cycling, and ecological stability. In previous research on soil temperature estimation, field measurement has been valuable. However its value is uncertain for regional scale research. A regression equation algorithm approach introduces the environmental factors into consideration. The correlations between soil temperature and environmental covariates may not be linear, and most of them conform to a parabolic relationship. Therefore, based on 53 years’ data (1958-2010) from 140 meteorological stations in Australia, this study applied a 3-parameter cosine wave model to fit the monthly air and soil temperature. Further, this study identified the correlations between the parameters and landscape factors using stepwise regression. The root mean square error (RMSE) and Nash-Sutcliffe efficiency coefficient (NS) were used to evaluate the accuracy of the model. The results showed that: (1) The cosine-wave function can effectively identify the monthly air/soil temperature fluctuation and the prediction accuracy increases gradually from north to south in Australia. (2) The precipitation, horizontal irradiation and elevation are predominant factors that affecting soil temperature fluctuation given a defined air temperature fluctuation. (3) Landscape factors regulate the hysteresis of air/soil temperature fluctuation. The hysteresis of soil temperature response to air temperature in Australia is in order of duration: central &amp;gt; south &amp;gt; north. Therefore, the application of the cosine function is a useful and novel technique for estimation of soil temperature, which could provide better understanding of how soil temperature fluctuation responds to the global warming.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/10/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on October 15, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/10/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/10/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-10-14T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-10-14T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-32&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #32&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Classification, segmentation and correlation of zoned minerals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leveraging observed soil heterotrophic respiration fluxes as a novel constraint on global-scale models&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Important constraints on soil organic carbon formation efficiency in subtropical and tropical grasslands&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tomography in Soil Science: From the First Experiments to Modern Methods (A Review)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The unexplored role of preferential flow in soil carbon dynamics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;classification-segmentation-and-correlation-of-zoned-minerals&quot;&gt;Classification, segmentation and correlation of zoned minerals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minerals exhibit compositional zoning patterns that can be related to changes in the environment in which they grew. Using statistical methods that have been designed to segment optical images, we have developed a procedure to segment zoned crystals using elemental maps. For a single mineral phase, compositional zones in individual crystals are correlated between multiple crystals. This allows us to quantify the complexity and variability of chemical zoning between different geological samples. Specifically, we employ a simple linear iterative clustering algorithm, which splits the chemical maps into spatially constrained regions of similar chemistry. The result is a texturally segmented crystal, akin to what would be identified by the human eye. To aid the segmentation and correlation of zones, we also introduce a new method to classify multiple mineral phases within a single thin section. This is based on a finite mixture model approach, which proves very effective in removing mixed pixels that will only introduce noise into the segmentation. We provide an example using the mineral phase plagioclase. Using two contemporaneous samples from an eruptive unit on the island of St. Kitts (Eastern Caribbean) we show that a volcanic bomb (-10 cm) and a scoria clast (-2 cm) have similar rim compositions but distinctly different core compositions. Our methodology will enable a statistical characterization of 2D complexity of crystals in a variety of different geo-scientific disciplines. This will allow the genesis of different mineral phases to be directly compared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;leveraging-observed-soil-heterotrophic-respiration-fluxes-as-a-novel-constraint-on-global-scale-models&quot;&gt;Leveraging observed soil heterotrophic respiration fluxes as a novel constraint on global-scale models&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microbially explicit models may improve understanding and projections of carbon dynamics in response to future climate change, but their fidelity in simulating global-scale soil heterotrophic respiration (R-H), a stringent test for soil biogeochemical models, has never been evaluated. We used statistical global R-H products, as well as 7821 daily site-scale R-H measurements, to evaluate the spatiotemporal performance of one first-order decay model (CASA-CNP) and two microbially explicit biogeochemical models (CORPSE and MIMICS) that were forced by two different input datasets. CORPSE and MIMICS did not provide any measurable performance improvement; instead, the models were highly sensitive to the input data used to drive them. Spatial variability in R-H fluxes was generally well simulated except in the northern middle latitudes (similar to 50 degrees N) and arid regions; models captured the seasonal variability of R-H well, but showed more divergence in tropic and arctic regions. Our results demonstrate that the next generation of biogeochemical models shows promise but also needs to be improved for realistic spatiotemporal variability of R-H. Finally, we emphasize the importance of net primary production, soil moisture, and soil temperature inputs, and that jointly evaluating soil models for their spatial (global scale) and temporal (site scale) performance provides crucial benchmarks for improving biogeochemical models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;important-constraints-on-soil-organic-carbon-formation-efficiency-in-subtropical-and-tropical-grasslands&quot;&gt;Important constraints on soil organic carbon formation efficiency in subtropical and tropical grasslands&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than 10% of Australia’s 49 M ha of grassland is considered degraded, prompting widespread interest in the management of these ecosystems to increase soil carbon (C) sequestration-with an emphasis on long-lived C storage. We know that management practices that increase plant biomass also increase C inputs to the soil, but we lack a quantitative understanding of the fate of soil C inputs into different soil organic carbon (SOC) fractions that have fundamentally different formation pathways and persistence in the soil. Our understanding of the factors that constrain SOC formation in these fractions is also limited, particularly within tropical climates. We used isotopically labelled residue (C-13) to determine the fate of residue C inputs into short-lived particulate organic matter (POM) and more persistent mineral-associated organic matter (MAOM) across a broad climatic gradient (Delta MAT 10 degrees C) with varying soil properties. Climate was the primary driver of aboveground residue mass loss which corresponded to higher residue-derived POM formation. In contrast, MAOM formation efficiency was constrained by soil properties. The differential controls on POM and MAOM formation highlight that a targeted approach to grassland restoration is required; we must identify priority regions for improved grazing management in soils that have a relatively high silt+clay content and cation exchange capacity, with a low C saturation in the silt+clay fraction to deliver long-term SOC sequestration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tomography-in-soil-science-from-the-first-experiments-to-modern-methods-a-review&quot;&gt;Tomography in Soil Science: From the First Experiments to Modern Methods (A Review)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract- The article provides an overview of the use of computed tomography in the study of soils from the first works to the present time. The development of computed tomography in the field of hardware and methods for processing tomographic data-from the first attempts to analyze soil structure using tomographic sections of low quality to modern methods of segmentation and analysis of volumetric structures using specialized software, correlation functions and neural networks-is discussed. The purpose of the article is to show the possibilities of methods for processing tomographic data in relation to studies of soil structure and to analyze possible trends of their further development. The article presents examples from the world experience of using computed tomography for a broad variety of soils, shows various methods of data segmentation that have been used from the first studies to the recent ones. The specific terminology coined in the course of the evolution of the method and various morphometric indicators for 2D and 3D images are presented, and a forecast of the prospects for the method in the near future is given.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-unexplored-role-of-preferential-flow-in-soil-carbon-dynamics&quot;&gt;The unexplored role of preferential flow in soil carbon dynamics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Water is a crucial factor controlling the fate and processing of soil organics. Water commonly flows through the vadose zone via preferential flow pathways, resulting in nonuniform and rapid infiltration. Hence, a large portion of the soil matrix is bypassed. Preferential flow paths, often associated with well-connected macropore networks (&amp;gt;300 pm 0), offer a unique balance between water availability, nutrient delivery, and re-oxygenation upon drainage. The heightened concentrations of moisture, nutrients, and oxygen make these locations optimal for high rates of microbial activity. Flow paths often display temporal stability. This stability results in repeated wetting and biogeochemical reactivation through time creating a lasting impact on micro-environmental conditions relevant to microbial functioning and carbon cycling in soil. Despite decades of research on preferential flow, there is still a need to link flow paths and the resultant heterogeneous moisture distributions to soil function. In this review, we discuss how preferential flow can serve as a framework of reference for the spatially and temporally heterogeneous biogeochemical cycling of soil carbon. We highlight the importance of combining current knowledge of pore-scale carbon dynamics with an appreciation of connected networks of hydraulically active pores/paths within the soil profile. Such combination opens new possibilities for upscaling pore-scale processes with the inclusion of resource heterogeneity at the macroscale. Working within this hydraulically connected framework can provide insight for the mechanistic representation of hot moments, which are temporally isolated large pulses of CO2 after rewetting or thawing events. We conclude with suggestions on knowledge gaps and stress the critical need of linking soil physics with biology to mechanistically understand soil functions.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/10/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on October 14, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/09/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/09/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-09-21T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-09-21T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-31&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #31&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A clean energy future isn’t set in stone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Numerical soil horizon classification from South Africa’s legacy database&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spatial variability-based sample size allocation for stratified sampling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil nutrients increase long-term soil carbon gains threefold on retired farmland&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linking decomposition rates of soil organic amendments to their chemical composition&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Papatuanuku, Earth Mother: indigenous knowledge in 21st century soil management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-clean-energy-future-isnt-set-in-stone&quot;&gt;A clean energy future isn’t set in stone&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social scientists and geoscientists must work together to critically evaluate and develop feasible visions for a sustainable future. Is a clean-energy economy more viable than a degrowth future?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;numerical-soil-horizon-classification-from-south-africas-legacy-database&quot;&gt;Numerical soil horizon classification from South Africa’s legacy database&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allocation of soil profiles to one or another soil class depends on the surveyor’s experience and knowledge. Inconsistent class designations can affect the downstream uses of soil information such as hydrological and ecological applications. Therefore, numerical classifications can be useful in creating property-based soil clusters. Quantitative classification of soil horizons can also be beneficial for guiding physicochemical thresholds used in taxonomic criteria. This study aimed at taking a step in applying numerical classification techniques to the South African soil legacy database to quantitatively cluster horizons. For each master horizon, the database was clustered into new “diagnostic” horizons through Partitioning Around Medoids (PAM) implemented in the Clustering Large Applications algorithm (CLARA). This algorithm has the benefit of using multiple subsets of the data making a more reliable initiation of medoids and it is a non-parametric approach making it more robust to outliers. To determine the optimal number of clusters, the silhouette width for 1 through 11 clusters was calculated. The number of clusters with the largest silhouette width was taken as the optimal number of clusters. The results of this study show that for O, E, and G (gleyed) horizons, the algorithm performs relatively well with the first two principle components capturing almost half of the variation in the data. However, for the A, B, and C horizons, the algorithm struggled to separate clusters sufficiently. The A horizon clusters only broadly corresponded to environmental factors (geography, climate, elevation, and geology) and the large clusters straddled numerous taxonomic thresholds. Moreover, the B horizon clusters correspond relatively well with environmental factors. Limitations identified, include bias in geographic location of modal soil profiles of the database, bias in the South African classification system, how to handle non-globular clusters, and outliers which add leverage to the clusters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spatial-variability-based-sample-size-allocation-for-stratified-sampling&quot;&gt;Spatial variability-based sample size allocation for stratified sampling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stratified sampling is one of the most commonly used sampling strategies for soil survey and mapping. An important issue in stratified sampling is the sample size allocation for each stratum. Neyman allocation is a typical sample size allocation approach in which the main idea is to assign more samples to a stratum with a larger internal standard deviation. By applying the spatial variability for sample size allocation, we proposed a new allocation approach (SVNA) for stratified spatial sampling. In this new approach, more samples were allocated to strata with both a bigger statistical standard deviation and larger spatial variability of the target variable. SVNA was evaluated using a simulated experiment based on real-world soil data of Jiangsu province, China. The target variable was soil organic matter (SOM), and land-use type was utilized for stratification. Simple random sampling (SRS) and spatial simulated annealing algorithm (SSA) were applied to determine sample locations. Results showed that the performance of SVNA generally was superior to Neyman allocation in terms of SOM content prediction at all sampling densities (4.28-0.19 points per km(2)) regardless of the application of SRS or SSA for sample location determination. The maximum reduction of mean squared error (MSE) for the SOM content prediction using SVNA was 11% using SRS and was 10% using SSA. Compared with Neyman allocation, SVNA obtained greater prediction accuracies in strata with large spatial variability and similar or slightly smaller prediction accuracies for strata with small spatial variability. Furthermore, the prediction accuracy of the SVNA approach tended to decrease when the sampling density was 0.37 points per km(2), and this sampling density threshold was not the same for each stratum. We concluded that SVNA is an efficient sample size allocation approach for stratified sampling in soil survey and mapping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-nutrients-increase-long-term-soil-carbon-gains-threefold-on-retired-farmland&quot;&gt;Soil nutrients increase long-term soil carbon gains threefold on retired farmland&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abandoned agricultural lands often accumulate soil carbon (C) following depletion of soil C by cultivation. The potential for this recovery to provide significant C storage benefits depends on the rate of soil C accumulation, which, in turn, may depend on nutrient supply rates. We tracked soil C for almost four decades following intensive agricultural soil disturbance along an experimentally imposed gradient in nitrogen (N) added annually in combination with other macro- and micro-nutrients. Soil %C accumulated over the course of the study in unfertilized control plots leading to a gain of 6.1 Mg C ha(-1) in the top 20 cm of soil. Nutrient addition increased soil %C accumulation leading to a gain of 17.8 Mg C ha(-1) in fertilized plots, nearly a threefold increase over the control plots. These results demonstrate that substantial increases in soil C in successional grasslands following agricultural abandonment occur over decadal timescales, and that C gain is increased by high supply rates of soil nutrients. In addition, soil %C continued to increase for decades under elevated nutrient supply, suggesting that short-term nutrient addition experiments underestimate the effects of soil nutrients on soil C accumulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;linking-decomposition-rates-of-soil-organic-amendments-to-their-chemical-composition&quot;&gt;Linking decomposition rates of soil organic amendments to their chemical composition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stock of organic carbon contained within a soil represents the balance between inputs and losses. Inputs are defined by the ability of vegetation to capture and retain carbon dioxide, effects that management practices have on the proportion of captured carbon that is added to soil and the application organic amendments. The proportion of organic amendment carbon retained is defined by its rate of mineralisation. In this study, the rate of carbon mineralisation from 85 different potential soil organic amendments (composts, manures, plant residues and biosolids) was quantified under controlled environmental conditions over a 547 day incubation period. The composition of each organic amendment was quantified using nuclear magnetic resonance and mid- and near-infrared spectroscopies. Cumulative mineralisation of organic carbon from the amendments was fitted to a two-pool exponential model. Multivariate chemometric algorithms were derived to allow the size of the fast and slow cycling pools of carbon to be predicted from the acquired spectroscopic data. However, the fast and slow decomposition rate constants could not be predicted suggesting that prediction of the residence time of organic amendment carbon in soil would likely require additional information related to soil type, environmental conditions, and management practices in use at the site of application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;papatuanuku-earth-mother-indigenous-knowledge-in-21st-century-soil-management&quot;&gt;Papatuanuku, Earth Mother: indigenous knowledge in 21st century soil management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 20 March 2017 the New Zealand parliament passed the Te Awa Tupua (Whanganui River Claims Settlement) Bill which established the Whanganui River as a legal ‘person’ with all of the rights, powers, duties, and liabilities of the same. The Act endorses and illustrates how Maori perceive their relationship to the natural world. The passing of the Act challenged the river people to restore their ancestral river to good health. Changes in land use beginning in the later part of the 19th century had seen soil fertility decline, water quality deteriorate and the soils that sustained life in its catchment increasingly washed out to sea. These impacts profoundly changed the lifestyles of the people that belonged to it. Describing the issues facing the river iwi (tribes) and their response to them will help illustrate traditional understandings relating to the river, the whenua (the land) and the life sustaining capacity of the soil. It also serves to demonstrate the relevance of traditional knowledge to addressing the current ecological crisis. This viewpoint focuses on key concepts from Maori understandings of the natural world that relate to the primary themes of this conference and suggest how they can contribute towards deepening and broadening our knowledge of soils and what needs to be done to sustain them. In particular the concept of ‘mauri’ will be explored and how that relates to the capacity of soils to support the life that belongs there. Maori, and many traditional peoples, regard the whole landscape as essentially interdependent and consider that the wellness of any part of it, be it soils, vegetation, water quality, etc., can only be understood within the context of the whole network of connections that sustain life. The challenge for researchers, from an indigenous perspective, is to be mindful of the ‘whole’ while focusing on the areas of their particular expertise.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/09/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on September 21, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/09/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/09/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-09-11T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-09-11T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-30&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #30&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil properties: Their prediction and feature extraction from the LUCAS spectral library using deep convolutional neural networks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assessing new sensor-based volume measurement methods for high-throughput bulk density estimation in the field under various soil conditions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-properties-their-prediction-and-feature-extraction-from-the-lucas-spectral-library-using-deep-convolutional-neural-networks&quot;&gt;Soil properties: Their prediction and feature extraction from the LUCAS spectral library using deep convolutional neural networks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil, as a non-renewable resource, should be monitored continuously to prevent its degradation and promote sustainable agriculture. Soil spectroscopy in the visible-near infrared range is a fast and cost-effective analytical technique to predict soil properties. Although traditional machine learning methods are widely used for modeling soil spectral data, large spectral datasets may require better analytical methods for big data. Here, we explored the modeling potential of deep convolutional neural networks (DCNNs) for soil properties based on a large soil spectral library. The European topsoil dataset provided by the Land Use/Cover Area frame Survey (LUCAS) was used for DCNN modeling with the original absorbance spectra. Two single-task 16-layer DCNN models (LucasResNet-16 and LucasVGGNet-16) were used to make regression predictions of seven soil properties and classification predictions of soil texture. The effects of data pre-processing on single-task and multi-task DCNN modeling were assessed. The SHapley Additive exPlanations method was used to interpret the output of a DCNN model (LucasResNet-16). The DCNN models produced accurate predictions for most soil properties, and were superior to a single-task shallow convolutional neural network and traditional machine learning methods. Spectral transformation was effective for predicting some soil properties, while spectral downsampling led to a reduction in the modeling accuracy. The performance of a multi-task DCNN model built on the basis of LucasResNet-16 was improved compared with the performance of the single-task model. Soil organic carbon content, nitrogen content, cation exchange capacity, pH, and calcium carbonate content were well predicted, with the root mean squared error of 19.130 g.kg(-1), 0.971 g.kg(-1), 6.614 cmol(+).kg(-1), 0.326, and 24.526 g.kg(-1) , respectively. The overall classification accuracy of soil texture was 0.749 (four groups) and 0.566 (12 levels). The position of feature wavelengths differed among the soil properties, for which multiple characteristic peaks were common. This study fully demonstrates the modeling potential of deep learning with soil ultraspectral data, which could enhance precision agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;assessing-new-sensor-based-volume-measurement-methods-for-high-throughput-bulk-density-estimation-in-the-field-under-various-soil-conditions&quot;&gt;Assessing new sensor-based volume measurement methods for high-throughput bulk density estimation in the field under various soil conditions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil bulk density (BD) is a key soil property in soil science. BD is measured at the scale of the soil horizon with conventional methods: core sampling and rubber balloon. Regardless of the method, BD measurement in the field is cumbersome and time consuming, especially in stony soils, and new, less invasive methods have emerged, but their measurement quality needs to be compared with conventional methods. The photogrammetric technique (SfM) consists of the reconstruction of a given scene in 3D from multi-view photographs. The aim of the present work is to assess the SfM as a rapid, accurate method of measuring the volume of undisturbed soil for BD measurements, regardless of the soil depth and stone content. Ten soil horizons were investigated from various types of soils with different soil properties, especially texture (10 to 48% of clay) and stone content (0 to 73%). The bulk density of each horizon was measured with a reference method (core sampling), an excavation method (rubber balloon) and two recently developed sensor-based methods: SfM and a lightweight flash LiDar. For the sensor-based methods, an automated post-processing method was developed to reduce the human operating time. The BDs measured from the SfM were significantly similar to those measured from core sampling. At this stage, the lightweight flash LiDar is not sufficient to measure the BD with high accuracy. Finally, we recommend the use of SfM to measure BD regarding its robustness in varying soil conditions, especially stony soils, and we discuss the potential of the method regarding the recent advances in its field use with smartphones.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/09/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on September 11, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/09/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/09/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-09-09T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-09-09T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-29&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #29&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pedological characteristics of artificialized soils: A snapshot&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How the composition of sandstone matrices affects rates of soil formation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Field test of two background temperature correction methods of dual probe heat pulse method&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agricultural Drought Prediction Based on Conditional Distributions of Vine Copulas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Advancing Space-Time Simulation of Random Fields: From Storms to Cyclones and Beyond&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mapping potential surface ponding in agriculture using UAV-SfM&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Development of a soil fertility index using on-line Vis-NIR spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Internet of Things (IoT) for double ring infiltrometer automation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A dual-probe heat pulse-based sensor that simultaneously determines soil thermal properties, soil water content and soil water matric potential&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pedological-characteristics-of-artificialized-soils-a-snapshot&quot;&gt;Pedological characteristics of artificialized soils: A snapshot&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The onset of industrialization entailed the increase in soil artificialization worldwide. Soils from artificialized zones (SAZ) are the result of urban, industrial, traffic, mining or recreational land use. Knowledge of their characteristics is a prerequisite for evaluating the ability of SAZ to perform key functions and provide soil ecosystem services. Based on a selection of 102 papers published between 1991 and 2017, this article aims at providing a quantitative vision of the pedological characteristics of the different categories of SAZs as a function of the land use and soil type (natural profile, soil developed on allochthonous material). We show that, overall, the inherent characteristics of SAZ topsoil generally depend on the soil type - soil of allochthonous material being more stony and poorer in the &amp;lt; 2 mu m fraction - while manageable characteristics are a function of both the soil type and the land use, with the exception of pH that is mainly driven by the land use. However, a good characterization of SAZs requires a more systematic description, sampling and analysis to obtain comprehensive knowledge of their characteristics as several features are still too rarely measured such as cationic exchange capacity, electrical conductivity, soil depth, and nutrient concentrations. Sealed soils are still too rarely considered despite their large surface area. Such a characterization would allow a better management of the ecosystem services that SAZs fulfill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-the-composition-of-sandstone-matrices-affects-rates-of-soil-formation&quot;&gt;How the composition of sandstone matrices affects rates of soil formation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soils deliver multiple ecosystem services and their long-term sustainability is fundamentally controlled by the rates at which they form and erode. Our knowledge and understanding of soil formation is not commensurate with that of soil erosion, in part due to the difficulty of measuring the former. However, developments in cosmogenic radionuclide accumulation models have enabled soil scientists to more accurately constrain the rates at which soils form from bedrock. To date, all three major rock types - igneous, sedimentary and metamorphic lithologies - have been examined in such work. Soil formation rates have been measured and compared between these rock types, but the impact of rock characteristics on soil formation rates, such as rock matrices and mineralogy, have seldom been explored. In this UK-based study, we used cosmogenic radionuclide analysis to investigate whether the lithological variability of sandstone governs pedogenesis. Soil formation rates were measured on two arable hillslopes at Woburn and Hilton, which are underlain by different types of arenite sandstone. Rates were faster at Woburn, and we suggest that this is due to the fact that the Woburn sandstone formation is less cemented that that at Hilton. Similarly, rates at Woburn and Hilton were found to be faster than those measured at two other sandstone-based sites in the UK, and faster than those compiled in a global inventory of cosmogenic studies on sandstone-based soils. We suggest that the cementing agents present in matrix-abundant wackes studied previously may afford these sandstones greater structural integrity and resistance to weathering. This work points to the importance of factoring bedrock matrices into our understanding of soil formation rates, and the biogeochemical cycles these underpin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;field-test-of-two-background-temperature-correction-methods-of-dual-probe-heat-pulse-method&quot;&gt;Field test of two background temperature correction methods of dual probe heat pulse method&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dual probe heat pulse (DPHP) method is a useful method to measure many soil physical properties in-situ, which play important roles in soil science, meteorology, hydrology and so on. It is essential to remove the effect of background temperature fluctuations for DPHP estimations. We compared two background temperature correction methods of DPHP method, linear trend method (LTM) and reference temperature method (RTM) in field experiments. We found that misused LTM lead to large errors in DPHP estimations with shallow burial depth. When the burial depth of temperature probe (d) of DPHP sensor is &amp;lt;14 mm, background temperature changes are related to environmental factors such as solar radiation and wind, and RTM can decrease the relative error (RE) in thermal conductivity (A) from 667% to 68%. Besides, our results also showed during the period from 9:00 to 16:00, the RTM method is valuable for getting accurate DPHP estimations with the 2 mm burial depth. After replacing LTM by RTM, REs were decreased to (6 +/- 28)% from (17 +/- 87) % in lambda, and were decreased to (9 +/- 17)% from (10 +/- 18)% in volumetric heat capacity (C-v). But RTM is also affected by other factors such as the spatially heterogeneous temperature distribution of tested sample and should be taken into account in the further studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;agricultural-drought-prediction-based-on-conditional-distributions-of-vine-copulas&quot;&gt;Agricultural Drought Prediction Based on Conditional Distributions of Vine Copulas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monitoring and prediction of agricultural drought are paramount to food security at the global and regional scales, particularly under the influence of climate change and anthropogenic activities. Soil moisture is an effective indicator for monitoring and characterizing agricultural drought. Soil moisture (agricultural drought) is mainly affected by precipitation (meteorological drought) and temperature (hot conditions). Owing to the flexibility of vine copulas in handling multidimensional variables by decomposing them into pair copula constructions (PCCs), we propose a novel drought prediction method using three predictors, namely antecedent meteorological drought, previous hot conditions, and persistent agricultural drought, based on the conditional distributions of C-vine copulas in a four-dimensional scenario. The proposed model was applied to agricultural drought (characterized by the standardized soil moisture index (SSI)) prediction with 1-2-months lead time for the summer season (i.e., August at a 6-months timescale) in China. Taking two severe agricultural drought events that occurred in many regions across China in August of 2006 and 2014 as validation cases, the SSI predictions with 1-2-months lead time using the conditional C-vine copulas model were found to be generally consistent with the corresponding historical SSI observations in most parts of China. Performance evaluation using the Nash-Sutcliffe efficiency (NSE), coefficient of determination (R-2), and F-1 score (F1S) for different climate regions also indicated that this model provided a reliable prediction of agricultural drought for most areas of China. The outcome of this study can serve as a guidance for drought prediction, early warning, and drought mitigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;advancing-space-time-simulation-of-random-fields-from-storms-to-cyclones-and-beyond&quot;&gt;Advancing Space-Time Simulation of Random Fields: From Storms to Cyclones and Beyond&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Realistic stochastic simulation of hydro-environmental fluxes in space and time, such as rainfall, is challenging yet of paramount importance to inform environmental risk analysis and decision making under uncertainty. Here, we advance random fields simulation by introducing the concepts of general velocity fields and general anisotropy transformations. This expands the capabilities of the so-called Complete Stochastic Modeling Solution (CoSMoS) framework enabling the simulation of random fields (RF’s) preserving: (a) any non-Gaussian marginal distribution, (b) any spatiotemporal correlation structure (STCS), (c) general advection expressed by velocity fields with locally varying speed and direction, and (d) locally varying anisotropy. We also introduce new copula-based STCS’s and provide conditions guaranteeing their positive definiteness. To illustrate the potential of CoSMoS, we simulate RF’s with complex patterns and motion mimicking rainfall storms moving across an area, spiraling fields resembling weather cyclones, fields converging to (or diverging from) a point, and colliding air masses. The proposed methodology is implemented in the freely available CoSMoS R package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mapping-potential-surface-ponding-in-agriculture-using-uav-sfm&quot;&gt;Mapping potential surface ponding in agriculture using UAV-SfM&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the environmental problems that could affect agriculture, one of the most critical is ponding. This may be defined as water storage on the surface in concavities and depressions due to soil saturation. Stagnant water can seriously affect crops and the management of agricultural landscapes. It is mainly caused by prolonged rainfall events, soil type, or wrong mechanization practices, which cause soil compaction. To better understand this problem and thus provide adequate solutions to reduce the related risk, high-resolution topographic information could be strategically important because it offers an accurate representation of the surface morphology. In the last decades, new remote sensing techniques provide interesting opportunities to understand the processes on the Earth’s surface based on geomorphic signatures. Among these, Uncrewed Aerial Vehicles (UAVs), combined with the structure-from-motion (SfM) photogrammetry technique, represent a solid, low-cost, rapid, and flexible solution for geomorphological analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This study aims to present a new approach to detect the potential areas exposed to water stagnation at the farm scale. The high-resolution digital elevation model (DEM) from UAV-SfM data is used to do this. The potential water depth was calculated in the DEM using the relative elevation attribute algorithm. The detection of more pronounced concavities and convexities allowed an estimation and mapping of the potential ponding conditions. The results were assessed by observations and field measurements and are promising, showing a Cohen’s k(X) accuracy of 0.683 for the planimetric extent of the ponding phenomena and a Pearson’s r(xy) coefficient of 0.971 for the estimation of pond water depth. The proposed workflow provides a useful indication to stakeholders for better agricultural management in lowland landscapes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;development-of-a-soil-fertility-index-using-on-line-vis-nir-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Development of a soil fertility index using on-line Vis-NIR spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil fertility index (SFI) is commonly used for soil fertility assessment, which is critical for managing in-field variabilities and maximizing crop production with minimum environmental impacts. However, the majority of earlier SFIs were laboratory-based soil analyses. This study developed a novel SFI using on-line collected visible and near-infrared (vis-NIR) spectra. Six agricultural fields were scanned using an on-line vis-NIR sensor (CompactSpec, Tec5 Technology, Germany), when 139 soil samples were collected and analyzed for soil pH, organic carbon, available- phosphorous (P), potassium, magnesium (Mg), calcium, sodium, moisture content (MC) and cation exchange capacity. A minimum dataset was developed comprising the fertility attributes that showed pairwise correlation (r) smaller than 0.75. This was followed by a principal component analysis to calculate the weight factor of each parameter to be used in the SFI formulation using a double-weighted additive function. The data matrix consisting of the SFI and soil spectra was divided into calibration (70 %) and prediction (30 datasets. The former set was subjected to a partial least squares regression to calibrate SFI model, whose accuracy was validated using the prediction set. Results showed that the derived SFI was moderately to highly correlated with P (r = 0.57), pH (r = 0.75), and Mg (r = 0.74) and weakly correlated with MC (r = 0.26). The online vis-NIR sensor predicted SFI with very good accuracy [coefficient of determination (R-2) = 0.75 and ratio of prediction to deviation (RPD) = 2.01]. Therefore, it is concluded that the vis-NIR can accurately predict SFI directly from on-line scanned soil spectra, which can effectively assess soil fertility and manage in-field variability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;internet-of-things-iot-for-double-ring-infiltrometer-automation&quot;&gt;Internet of Things (IoT) for double ring infiltrometer automation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Double ring infiltrometer is a simple device used to measure water infiltration rate in the soil, one of the most important hydro physical characteristics and an essential parameter for various applications including: surface irrigation and drainage projects, infiltration or water purification basins, seepage losses at canals, soil leaching at waste storage sites. However, the high spatial variability of a soil makes a single point measurement rarely representative of an entire field. Nonetheless, Double Ring Infiltration tests are tedious, time consuming and require continuous attention, hence limiting the number of tests that may be performed simultaneously on a given site. In the present research, an automated Internet of Things (IoT) double ring infiltrometer (DRI) is developed and validated in a loamy field. It consists of a DRI equipped with an ESP-32 microcontroller chip, a GPS module, a solenoid valve, a DIY conductance water level sensor, and a SD card module powered by a 12 V 11000mAh Li-ion battery charged by a 10 W solar panel. The double ring infiltrometer is designed to calculate the infiltration rate in real time, to store the data with the time stamp and geographical coordinates on an SD card or, to use a cloud service platform to upload the data over the internet. The aim is to facilitate soil infiltration mapping for precision agriculture and to build a soil infiltration inventory that could be used to continuously improve existing soil database. The system was assembled and tested at nine different locations on a loamy soil experimental field. For validation, conventional (manually operated) tests were conducted at the same time. The system proved to be reliable (R2 = 0.99), cost effective (115$) and a hassle-free solution, ideal for multiple soil infiltration measurements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-dual-probe-heat-pulse-based-sensor-that-simultaneously-determines-soil-thermal-properties-soil-water-content-and-soil-water-matric-potential&quot;&gt;A dual-probe heat pulse-based sensor that simultaneously determines soil thermal properties, soil water content and soil water matric potential&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dual-probe heat pulse (DPHP) sensor is a robust tool that can measure soil thermal properties and associated soil physical properties and processes. A new DPHP based sensor was developed to simultaneously measure soil thermal properties, soil water content and soil water matric potential. A series of experiments were performed to evaluate the sensor performance. The new sensor was able to measure each soil property with acceptable accuracy. The accuracy of the matric potential determinations was approximately 10% in log scale. The effective range for w measurements was -1000 to -2.5 m of water, and the accuracy of the w determinations was best between -350 and -2.5 m of water, which included values of field capacity and wilting point for most soils and crops. The sensor design included a single heater wire to provide simultaneous heat inputs to two different materials, i.e., the soil and the sensor porous medium. The single heater wire did not influence sensor accuracy as long as the soil and the sensor porous medium thermal conductivity values were not significantly different. The new DPHP based sensor effectively measured various soil properties, including soil water matric potential, soil water content, and soil thermal property values.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/09/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on September 09, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/08/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/08/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-08-31T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-08-31T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-28&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #28&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proposed algorithm for the identification of rural areas with regard to variability of soil quality.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use of metabolomics to quantify changes in soil microbial function in response to fertiliser nitrogen supply and extreme drought&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Altered mineral mapping based on ground-airborne hyperspectral data and wavelet spectral angle mapper tri-training model: Case studies from Dehua-Youxi-Yongtai Ore District, Central Fujian, China&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Iterative Deep Learning (IDL) for agricultural landscape classification using fine spatial resolution remotely sensed imagery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;proposed-algorithm-for-the-identification-of-rural-areas-with-regard-to-variability-of-soil-quality&quot;&gt;Proposed algorithm for the identification of rural areas with regard to variability of soil quality&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The development of agriculture in many countries and its productivity are considerably differentiated in terms of space. At present, Poland has agricultural areas which in many respects can compete with agriculture in the member states of the European Union. However, in some areas agricultural production run by private farms owned by individuals is on the verge of or falls below the limit of profitability. The priorities of the common agricultural policy in the European Union (EU) include a willingness to improve the quality of life in rural areas and effective utilization of their resources. Another goal is to support agricultural activity and align development chances for farms in areas featuring adverse environmental conditions and low soil productivity. This article presents the results of studies regarding the development of a method for identifying useless agricultural land. The study covered 44 villages with a registered surface area totalling 53941.00 ha, situated in the district of Brzoz ‘ ow, Subcarpathian voivodeship, in south-eastern Poland. Studies showed that it is possible to identify problem areas for agriculture, thanks to which the produced methodology may prove to be a useful tool in land consolidation works facilitating reasonable planning of the development of such areas. Thus, a universal tool can be designed for analysing large areas, e.g., communes, districts or voivodeships, and a high level of consistency of results can be a guarantee of reliable decisions regarding the development strategy for the specific area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-of-metabolomics-to-quantify-changes-in-soil-microbial-function-in-response-to-fertiliser-nitrogen-supply-and-extreme-drought&quot;&gt;Use of metabolomics to quantify changes in soil microbial function in response to fertiliser nitrogen supply and extreme drought&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Climate change is expected to increase the frequency and severity of droughts in many regions of the world. Soil health is likely to be negatively impacted by these extreme events. It is therefore important to understand the impact of drought on soil functioning and the delivery of soil-related ecosystem services. This study aimed to assess the resilience and change in physiological status of the microbial community under extreme moisture stress conditions using novel metabolic profiling approaches, namely complex lipids and untargeted primary metabolites. In addition, we used phospholipid fatty acid (PLFA) profiling to identify changes in microbial community structure. Soil samples were collected during a natural, extreme drought event and post-drought from replicated grassland split plots, planted with either deep-rooting Festulolium (cv. AberNiche) or Lolium perenne L. (cv. AberEcho), receiving nitrogen (N) fertiliser loading rates at either 0 or 300 kg N ha-1 yr- 1. These plots were split at the start of the drought period, and half of each subplot was irrigated with water throughout the drought period at a rate of 50 mm week-1 to alleviate moisture stress. PLFA analysis revealed a distinct shift in microbial community between drought and post-drought conditions, primarily driven by N loading and water deficit. Complex lipid analysis identified 239 compounds and untargeted analysis of primary metabolites identified 155 compounds. Both soil complex lipids and primary metabolites showed significant changes under drought conditions. Additionally, the irrigated ‘reference’ plots had a significantly higher cumulative greenhouse gas (CO2 and N2O) flux over the period of sampling. Recovery of the microbial lipidome and metabolome to reference plot levels post-drought was rapid (within days). Considerable changes in soil primary metabolomic and lipidomic concentrations shown in this study demonstrate that while soil metabolism was strongly affected by moisture stress, the system (plant and soil) was highly resilient to an intense drought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;altered-mineral-mapping-based-on-ground-airborne-hyperspectral-data-and-wavelet-spectral-angle-mapper-tri-training-model-case-studies-from-dehua-youxi-yongtai-ore-district-central-fujian-china&quot;&gt;Altered mineral mapping based on ground-airborne hyperspectral data and wavelet spectral angle mapper tri-training model: Case studies from Dehua-Youxi-Yongtai Ore District, Central Fujian, China&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mineral mapping is an important procedure for the utilization of mineral resources, and it is also significant to the analysis of mineralization zone especially for altered minerals. The emergence of remote sensing, especially hyperspectral data has become a new approach for mineral mapping on a wide scale. In addition, spectral angle mapping (SAM) is a commonly used classifier to distinguish the minerals, but the discrimination ability is weak on a mapping scale, and the identification accuracy is poor for a series of minerals with similar spectral curves when a single classifier is applied. In this work, altered minerals are identified at Dehua-Youxi-Yongtai Ore District uniting ground and airborne hyperspectral data, and wavelet SAM (WSAM) tri-training model is constructed to discriminate the category of 9 altered minerals. Experimental results demonstrate that the proposed technique provides the identification accuracy of 82% and 70% for virtual and XRD verifications, and the mapping result is believable compared with measured sampling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;iterative-deep-learning-idl-for-agricultural-landscape-classification-using-fine-spatial-resolution-remotely-sensed-imagery&quot;&gt;Iterative Deep Learning (IDL) for agricultural landscape classification using fine spatial resolution remotely sensed imagery&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The agricultural landscape can be interpreted at different semantic levels, such as fine low-level crop (LLC) classes (e.g., Wheat, Almond, and Alfalfa) and broad high-level crop (HLC) classes (e.g., Winter crops, Tree crops, and Forage). The LLC and HLC are hierarchically correlated with each other, but such intrinsically hierarchical relationships have been overlooked in previous crop classification studies in remote sensing. In this research, a novel Iterative Deep Learning (IDL) framework was proposed for the classification of complex agricultural landscapes using remotely sensed imagery. The IDL adopts an object-based convolutional neural network (OCNN) as the basic classifier for both the LLC and HLC classifications, which has the advantage of maintaining precise crop parcel boundaries. In IDL, the HLC classification implemented by the OCNN is conditional upon the LLC classification probabilities, whereas the HLC probabilities combined with the original imagery are, in turn, re-used as inputs to the OCNN to enhance the LLC classification. Such an iterative updating procedure forms a Markov process, where both the LLC and HLC classifications are refined and evolve collaboratively. The effectiveness of the IDL was tested on two heterogeneous agricultural fields using fine spatial resolution (FSR) SAR and optical imagery. The experimental results demonstrate that the iterative process of IDL helps to resolve contradictions within the class hierarchies. The new proposed IDL consistently increased the accuracies of both the LLC and HLC classifications with iteration, and achieved the highest accuracies for each at four iterations. The average overall accuracies were 88.4% for LLC and 91.2% for HLC, for both study sites, far greater than the accuracies of the state-of-the-art benchmarks, including the pixel-wise CNN (81.7% and 85.9%), object-based image analysis (OBIA) (84.0% and 85.8%), and OCNN (84.0% and 88.4%). To the best of our knowledge, the proposed model is the first to identify and use the relationship between the class levels in an ontological hierarchy in a remote sensing classification process. It is applied here to increase progressively the accuracy of classification at two levels for a complex agricultural landscape. As such IDL represents an entirely new paradigm for remote sensing image classification. Moreover, the promising results demonstrate the great potential of the proposed IDL with wide application prospect.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/08/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on August 31, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/08/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/08/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-08-30T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-08-30T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-29&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #29&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;VNIR and MIR spectroscopy of PLFA-derived soil microbial properties and associated soil physicochemical characteristics in an experimental plant diversity gradient.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The blue carbon wealth of nations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Both carbon sequestration and yield are related to particulate organic carbon stability affected by organic amendment origins in mollisol&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A two-field geostatistical model combining point and areal observations-A case study of annual runoff predictions in the Voss area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vnir-and-mir-spectroscopy-of-plfa-derived-soil-microbial-properties-and-associated-soil-physicochemical-characteristics-in-an-experimental-plant-diversity-gradient&quot;&gt;VNIR and MIR spectroscopy of PLFA-derived soil microbial properties and associated soil physicochemical characteristics in an experimental plant diversity gradient&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hutengs, C; Eisenhauer, N; (…); Vohland, M
Sep 2021 | SOIL BIOLOGY &amp;amp; BIOCHEMISTRY 160 , pp.8319-8319
Improving our understanding of the functions and processes of soil microbial communities and their interactions with the physicochemical soil environment requires large amounts of timely and cost-efficient soil data, which is difficult to obtain with routine laboratory-analytical methods. Soil spectroscopy with portable visible-to-near infrared (VNIR) and mid-infrared (MIR) instruments can fill this gap by facilitating the rapid acquisition of biotic and abiotic soil information. In this study, we evaluated the capabilities of VNIR and MIR spectroscopy to analyze soil physicochemical and microbial properties in a long-term grassland biodiversity-ecosystem functioning experiment. Soil samples were collected at the Jena Experiment (Jena, Germany) and measured with portable VNIR and MIR spectrometers in field-moist condition to determine their potential for on-site data collection and analysis. Reference data to calibrate spectroscopic models were acquired with routine analytical methods, including PLFA extractions of microbial biomarkers. We further collected reference VNIR and MIR data on pre-treated soils (dried and finely ground) to assess the anticipated impact of field measurements on spectroscopic calibrations. MIR spectra allowed more accurate estimates of soil physicochemical and microbial properties than VNIR data on pre-treated samples. For soils in field condition, MIR calibrations were more accurate for physicochemical properties, but VNIR data gave significantly better estimates of microbial properties. Combined VNIR/MIR estimates achieved the most accurate estimation results for all soil properties in each case. Soil physicochemical properties could be estimated from VNIR/MIR data with high accuracy (R2 = 0.72-0.99) on pre-treated soil samples, whereas the results for soil microbial properties were more moderate (R2 = 0.66-0.72). On field-moist soils, estimation accuracies decreased notably for organic and inorganic carbon (Delta RMSE = 52-72%), improved slightly for soil texture (Delta RMSE = 4-7%) and decreased slightly for microbial properties (Delta RMSE = 4-9%). The VNIR/MIR estimates derived from soils in field condition were sufficiently accurate to detect experimental plant treatment effects on organic carbon, as well as bacterial and fungal biomass. We further found that spectroscopic estimates of soil microbial properties were primarily enabled through indirect correlations with spectrally active soil constituents, i.e., associations between soil microbial properties and the physicochemical soil environment. Our findings highlight the capacity of VNIR and MIR spectroscopy to analyze the physicochemical soil environment, including potential on-site data collection and analysis on soils in field condition, and indicate that VNIR/MIR data can estimate soil microbial properties when soil physicochemical properties shape the distribution of soil microbial communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-blue-carbon-wealth-of-nations&quot;&gt;The blue carbon wealth of nations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bertram, C; Quaas, M; (…); Rickels, W
Aug 2021 | NATURE CLIMATE CHANGE 11 (8) , pp.704-+
Carbon sequestration and storage in mangroves, salt marshes and seagrass meadows is an essential coastal ‘blue carbon’ ecosystem service for climate change mitigation. Here we offer a comprehensive, global and spatially explicit economic assessment of carbon sequestration and storage in three coastal ecosystem types at the global and national levels. We propose a new approach based on the country-specific social cost of carbon that allows us to calculate each country’s contribution to, and redistribution of, global blue carbon wealth. Globally, coastal ecosystems contribute a mean +/- s.e.m. of US190.67 +/- 30 bn yr(-1) to blue carbon wealth. The three countries generating the largest positive net blue wealth contribution for other countries are Australia, Indonesia and Cuba, with Australia alone generating a positive net benefit of US$22.8 +/- 3.8 bn yr(-)(1) for the rest of the world through coastal ecosystem carbon sequestration and storage in its territory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blue carbon ecosystems take up and store substantial amounts of carbon. This represents an important ecosystem service in the context of climate change, with coastal ecosystems contributing nearly US$200 bn yr(-)(1) to blue carbon wealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;both-carbon-sequestration-and-yield-are-related-to-particulate-organic-carbon-stability-affected-by-organic-amendment-origins-in-mollisol&quot;&gt;Both carbon sequestration and yield are related to particulate organic carbon stability affected by organic amendment origins in mollisol&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Purpose Exploring how organic amendments influence carbon sequestration by affecting particulate organic carbon (POC) and determining the optimum amendment for protecting and restoring mollisol and increasing yields. Methods Differences of POC properties and maize yields in 3-year soils amended with organic material of different origins were studied. POC was separated by a wet sieving method, and the structure was analyzed by C-13 NMR spectroscopy. Results We found that SOC accumulation in soils amended with plant origin organic materials resulted from increasing organic fractions other than POC, while that in soils amended with animal origin materials resulted from increasing POC. The proportion of POC net variation in SOC net variation was significantly negatively correlated with SOC (p &amp;lt; 0.01). POC, mainly composed of alkyl C and alkoxyl C (more than 68%), had its stability more accurately evaluated through combined analysis of the carbonyl C content and alkyl C/alkoxyl C ratio. The addition of organic materials improved POC stability by increasing the alkyl C/alkoxyl C ratio and decreasing the carbonyl C content. Maize yields were positively correlated with SOC content and POC stability (p &amp;lt; 0.01), which increased by at least 2012 kg ha(-1) with the addition of organic materials. Conclusion Increasing more stable POC will promote the carbon sink. The order of the stability of POC in mollisol amended with organic materials of different origins was woody plant material &amp;gt; herb material &amp;gt; livestock dung &amp;gt; poultry dung. The woody plant material was the optimum organic amendment for mollisol, enhanced POC stability, and promoted SOC sequestration while increasing the yield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-two-field-geostatistical-model-combining-point-and-areal-observations-a-case-study-of-annual-runoff-predictions-in-the-voss-area&quot;&gt;A two-field geostatistical model combining point and areal observations-A case study of annual runoff predictions in the Voss area&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We estimate annual runoff by using a Bayesian geostatistical model for interpolation of hydrological data of different spatial support: streamflow observations from catchments (areal data), and precipitation and evaporation data (point data). The model contains one climatic spatial effect that is common for all years under study, and 1 year specific spatial effect. Hence, the framework enables a quantification of the spatial variability caused by long-term weather patterns and processes. This can contribute to a better understanding of biases and uncertainties in environmental modelling. The suggested model is evaluated by predicting annual runoff for catchments around Voss in Norway and through a simulation study. We find that on average we benefit from combining point and areal data compared to using only one of the data types, and that the interaction between nested areal data and point data gives a spatial model that takes us beyond smoothing. Another finding is that when climatic effects dominate over annual effects, systematic under- and overestimation of runoff can be expected over time. However, a dominating climatic spatial effect also implies that short records of runoff from an otherwise ungauged catchment can lead to large improvements in the predictive performance.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/08/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on August 30, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/08/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/08/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-08-07T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-08-07T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-27&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #27&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Toward Developing a Generalizable Pedotransfer Function for Saturated Hydraulic Conductivity Using Transfer Learning and Predictor Selector Algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Robust Drought Index Accounting Changing Precipitation Characteristics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The impact of climate change on the productivity of conservation agriculture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Global patterns of geo-ecological controls on the response of soil respiration to warming&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Microplastics in terrestrial ecosystems: Moving beyond the state of the art to minimize the risk of ecological surprise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;toward-developing-a-generalizable-pedotransfer-function-for-saturated-hydraulic-conductivity-using-transfer-learning-and-predictor-selector-algorithm&quot;&gt;Toward Developing a Generalizable Pedotransfer Function for Saturated Hydraulic Conductivity Using Transfer Learning and Predictor Selector Algorithm&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pedotransfer functions (PTFs) are being instrumental in saturated hydraulic conductivity (K-s) estimation. Despite various advancements, the performance of existing generic K-s predicting PTFs need augmentation. This study developed a robust K-s predicting PTF using a machine learning (ML) algorithm and exhaustive data set for 324 soils with 28 properties sampled over a tropical savanna region of India. Four ML algorithms were evaluated for this purpose, and random forest (RF) outperformed all others. A substantial improvement to the prediction by RF-based PTF was achieved through predictor selection using a hybrid wrapper-embedded algorithm. The predictor selection algorithm selected eight pertinent predictors (HID-S): S, Si, C, FSF, C-u, GMD, D-60, and D-10. The mean absolute error (MAE), root mean squared error (RMSE), coefficient of determination (R-2), and Nash-Sutcliffe efficiency (NSE) obtained as average tenfold cross-validation scores for RF algorithm training with HID-S were 0.87, 1.47, 0.94, and 0.94, respectively. The developed PTF (RF-HID-S) was evaluated alongside the recently published PTFs by Araya and Ghezzehei (2019, ), within and outside the study region. In that process, it was observed that the RF-HID-S possessed superior prediction proficiency compared to the recently published and commonly used PTFs in both cases. These findings mark RF-HID-S as the most robust generalizable PTF, which may further be evaluated in different parts of the world. Moreover, looking at the performance of the eight selected predictors within and outside the study region, they can be considered for experiment design globally to make K-s estimation accurate and cost-effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-robust-drought-index-accounting-changing-precipitation-characteristics&quot;&gt;A Robust Drought Index Accounting Changing Precipitation Characteristics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A realistic evaluation of drought onset is inevitable for the effective implementation of mitigation strategies. Meteorological droughts indicating the onset of drought propagation are usually quantified through unbiased indices that consider the month-wise magnitude variations in historical climatic variables, while completely ignoring their intramonthly distributions. However, the applicability of such indices under the present scenario of changing climate, where intense short wet spells are reportedly increasing, is questionable. Such changes in the wet spells could eventually lead to prolonged intramonthly dry spells, which in turn will pose many agricultural and socioeconomic risks. To monitor the changed scenario realistically, we propose a new drought index-the Standardized Net-Precipitation Distribution Index (SNEPI), which incorporates the distribution characteristics of the daily net-precipitation variable. The applicability of SNEPI is critically evaluated using synthetically generated and observed precipitation series over six diverse climatic locations of India, at 1-, 3-, 6-, and 12-month time scales. The utility of SNEPI is more profound for longer time scales, understandably due to the enhanced emphasis imparted on the distribution of rainfall spells by the longer periods. Standardized Net-Precipitation Distribution Index proves to be efficient in capturing the present scenario of increasing dryness (wetness) in wet (dry) regions when compared with the traditional Standardized Precipitation Evapotranspiration Index. Hence, the proposed index, which incorporates the changing precipitation characteristics, may aid in better quantification and monitoring of meteorological drought under the scenario of changing climate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-impact-of-climate-change-on-the-productivity-of-conservation-agriculture&quot;&gt;The impact of climate change on the productivity of conservation agriculture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors assess the productivity of conservation agriculture systems for eight major crops under current and future climate using a global-scale probabilistic machine-learning approach, revealing substantial differences in yield gain probabilities across crop type, management practice, climate zone and geography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conservation agriculture (CA) is being promoted as a set of management practices that can sustain crop production while providing positive environmental benefits. However, its impact on crop productivity is hotly debated, and how this productivity will be affected by climate change remains uncertain. Here we compare the productivity of CA systems and their variants on the basis of no tillage versus conventional tillage systems for eight major crop species under current and future climate conditions using a probabilistic machine-learning approach at the global scale. We reveal large differences in the probability of yield gains with CA across crop types, agricultural management practices, climate zones and geographical regions. For most crops, CA performed better in continental, dry and temperate regions than in tropical ones. Under future climate conditions, the performance of CA is expected to mostly increase for maize over its tropical areas, improving the competitiveness of CA for this staple crop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;global-patterns-of-geo-ecological-controls-on-the-response-of-soil-respiration-to-warming&quot;&gt;Global patterns of geo-ecological controls on the response of soil respiration to warming&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While soil respiration is known to be controlled by a range of biotic and abiotic factors, its temperature sensitivity in global models is largely related to climate parameters. Here, we show that temperature sensitivity of soil respiration is primarily controlled by interacting soil properties and only secondarily by vegetation traits and plant growth conditions. Temperature was not identified as a primary driver for the response of soil respiration to warming. In contrast, the nonlinearity and large spatial variability of identified controls stress the importance of the interplay among soil, vegetation and climate parameters in controlling warming responses. Global models might predict current soil respiration but not future rates because they neglect the controls exerted by soil development. To accurately predict the response of soil respiration to warming at the global scale, more observational studies across pedogenetically diverse soils are needed rather than focusing on the isolated effect of warming alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding the temperature sensitivity of soil respiration is critical to determining soil carbon dynamics under climate change. Spatial heterogeneity in controls highlights the importance of interactions between vegetation, soil and climate in driving the response of respiration to warming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;microplastics-in-terrestrial-ecosystems-moving-beyond-the-state-of-the-art-to-minimize-the-risk-of-ecological-surprise&quot;&gt;Microplastics in terrestrial ecosystems: Moving beyond the state of the art to minimize the risk of ecological surprise&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microplastic (plastic particles measuring &amp;lt;5mm) pollution is ubiquitous. Unlike in other well-studied ecosystems, for example, marine and freshwater environments, microplastics in terrestrial systems are relatively understudied. Their potential impacts on terrestrial environments, in particular the risk of causing ecological surprise, must be better understood and quantified. Ecological surprise occurs when ecosystem behavior deviates radically from expectations and generally has negative consequences for ecosystem services. The properties and behavior of microplastics within terrestrial environments may increase their likelihood of causing ecological surprises as they (a) are highly persistent global pollutants that will last for centuries, (b) can interact with the abiotic environment in a complex manner, (c) can impact terrestrial organisms directly or indirectly and (d) interact with other contaminants and can facilitate their transport. Here, we compiled findings of previous research on microplastics in terrestrial environments. We systematically focused on studies addressing different facets of microplastics related to their distribution, dispersion, impact on soil characteristics and functions, levels of biological organization of tested terrestrial biota (single species vs. assemblages), scale of experimental study and corresponding ecotoxicological effects. Our systematic assessment of previous microplastic research revealed that most studies have been conducted on single species under laboratory conditions with short-term exposures; few studies were conducted under more realistic long-term field conditions and/or with multi-species assemblages. Studies targeting multi-species assemblages primarily considered soil bacterial communities and showed that microplastics can alter essential nutrient cycling functions. More ecologically meaningful studies of terrestrial microplastics encompassing multi-species assemblages, critical ecological processes (e.g., biogeochemical cycles and pollination) and interactions with other anthropogenic stressors must be conducted. Addressing these knowledge gaps will provide a better understanding of microplastics as emerging global stressors and should lower the risk of ecological surprise in terrestrial ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/08/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on August 07, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/08/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/08/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-08-06T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-08-06T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-26&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #26&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Returning lands to nature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Boosting the generalization ability of Vis-NIR-spectroscopy-based regression models through dimension reduction and transfer learning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One shot evaluation of NPK in soils by “electronic tongue”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trafficking intensity index for soil compaction management in grasslands&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Geophysics conquering new territories: The rise of “agrogeophysics”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developing a strategy for the national coordinated soil moisture monitoring network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;returning-lands-to-nature&quot;&gt;Returning lands to nature&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Land-use-induced ecosystem reduction and degradation has profound impacts on the Earth system. Proceeding with currently unsustainable land use may jeopardize climate and ecosystem restoration targets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;boosting-the-generalization-ability-of-vis-nir-spectroscopy-based-regression-models-through-dimension-reduction-and-transfer-learning&quot;&gt;Boosting the generalization ability of Vis-NIR-spectroscopy-based regression models through dimension reduction and transfer learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calibration regression models based on visible and near-infrared (Vis/NIR) spectroscopy are now widely used in the rapid non-destructive prediction of agricultural products’ quality parameters. However, the distributions of products’ quality parameters and spectral responses are different in various batches of products, so a calibration regression model built on one dataset might be ineffective when tested in another. How to improve the generalization ability of models is a crucial problem and is formulated as ‘Calibration Transfer’. Calibration transfer was firstly proposed to eliminate the difference of spectral responses between spectrometers, but now it has been applied in the transfer between different domains of spectral samples or different components. In this paper, we proposed two robust models with great generalization ability in the calibration transfer task, respectively using dimension reduction and transfer learning, namely SPRS (Standard normal variate, Partial least squares dimension reduction, Ridge regression, Slope/bias) and SNV-based Aug-TrAdaBoost.R2. We tested the two models in spectral datasets of tea leaves to predict the moisture content of samples, it was found that SPRS and SNV-based Aug-TrAdaBoost.R2 can reach great performance over both source and target domains across different batches, different varieties, and different classes of tea leaf samples. SPRS and SNV-based Aug-TrAdaBoost.R2 achieved R2 values of 0.9314 and 0.9895 in cross-tea-class prediction whereas traditional calibration method PLSR + S/B only achieved 0.4874. SPRS had low computation complexity and was more robust while SNV-based Aug-TrAdaBoost.R2 had higher accuracy in target domain prediction but was computationconsuming. The two proposed models showed the potentials of online automatic quality parameters prediction and high-accuracy prediction across domains of various samples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;one-shot-evaluation-of-npk-in-soils-by-electronic-tongue&quot;&gt;One shot evaluation of NPK in soils by “electronic tongue”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart introduction of fertilizers in the soil should help to decrease the negative impact of chemicals on the environment without dramatic reduction of crop yield. The amounts of fertilizers have to be carefully tuned according to actual nutrients content in the soil and vegetation period of the plants. Since most of the chemical soil analyses are performed in the laboratory nowadays, fast and simple analytical tools have to be developed for this task. In this study, a potentiometric multisensor system was used for simultaneous determination of the N, P and K in the water extracts of the soils. It was shown that potentimetric sensors with multivariate data processing can be used for assessment of all three macronutrients, along with estimation of pH and conductivity of soil samples. Correlation coefficients between targeted parameters and sensor responses varied from 0.69 to 0.96. The quantification of N was possible with RMSE of 50 mg/kg in the range 60-426 mg/kg. The main benefits of the proposed approach are the short measurement duration - just 8 min for all the parameters, and reagentless procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;assessment-of-apparent-n-mineralization-at-field-scale&quot;&gt;Assessment of apparent N mineralization at field scale&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quantification of nitrogen mineralization at the field scale is necessary to improve current N fertilizer recommendations. The objective of this study was to identify a suitable set of explanatory variables and an appropriate modelling framework to estimate the average daily amount of N mineralized (DANM) during a corn (Zea mays L.) growing season. In six field experiments in Flat Inland Pampas, Argentina, DANM was evaluated in three different homogeneous zones (HZ), which were defined based on terrain elevation. Mixed-effect generalized linear models were developed that included growing season as random effect as well as HZ, sand, clay, silt, soil organic carbon, and normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI) as fixed effects. Results showed that DANM ranged from 0.19 to 1.25 kg N ha(-1) day(-1) with a mean of 0.64 kg N ha(-1) day(-1), which is equivalent to 110 kg N ha(-1) for the corn growing season. The best model included HZ, sand, and early NDVI measurements, and predicted DANM with an RMSE of 0.19 kg N ha(-1) day(-1). Thus, the model should be improved and tested in the Inland Flat Pampas before it could be used to assess N fertilizer application rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;trafficking-intensity-index-for-soil-compaction-management-in-grasslands&quot;&gt;Trafficking intensity index for soil compaction management in grasslands&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good soil structure provides multiple benefits for society but in grass-based production systems is underpinned by trafficking management regime. For Irish soils, there is no soil trafficking intensity index that considers the effect of geo-climatic variability or differences in drainage classes on soil compaction risk. Grazing and machinery activity data were compiled across 38 managed grasslands along with common soil structural quality indicators in order to develop and validate a ‘soil trafficking intensity index for compaction (STICi)’. Two component indices ofSTIC(i)were developed: (a) a grazing trafficking index (G(i), kg x year ha(-1)) and (b) a machinery trafficking index (M-i, kg x year ha(-1)). The average annual grazing trafficking pressure observed was 213,914 kg x year ha(-1), and the average annual machinery trafficking pressure was 4,412 kg x year ha(-1). These figures represent thresholds above which soils are at higher risk of compaction. M(i)spanned a wider range (-2.1 &amp;lt;= M-i &amp;lt;= 2.8) compared with G(i)(-1.32 &amp;lt;= G(i) &amp;lt;= 1.06).STIC(i)and components, when disaggregated by soil drainage class, were able to detect changes in direct indicators of soil structural quality, such as bulk density, total porosity, water holding capacity, water conductivity and visual soil assessment.STICi(M(i)and G(i)) were also related to indirect indicators, such as, soil carbon content, earthworms and microbial biomass. In general, poorly drained sites showed higher vulnerability to machinery trafficking intensity compared with grazing trafficking pressure. At national scale,STIC(i)can be utilized to identify soils at risk of compaction and underpin targeted management advice for supporting sustainable grassland production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;geophysics-conquering-new-territories-the-rise-of-agrogeophysics&quot;&gt;Geophysics conquering new territories: The rise of “agrogeophysics”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agriculture is facing immense challenges. We have to produce enough food while safe-guarding the environment for future generations. This results in the need to use less water and fertilizer, and to harness soil quality. Key to achieving this goal is improving the understanding of processes and interactions governing the soil-plant-atmosphere continuum of agricultural ecosystems. Geophysical tools have great potential to better characterize and quantify these processes noninvasively from the plot to landscape scale. Nevertheless, a number of challenges remain for geophysical results to be better exploited by different scientific communities and by decision-makers. In this special section, we explore ongoing research in the relatively new field of agrogeophysics, and we provide an overview of potential applications and highlight future research needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;developing-a-strategy-for-the-national-coordinated-soil-moisture-monitoring-network&quot;&gt;Developing a strategy for the national coordinated soil moisture monitoring network&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil moisture is a critical land surface variable, affecting a wide variety of climatological, agricultural, and hydrological processes. Determining the current soil moisture status is possible via a variety of methods, including in situ monitoring, remote sensing, and numerical modeling. Although all of these approaches are rapidly evolving, there is no cohesive strategy or framework to integrate these diverse information sources to develop and disseminate coordinated national soil moisture products that will improve our ability to understand climate variability. The National Coordinated Soil Moisture Monitoring Network initiative has developed a national strategy for network coordination with NOAA’s National Integrated Drought Information System. The strategy is currently in review within NOAA, and work is underway to implement the initial milestones of the strategy. This update reviews the goals and steps being taken to establish this national-scale coordination for soil moisture monitoring in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/08/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on August 06, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/08/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/08/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-08-05T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-08-05T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-25&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #25&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A comparison between three legacy soil maps of Zambia at national scale: The spatial patterns of legend units and their relation to soil properties.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dielectric models for moisture determination of soils with variable organic matter content&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ten challenges for the future of pedometrics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pedotransfer functions for estimating soil hydraulic properties from saturation to dryness&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil weathering behavior assessed by combined spectral ranges: Insights into aggregate analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-comparison-between-three-legacy-soil-maps-of-zambia-at-national-scale-the-spatial-patterns-of-legend-units-and-their-relation-to-soil-properties&quot;&gt;A comparison between three legacy soil maps of Zambia at national scale: The spatial patterns of legend units and their relation to soil properties&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We examined three soil maps of Zambia, two published at scales of 1:1 million - the Exploratory Soil Map of Zambia (ESMZ) and the Vegetation-Soil Map produced by Trapnell and colleagues in 1947 - and one at 1:3 million, the Soil Atlas of Africa (SAA). We estimated components of variance for measurements of clay, sand and organic carbon content and bulk density of the soil across the country using models which included different mean values for soil map units as random effects. For all but organic carbon content there was significant variation accounted for by differences between legend units for two of the maps, ESMZ with legend units based on the FAO-Unesco and SAA with legend units based on the World Reference Base respectively. This was despite their small cartographic scale. For the Vegetation-Soil Map, we examined differences between broad soil physiographic units. These did not account for significant variation in the soil properties. There were clear similarities between the soil physiographic units of the Soil-Vegetation Map and broader physiographic units into which the legend units of the ESMZ are grouped. The spatial pattern of soil units of the SAA was the most spatially heterogeneous, as measured by the sum of indicator variograms, despite being at the smallest published scale. It was apparent that some of the soil variation within the largest physiographic unit of the Soil-Vegetation Map, the Plateau Soils, as expressed by the map units of the SAA was significantly associated with the different vegetation units mapped in 1947. These studies show how quantitative assessment of legacy soil information may help us understand its potential and limitations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dielectric-models-for-moisture-determination-of-soils-with-variable-organic-matter-content&quot;&gt;Dielectric models for moisture determination of soils with variable organic matter content&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An accurate calibration function relating soil dielectric permittivity to its volumetric water content is essential for reliable measurements of soil moisture with the use of dielectric sensors. In the operational frequency range of popular capacitance and impedance sensors, various soil properties may influence the relation between the soil moisture and dielectric permittivity, which may worsen the measurement accuracy of a sensor. The aim of this paper is to investigate the relations among the organic matter content, dry bulk density, volumetric water content and dielectric permittivity in the 10-500 MHz frequency range, which covers the frequency range of operation of common soil moisture dielectric sensors operating in the frequency domain. Samples of soil material of belonging to sand, sandy loam and silt loam texture classes with varied organic matter content were measured with the use of a coaxial-like open-ended seven-rod probe connected to a vector-network-analyzer. A new simplified dielectric model is presented in order to accurately describe the obtained spectra. Next, several models connecting the real part of dielectric permittivity and volumetric water content, taking account of the impact of bulk density, were examined. It was found that two linear segmented models fitted to the obtained data better in the case of soil materials of sandy loam and silt loam textures. The best segmented model exhibited RMSE of about 0.023 m(3) m(-3) in comparison to about 0.04 m(3) m(-3) in the case of a simple linear model without density correction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ten-challenges-for-the-future-of-pedometrics&quot;&gt;Ten challenges for the future of pedometrics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pedometrics, the application of mathematical and statistical methods to the study of the distribution and genesis of soils, has broadened its scope over the past two decades. The primary focus of pedometricians has traditionally been on spatial and spatio-temporal soil inventories with numerical soil classification, geostatistical modelling of spatial variation and mapping. The rapid development of remote and proximal soil sensing as well as data-driven statistical modelling techniques have had a major impact on pedometrics over the past decades. During this time, a general demand for quantitative digital soil information for environmental modelling and management has compelled pedometricians to address other soil-related questions from a quantitative point of view: soil genesis and utility and quality of soil. While scientific progress is largely an autonomous process that is difficult to steer, research efforts could benefit from an agenda with pressing pedometric research topics. This paper defines and discusses ten recent or longstanding pedometrics challenges, with the attempt to identify knowledge gaps and suggest new concepts and methods to overcome them. The ten challenges were selected through a collaborative effort and may serve as a guidance for future pedometrics research and to foster collaboration among soil scientists. The challenges discussed in this paper are also indicators of the current understanding and state of knowledge from which progress can be measured in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pedotransfer-functions-for-estimating-soil-hydraulic-properties-from-saturation-to-dryness&quot;&gt;Pedotransfer functions for estimating soil hydraulic properties from saturation to dryness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current pedotransfer functions (PTFs) for estimating soil hydraulic curves are mostly developed to predict parameters of the Mualem-van Genuchten hydraulic functions. The Mualem-van Genuchten functions are recognised to be inadequate in representing soil water retention hydraulic conductivity curves at low pressure head ranges. This study presents neuroFX, a suite of PTFs, for estimating soil water retention and unsaturated hydraulic conductivity curves from saturation to complete dryness based on the Fredlund-Xing-Wang (FXW) model. The PTFs were calibrated using the neuro-m neural networks approach with three different sets of inputs: (1) SSCBD uses the sand, silt, and clay fractions, and bulk density; (2) SSC uses the sand, silt and clay fractions, and (3) soil textural class input. NeuroFX PTFs were trained using fitted parameters of the FXW model from selected data in the UNSODA database and validated using 5-fold cross-validation that was repeated 10 times. NeuroFX provides an uncertainty estimate of hydraulic parameters. The prediction quality of neuroFX was compared with two existing PTFs: ROSETTA and Brunswick-Weber (BW) PTFs. Based on multiple criteria, we found that neuroFX performed better than ROSETTA and BW PTFs in the same test sample. NeuroFX PTF with the SSCBD input yielded the best prediction of soil water retention and unsaturated hydraulic conductivity curves with RMSE in water content of 0.052 cm(3) cm(-3) and RMSE in log(10)(K) = 0.732 (in the magnitude of cm day(-1)), indicating the importance of including bulk density in the input of PTFs. NeuroFX was then used to map parameters of the FXW model for the whole of the continental USA over 6 depth intervals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-weathering-behavior-assessed-by-combined-spectral-ranges-insights-into-aggregate-analysis&quot;&gt;Soil weathering behavior assessed by combined spectral ranges: Insights into aggregate analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most research applying spectral sensors has focused on soil attributes quantification, with strong statistics and hundreds of data. Nevertheless, the explanation of the fundamental relationship between several spectral ranges and specific soil processes remains unclear. Soil sensing can be performed in many spectral ranges, however, the focus is usually on a specific one, which limits the knowledge of the phenomenon. Thus, this work investigated the synergistic performance of several spectral ranges (Gamma-ray; X-ray fluorescence, XRF; visible, Vis; near infrared, NIR; shortwave infrared, SWIR; and mid-infrared, MIR) on the weathering process of soils developed from magmatic material. Two soil profiles from Southeast Brazil (Sao Paulo state) were analyzed, assessing their chemical, physical and mineralogical data. The same profiles were analyzed by the indicated spectral ranges, which were related to mineralogy, weathering indices and mass balance (MB). The elements provided by Gamma-ray were related to the soil mineralogy and weathering degree of horizons. The XRF data enabled the calculation of MB and weathering indices, which were similar to those calculated by the traditional analysis. The spectra of the Vis-NIR-SWIR-MIR region presented alterations in their behavior related to the weathering degree of horizons. This synergic approach separated soil horizons by weathering degree more efficiently than a single spectral region. Single spectral measurements identified several elements and indices, which explained the weathering process. These results support further understanding of large datasets and their validation in statistical modeling.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/08/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on August 05, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/08/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/08/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-08-04T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-08-04T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-24&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #24&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nitrogen and phosphorus co-limit mineralization of labile carbon in deep subsoil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spatial evaluation and trade-off analysis of soil functions through Bayesian networks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Towards a standardization of soil-related ecosystem service assessments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A decision support framework assessing management impacts on crop yield, soil carbon changes and nitrogen losses to the environment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Machine learning in space and time for modelling soil organic carbon change&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perspectives on data-driven soil research&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identifying the fingerprint of permanganate oxidizable carbon as a measure of labile soil organic carbon using Fourier transform mid-infrared photoacoustic spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil organic carbon in irrigated agricultural systems: A meta-analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nitrogen-and-phosphorus-co-limit-mineralization-of-labile-carbon-in-deep-subsoil&quot;&gt;Nitrogen and phosphorus co-limit mineralization of labile carbon in deep subsoil&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peixoto, L; Elsgaard, L; (…); Olesen, JE
Jul 2021 | EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF SOIL SCIENCE 72 (4) , pp.1879-1884
The growth of deep-rooted crops has the potential to increase carbon deposition within deep subsoil layers, thereby contributing to climate change mitigation. Yet, the mechanisms of labile carbon stabilization in deep subsoils remain uncertain. Here we studied the effect of nitrogen, phosphorus and sulphur limitations on the microbial mineralization of added glucose and an artificial root exudate mixture (both spiked with C-14-glucose) in intact soil samples from a deep subsoil (5-6 m) over a 10-week incubation period, where the temporal respiration of CO2 and (CO2)-C-14 were quantified. We found that mineralization was co-limited by nitrogen and phosphorus, but the cumulative amount of CO2 emitted was significantly larger from artificial root exudates than glucose, suggesting that the nitrogen carried in amino acids in root exudates (here, L-arginine) was sufficient to overcome the nitrogen limitation in this subsoil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highlights&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Labile C substrates and nutrients from deep-rooted crops may affect the potential for C sequestration in subsoil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deep subsoil was incubated with glucose and artificial root exudates amended with N, P, and S.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C mineralization was co-limited by N and P, but less so in soil amended with glucose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amino acid derived-N in exudates from deep-rooted crops may alleviate the N limitation in deep subsoils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spatial-evaluation-and-trade-off-analysis-of-soil-functions-through-bayesian-networks&quot;&gt;Spatial evaluation and trade-off analysis of soil functions through Bayesian networks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vrebos, D; Jones, A; (…); Meire, P
Jul 2021 | EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF SOIL SCIENCE 72 (4) , pp.1575-1589
There is increasing recognition that soils fulfil many functions for society. Each soil can deliver a range of functions, but some soils are more effective at some functions than others due to their intrinsic properties. In this study we mapped four different soil functions on agricultural lands across the European Union. For each soil function, indicators were developed to evaluate their performance. To calculate the indicators and assess the interdependencies between the soil functions, data from continental long-term simulation with the DayCent model were used to build crop-specific Bayesian networks. These Bayesian Networks were then used to calculate the soil functions’ performance and trade-offs between the soil functions under current conditions. For each soil function the maximum potential was estimated across the European Union and changes in trade-offs were assessed. By deriving current and potential soil function delivery from Bayesian networks a better understanding is gained of how different soil functions and their interdependencies can differ depending on soil, climate and management. Highlights&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When increasing a soil function, how do trade-offs affect the other functions under different conditions? Bayesian networks evaluate trade-offs between soil functions and estimate their maximal delivery. Maximizing a soil function has varied effects on other functions depending on soil, climate and management. Differences in trade-offs make some locations more suitable for increasing a soil function then others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;towards-a-standardization-of-soil-related-ecosystem-service-assessments&quot;&gt;Towards a standardization of soil-related ecosystem service assessments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of ecosystem services (ES) creates understanding of the value of ecosystems for human well-being. With regard to soils, it provides a framework for assessments of soil contributions and soil management impacts. However, a lack of standardization impedes comparisons between assessment studies and the building of synthesis information. The Common International Classification of Ecosystem Services (CICES) is an important step forward, although its application to soils is not without difficulty. CICES version 5.1 defines 83 ES classes, of which only some are relevant for soils. We compiled two subsets of CICES classes: one set of soil-related ES comprising 29 services defined as directly and quantifiably controlled by soils and their properties, processes and functions, and another set of 40 ES defined as being affected by agricultural soil management.Additionally, we conducted a systematic literature review, searching for published lists of soil-related ES that claim completeness. We identified 11 relevant lists. Of all CICES classes, 12 were included in more than 75% of the lists, whereas another 36 classes were included in 25-75% of them. Regarding the suitability of the CICES classification for addressing ES in the context of soils and their agricultural management, we identified constraints, such as overlaps, gaps, and highly specific or very broad class definitions.Close cooperation between the soil research and ES communities could ensure better consideration of soils in future CICES updates. A shortlist of 25 service classes affected by agricultural soil management facilitates a standardized approach and may function as checklists in impact assessments. Highlights&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standardized definitions are needed to allow meta-analysis of ecosystem service studies and improve assessments. CICES defines 83 detailed classes of ecosystem services, suggested as a “default list”. We identified 29 classes as soil related and 40 classes as affected by agricultural soil management. Both subsets facilitate ecosystem service assessments in soil research and comparability of results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-decision-support-framework-assessing-management-impacts-on-crop-yield-soil-carbon-changes-and-nitrogen-losses-to-the-environment&quot;&gt;A decision support framework assessing management impacts on crop yield, soil carbon changes and nitrogen losses to the environment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agricultural management practices have multiple impacts on farming systems, including crop yield, soil fertility parameters such as soil organic carbon (SOC), and environmental quality. Agricultural decision support tools (DSTs) are key in sustainable farm strategies to optimize yield and minimize environmental losses because both the current agroecosystem properties as well as the effectiveness of management practices are highly variable in time and space. Here, we introduce a highly data-driven framework focusing on the evaluation of agronomic measures to reach agronomic and environmental targets. We demonstrate the potential of this approach by a proof of principle for 81 selected farm types across Europe, focusing on measures with respect to crop rotation, fertilization and soil tillage. Synthesizing data from long-term experiments and meta-analytical models, we estimated the impact of these measures on crop yield, SOC and N surpluses, while accounting for site-specific properties for the current and desired situation. The impacts of these measures on all farm types have been quantified, and optimum sets of agronomic measures have been selected in order to maximize crop yield and SOC levels and minimize N surpluses to reach the critical values for NO(3)(-)concentrations in groundwater. Our results, quantifying trade-offs among sustainability indicators that have traditionally been analyzed separately, illustrate that the suitability of measures varies by soil, climate and crop types within Europe. Our approach is promising for mapping region-specific management recommendations and evaluating the effectiveness of agronomic measures over multiple environmental goals and targets. Highlights&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We find a lack of empirical-based DSTs holistically assessing agronomic practices and indicators. Meta-analytical models were used to assess impacts of best fertilizer, tillage and crop measures. Our multi-criteria analysis shows impacts vary with crop, soil and climate in European regions. We demonstrate our developed framework focusing on crop yield, soil carbon and nitrogen losses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;machine-learning-in-space-and-time-for-modelling-soil-organic-carbon-change&quot;&gt;Machine learning in space and time for modelling soil organic carbon change&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spatially resolved estimates of change in soil organic carbon (SOC) stocks are necessary for supporting national and international policies aimed at achieving land degradation neutrality and climate change mitigation. In this work we report on the development, implementation and application of a data-driven, statistical method for mapping SOC stocks in space and time, using Argentina as a pilot. We used quantile regression forest machine learning to predict annual SOC stock at 0-30 cm depth at 250 m resolution for Argentina between 1982 and 2017. The model was calibrated using over 5,000 SOC stock values from the 36-year time period and 35 environmental covariates. We preprocessed normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI) dynamic covariates using a temporal low-pass filter to allow the SOC stock for a given year to depend on the NDVI of the current as well as preceding years. Predictions had modest temporal variation, with an average decrease for the entire country from 2.55 to 2.48 kg C m(-2)over the 36-year period (equivalent to a decline of 211 Gg C, 3.0% of the total 0-30 cm SOC stock in Argentina). The Pampa region had a larger estimated SOC stock decrease from 4.62 to 4.34 kg C m(-2)(5.9%) during the same period. For the 2001-2015 period, predicted temporal variation was seven-fold larger than that obtained using the Tier 1 approach of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change and United Nations Convention to Combat Desertification. Prediction uncertainties turned out to be substantial, mainly due to the limited number and poor spatial and temporal distribution of the calibration data, and the limited explanatory power of the covariates. Cross-validation confirmed that SOC stock prediction accuracy was limited, with a mean error of 0.03 kg C m(-2)and a root mean squared error of 2.04 kg C m(-2). In spite of the large uncertainties, this work showed that machine learning methods can be used for space-time SOC mapping and may yield valuable information to land managers and policymakers, provided that SOC observation density in space and time is sufficiently large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;perspectives-on-data-driven-soil-research&quot;&gt;Perspectives on data-driven soil research&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil is a complex system in which biological, chemical and physical interactions take place. The behaviour of these interactions changes in spatial scale from the atomic to the global, and in time. To understand how this system works, soil scientists usually rely on incremental improvements in the knowledge by refinement of theories through hypothesis testing and development using carefully designed experiments. In the last two decades, the primacy of this knowledge construction process has been challenged by the development of large soil databases and algorithms such as machine learning. The data-driven research approach to soil science, the inference of soil knowledge directly from data by using computational tools and modelling techniques, is becoming more popular. Despite the wide adoption of a data-driven research approach to soil science, there has been little discussion on how a research driven by data instead of hypotheses affects scientific progress. In this paper, we provide an introductory perspective on data-driven soil research by discussing some of the issues and opportunities of knowledge discovery from soil data. We show that while data-driven soil research may seem revolutionary for some, soil science has a long history of exploratory efforts to generate knowledge from data. Empirical and factual soil classifications, for example, were data driven. We further discuss, with examples, (i) data, databases and the logic of data storage for data-driven soil research, (ii) the issues of extreme empiricist claims that arise corollary to the increase in the use of computational tools, and (iii) the challenge of formulating a scientific explanation based on patterns observed in the data and data analysis tools. By considering the epistemic challenges of the data-driven scientific research in the light of the historical literature, we found that there is a continuity of practices, some being certainly amplified by recent technological changes, but that the core methods of scientific enquiry from data remain essentially unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;identifying-the-fingerprint-of-permanganate-oxidizable-carbon-as-a-measure-of-labile-soil-organic-carbon-using-fourier-transform-mid-infrared-photoacoustic-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Identifying the fingerprint of permanganate oxidizable carbon as a measure of labile soil organic carbon using Fourier transform mid-infrared photoacoustic spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Permanganate oxidizable carbon (POXC) is a sub-pool of labile soil organic carbon (SOC) and is defined as the carbon (C) that can be oxidized by potassium permanganate (KMnO4). Determination of the content of POXC has been used as a way to measure labile C and may be related to soil microbial biomass and particulate organic C. Fourier transform mid-infrared photoacoustic spectroscopy (FTIR-PAS) has been used for characterizing the chemical composition of soil organic matter. The objective of the current study was to identify the chemical information in the FTIR-PAS spectra that is unique to POXC and therefore associated with labile C. FTIR-PAS was used for characterizing SOC using a set of soil samples collected in four different countries (Laos, Malaysia, Peru and Thailand, n = 575). Partial least squares (PLS) regression was used to correlate the collected FTIR-PAS spectra with both POXC and total SOC. The FTIR-PAS spectra combined with the PLS method was useful for predicting both SOC and POXC. However, SOC and POXC were also highly correlated (R-2 = 0.84), and because POXC can be seen as a fraction of total SOC, a method for extracting the FTIR-PAS fingerprint of the POXC model that is independent of SOC was applied for the first time. The results showed that the POXC prediction was mainly based on its strong correlation with SOC and there was little information unique to POXC. However, the results do indicate four dominant peaks at 1,574, 1,495, 1,138 and 1,041 cm(-1) to be specific for POXC. These peaks can be ascribed to amide II, aromatics, polysaccharides and carbohydrates, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highlights&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Permanganate oxidizable carbon (POXC) was predicted using FTIR-photoacoustic spectroscopy (FTIR-PAS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The POXC prediction using FTIR-PAS is mainly based on its high correlation with SOC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A method extracting the unique spectral features of POXC independently of SOC was applied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 11% of the information used to predict POXC was identified as unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four dominant peaks were found to represent the POXC fingerprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-organic-carbon-in-irrigated-agricultural-systems-a-meta-analysis&quot;&gt;Soil organic carbon in irrigated agricultural systems: A meta-analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last 200 years, conversion of non-cultivated land for agriculture has substantially reduced global soil organic carbon (SOC) stocks in upper soil layers. Nevertheless, practices such as no- or reduced tillage, application of organic soil amendments, and maintenance of continuous cover can increase SOC in agricultural fields. While these management practices have been well studied, the effects on SOC of cropping systems that incorporate irrigation are poorly understood. Given the large, and expanding, agricultural landbase under irrigation across the globe, this is a critical knowledge gap for climate change mitigation. We undertook a systematic literature review and subsequent meta-analysis of data from studies that examined changes in SOC on irrigated agricultural sites through time. We investigated changes in SOC by climate (aridity), soil texture, and irrigation method with the following objectives: (i) to examine the impact of irrigated agriculture on SOC storage; and (ii) to identify the conditions under which irrigated agriculture is most likely to enhance SOC. Overall, irrigated agriculture increased SOC stocks by 5.9%, with little effect of study length (2-47 years). However, changes in SOC varied by climate and soil depth, with the greatest increase in SOC observed on irrigated semi-arid sites at the 0-10 cm depth (14.8%). Additionally, SOC increased in irrigated fine- and medium-textured soils but not coarse-textured soils. Furthermore, while there was no overall change to SOC in flood/furrow irrigated sites, SOC tended to increase in sprinkler irrigated sites, and decrease in drip irrigated sites, especially at depths below 10 cm. This work sheds light on the nuances of SOC change across irrigated agricultural systems, highlights the importance of studying SOC storage in deeper soils, and will help guide future research on the impacts of irrigated agriculture on SOC.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/08/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on August 04, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/08/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/08/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-08-03T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-08-03T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-23&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #23&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evaluation of soil organic matter from integrated production systems using laser-induced fluorescence spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spatial decoupling of legacy phosphorus in cropland: Soil erosion and deposition as a mechanism for storage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How does soil compaction alter nitrous oxide fluxes? A meta-analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new model for an improved AMSR2 satellite soil moisture retrieval over agricultural areas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the impact of increasing drought on the relationship between soil water content and evapotranspiration of a grassland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evaluation-of-soil-organic-matter-from-integrated-production-systems-using-laser-induced-fluorescence-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Evaluation of soil organic matter from integrated production systems using laser-induced fluorescence spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agricultural areas under integrated production systems, such as Integrated Crop-Livestock-Forest System (CLFS), have the potential to sequestrate carbon (C) since both Soil Organic Matter (SOM) content and trees biomass increase thus mitigating the emission of greenhouse gases (GHGs) from agriculture. Regarding soil aspects, the C content stands out as the main indicator, but the structural aspect of SOM is also relevant since it plays a key role in the chemical stability of C compounds and the soil lifetime of C compounds. Laser-Induced Fluorescence Spectroscopy (LIFS) is an effective technique to evaluate the SOM humification index (HLIFS) from practically intact whole soil samples under different agricultural systems. Thus, the objective of this study was to analyze the SOM humification index in different integrated systems, such as Integrated Crop-Livestock-Forest System (CLFS), Integrated Livestock-Forest System (LFS), Integrated Crop-Livestock System (CLS), and in references areas, such as Intensive Pasture (INT), Extensive Pasture (EXT) and Native Forest (NF). For this purpose, samples of Redyellow Latosol (Haplorthox by Soil taxonomy) from the experimental site located at Embrapa Pecu ‘ aria Sudeste (Southeast of Brazil) were collected five years after the establishment of the integrated systems. Samples were collected at soil depths of 0-5, 5-10, 10-20, 20-30, 30-40, 40-60, 60-80, and 80-100 cm. Pellets of the whole soil samples were prepared for LIFS analysis. In these areas, SOM humification indices (HLIFS) presented the following descending order: CLS &amp;gt; EXT &amp;gt; INT &amp;gt; LFS &amp;gt; CLFS &amp;gt; NF. Previous results have shown a greater soil organic carbon stock in these integrated production systems than in the NF area, suggesting C sequestration in agricultural soil. In the present study, SOM was classified by LIFS as more chemically stable in integrated production systems than in native vegetation. Higher amounts of fluorescent compounds were identified from LIFS data, probably resulting from condensed aromatic groups. SOM with more recalcitrant groups normally has a longer lifetime in the soil, indicating a long-term contribution to mitigating climate change by avoiding fast SOM decomposition and CO2 return to the atmosphere. Also, for the first time, this study was able to identify a positive correlation (R = 0.79) between the SOM humification index (HLIFS) and the Cation Exchange Capacity (CEC)/C content ratio of whole soil samples, another innovative contribution from soil LIFS analyses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spatial-decoupling-of-legacy-phosphorus-in-cropland-soil-erosion-and-deposition-as-a-mechanism-for-storage&quot;&gt;Spatial decoupling of legacy phosphorus in cropland: Soil erosion and deposition as a mechanism for storage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agricultural production continues to be implicated as one cause of eutrophication of water courses and water bodies in many agro-ecosystems. The generally-held consensus is that soil erosion by water is a major mechanism for loss of phosphorus (P) to adjacent water bodies and down-stream reservoirs from crop and grazing lands. Nonetheless, it does not explain the whole story of the fate of P losses applied to soils. This study assessed the spatial distribution of P as a consequence of historical erosion and redistribution of soil in an agricultural field in the Lake Erie basin in southern Ontario. Combining stratified random sampling with geospatial analysis of landscape position, plant-available (Olsen) P concentrations and stocks were measured and compared to other soil properties and related to soil erosion and redistribution. Toe-slope and foot-slope positions had two to three times the Olsen P stocks compared to summit landscape positions (mean of 52 +1- 9 kg P ha(-1) and 47 +1- 9 kg P ha(-1) versus 20 +/- 2 kg P ha(-1), respectively) which was attributed to both water and tillage erosion. Burial of P beneath the plowing depth showed that the toe-slopes had over two to three times more Olsen P stocks below 25 cm depth compared to all other landscape positions. Olsen P stocks were significantly related (R-2 = 0.50; p &amp;lt; 0.001) to soil organic carbon (SOC) stocks which was a consequence of historical soil erosion and redistribution in the field. The fate of legacy P in soils may be dependent upon the history of erosion and redistribution resulting in deposition of P in toe-slope and foot-slope positions in an agricultural landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-does-soil-compaction-alter-nitrous-oxide-fluxes-a-meta-analysis&quot;&gt;How does soil compaction alter nitrous oxide fluxes? A meta-analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nitrous oxide (N2O) is a potent greenhouse gas and precursor of ozone layer depletion. Managed terrestrial ecosystems are major anthropogenic sources of N2O, primarily generated in the soil. The physical makeup of the soil interplays with the underlying biochemistry that produces N2O. Therefore, it has been conceptualized that either compacting or loosening the soil will alter N2O emissions; however, a unified framework of these relationships is yet to be established. Here, we compiled, reviewed and analyzed available field studies that have evaluated how applied compaction or alleviation of compacted soils impacts N2O emissions. Of the 108 available pairwise comparisons, 82 % of the cases showed detrimental increases in N2O emissions caused by increased compaction. Overall, N2O emissions nearly doubled because of soil compaction effects (P &amp;lt; 0.05). This doubling of N2O emissions was linked to a relative reduction of 9 % in soil porosity (i.e., 0.05 cm3 cm-3) caused by applied compaction. This linkage to soil porosity was clearly evident in both croplands and pastures. Across the managed terrestrial ecosystems evaluated, the strongest relative effects of compaction on N2O emissions were found in forest and pasture soils. Overall, N2O emissions in forest soils showed a fivefold increase caused by compaction (P &amp;lt; 0.05; n = 11). This massive response in forest soils can be attributed to: i) their low N2O emission baseline; ii) their acidic pH, which intrinsically favors N2O emissions; iii) having some of the heaviest traffic loads found across our meta-analysis (e.g., 16 Mg); and iv) an increase in soil microporosity. Pasture soils also displayed substantial compaction effects on N2O emissions, with a threefold increase (P &amp;lt; 0.05; n = 25). This was explained in part by the elevated nitrogen input rates in pastures (e.g., 600-1000 kg N ha-1). Conversely, alleviation of soil compaction by implementing controlled traffic farming (CTF) in vegetable and grain croplands reduced N2O emissions consistently in all available pairwise comparisons (P &amp;lt; 0.05; n = 19). At the field scale, CTF greatly decreased N2O emissions by one-third compared with farmlands managed with conventional random traffic (4.48 versus 2.86 kg N2O-N ha-1). However, after reviewing the available literature, we witnessed a paucity of information about how long it takes for soils to self-alleviate from the detrimental effects of compaction on N2O emissions. Additionally, insights gained through meta-analysis revealed the interplay of soil compaction with underlying heavy textures, acidic pH, and reduced porosities, which collectively exacerbate N2O emissions. Nevertheless, these complex interactions operate differentially across contrasting land use options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-new-model-for-an-improved-amsr2-satellite-soil-moisture-retrieval-over-agricultural-areas&quot;&gt;A new model for an improved AMSR2 satellite soil moisture retrieval over agricultural areas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This study evaluates the potential of AMSR2 (Advance Microwave Scanning Radiometer2) data for the estimation of Volumetric Soil Moisture (VSM) for bare and agricultural areas. At the first step, the sensitivity of the Microwave Polarization Difference Index (MPDI) to variations in soil and vegetation characteristics were examined at different frequencies. At lower frequencies, the signal attenuation due to vegetation is minimal and thus, denser vegetation usually depolarizes the soil emission. Interestingly, the results also reveal that at higher frequencies, the sensitivity of V and H polarizations over relatively dense vegetation covers is not the same at all. Therefore, MPDI at both low and high frequencies can be a good indicator of the soil moisture and Vegetation Water Content (VWC), respectively. After evaluation of AMSR2 datasets, a model called Multi-channel/MPDIbased Land Parameters Retrieval Model (MMLPRM) is proposed. The MMLPRM optimizes optical depth of vegetation and soil dielectric constant, with simultaneous retrieval of soil moisture and surface temperature by using the AMSR2 brightness temperature data. This algorithm also includes the surface roughness parameters to increase the soil moisture retrieval efficiency. In this way, calibration and validation have been done, using in situ observations of 50 monitoring stations obtained from the International Soil Moisture Network (ISMN) over the United States. Consequently, the analysis on the MMLPRM retrieval model demonstrates its potential and usefulness for soil moisture retrieval. The outcome of this study will help in estimating the accurate soil moisture to optimize the irrigation management strategies and help in water conservation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;on-the-impact-of-increasing-drought-on-the-relationship-between-soil-water-content-and-evapotranspiration-of-a-grassland&quot;&gt;On the impact of increasing drought on the relationship between soil water content and evapotranspiration of a grassland&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weighable lysimeters were used to study the relation between soil water content (SWC) and the actual evapotranspiration (ETa) of grassland under two different climate regimes of Rollesbroich and Selhausen but for an identical soil from Rollesbroich. All components of the water balance were determined from 2012 until 2018. Budyko analysis was used to characterize the hydrological status of the studied sites. Wavelet analysis was also applied to study the power spectrum of ETa, vegetation-height-adjusted reference evapotranspiration (ETcrop), and water stress index (WSI) defined as ETa/ETcrop, as well as SWC at three different depths and the coherence between SWC and ETa and WSI. The Budyko analysis showed that 2018 resulted in a shift of both locations towards more water-limited conditions, although Rollesbroich remained an energy-limited system. Based on the power spectrum analysis, the annual timescale is the dominant scale for the temporal variability of ETa, ETcrop, and SWC. The results also showed that increasing dryness at the energy-limited site led to more temporal variability of SWC at all depths at the annual timescale. Wavelet coherence analysis showed a reduction of the phase shift between SWC and ETa at an annual scale caused by the increase in dryness during the measurement period. We found that phase shifts between SWC and ETa and SWC and WSI were stronger at the water-limited site than at the energy-limited site. The wavelet coherence analysis also showed that from 2014 to 2018, the control of ETa and WSI on SWC increased due to higher dryness of soil.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/08/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on August 03, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/08/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/08/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-08-02T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-08-02T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-22&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #22&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shift to plant-based diets: are we missing the point?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can agroecology improve food security and nutrition? A review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assessing map accuracy from a suite of site-specific, non-site specific, and spatial distribution approaches.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hybrid LIBS-Raman-LIF systems for multi-modal spectroscopic applications: a topical review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-shift-to-plant-based-diets-are-we-missing-the-point&quot;&gt;The shift to plant-based diets: are we missing the point?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is increasing consensus that limiting consumption of meat and dairy products can contribute to lowering the environmental impact of diets. At the same time, the market for ultra-processed plant-based substitutes for meat and dairy (ie. ‘milk’, ‘cheese’ and ‘yoghurt’) is expanding to meet changing consumer demands. This shift far outpaces the revision of dietary guidelines and other nutritional guidance. Here, we identify significant knowledge gaps in the nutritional composition of meat and dairy substitutes as well as the extent to which they comprise modern diets in many countries in the WHO European Region. We also highlight that most dietary models are not based on real-life dietary patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;can-agroecology-improve-food-security-and-nutrition-a-review&quot;&gt;Can agroecology improve food security and nutrition? A review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agroecology increasingly has gained scientific and policy recognition as having potential to address environmental and social issues within food production, but concerns have been raised about its implications for food security and nutrition, particularly in low-income countries. This review paper examines recent evidence (1998-2019) for whether agroecological practices can improve human food security and nutrition. A total of 11,771 articles were screened by abstract and title, 275 articles included for full review, with 56 articles (55 cases) selected. A majority of studies (78%) found evidence of positive outcomes in the use of agroecological practices on food security and nutrition of households in low and middle-income countries. Agroecological practices included crop diversification, intercropping, agroforestry, integrating crop and livestock, and soil management measures. More complex agroecological systems, that included multiple components (e.g., crop diversification, mixed crop-livestock systems and farmer-to-farmer networks) were more likely to have positive food security and nutrition outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;assessing-map-accuracy-from-a-suite-of-site-specific-non-site-specific-and-spatial-distribution-approaches&quot;&gt;Assessing map accuracy from a suite of site-specific, non-site specific, and spatial distribution approaches.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assessing a map’s accuracy and efficacy requires careful consideration and calculation of a comprehensive set of measures, particularly when characteristics in geospatial datasets may be used for addressing multiple objectives. We describe a map accuracy assessment framework for categorical geospatial data over large areas that utilizes site-specific (plot-pixel), non-site specific (area estimates), and comparative accuracy (spatial and statistical distributions) methods. This comprehensive framework spans the range of approaches applied in most other studies, maximizing opportunities for both within- and between-study comparisons. The analysis framework incorporated recommended good practices for sampling design, response design, analysis protocols, and designbased inference for providing rigorous estimates of accuracy and precision. Further partitioning of disagreement allows users to assess the relative importance of spatial location versus total abundance of map classes to map error; we introduced a ratio of allocation disagreement to quantity disagreement for comparing relative importance of each across datasets. Assessment of fuzzy membership with linguistic scales may have minimal effect on overall accuracy, but can provide substantial improvement in user’s accuracy and producer’s accuracy for uncommon classes. We adapted non-site specific approaches to provide metrics and insights into spatial variability of map accuracy of thematic classes. Comparing estimates based on reference data and co-located samples of map data may reveal potential issues with reference data. We demonstrated example applications all components of the assessment framework for thematic maps of early successional forest and other land cover classes across the western Great Lakes region, USA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hybrid-libs-raman-lif-systems-for-multi-modal-spectroscopic-applications-a-topical-review&quot;&gt;Hybrid LIBS-Raman-LIF systems for multi-modal spectroscopic applications: a topical review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This review discusses the importance of hyphenating different laser-based techniques such as Laser-Induced Breakdown Spectroscopy (LIBS), Raman spectroscopy and Laser-Induced Fluorescence spectroscopy (LIF) and the applications of the hybrid systems. These spectroscopic techniques, in single and multi-modes, are widely accepted as an efficient tool to retrieve information from atomic and molecular systems such as knowledge on chemical bonds, molecular structure and geometry, interactions and related mechanisms etc. Analytical capabilities of such systems which combine LIBS, Raman, and LIF are highly desirable since one can acquire complementary information from the same sample enabling a remarkable potential for various applications in diverse fields like archeology, mineralogy, planetary explorations, clinical chemistry, biomedical and environmental monitoring etc to extract more information. In this review, attention has been devoted to the works of combined LIBS-LIF-Raman technique in different fields and its significance, along with brief discussions on other combinations like LIBS-Raman, LIBS-LIF, and Raman-LIF.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/08/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on August 02, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/07/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/07/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-07-07T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-07-07T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-21&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #21&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil organic carbon estimation using VNIR-SWIR spectroscopy: The effect of multiple sensors and scanning conditions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using ground-penetrating radar to investigate the thickness of mollic epipedons developed from loessial parent material&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evaluating validation strategies on the performance of soil property prediction from regional to continental spectral data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Digital soil maps can perform as well as large-scale conventional soil maps for the prediction of catchment baseflows&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimation of root zone soil moisture from ground and remotely sensed soil information with multisensor data fusion and automated machine learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-organic-carbon-estimation-using-vnir-swir-spectroscopy-the-effect-of-multiple-sensors-and-scanning-conditions&quot;&gt;Soil organic carbon estimation using VNIR-SWIR spectroscopy: The effect of multiple sensors and scanning conditions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visible-near infrared-shortwave infrared (VNIR-SWIR) spectroscopy is being increasingly used for soil organic carbon (SOC) assessment. Common practice consists of scanning soil samples using a single spectrometer. Considerations have rarely been documented of the effects of using multiple instruments and scanning conditions on SOC model calibration that occur when merging soil spectral libraries (SSLs), particularly in soils with low SOC concentration and using both field spectroradiometers and laboratory fixed spectrometers. To address this gap, we scanned 143 low-SOC-content soil samples using three spectrometers (ASD FieldSpec 3, ASD FieldSpec 4, and FOSS XDS) and four setup features - FOSS, contact probe (CP), dark-box (DB), and open laboratory (LAB) - at three laboratories. The application of an internal soil standard (ISS) to align one laboratory spectrum with another for spectral correction and spectral merging of various SSLs was examined. SOC models were developed using i) data from each single spectrometer - single laboratory separately and ii) merged data from multiple spectrometers - different laboratories, applying the 1st derivatives of spectra and random forest (RF) regression. The results indicate that the spectral shape and wavelength position of key features obtained from all spectrometers and setups did not show any noticeable differences, though spectra based on FOSS setup, particularly on low-SOC samples, demonstrated greater range in absolute derivative values regardless of ISS application. The derivative ISS-corrected spectra showed less variation among different spectrometers compared to their uncorrected raw reflectance spectra. All single spectrometer models predicted SOC reasonably well. However, the spectra acquired by the FOSS setup predicted SOC more accurately (R2 = 0.77, RPIQ = 3.30, RMSE = 0.22 %, and SD = 0.04) than the spectra acquired by the other setups. The models derived from merged uncorrected raw reflectance spectra yielded poor results (R2 = 0.48, RPIQ = 2.33, RMSE = 0.33 %, and SD = 0.10); nevertheless, assessment of SOC using the 1st derivative ISS-corrected merged SSLs considerably improved the prediction accuracy (R2 = 0.70, RPIQ = 3.10, RMSE = 0.25 %, and SD = 0.06). Hence, the derivative spectra coupled with the ISS correction improved the accuracy of SOC prediction models obtained from the merged soil spectra collected in different environments using different instruments. We therefore recommend application of the ISS spectral alignment method linked to the 1st derivative approach to enhance the compilation of SSLs at the regional and global scales for SOC assessment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-ground-penetrating-radar-to-investigate-the-thickness-of-mollic-epipedons-developed-from-loessial-parent-material&quot;&gt;Using ground-penetrating radar to investigate the thickness of mollic epipedons developed from loessial parent material&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The information of mollic epipedon (ME) thickness was essential for evaluation and protection of Mollisol resource. However, the traditional methods including the soil profile method, soil probes, and the drilling method, are low efficient and accurate for large area survey of soil thickness. In this study, the ground penetrating radar (GPR) was employed to detect the thickness of ME with underlying loessial parent material (LPM) along three slopes in straight, convex, and concave shapes in northeast China. The accuracy of GPR for measuring the ME thickness was verified by using excavation profile and pre-buried iron pipes. The effects of soil moisture and bulk density on soil permittivity were also investigated based on indoor experiments. The results indicated that the soil permittivity increased and decreased with the increase of bulk density and soil moisture, respectively. The relationships among soil moisture, bulk density and permittivity of both Mollisol and LPM could be described by two fitted equations, and the errors of the prediction equations was in the range of 0.32 %-5.10 %. The errors of GPR to measure the ME thickness was in the range of 3.72 %-10.64 %. The spatial distribution of the ME thickness along the three slopes varied, and the concave slope had a thicker ME than the convex and straight slope. Meanwhile, similar trends were shown that the sedimentation at the slope foot led to the thickest ME, while soil erosion at the slope shoulder and back resulted in the thinnest ME. This study could provide an efficient and accurate method to investigate soil thickness for further evaluation and protection of soil resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evaluating-validation-strategies-on-the-performance-of-soil-property-prediction-from-regional-to-continental-spectral-data&quot;&gt;Evaluating validation strategies on the performance of soil property prediction from regional to continental spectral data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visible-near infrared (vis-NIR) spectroscopy has been widely used to characterize soil information from field to global scales. Before applying a calibrated spectral predictive model to acquire soil information, either independent validation or k-fold cross validation is used to evaluate model performance. However, there is no consensus on which validation strategy is more suitable and robust when evaluating model performance for the studies in different scales. The objective of this study is to evaluate and compare the model performance of two validation strategies coupling different calibration sizes (a ratio of calibration to validation of 2:1, 4:1 and 9:1) and calibration sampling strategies (random sampling (RS), rank, Kennard-Stone (KS), rank-Kennard-Stone (RKS) and conditioned Latin hypercube sampling (cLHS)) across scales. A total of 17,272 vis-NIR spectra of mineral soils from LUCAS data (continental scale) and their soil organic carbon (SOC) and clay contents were used in this study, and the dataset was further split into national (2761 samples in France) and five regional datasets (110 to 248 samples from five French administrative regions). To eliminate the effect of changing validation set on the model performance, a consistent test set (20% of total samples at each scale) was split to evaluate all the combinations involved in two validation strategies. The Lin’s concordance correlation coefficient (CCC) of the cubist model were stable for both SOC and clay for different calibration sizes, calibration sampling and validation strategies for a large calibration size (&amp;gt;1400) at the national and continental scales. A larger calibration size can potentially improve model performance for a small dataset (&amp;lt;300) at the regional scale, and a wider calibration range would result in better model performance. No silver bullet was found among the different calibration sampling strategies at the regional scale. For five French regions (small data set), we found a high variation (95th percentile minus the 5th percentile) in the CCC among the models built from 50 repeated RS (0.10-0.44 for SOC, 0.16-0.52 for clay) and cLHS (0.08-0.40 for SOC, 0.12-0.36 for clay). This finding indicates that a one-time RS or cLHS for selecting the calibration set has high uncertainty in model evaluation for a small dataset and therefore should be used with caution. Therefore, we suggest the following: (1) for a large data set (thousands), either one-time random sampling for independent validation or k-fold cross validation would be appropriate; (2) for a small data set (dozens to hundreds), k-fold cross validation and/or repeated random sampling for independent validation would be more robust for spectral predictive model evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;digital-soil-maps-can-perform-as-well-as-large-scale-conventional-soil-maps-for-the-prediction-of-catchment-baseflows&quot;&gt;Digital soil maps can perform as well as large-scale conventional soil maps for the prediction of catchment baseflows&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rapid advance of digital soil mapping (DSM) has resulted in the generation of fine resolution soils spatial datasets with associated uncertainty that can be as accurate but more cost-effective and faster to produce than conventional soil maps. There is documented and increasing interest by policy makers and end-users in moving from conventional soil mapping to DSM; however, the wider operational use of DSM depends on demonstrating the effectiveness of DSM in fulfilling user needs and requirements along with providing DSM products that can be easily used by non-specialists. In this study we used the Hydrology of Soil Types (HOST) classification scheme, which was devised to predict flows in ungauged catchments and is used by both the research and policy maker communities in the UK, as the exemplar for comparing the efficiency of HOST class maps produced using both DSM and conventional soil map approaches for predicting catchment hydrological response. The performance for hydrological predictions of a detailed (1:25,000 scale) polygon HOST class map and a HOST-DSM class map produced via spatial disaggregation was assessed by comparing Base Flow Index (BFI) calculated using HOST class proportions from both maps with BFI calculated using flow data from gauges in 39 selected catchments. Results showed that the disaggregated HOST-DSM class map gave similar or even better BFI predictions than the conventional polygon-based HOST class map, while also providing a better insight on spatial soil variability within map units and its effect on hydrological predictions. This study demonstrates the potential of DSM to produce soil hydrological maps that provide comparable or better baseflow predictions than maps produced using detailed and intensive soil surveying. The study results also suggest that translating DSM of classes to more easily interpretable mapping datasets and incorporating prediction uncertainty in the final DSM product, as in the case of BFI maps based on HOST-DSM classes, could help with facilitating the transition towards a wider operational use of DSM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;estimation-of-root-zone-soil-moisture-from-ground-and-remotely-sensed-soil-information-with-multisensor-data-fusion-and-automated-machine-learning&quot;&gt;Estimation of root zone soil moisture from ground and remotely sensed soil information with multisensor data fusion and automated machine learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Root zone soil moisture (RZSM) estimation and monitoring based on high spatial resolution remote sensing information such as obtained with an Unmanned Aerial System (UAS) is of significant interest for field-scale precision irrigation management, particularly in water-limited regions of the world. To date, there is no accurate and widely accepted model that relies on UAS optical surface reflectance observations for RZSM estimation at high spatial resolution. This study is aimed at the development of a new approach for RZSM estimation based on the fusion of high spatial resolution optical reflectance UAS observations with physical and hydraulic soil information integrated into Automated Machine Learning (AutoML). The H2O AutoML platform includes a number of advanced machine learning algorithms that efficiently perform feature selection and automatically identify complex relationships between inputs and outputs. Twelve models combining UAS optical observations with various soil properties were developed in a hierarchical manner and fed into AutoML to estimate surface, near-surface, and root zone soil moisture. The addition of independently measured surface and near-surface soil moisture information to the hierarchical models to improve RZSM estimation was investigated. The accuracy of soil moisture estimates was evaluated based on a comparison with Time Domain Reflectometry (TDR) sensors that were deployed to monitor surface, near-surface and root zone soil moisture dynamics. The obtained results indicate that the consideration of physical and hydraulic soil properties together with UAS optical observations improves soil moisture estimation, especially for the root zone with a RMSE of about 0.04 cm3 cm-3. Accurate RZSM estimates were obtained when measured surface and near-surface soil moisture data was added to the hierarchical models, yielding RMSE values below 0.02 cm3 cm-3 and R and NSE values above 0.90. The generated high spatial resolution RZSM maps clearly capture the spatial variability of soil moisture at the field scale. The presented framework can aid farm scale precision irrigation management via improving the crop water use efficiency and reducing the risk of groundwater contamination.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/07/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on July 07, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/07/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/07/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-07-01T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-07-01T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-22&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #22&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Responses of soil carbon and nitrogen cycles to the physical influences of rock fragment in soils&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A review on the possible factors influencing soil inorganic carbon under elevated CO2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Development of functions to predict soil hydraulic properties that account for solution sodicity and salinity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identification of minerals in subtropical soils with different textural classes by VIS-NIR-SWIR reflectance spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A rapid qualitative methodology for ecological integrity assessment across a Mediterranean island’s landscapes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A framework for ecosystem service assessment using GIS interoperability standards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;responses-of-soil-carbon-and-nitrogen-cycles-to-the-physical-influences-of-rock-fragment-in-soils&quot;&gt;Responses of soil carbon and nitrogen cycles to the physical influences of rock fragment in soils&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rock fragments (RFs, mineral particles with diameter &amp;gt; 2 mm) can substantially influence soil carbon (C) and nitrogen (N) cycles through different physical mechanisms. These physical mechanisms include changing soil hydraulic parameters (vSH) by reducing fine earth bulk density (vSHBD) and volume (vSHVo), and affecting soil C and N stocks (vCN) by reducing fine earth bulk density (vCNBD) and volume (vCNVo), and increasing fine earth C and N concentrations (vCNCo). In this study, based on soil and climate data in a typical hilly area of China, we construct scenarios by considering these physical mechanisms to investigate the responses of key soil C and N outputs (carbon dioxide or CO2, and nitrous oxide or N2O emissions, and N leaching) to RF content (RFC) in DNDC and DayCent models. Results showed that when considering vSH and vCN, parabolic relationships were observed between these soil C and N outputs and RFC, with maximum in RFC = 0.3-0.6 g g(-1). The vCN dominated the responses of soil CO2 emission to RFC, while vSH exerted comparative contributions to the responses of soil N2O emission and N leaching. When only considering vSH, opposite contributions of vSHBD and vSHVo were observed in DNDC model, and contributions of vSHBD overwhelmed those of vSHVo. However, vSHVo dominated these responses in DayCent model. When only considering vCN, the vCNCo dominated these responses, though considerable superimposed influences of vCNBD and vCNVo appeared under high RFC. The discrepancies between these responses to RFC in DNDC and DayCent models might be due to the different model complexities in simulating soil hydrology, biogeochemistry, and the role of bulk density in these models. Relatively, more distinct responses were achieved in DNDC model. These findings can extend our understandings of RFs and soil C and N cycles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-review-on-the-possible-factors-influencing-soil-inorganic-carbon-under-elevated-co2&quot;&gt;A review on the possible factors influencing soil inorganic carbon under elevated CO2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil inorganic carbon (SIC) is the largest pool (approximate to 950 Pg of soil carbonate + 1404 Pg of bicarbonate in groundwater; i.e., 1 Pg = 10(15) g = 1 gigaton) of the global carbon cycle at a 100 cm depth, and it might be a significant carbon source and sink in arid and semi-arid regions. The knowledge of the impacts of changing climatic conditions on this important soil structural component is minimal. This review paper provides an inclusive compilation of the available information on potential natural and anthropogenic factors triggering soil acidification and weathering mechanisms under elevated CO2. Furthermore, the consequences of elevated atmospheric CO2 on the SIC pool, soil quality, and compromised ecosystem services have been explored. Soil water content and precipitation are critical factors that influence the effects of elevated CO2 in the SIC pool. Soil microbiological properties, respiration, depth, weathering, precipitation, acidity, and fertilization are emphasized here owing to the high degree of interrelationship between these factors on influencing overall soil quality. These phenomena are then outlined together with comments about possible short and long-term consequences in SIC stock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;development-of-functions-to-predict-soil-hydraulic-properties-that-account-for-solution-sodicity-and-salinity&quot;&gt;Development of functions to predict soil hydraulic properties that account for solution sodicity and salinity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturated soil hydraulic conductivity (K-sat) and the soil water characteristic curve have been predicted from soil texture, bulk density, and other soil physical properties. These previous functions do not account for soil clay mineralogy or soil solution composition. The objectives of this study were to: (1) analyze the performance of previously developed pedotransfer functions (PTFs) on saline and sodic soils, (2) predict hydraulic properties of saline and sodic soils with a range of clay mineralogy, and (3) develop PTFs that account for clay mineralogy and solution composition. Most PTFs do not perform well on soils with smectitic clay mineralogy and usually overestimate K-sat and under-estimate soil water characteristic on smectite clay dominant soils. Accounting for soil cation exchange capacity (CEC) as an indicator of soil clay types and solution composition improved the prediction of K-sat which had a geometric root mean squared error of 3.28 cm day(-1) compared to 6.04 cm day(-1) for the best performing PTF from the literature. A PTF we developed to predict soil water characteristic curve was able to predict soil water characteristic curve with a root mean squared error of 0.032 g g(-1) compared to 0.082 g g(-1) for the best performing previously published PTF. The PTFs developed in this study improved prediction of soil hydraulic properties on salt affected soils by using soil CEC to account for soil clay behavior and responsiveness to the soil solution composition. The PTFs reported here can easily be used to predict the K-sat and the soil water characteristic curve of soils in response to changes in irrigation water quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;identification-of-minerals-in-subtropical-soils-with-different-textural-classes-by-vis-nir-swir-reflectance-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Identification of minerals in subtropical soils with different textural classes by VIS-NIR-SWIR reflectance spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The physical and chemical attributes of soils are strongly influenced by the nature of the minerals they contain and their concentration. Thus, soil texture is directly dependent on the content in clayey minerals, which influences a number of characteristics such as water dynamics. Although the mineralogical composition of soil is usually determined by X-ray diffraction spectroscopy, this technique is expensive and time-consuming, and uses toxic materials, all of which makes it impractical for obtaining large data sets. Also, available methods for acquiring, interpreting and examining visible-near infrared-shortwave infrared (VIS-NIR-SWIR) spectra are largely ineffective with tropical soils. The aim of this work was to ascertain whether VIS-NIR-SWIR reflectance spectroscopy (350-2500 nm) is useful for identifying minerals in subtropical soils as classified by textural class. For this purpose, soil samples were collected at 66 points at three different soil depths (0-20, 20-40 and 40-60 cm) over a study area located in the State of Rio Grande do Sul (Brazil). The soil texture were determined with the pipette method, and soil spectra were recorded on a FieldSpec Pro VIS-NIR-SWIR laboratory spectrophotometer. Soil minerals were identified, and their proportions determined, from the second-derivative of the Kubelka-Munk (KM) function for the spectra. Five main minerals were thus identified from their spectral signatures, namely: hematite, goethite, kaolinite, chlorite and illite. Identification of the minerals was facilitated by classifying the samples according to texture. The higher the clay content was, the higher was the spectral amplitude of the minerals identified. Those textural classes with the highest clay contents exhibited the greatest proportions of iron oxides and of clay minerals such as kaolinite. These relationships allowed more comprehensive analysis of the soils and expeditious characterization of the study area in terms of texture and mineralogy with a view to facilitating decision-making agricultural support policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-rapid-qualitative-methodology-for-ecological-integrity-assessment-across-a-mediterranean-islands-landscapes&quot;&gt;A rapid qualitative methodology for ecological integrity assessment across a Mediterranean island’s landscapes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rapid qualitative field methods can be used to evaluate ecological integrity (EI) at a landscape level. This study evaluates the EI of 63 landscape types (LCTs) in Cyprus derived from Landscape Character Mapping. Following a stratified sampling, LCTs were evaluated using 209 Land Description Units (LDUs) i.e., homogeneous map entities, sharing a similar pattern of natural and cultural elements. In every LDU, six ecological integrity (EI) indicators were visually assessed consistently namely naturalness, habitat continuity, number of habitats, dominant habitat type, management intensity and scale. TwoStep Cluster Analysis was employed to identify EI categories, and Categorical Principal Components Analysis (CATPCA) to associate the individual indicators with overall EI in the LDUs. Linear regressions were used to predict EI based on the most important indicators. Forested and shrubland landscapes have consistently good EI with low variation, while urbanized and agricultural landscapes have lower EI. There is great variation in the number of agricultural landscape types and their EI. There are significant linear relationships between EI and naturalness, habitat continuity and intensity. The novelty of this work lies with the fact that it provides the first island-wide study in the Mediterranean assessing EI spatially through a small number of indicators. Results indicate that LCA can be an appropriate consistent and inexpensive spatial framework for assessing EI, which can be directly associated with management intervention to maintain or improve EI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-framework-for-ecosystem-service-assessment-using-gis-interoperability-standards&quot;&gt;A framework for ecosystem service assessment using GIS interoperability standards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ecosystem Services Web Services (ESWS) are new web-based approaches to quantifying the benefits that humans derive from nature. Specifically, ESWS are the application of open web standards to ecosystem service assessment to facilitate creation, iteration, and dissemination in a seamless way. This integration streamlines collaboration, automation, and curation, while providing an open interface through which novel advances can be incorporated. The approach creates a new level of interoperability through data provenance whereby each transition between processing steps employs standards that ensure cohesive workflows across models and platforms. This imparts a modularity that can be examined and extended at every step.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/07/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on July 01, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/06/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/06/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2021-06-24T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-06-24T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-20&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #20&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One size does not fit all: Toward regional conservation practice guidance to reduce phosphorus loss risk in the Lake Erie watershed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Regional ensemble modeling reduces uncertainty for digital soil mapping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Concept, Practice, Application and Results of Locally Based Monitoring of the Environment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connecting Top-Down and Bottom-Up Approaches in Environmental Observing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Use of Digital Platforms for Community-Based Monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amalgamation and harmonization of soil survey reports into a multi-purpose database&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multisensor fusion of remotely sensed vegetation indices using space-time dynamic linear models&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do soil health tests match farmer experience? Assessing biological, physical, and chemical indicators in the Upper Midwest United States&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evaluating three calibration transfer methods for predictions of soil properties using mid-infrared spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continuous in situ soil nitrate sensors: The importance of high-resolution measurements across time and a comparison with salt extraction-based methods&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bayesian-based time-varying multivariate drought risk and its dynamics in a changing environment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transferring Hydrologic Data Across Continents - Leveraging Data-Rich Regions to Improve Hydrologic Prediction in Data-Sparse Regions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;one-size-does-not-fit-all-toward-regional-conservation-practice-guidance-to-reduce-phosphorus-loss-risk-in-the-lake-erie-watershed&quot;&gt;One size does not fit all: Toward regional conservation practice guidance to reduce phosphorus loss risk in the Lake Erie watershed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agricultural phosphorus (P) losses to surface water bodies remain a global eutrophication concern, despite the application of conservation practices on farm fields. Although it is generally agreed upon that the use of multiple conservation practices (“stacking”) will lead to greater improvements to water quality, this may not be cost effective to farmers, reducing the likelihood of adoption. At present, wholesale recommendations of conservation practices are given; however, the application of specific conservation practices in certain environments (e.g., no-till with surface application, cover crops) may not be effective and can even lead to unintended consequences. In this paper, we present the Lake Erie watershed as a case study. The Lake Erie watershed contains regions with unique physical geographies that include differences in climate, soil, topography, and land use, which have implications for both P transport from agricultural fields and the efficacy of conservation practices in mitigating P losses. We define major regions within the Lake Erie watershed where common strategies for conservation practice implementation are appropriate, and we propose a five-step plan for bringing regionally tailored, adaptive, and cost-conscious conservation practice into watershed planning. Although this paper is specific to the Lake Erie watershed, our framework can be transferred across broader geographic regions to provide guidance for watershed planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;regional-ensemble-modeling-reduces-uncertainty-for-digital-soil-mapping&quot;&gt;Regional ensemble modeling reduces uncertainty for digital soil mapping&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent country and continental-scale digital soil mapping efforts have used a single model to predict soil properties across large regions. However, different ecophysiographic regions within large-extent areas are likely to have different soil-landscape relationships so models built specifically for these regions may more accurately capture these relationships relative to a ‘global’ model. We ask the question: Is a single ‘global’ model sufficient or are regionally-specific models useful for accurate digital soil mapping? We test this question by modeling soil depth classes across the 432,000 km(2) upper Colorado River Basin in the Western USA using a single global model, multiple ecophysiographic models, and ensembles of the ecophysiographic models.
Effective soil depth class observations (n = 12,194) were derived from multiple soil databases. Fifty-seven environmental covariates were derived from a 30 m digital elevation model, climate data, satellite imagery, and aeroradiometric data. Three independent land classifications were used to stratify the area. Two expert-derived land classifications, USDA Major Land Resource Areas (MLRA) and US-EPA Level III ecoregions, divided the study area into multiple ecophysiographic regions based on vegetation and broad-scale physiographic differences. The third land classification divided the study area into broad landforms.
Soil depth observations were split into separate training (n = 10,470) and validation (n = 1,724) datasets. First, a ‘global’ random forest model was used to model soil depth classes using all training observations and covariates. ‘Global’ denotes a model built with all training data across the extent of the area, not a model at world extent. Second, the land classifications were used to subset the observations into ecophysiographic sub-datasets and random forest models were refit for each region. Models fit by ecophysiographic region are referred to as regional models. Thirdly, predictions from each regional model were fused into regional-ensemble models. Accuracy, Brier scores, and Shannon’s entropy were used to compare model accuracy and uncertainty. Regional ecophysiographic models were also compared to models built for geographic areas that were defined solely to be approximately equal in area. Training dataset density and the imbalance ratio were investigated to determine if data characteristics influenced regional accuracy/uncertainty metrics.
Accuracy for the global model using the validation set was 62.8%. Regional model accuracies ranged between 56.1% and 75.0%. We found: 1) useful inter-regional differences in global model accuracy were revealed when the global model was validated by region, 2) no consistent relationship between training observation density and accuracy/uncertainty metrics, 3) no meaningful differences in accuracy and uncertainty metrics between physiographic and geographic regions, 4) ensembles of regionally-specific models were approximately as accurate as global models, and 5) both region-specific models and ensembles of regional models were less uncertain than the global model. Overall, we recommend the use of soil depth class predictions made from MLRA regional ensemble models because this prediction had higher accuracy than the ecoregion ensemble model prediction, but lower uncertainty than both the global model and the landform ensemble model predictions. We answer our question: Ensembles of regionally-specific models are approximately as accurate as global models, but result in less uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-concept-practice-application-and-results-of-locally-based-monitoring-of-the-environment&quot;&gt;The Concept, Practice, Application and Results of Locally Based Monitoring of the Environment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Locally based monitoring is typically undertaken in areas in which communities have a close attachment to their natural resource base. We present a summary of work to develop a theoretical and practical understanding of locally based monitoring and we outline tests of this approach in research and practice over the past 20 years. Our tests show that locally based monitoring delivers credible data at local scale independent of external experts and can be used to inform local and national decision making within a short time frame. We believe that monitoring conducted by and anchored in communities will gain in importance where scientist-led monitoring is sparse or too expensive to sustain and for ecosystem attributes in cases in which remote sensing cannot provide credible data. The spread of smartphone technology and online portals will further enhance the importance and usefulness of this discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;connecting-top-down-and-bottom-up-approaches-in-environmental-observing&quot;&gt;Connecting Top-Down and Bottom-Up Approaches in Environmental Observing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Effective responses to rapid environmental change rely on observations to inform planning and decision-making. Reviewing literature from 124 programs across the globe and analyzing survey data for 30 Arctic community-based monitoring programs, we compare top-down, large-scale program driven approaches with bottom-up approaches initiated and steered at the community level. Connecting these two approaches and linking to Indigenous and local knowledge yields benefits including improved information products and enhanced observing program efficiency and sustainability. We identify core principles central to such improved links: matching observing program aims, scales, and ability to act on information; matching observing program and community priorities; fostering compatibility in observing methodology and data management; respect of Indigenous intellectual property rights and the implementation of free, prior, and informed consent; creating sufficient organizational support structures; and ensuring sustained community members’ commitment. Interventions to overcome challenges in adhering to these principles are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-use-of-digital-platforms-for-community-based-monitoring&quot;&gt;The Use of Digital Platforms for Community-Based Monitoring&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Environmental observing programs that are based on Indigenous and local knowledge increasingly use digital technologies. Digital platforms may improve data management in community-based monitoring (CBM) programs, but little is known about how their use translates into tangible results. Drawing on published literature and a survey of 18 platforms, we examine why and how digital platforms are used in CBM programs and illuminate potential challenges and opportunities. Digital platforms make it easy to collect, archive, and share CBM data, facilitate data use, and support understanding larger-scale environmental patterns through interlinking with other platforms. Digital platforms, however, also introduce new challenges, with implications for the sustainability of CBM programs and communities’ abilities to maintain control of their own data. We expect that increased data access and strengthened technical capacity will create further demand within many communities for ethically developed platforms that aid in both local and larger-scale decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;amalgamation-and-harmonization-of-soil-survey-reports-into-a-multi-purpose-database&quot;&gt;Amalgamation and harmonization of soil survey reports into a multi-purpose database&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a growing demand for standardized, easily accessible, and detailed information pertaining to soil and its variability across the landscape. Typically, this information is only available for selected areas in the form of local or regional soil surveys reports which are difficult, and costly, to develop. Additionally, soil surveying protocols have changed with time, resulting in inconsistencies between surveys conducted over different periods. This article describes systematic procedures applied to generate an aspatial, terminologically, and unit-consistent, database for forest soils from county-based soil survey reports for the province of New Brunswick, Canada. The procedures involved (i) amalgamating data from individual soil surveys following a hierarchical framework, (ii) summarizing and grouping soil information by soil associations, (iii) assigning correct soil associates to each association, with each soil associate distinguished by drainage classification, (iv) assigning pedologically correct horizon sequences, as identified in the original soil surveys, to each soil associate, (v) assigning horizon descriptors and measured soil properties to each horizon, as outlined by the Canadian System of Soil Classification, and (vi) harmonizing units of measurement for individual soil properties. Identification and summarization of all soil associations (and corresponding soil associates) was completed with reference to the principal soil-forming factors, namely soil parent material, topographic surface expressions, soil drainage, and dominant vegetation type(s). This procedure, utilizing 17 soil surveys, resulted in an amalgamated database containing 106 soil associations, 243 soil associates, and 522 soil horizon sequences summarizing the variability of forest soil conditions across New Brunswick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;multisensor-fusion-of-remotely-sensed-vegetation-indices-using-space-time-dynamic-linear-models&quot;&gt;Multisensor fusion of remotely sensed vegetation indices using space-time dynamic linear models&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High spatiotemporal resolution maps of surface vegetation from remote sensing data are desirable for vegetation and disturbance monitoring. However, due to the current limitations of imaging spectrometers, remote sensing datasets of vegetation with high temporal frequency of measurements have lower spatial resolution, and vice versa. In this research, we propose a space-time dynamic linear model to fuse high temporal frequency data (MODIS) with high spatial resolution data (Landsat) to create high spatiotemporal resolution data products of a vegetation greenness index. The model incorporates the spatial misalignment of the data and models dependence within and across land cover types with a latent multivariate Matern process. To handle the large size of the data, we introduce a fast estimation procedure and a moving window Kalman smoother to produce a daily, 30-m resolution data product with associated uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-soil-health-tests-match-farmer-experience-assessing-biological-physical-and-chemical-indicators-in-the-upper-midwest-united-states&quot;&gt;Do soil health tests match farmer experience? Assessing biological, physical, and chemical indicators in the Upper Midwest United States&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil health testing provides an integrated assessment of biological, physical, and chemical attributes to inform the sustainable management of farm fields. However, it is unclear how tests reflect farmers’ own assessments of soil quality and agronomic performance, which may disproportionately influence farm management practices. We asked farmers in three regions of Michigan to identify three fields to compare their own assessments against soil health tests: a “best,” a “worst,” and a “non-row crop” reference field. Each field was tested for soil aggregate stability, available water capacity, soil organic matter (SOM), mineralizable carbon (MinC), permanganate oxidizable carbon (POXC), pH, P, and K. We evaluated soil health scores using paired t tests to compare results from contrasting fields with farmers’ assessments of each field. Across all farms, the overall soil health test score for cropped fields was significantly higher on fields farmers rated as “Best.” This result was driven solely by physical and biological (including C) parameters; inorganic chemical tests did not distinguish among field types. On reference fields in all regions, biological parameters were consistently higher, but inorganic chemical and physical measures were not. The performance of soil C measures was inconsistent: SOM and MinC consistently detected significant differences between “Best” and “Worst” cropped fields, but POXC did not. Our results suggest that common soil health assays for physical and biological attributes generally align well with farmers’ assessments of their fields. That soil health tests match farmer experience reinforces the value of these tests as a meaningful guide for soil management decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evaluating-three-calibration-transfer-methods-for-predictions-of-soil-properties-using-mid-infrared-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Evaluating three calibration transfer methods for predictions of soil properties using mid-infrared spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mid-infrared (MIR) spectroscopy models have been developed for rapid assessment of soils but are often soil and instrument specific because of differences in laboratory conditions and sensor setup. Calibration transfer is required to apply a spectral model such as partial least squares (PLS) regression developed from a primary instrument to a spectral dataset measured by a secondary instrument with statistically retained accuracy and precision. The study aimed to compare the performance of three transfer methods (i.e., direct standardization [DS], piecewise direct standardization [PDS], and spectral space transfer [SST]) and investigate the effects of transfer sample size and sample selection methods. The transfer methods were developed for predicting total C, clay, silt, and sand contents, cation exchange capacity (CEC), pH in water (pH(W)) and CaCl2, CaCO3 equivalent, and -1,500-kPa water retention using spectral measurements of a secondary instrument. Calibration transfer methods of three PLS models for estimating soil properties with a high (total C), intermediate (clay content), and low (pH(W)) predictability were discussed. The effect of sample size required for the development of the calibration transfer and the selection method of the transferred samples were investigated. It was found that SST was most favorable for a relatively small sample size used in calibration transfer (&amp;lt;= 12 samples). The performance of transfer methods was optimal when the transfer samples accounted for the variability of MIR spectra from the secondary instrument. We conclude that SST and PDS have the potential to be applied in spectroscopy for predicting soil properties using secondary instruments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;continuous-in-situ-soil-nitrate-sensors-the-importance-of-high-resolution-measurements-across-time-and-a-comparison-with-salt-extraction-based-methods&quot;&gt;Continuous in situ soil nitrate sensors: The importance of high-resolution measurements across time and a comparison with salt extraction-based methods&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil NO3- affects microbial processes, plant productivity, and environmental N losses. However, the ability to measure soil NO3- is limited by labor-intensive sampling and laboratory analyses. Hence, temporal variation in soil solution NO3- concentration is poorly understood. We evaluated a new potentiometric sensor that continuously measures soil solution NO3- concentration with unprecedented specificity due to a novel membrane that serves as a barrier to interfering anions. First, we compared sensor and salt extraction-based measurements of soil NO3- in well-controlled laboratory conditions. Second, using 60 d of in situ soil NO3- measurements every 10 s, we quantified temporal variation and the effect of sampling frequency on field estimations of mean daily NO3- concentration both within and across days. In the laboratory, sensors measured soil NO3- concentration without significant difference from theoretical adjusted soil NO3- concentration or conventional salt extraction-based methods. In the field, the sensors demonstrated no within-day pattern in soil NO3- concentration, although individual measurements within a day differed by as much as 20% from the daily mean. Across days, when soil solution NO3- was dynamic (early spring) and sampling frequency was &amp;gt;5 d, estimates of mean daily NO3- concentration were &amp;gt;20% from the actual mean daily concentration. In situ soil sensors offer potential to improve fundamental and applied sciences. However, in most situations, sensors will measure soil properties in a different manner than conventional salt-extract soil sampling-based approaches. Research will be required to interpret sensor measurements and optimize sensor deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bayesian-based-time-varying-multivariate-drought-risk-and-its-dynamics-in-a-changing-environment&quot;&gt;Bayesian-based time-varying multivariate drought risk and its dynamics in a changing environment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drought is one of the most damaging but least understood environmental disasters. The time-varying multi variate drought risk and its dynamics have remained unresolved in a changing environment. To this end, a Bayesian framework with time in its location parameter as a covariate was introduced in this study to conduct time-varying distributions of duration and severity. Besides, the joint distribution of precipitation and runoff was developed by bivariate non-parameter density kernel estimation for multivariate drought index NKMSDI (Nonparametric Kernel Multivariate Standardized Drought Index) and Expected Waiting Time (EWT)-based return period was used to estimate drought risk. Finally, the time-varying risk trends were explored and verified via correlations between drought risk and Normalized Difference Vegetation Index series. Results indicate that: (1) bivariate return period is more accurate than univariate return period for drought risk assessment and return periods under non-stationary assumption are more reasonable than those under stationary assumption; (2) the multivariate drought risks present obviously increasing trends and the western basin shows the highest increasing rate; and (3) the increasing drought risks exhibit strong association with sunspot activities and local vegetation dynamics. In general, this study provides new insights into drought risk and its dynamics under the time-varying drought properties condition, which is highly important for robust and effective management practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;transferring-hydrologic-data-across-continents---leveraging-data-rich-regions-to-improve-hydrologic-prediction-in-data-sparse-regions&quot;&gt;Transferring Hydrologic Data Across Continents - Leveraging Data-Rich Regions to Improve Hydrologic Prediction in Data-Sparse Regions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a drastic geographic imbalance in available global streamflow gauge and catchment property data, with additional large variations in data characteristics. As a result, models calibrated in one region cannot normally be migrated to another without significant modifications. Currently in these regions, non-transferable machine learning models are habitually trained over small local data sets. Here we show that transfer learning (TL), in the senses of weight initialization and weight freezing, allows long short-term memory (LSTM) streamflow models that were pretrained over the conterminous United States (CONUS, the source data set) to be transferred to catchments on other continents (the target regions), without the need for extensive catchment attributes available at the target location. We demonstrate this possibility for regions where data are dense (664 basins in Great Britain), moderately dense (49 basins in central Chile), and scarce with only remotely sensed attributes available (5 basins in China). In both China and Chile, the TL models showed significantly elevated performance compared to locally trained models using all basins. The benefits of TL increased with the amount of available data in the source data set, and seemed to be more pronounced with greater physiographic diversity. The benefits from TL were greater than from pretraining LSTM using the outputs from an uncalibrated hydrologic model. These results suggest hydrologic data around the world have commonalities which could be leveraged by deep learning, and synergies can be had with a simple modification of the current workflows, greatly expanding the reach of existing big data. Finally, this work diversified existing global streamflow benchmarks.
Plain Language Summary We introduced a method to utilize available big data to better start and warm up a machine learning streamflow model that is later fine-tuned for prediction in basins on other continents (Asia, South America and Europe). This procedure noticeably improved streamflow volume prediction for different scenarios with varying amounts of data in the target basins (in terms of time period, length of collected data, and number of basins having data). This allows thousands of basins across the world with only a few years’ worth of streamflow observations to benefit from improved modeling and accuracy resulting from the use of deep learning.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/06/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on June 24, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>
