<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Brendan Malone</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2017-02-13T10:40:33+11:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Brendan Malone</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intensive Digital Soil Mapping Workshop. Vancouver, Canada]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/02/vancouver" />
  <id>/2017/02/vancouver</id>
  <updated>2017-02-08T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-02-08T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Between January 24-27, 2017 the Sydney Soil Schools team were situated in Vancouver, Canada providing an intensive hands on workshop in digital soil mapping. The team consisted of Prof. Alex McBratney, Prof. Budiman Minansy and Dr. Brendan Malone. They were invited by the Canadian Government, whom recently have embarked on a national project of the digital mapping the countries’ soil resource, and with a particular interest in mapping soil carbon stocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/20171302vancouver/vancouver1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Vancouver sites&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 1. Intensive digital soil mapping workshop was held in Vancouver, Canada. Beautiful city and wonderful hosts.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants of the workshop included scientists from Agri-Food Canada in addition to scientists from each of the provisional governments of Canada. Other participants included researchers and students (undergraduate and post graduate) from the universities: University of British Columbia, Simon Fraser University, University of New Brunswick, and the University of Saskatchewan. In total 28 bright and motivated people came for 4 days of all things digital soil mapping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/20171302vancouver/vancouver2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Workshop participants&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 2. Keen participants of the digital soil mapping workshop which was held at the Downtown Campus of Simon Fraser University.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course included a short lecture series about the fundamentals of digital soil mapping, and common methods and practices of digital soil mapping. A lecture describing the global efforts of creating a digital soil map of the world (under the auspices of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.globalsoilmap.net/specifications&quot;&gt;GlobalSoilMap&lt;/a&gt; project) was of particular keen interest to the Canadian participants. More importantly, the course covered a curriculum of learning that is necessary to understand how to do digital soil mapping. The course materials were recently published (by the Sydney Soils School team) the book titled, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.springer.com/gp/book/9783319443256&quot;&gt;Using R for Digital Soil Mapping&lt;/a&gt;. These course materials cover the very basics of programmatic scripting, to GIS applications, then to the more complex materials about the data science that underpins the production digital soil maps and their associated uncertainties, among other interesting digital soil related topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/20171302vancouver/vancouver3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Workshop participants&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 3. The digital soil mapping workshop was all about getting the particpants an experiential program of doing it for real and developing a workflow that can be applied for their own applications.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all, the 4 day training program and jam packed with learning and importantly, heaps of discussion. From feedback, the course was hugely successful that we believe will provide the necessary starting point for Canada to achieve their aspirational goal of developing a digital soil information system for the country. Despite the cool and sometimes snowing weather conditions, our Canadian hosts were wonderfully warm and keen to learn what the Sydney Soil School had to share.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/02/vancouver&quot;&gt;Intensive Digital Soil Mapping Workshop. Vancouver, Canada&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on February 08, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/02/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2017/02/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2017-02-08T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-02-08T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2017-4&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2017 #4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exploring-the-biophysical-option-space-for-feeding-the-world-without-deforestation&quot;&gt;Exploring the biophysical option space for feeding the world without deforestation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms11382&quot;&gt;online link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Erb, KH; Lauk, C; Kastner, T; Mayer, A; Theurl, MC; Haberl, H&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;NATURE COMMUNICATIONS&lt;/em&gt;, 7 11382-11382; APR 19 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Safeguarding the world’s remaining forests is a high-priority goal. We
assess the biophysical option space for feeding the world in 2050 in a
hypothetical zero-deforestation world. We systematically combine
realistic assumptions on future yields, agricultural areas, livestock
feed and human diets. For each scenario, we determine whether the supply
of crop products meets the demand and whether the grazing intensity
stays within plausible limits. We find that many options exist to meet
the global food supply in 2050 without deforestation, even at low
crop-yield levels. Within the option space, individual scenarios differ
greatly in terms of biomass harvest, cropland demand and grazing
intensity, depending primarily on the quantitative and qualitative
aspects of human diets. Grazing constraints strongly limit the option
space. Without the option to encroach into natural or semi-natural land,
trade volumes will rise in scenarios with globally converging diets,
thereby decreasing the food self-sufficiency of many developing regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hydropedology-and-the-societal-challenge-of-realizing-the-2015-united-nations-sustainable-development-goals&quot;&gt;Hydropedology and the Societal Challenge of Realizing the 2015 United Nations Sustainable Development Goals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vzj.geoscienceworld.org/content/15/12/vzj2016.09.0080&quot;&gt;online link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Bouma, J&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;VADOSE ZONE JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, 15 (12):NIL_57-NIL_63; DEC 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The UN Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) offer a major challenge for
both society and the science community. Hydropedology, combining the
expertise of soil physicists and pedologists, plays a key role in
realizing goals focused on food, water, climate, and ecology, requiring
interdisciplinary research. This update explores emerging trends and
future work, focusing on examples of contributions by pedology to
measuring and modeling in hydropedological studies. Many soil types
create heterogeneous flow patterns that are difficult to characterize
using current soil databases and physical flow models. The clear
potential of hydropedology to produce better modeling results than those
obtained from separate contributions by the two subdisciplines can,
however, only be established by field validation of modeling results
using different types of data and models. Overall soil input in
interdisciplinary SDG-oriented research includes chemical and biological
aspects that become more representative by considering hydropedological
conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;processes-and-modeling-of-initial-soil-and-landscape-development-a-review&quot;&gt;Processes and Modeling of Initial Soil and Landscape Development: A Review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vzj.geoscienceworld.org/content/15/12/vzj2016.05.0048&quot;&gt;online link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Maurer, T; Gerke, HH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;VADOSE ZONE JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, 15 (12):NIL_3-NIL_30; DEC 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The development pathway of a landscape depends to a degree on the
initial spatial distributions of mineral and organic components. The
interaction between structures and ecohydrological processes during the
critical initial development period is scarcely understood and often
difficult to observe. While viable modeling approaches exist for most
aspects of initial development (e.g., landscape evolution, vegetation
succession), a deeper understanding of the prevailing feedback
mechanisms requires a comprehensive, integrated modeling approach. We
present a review of the current literature regarding the description of
initial structures, the state-of-the-art of research on
structure-forming processes and their interaction with existing and
newly emerging structures, as well as the corresponding modeling
efforts. The most relevant aspects are (i) sediment translocation
processes and initial evolution of topography, (ii) surface crusting,
(iii) vegetation succession, and (iv) the evolution of the soil pore
space. Based on existing conceptions for integrated modeling of the
coevolution of structures and ecohydrological behavior, we outline an
integrative modeling framework that is based on a three-dimensional
spatial structural model of initial sediment distributions, which can be
used to: (i) analyze the spatiotemporal development dynamics depending
on initial structures; and (ii) relate the simulated structural
development to available observations of initial ecohydrological
development. We discuss possible validation and generalization
strategies of modeling results, and propose to define three-dimensional
spatial functional catchment units (process domains) characterized by
specific structural dynamics and the dominant ecohydrological processes.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/02/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on February 08, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/01/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2017/01/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2017-01-26T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-01-26T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2017-3&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2017 #3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hybrid-integration-of-multilayer-perceptron-neural-networks-and-machine-learning-ensembles-for-landslide-susceptibility-assessment-at-himalayan-area-india-using-gis&quot;&gt;Hybrid integration of Multilayer Perceptron Neural Networks and machine learning ensembles for landslide susceptibility assessment at Himalayan area (India) using GIS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S034181621630368X&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Pham, BT; Bui, DT; Prakash, I; Dholakia, MB&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;CATENA&lt;/em&gt;, 149 52-63; 1 FEB 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The main objective of this study is to evaluate and compare the
performance of landslide models using machine learning ensemble
technique for landslide susceptibility assessment. This technique is a
combination of ensemble methods (AdaBoost, Bagging, Dagging, MultiBoost,
Rotation Forest, and Random SubSpace) and the base classifier of
Multiple Perceptron Neural Networks (MLP Neural Nets). Ensemble
techniques have been widely applied in other fields; however, their
application is still rare in the assessment of landslide problems.
Meanwhile, MLP Neural Nets, which is known as an artificial neural
network, has been applied widely and efficiently in landslide problems.
In the present study, landslide models of part Himalayan area (India)
have been constructed and validated. For the evaluation and comparison
of these models, receiver operating characteristic curve and Chi Square
test methods have been applied. Overall, all landslide models performed
well in landslide susuceptibility assessment but the performance of the
MultiBoost model is the highest (AUC = 0.886), followed by Dagging model
(AUC = 0.885), the Rotation Forest model (AUC = 0.882), the Bagging and
Random SubSpace models (AUC = 0.881), and the AdaBoost model (AUC =
0.876), respectively. Moreover, machine learning ensemble models have
improved significantly the performance of the base classifier of MLP
Neural Nets (AUC = 0.874). Analysis of results indicates that landslide
models using machine learning ensemble frameworks are promising methods
which can be used as alternatives of individual base classifiers for
landslide susceptibility assessment of other prone areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ecosystem-responses-to-land-abandonment-in-western-mediterranean-mountains&quot;&gt;Ecosystem responses to land abandonment in Western Mediterranean Mountains&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0341816216303241&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Romero-Diaz, A; Ruiz-Sinoga, JD; Robledano-Aymerich, F; Brevik, EC;
Cerda, A&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;CATENA&lt;/em&gt;, 149 824-835; SI 3 FEB 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Agricultural expansion in the Mediterranean resulted in plant and soil
degradation due to the intensive use, climate conditions, and rugged
terrain. After abandonment, the recovery of vegetation contributed to
improvement in soil quality from a hydrological, pedological and
geomorphological point of view. This paper shows three examples of
ecosystem evolution in abandoned fields in Valencia, Murcia and
Andalucia and the application of different methodological approaches
that resulted in similar findings. In Valencia, the main responses were
the recovery of vegetation after land abandonment and an increase in
organic matter and infiltration capacity of soils. In Murcia, with the
exception of some terraced areas on marls, where erosion processes
following abandonment were important, land abandonment resulted in
vegetation recovery, improved soil properties, and reduced surface wash
and soil losses. In Andalucia, research along climatological gradients
showed the relationship between vegetation patterns and soil moisture
and the control that climate exerts on hydrological and erosive
behaviour. The experimental research conducted in three different
regions in Western Mediterranean demonstrated that abandonment can
result in recovery of the geo-ecosystem as vegetation and soil quality
improvements were shown. The marls areas in Murcia were the exception
with low soil quality and low vegetation cover, and as a consequence
showed evidence of high erosion rates after abandonment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hydropedology-and-the-societal-challenge-of-realizing-the-2015-united-nations-sustainable-development-goals&quot;&gt;Hydropedology and the Societal Challenge of Realizing the 2015 United Nations Sustainable Development Goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vzj.geoscienceworld.org/content/15/12/vzj2016.09.0080&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Bouma, J&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;VADOSE ZONE JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, 15 (12):NIL_57-NIL_63; DEC 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The UN Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) offer a major challenge for
both society and the science community. Hydropedology, combining the
expertise of soil physicists and pedologists, plays a key role in
realizing goals focused on food, water, climate, and ecology, requiring
interdisciplinary research. This update explores emerging trends and
future work, focusing on examples of contributions by pedology to
measuring and modeling in hydropedological studies. Many soil types
create heterogeneous flow patterns that are difficult to characterize
using current soil databases and physical flow models. The clear
potential of hydropedology to produce better modeling results than those
obtained from separate contributions by the two subdisciplines can,
however, only be established by field validation of modeling results
using different types of data and models. Overall soil input in
interdisciplinary SDG-oriented research includes chemical and biological
aspects that become more representative by considering hydropedological
conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;processes-and-modeling-of-initial-soil-and-landscape-development-a-review&quot;&gt;Processes and Modeling of Initial Soil and Landscape Development: A Review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vzj.geoscienceworld.org/content/15/12/vzj2016.05.0048&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Maurer, T; Gerke, HH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;VADOSE ZONE JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, 15 (12):NIL_3-NIL_30; DEC 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The development pathway of a landscape depends to a degree on the
initial spatial distributions of mineral and organic components. The
interaction between structures and ecohydrological processes during the
critical initial development period is scarcely understood and often
difficult to observe. While viable modeling approaches exist for most
aspects of initial development (e.g., landscape evolution, vegetation
succession), a deeper understanding of the prevailing feedback
mechanisms requires a comprehensive, integrated modeling approach. We
present a review of the current literature regarding the description of
initial structures, the state-of-the-art of research on
structure-forming processes and their interaction with existing and
newly emerging structures, as well as the corresponding modeling
efforts. The most relevant aspects are (i) sediment translocation
processes and initial evolution of topography, (ii) surface crusting,
(iii) vegetation succession, and (iv) the evolution of the soil pore
space. Based on existing conceptions for integrated modeling of the
coevolution of structures and ecohydrological behavior, we outline an
integrative modeling framework that is based on a three-dimensional
spatial structural model of initial sediment distributions, which can be
used to: (i) analyze the spatiotemporal development dynamics depending
on initial structures; and (ii) relate the simulated structural
development to available observations of initial ecohydrological
development. We discuss possible validation and generalization
strategies of modeling results, and propose to define three-dimensional
spatial functional catchment units (process domains) characterized by
specific structural dynamics and the dominant ecohydrological processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;from-robustness-to-resilience-a-network-price-identity-approach&quot;&gt;From robustness to resilience: A network Price identity approach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1476945X16300794&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Dragicevic, AZ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;ECOLOGICAL COMPLEXITY&lt;/em&gt;, 28 47-53; DEC 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
We model a closed-loop network of agents distributed among subnetworks
and study the sustainability of network structures in presence of random
perturbations. The model outcomes show that the stability of
compartmentalized networks built on uniform operators depends on
perturbations on between-subnetwork coupling, while the stability of
networks built on mutation operators depends on their assimilation
capacity. Through the study of eigenvalues of the Laplacian, we succeed
in measuring the degree of network robustness and resilience. Our
results also permit to situate the Price theorem, both in its standard
and expanded forms, in the context of network evolutionary variational
identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fuzzy-based-energy-efficient-sensor-network-protocol-for-precision-agriculture&quot;&gt;Fuzzy based energy efficient sensor network protocol for precision agriculture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0168169916308250&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Maurya, S; Jain, VK&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;COMPUTERS AND ELECTRONICS IN AGRICULTURE&lt;/em&gt;, 130 20-37; NOV 15 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Today’s, wireless sensor network have become a more emerging technology
in precision agriculture. This paper proposes a novel approach based on
sensor network technology to control the irrigation in agricultural
field automatically. All sensor nodes deployed in the field,
continuously sense soil temperature, soil moisture and air humidity of
the agricultural field and transmit this information to base station
only when the user defined periodic timer or sensed attributes values
exceed desired threshold. In the proposed routing protocol, region-based
static clustering approach is used to provide efficient coverage over
entire agricultural area and threshold sensitive hybrid routing is used
for transmitting sensed data to base station. The proposed protocol uses
fuzzy logic technique to select the best cluster head among other sensor
nodes in a particular round which minimizes the energy consumption of
nodes in every data transmission period. The proposed energy-efficient
protocol is compared with existing benchmark EEHC, DEEC, DDEEC and RBHR
routing protocols. The analysis and experimental results show a
significant decrement in data transmission rate due to user-defined
transmission thresholds. The balanced use of fuzzy logic technique,
static clustering and hybrid routing approach efficiently reduce energy
consumption of sensor nodes in every data transmission round and
prolongs the overall network lifetime by 173.16%, 149.22%, 99.49% and
4739% as compared to EEHC, DEEC, DDEEC and RBHR protocol respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mapping-almond-orchard-canopy-volume-flowers-fruit-and-yield-using-lidar-and-vision-sensors&quot;&gt;Mapping almond orchard canopy volume, flowers, fruit and yield using lidar and vision sensors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0168169916308249&quot;&gt;Online Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Underwood, JP; Hung, C; Whelan, B; Sukkarieh, S&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;COMPUTERS AND ELECTRONICS IN AGRICULTURE&lt;/em&gt;, 130 83-96; NOV 15 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
This paper present a mobile terrestrial scanning system for almond
orchards, that is able to efficiently map flower and fruit distributions
and to estimate and predict yield for individual trees. A mobile robotic
ground vehicle scans the orchard while logging data from on-board lidar
and camera sensors. An automated software pipeline processes the data
offline, to produce a 3D map of the orchard and to automatically detect
each tree within that map, including correct associations for the same
trees seen on prior occasions. Colour images are also associated to each
tree, leading to a database of images and canopy models, at different
times throughout the season and spanning multiple years. A canopy volume
measure is derived from the 3D models, and classification is performed
on the images to estimate flower and fruit density. These measures were
compared to individual tree harvest weights to assess the relationship
to yield. A block of approximately 580 trees was scanned at peak bloom,
fruit-set and just before harvest for two subsequent years, with up to
50 trees individually harvested for comparison. Lidar canopy volume had
the strongest linear relationship to yield with R-2 = 0.77 for 39 tree
samples spanning two years. An additional experiment was performed using
hand-held photography and image processing to measure fruit density,
which exhibited similar performance (R-2 = 0.71). Flower density
measurements were not strongly related to yield, however, the maps show
clear differentiation between almond varieties and may be useful for
other studies&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/01/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on January 26, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[NEW PAPER! Rapid assessment of petroleum-contaminated soils with infrared spectroscopy]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/01/rapidassess" />
  <id>/2017/01/rapidassess</id>
  <updated>2017-01-25T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-01-25T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;rapid-assessment-of-petroleum-contaminated-soils-with-infrared-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Rapid assessment of petroleum-contaminated soils with infrared spectroscopy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Published in Geoderma 289 (2017) 150-160.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first paper from newly intitated PhD student in the Soil Security Laboratory, Wartini Ng. Soil sensing using infrared spectroscopy has been proposed as an alternative to conventional soil analysis to detect soil contamination. &lt;a href=&quot;/downloads/journal/malone2017_1.pdf&quot;&gt;This study&lt;/a&gt; evaluated the use of field portable and laboratory benchtop infrared spectrometers in both the near infrared (NIR) and mid infrared (MIR) region for rapid, non-destructive assessment of petroleum contaminated soils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A laboratory study of soils spiked with petroleum products showed that several
factors can affect the infrared absorbance. These include soil texture, organic matter content, and the types and
concentrations of contaminants. Despite these factors, infrared regions that are affected by hydrocarbon contamination
can be readily found in 2990-2810 cm???1 in the MIR range, and 2300-2340 nm in the NIR range. Using
continuum-removed spectra, the effects of soil and contaminant factors on the absorbance peaks were isolated.
This study also created statistical models to predict total recoverable petroleum hydrocarbons concentration in
soils by utilizing the absorption features found in the mid-infrared region spectra. Subsequently, three different
approaches were tested for the prediction of Total Recoverable Hydrocarbon (TRH) concentration on 72 field
contaminated samples: (i) linear regression using only 1 infrared region, (ii) multiple linear regression (MLR)
using 4 regions in the MIR, and (iii) partial least square regression (PLSR) which use the whole spectra. The
model created usingMLR approach for portableMIR spectrometer outperformed the benchtopMIR spectrometer
with a coefficient of determination (R2) of 0.71 and 0.53 respectively.While PLSR model for portable spectrometer
show a better prediction for TRH prediction (R2 = 0.75), the MLR can also achieve a similar performance
(R2 = 0.71) by using only 4 regions in the MIR spectra as predictors.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/01/rapidassess&quot;&gt;NEW PAPER! Rapid assessment of petroleum-contaminated soils with infrared spectroscopy&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on January 25, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[NEW PAPER! Digital soil mapping of soil carbon at the farm scale. A spatial downscaling approach in consideration of measured and uncertain data]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/01/downscale" />
  <id>/2017/01/downscale</id>
  <updated>2017-01-24T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-01-24T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;digital-soil-mapping-of-soil-carbon-at-the-farm-scale-a-spatial-downscaling-approach-in-consideration-of-measured-and-uncertain-data&quot;&gt;Digital soil mapping of soil carbon at the farm scale: A spatial downscaling approach in consideration of measured and uncertain data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Published in Geoderma 290 (2017) 91-99.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initiated during 2015, Quentin Styc was a visiting intern student from France to our soil security laboratory for 3 months. I had this idea of spatial downscaling and trying to include observational data into the scheme. Quentin was happy to work on this little problem, and actually presented some preliminary results on this at the 2015 Pedometrics Conference. At the beginning of 2016, i was troubled by the fact that we were not taking into account the uncertainties of the map to be downscaled. Then Budiman Minansy suggested we should use a sequential guassian simulation approach, which more-or-less became generating random fields with some predefined spatial structure to add some deviation about the mean. Doing simulations of these random fields with followed up with spatial downscaling, and incorporation of observational data. Overall &lt;a href=&quot;/downloads/journal/malone2017_2.pdf&quot;&gt;this paper&lt;/a&gt; represents a tem effort, and a traiing opportuntiy for an up and coming soil scientists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read on for the journal abstract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this paper a spatial downscaling method is explored for generating appropriate farm scale digital soil maps. The digital soil map product to be downscaled is an Australian national extent soil carbon map (100 m grid resolution). Taking into account the associated prediction uncertainties of this map, we used a simulation approach based on Gaussian random fields to generate plausible mapping realisations that were in turn downscaled to 10 m resolution for a farm in North-western NSW, Australia. We were able to derive both a downscaled map of soil carbon and associated prediction variance with this approach. Building further upon this development, we then incorporated a bias correction step into the spatial downscaling procedure which permits the inclusion
of field observations as a way to moderate the downscaling results to better reflect actual conditions on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on an independent validation dataset, it was found that incorporating field observations increase the concordance correlation coefficient to 0.8 from 0.2. This relatively lower correlation achieved using spatial downscaling alone was due to the national scale mapping for the study area being positively biased in the area
of interest. It was found that downscaling that incorporates observational data was marginally better if not comparable to using a point-based digital soil mapping approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advantage of spatial downscaling is that it can be implemented in situations of data scarcity. This will be ideal for on farm soil monitoring in situations where
detailed soil mapping is initially not available. For example, soil carbon auditing schemes requiring prior soil information for implementation of design-based soil sampling could potentially be universally applied with such a
spatial downscaling approach.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/01/downscale&quot;&gt;NEW PAPER! Digital soil mapping of soil carbon at the farm scale. A spatial downscaling approach in consideration of measured and uncertain data&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on January 24, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[NEW PAPER! Soil carbon 4 per mille]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/01/4permille" />
  <id>/2017/01/4permille</id>
  <updated>2017-01-24T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-01-24T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;soil-carbon-4-per-mille&quot;&gt;Soil carbon 4 per mille&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Published in Geoderma 292 (2017) 59-86.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ‘4 per mille Soils for Food Security and Climate’ was launched at the COP21 with an aspiration to increase global soil organic matter stocks by 4 per 1000 (or 0.4 %) per year as a compensation for the global emissions of greenhouse gases by anthropogenic sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/downloads/journal/malone2017_3.pdf&quot;&gt;This paper&lt;/a&gt; surveyed the soil organic carbon (SOC) stock estimates and sequestration potentials from 20 regions in the world: New Zealand, Chile, South Africa, Australia, Tanzania,
Indonesia, Kenya, Nigeria, India, China Taiwan, South Korea, China Mainland, United States of America, France, Canada, Belgium, England &amp;amp; Wales, Ireland, Scotland, and Russia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we asked whether the 4 per mille initiative is feasible for the region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outcomes highlight region specific efforts and scopes for soil carbon sequestration. Reported soil C sequestration rates globally show that under best management practices, 4 per mille or even higher sequestration rates can be accomplished. High C sequestration rates (up to 10 per mille) can be achieved for soils with low initial SOC stock (topsoil less than 30 t C ha???1), and at the first twenty years after implementation of best management practices. Additionally, areas which have reached equilibrium will not be able to further increase their sequestration. it was found that most studies on SOC sequestration only consider topsoil (up to 0.3m
depth) as it is considered to be most affected by management techniques. The 4 per mille number was based on a blanket calculation of the whole global soil profile C stock, however the potential to increase SOC is mostly on managed agricultural lands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If we consider 4 per mille in the top 1m of global agricultural soils, SOC sequestration
is between 2-3 Gt C per year, which effectively offset 20-35% of global anthropogenic greenhouse gas emissions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a strategy for climate change mitigation, soil carbon sequestration buys time over the next ten to twenty years while other effective sequestration and lowcarbon technologies become viable. The challenge for cropping farmers is to find disruptive technologies that will further improve soil condition and deliver increased soil carbon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Progress in 4 per mille requires collaboration and communication between scientists, farmers, policy makers, and marketeers.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/01/4permille&quot;&gt;NEW PAPER! Soil carbon 4 per mille&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on January 24, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/01/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2017/01/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2017-01-16T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-01-16T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2017-2&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2017 #2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rearranging-agricultural-landscapes-towards-habitat-quality-optimisation-in-silico-application-to-pest-regulation&quot;&gt;Rearranging agricultural landscapes towards habitat quality optimisation: In silico application to pest regulation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1476945X16300538&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Parisey, N; Bourhis, Y; Roques, L; Soubeyrand, S; Ricci, B; Poggi, S&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;ECOLOGICAL COMPLEXITY&lt;/em&gt;, 28 113-122; DEC 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1476945X16300538&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Modern agriculture suffers from its dependence on chemical inputs and
subsequent impacts on health and environment. Alternatively, protecting
crops against pests can be achieved through the reinforcement of
regulation ecological services. Our work propounds a data-driven
methodological framework to derive relevant agricultural landscape
rearrangements enhancing populations of beneficial organisms regulating
pests.Building on spatialised entomological and geographic data, we
developed a parsimonious reaction diffusion model describing the
population dynamics of beneficial organisms. Parameter estimation was
carried out in a Bayesian framework accounting for uncertainty in the
measurement.Thousands of agricultural landscapes were generated under
agronomic specifications dealt with as constraint satisfaction problems.
Population dynamics was simulated on each landscape with the fitted
reaction-diffusion model mentioned above, and two metrics of abundances
allowed the assessment of the regulation performance of the landscape
spatial arrangements. One metric is a mean field performance criterion
assessing the regulation performance from the landscape composition
only, the other is a spatial performance metric assessing the
performance resulting from the whole landscape spatial configuration.
The former is computed with a non-spatialised form of the population
dynamics model, the latter results from the reaction-diffusion model of
the population dynamics. Comparing these metrics enabled to quantify the
impact of spatial arrangements, hence allowing arrangements
proposals.This framework was applied to the case study of a ground
beetle species involved in the biological regulation of weeds. The
arrangement proposals abides by the productive agronomic constraint that
is the landscape composition, while they allow for significant habitat
quality enhancement (or deterioration) for the beneficial organism (or a
pest). Minor adaptations of our integrated data-driven approach would
suit numerous situations ranging from the provision of enhanced
ecosystem services to land management for conservation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;toward-mapping-crop-progress-at-field-scales-through-fusion-of-landsat-and-modis-imagery&quot;&gt;Toward mapping crop progress at field scales through fusion of Landsat and MODIS imagery&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0034425716304369&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Gao, F; Anderson, MC; Zhang, XY; Yang, ZW; Alfieri, JG; Kustas, WP;
Mueller, R; Johnson, DM; Prueger, JH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT&lt;/em&gt;, 188 9-25; JAN 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The ability to regionally monitor crop progress and condition through
the growing season benefits both crop management and yield estimation.
In the United States, these metrics are reported weekly at state or
district (multiple counties) levels by the U.S. Department of
Agriculture (USDA) National Agricultural Statistics Service (NASS) using
field observations provided by trained local reporters. However, the
ground data collection process supporting this effort is time consuming
and subjective. Furthermore, operational crop management and yield
estimation efforts require information with more granularity than at the
state or district level. This paper evaluates remote sensing approaches
for mapping crop phenology using vegetation index time-series generated
by fusing Landsat and MODIS (Moderate Resolution Imaging
Spectroradiometer) surface reflectance imagery to improve temporal
sampling over that provided by Landsat alone. The case study focuses on
an agricultural region in central Iowa from 2001 to 2014. Our objectives
are 1) to assess Landsat-MODIS data fusion results over cropland; 2) to
map crop phenology at 30 m resolution using fused surface reflectance
data; and 3) to identify the relationships between remotely sensed crop
phenology metrics and the crop progress stages reported by NASS. The
results show that detailed spatial and temporal variability in
vegetation development across this landscape can be identified using the
fused Landsat-MODIS data. The mean difference (bias) in Normalized
Difference Vegetation Index (NDVI) between actual Landsat observations
and the fused Landsat-MODIS data, generated for Landsat overpass dates,
is in the range of 0.011 to 0.028 for every year. The derived
phenological metrics show distinct features for different crops and
natural vegetation at field scales. Strong correlations are observed
between remotely sensed phenological stages, based on NDVI curve
inflection points, and the observed crop physiological growth stages
from the NASS Crop Progress (CP) reports. The green-up dates detected
from remote sensing data typically occurred during crop vegetative
stages when 2-4 leaves were developed for both corn and soybeans, or
about 1-3 weeks after the reported emergence dates when the plant were
first visible to ground based observers. Despite being a lagging
indicator, remotely sensed green-up can be used effectively to backcast
emergence, e.g. as input to spatially distributed crop models. The
differences in green-up date between corn and soybean were 8-10 days,
consistent with the offset in emergence dates reported by NASS at
district level. The reported harvest dates were typically about 2-3
weeks after the dormancy stage was detected via remote sensing for corn
and about 1-2 weeks for soybeans. This suggests that probable harvest
times for individual fields may be predicted 1-3 weeks ahead using
remote sensing data. The results suggest that crop phenology and certain
growth stages at field scales (30 m spatial resolution) can be linked
and mapped by integrating imagery from multiple remote sensing
platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;landslide-mapping-from-aerial-photographs-using-change-detection-based-markov-random-field&quot;&gt;Landslide mapping from aerial photographs using change detection-based Markov random field&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0034425716303807&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Li, ZB; Shi, WZ; Lu, P; Yan, L; Wang, QM; Miao, ZL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT&lt;/em&gt;, 187 76-90; DEC 15 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Landslide mapping (LM) is essential for hazard prevention, mitigation,
and vulnerability assessment. Despite the great efforts over the past
few years, there is room for improvement in its accuracy and efficiency.
Existing LM is primarily achieved using field surveys or visual
interpretation of remote sensing images. However, such methods are
highly labor-intensive and time-consuming, particularly over large
areas. Thus, in this paper a change detection-based Markov random field
(CDMRF) method is proposed for near-automatic LM from aerial
orthophotos. The proposed CDMRF is applied to a landslide-prone site
with an area of approximately 40 km2 on Lantau Island, Hong Kong.
Compared with the existing region-based level set evolution (RLSE), it
has three main advantages: 1) it employs a more robust threshold method
to generate the training samples; 2) it can identify landslides more
accurately as it takes advantages of both the spectral and spatial
contextual information of landslides; and 3) it needs little parameter
tuning. Quantitative evaluation shows that it outperforms RLSE in the
whole study area by almost 5.5% in Correctness and by 4% in Quality. To
our knowledge, it is the first time CDMRF is used to LM from bitemporal
aerial photographs. It is highly generic and has great potential for
operational LM applications in large areas and also can be adapted for
other sources of imagery data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;does-amsr2-produce-better-soil-moisture-retrievals-than-amsr-e-over-australia&quot;&gt;Does AMSR2 produce better soil moisture retrievals than AMSR-E over Australia?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S003442571630428X&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Cho, ES; Su, CH; Ryu, D; Kim, H; Choi, M&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT&lt;/em&gt;, 188 95-105; JAN 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The Advanced Microwave Scanning Radiometer 2 (AMSR2), a follow-up
microwave sensor to the AMSR for Earth Observing System (AMSR-E), was
launched on the Global Change Observation Mission 1- Water (GCOM-W1)
satellite in May 2012. It is as yet unclear if instrumental improvements
in AMSR2 over AMSR-E have led to better soil moisture (SM) estimates,
especially since there is no overlapping period of data between the
sensors. This study focuses on comparing the results of AMSR2 and AMSR-E
SM over Australia, distinguishing four Koppen climate zones to determine
if AMSR2 is better than AMSR-E. This is achieved by selecting two
year-long comparative time periods from the operating periods of AMSR-E
and AMSR2, based on their statistical similarities in modeled SM as a
proxy, using Modem Era Retrospective-analysis for Research and
Applications-Land (MERRAL). The AMSR2 and AMSR-E C- and X-band SM
derived from the Land Parameter Retrieval Model (LPRM) was evaluated.
Both AMSR2 C- and X-band SM products were found to show similar temporal
patterns and spatial agreement with AMSR-E C- and X-band SM, supported
by unbiased root mean square difference (ubRMSD) and R-values with
MERRA-L SM, respectively. Using lag-based instrumental variable analysis
to estimate the random error component of SM retrievals, the
noise-to-signal ratios in AMSR2 X-band SM were found to be slightly
higher than their AMSR-E counterparts. The improvements in AMSR2, such
as the superior radiometric sensitivity and spatial resolution, have
therefore not led to statistically significant differences in
performance for LPRM retrievals at 1/2 degrees x 1/2 degrees grid
resolution, when compared with AMSR-E. However, similarities in the
metrics for AMSR2 and AMSR-E SM suggest that AMSR2 provides a valuable
continuation to AMSR-E.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-moisture-prediction-of-bare-soil-profiles-using-diffuse-spectral-reflectance-information-and-vadose-zone-flow-modeling&quot;&gt;Soil moisture prediction of bare soil profiles using diffuse spectral reflectance information and vadose zone flow modeling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0034425716304011&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Babaeian, E; Homaee, M; Montzka, C; Vereecken, H; Norouzi, AA; van
Genuchten, MT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT&lt;/em&gt;, 187 218-229; DEC 15 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Soil hydraulic property information of the vadose zone is key to
quantifying the temporal and spatial variability of soil moisture, and
for modeling water flow and contaminant transport processes in the near
surface. This study deals with exploring the feasibility of using
diffuse soil spectral information in the visible, near-infrared and
shortwave infrared range (350-2500 nm) to estimate coarse-scale soil
hydraulic parameters and predict soil moisture profiles using a
topography-based aggregation scheme in conjunction with a 1D mechanistic
water flow model. Three different types of parametric transfer functions
(so-called spectrotransfer functions, STFs; pedotransfer functions,
PTFs; and spectral pedotransfer functions, SPTF5) were aggregated from
the point scale to 1 km(2) pixel size. to provide coarse scale estimates
of van Genuchten-Mualem (VGM) hydraulic parameters. The coarse scale
hydraulic parameters were evaluated by simulating soil water dynamics of
the 1 km(2) pixels across the Zanjanrood River sub-watershed (ZRS) in
northwest Iran. Resultant soil water states were compared with
ground-truth measurements and advanced synthetic aperture radar (ASAR)
estimates of soil water content. The topography-based aggregation scheme
was found to provide effective values of the VGM hydraulic parameters
across the ZRS study site. The coarse scale STFs performed best in terms
of simulating surface, near-surface and subsurface soil water dynamics,
followed by the coarse scale SPTFs and PM, which performed similarly.
The average simulated soil water contents of the surface layer closely
correlated with ASAR estimates during relatively wet periods. Simulated
subsurface soil water dynamics matched well with the ground-truth
measurements. These findings indicate the feasibility of using spectral
data to predict VGM hydraulic parameters and, ultimately, to predict
soil water dynamics at the larger scales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;on-the-performance-of-remote-sensing-time-series-reconstruction-methods---a-spatial-comparison&quot;&gt;On the performance of remote sensing time series reconstruction methods - A spatial comparison&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0034425716303972&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Zhou, J; Jia, L; Menenti, M; Gorte, B&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;REMOTE SENSING OF ENVIRONMENT&lt;/em&gt;, 187 367-384; DEC 15 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The satellite observed Normalized Difference Vegetation Index (NDVI)
time series, which describe the temporal and spatial variability of
global terrestrial vegetation, are inevitably contaminated by clouds,
aerosol, snow and ice cover. In general all these conditions yield
negative deviations in the time series of NDVI. Many time series
reconstruction models have been developed to eliminate effect of the
negative deviations and most of them perform differently in different
applications and regions. The Harmonic Analysis (HA), Double logistic
(DL), Asymmetric Gaussian (AG), Whittaker smoother (WS) and
Savitzky-Golay filter (SG) are five of the most widely used time series
reconstruction models owing to their simplicity of implementation or the
capability to extract phenological metrics from the time series. The
performance of these models varies with the NDVI signal and the noise
distribution, however, and until now there is no consensus on which
method outperforms all others under all situations. Since the NDVI
signal and the noise distribution are highly dependent on regional
climate and land cover, the reconstruction performance is expected to be
spatially variable. Thus this study compared the five reconstruction
models at pixel scale to provide practical and biome- specific
recommendations for future time series reconstruction applications.
Specifically, the 14 years raw daily reflectance data and ancillary
Quality Assessment (QA) information from the MODIS sensor were used to
generate pixel reference series and noisy series. Then the five
candidate models were applied to both reference series and noisy series
and three reconstruction performance metrics i.e. Overall Reconstruction
Error (ORE), Fitting Related Error (FRE), and Normalized Noise Related
Error (NNRE), were calculated. Finally, the performance of the five
candidate reconstruction models was evaluated by applying the three
metrics. The preliminary results showed that when considering ORE only,
the Asymmetric Gaussian model outperforms other models over most areas
of high latitude boreal region, while the Savitzky-Golay model gives the
best reconstruction performance in tropical and subtropical regions. The
FRE and the NNRE helped to reveal the main error sources in the
reconstruction in different regions. The comparison method developed and
applied in this study led to suggest adaptive selection of the best
reconstruction model for specific NDVI signals and noise distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;scale-and-scaling-in-soils&quot;&gt;Scale and scaling in soils&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0016706116303640&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Pachepsky, Y; Hill, RL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GEODERMA&lt;/em&gt;, 287 4-30; SI FEB 1 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Scale is recognized as a central concept in the description of the
hierarchical organization of our world. Pressing environmental and
societal problems require an understanding of how processes operate at
different scales, and how they can be linked across scales. Soil science
as many other disciplines obtain the bulk of their empirical information
at fine scales, whereas results of environmental diagnostics,
monitoring, and predictions are needed to make important policy
decisions at much larger scales. It becomes imperative to relate the
information that is available and produced at different scales. The
objective of this work is to present an overview of concepts that are
currently used to define and relate scales in soil studies. The paper is
not intended to be a compendium, but rather should be viewed as material
for discussion, reference, and critique. It discusses definitions and
terminology, including general approaches of scale problems in
environmental studies that are applicable to soils, including
hierarchies, measurement metrics, similitude, non-geometric scale
metrics, and notions of upscaling and downscaling. Concepts of general
scaling methods and theories are dimensional analysis, power law
scaling, space and time dependent scaling. A section on spatiotemporal
patterns introduces scaling ideas that were used in soil studies such as
empirical orthogonal functions, data assimilation, and cumulative
distribution function matching. Reviewed scaling methods developed
specifically to soil studies include geometric similitude of pore
spaces, scaling with Richards equation, scale dependencies of water and
solute flux model parameters, scaling based on temporal stability,
overland flow and sediment transport as the scaling phenomenon, and the
relevance of scaling to pedotransfer functions. An outlook for scaling
research in soils is presented that shows the needs of additional
research and the feasibility of using scaling to enrich and advance soil
research to help face the grand challenges of modern times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-unified-expression-for-grain-size-distribution-of-soils&quot;&gt;A unified expression for grain size distribution of soils&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0016706116307649&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Li, Y; Huang, CM; Wang, BL; Tian, XF; Liu, JJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GEODERMA&lt;/em&gt;, 288 105-119; FEB 15 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Grain size distribution (GSD) is fundamental for soils and usually
described by a set of graphic parameters (e.g., median size, kurtosis,
skewness, uniform and curvature coefficient). Some probability
distributions (e.g., lognormal and Weibull distribution) are used for
special cases, but no general expression is available. In this paper we
propose a general distribution form of P(D) = CD(-mu)exp(-D/Dc) for
various soil materials, with P(D) the exceedance percentage and C,mu and
D-c are parameters determined by the grain size frequency data. The
power-law and exponential part of this expression respectively responds
to the self-similar and random processes of grain fragmentation and
accumulation in soil generation and evolution. The GSD parameters are
distinct in soils and their variation reflects the changes in grain
composition, such as the grain migration and segregation in landslides,
avalanches, debris flows and sedimentary deposits. In addition, the GSD
also fits the pore size of granular materials, confirming the grain-pore
duality and suggesting an important role of the GSD expression in
dynamics of soils and granular media in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;does-organic-farming-accumulate-carbon-in-deeper-soil-profiles-in-the-long-term&quot;&gt;Does organic farming accumulate carbon in deeper soil profiles in the long term?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0016706116305109&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Blanco-Canqui, H; Francis, CA; Galusha, TD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;GEODERMA&lt;/em&gt;, 288 213-221; FEB 15 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Organic farming systems provide the opportunity to deliver more soil
ecosystem services than conventional practices. One such service could
be soil organic C (SOC) accumulation, but recent debates suggest that
this is unclear. Furthermore, organic farming potential to accumulate
SOC for the entire soil profile is not well known. We quantified the
cumulative SOC stocks, aggregate-associated SOC, and particulate organic
matter (POM) concentrations for the 0-100 cm depth of the soil profile
in a comparative crop rotation experiment in eastern Nebraska after &amp;gt;20
yr of management. We studied: 1) conventional farming, 2) conventional
farming with diversified rotation, 3) organic rotation with alfalfa
(Medicago sativa L) as green manure, and 4) organic rotation receiving
37 Mg ha(-1) yr(-1) cattle manure. All the treatments had been managed
for 40 yr except the organic rotation with green manure, which had been
in place for 20 yr. Organic farming increased SOC stock, aggregate
associated SOC, and POM concentrations but only in the 0-15 cm soil
depth. The SOC stock under organic cattle manure system was 19% greater
than under conventional farming (33.1 Mg ha(-1)) and 13% greater than
under conventional farming with diversified rotation (34.8 Mg ha(-1)).
The SOC stock under organic rotation with green manure (36.6 Mg ha(-1))
was 10% greater than in conventional farming. Results suggest that
organic cropping systems accumulated SOC at 0.16 Mg C ha(-1) yr(-1) with
cattle manure and 0.18 Mg C ha(-1) yr(-1) with green manure. Growing
alfalfa for only two years in the 4-yr organic rotation probably limited
its potential to increase SOC for the whole soil profile. Overall, in
the long term, organic farming increases SOC stock but only in the upper
15 cm of the soil profile&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/01/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on January 16, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2017/01/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2017/01/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2017-01-09T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2017-01-09T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2017-1&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2017 #1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stability-of-peatland-carbon-to-rising-temperatures&quot;&gt;Stability of peatland carbon to rising temperatures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms13723&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt; to paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Peatlands contain one-third of soil carbon (C), mostly buried in deep,
saturated anoxic zones (catotelm). The response of catotelm C to climate
forcing is uncertain, because prior experiments have focused on surface
warming. We show that deep peat heating of a 2 m-thick peat column
results in an exponential increase in CH4 emissions. However, this
response is due solely to surface processes and not degradation of
catotelm peat. Incubations show that only the top 20-30 cm of peat from
experimental plots have higher CH4 production rates at elevated
temperatures. Radiocarbon analyses demonstrate that CH4 and CO2 are
produced primarily from decomposition of surface-derived modern
photosynthate, not catotelm C. There are no differences in microbial
abundances, dissolved organic matter concentrations or degradative
enzyme activities among treatments. These results suggest that although
surface peat will respond to increasing temperature, the large reservoir
of catotelm C is stable under current anoxic conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;carbon-accounting&quot;&gt;Carbon accounting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/nclimate/journal/v6/n11/full/nclimate3137.html&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt; to paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Atmospheric CO2 concentrations are at the highest level for around 15 million years. Accurate accounting is crucial for informed decision-making on how to curb the rise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;molecular-fingerprint-of-soil-organic-matter-as-an-indicator-of-pedogenesis-processes-in-technosols&quot;&gt;Molecular fingerprint of soil organic matter as an indicator of pedogenesis processes in Technosols&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11368-016-1523-1&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt; to paper&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Technosol management is one of the greatest challenges for the future,
more specifically as regards supporting and/or restoring ecosystems. The
understanding of natural soil organic matter (SOM) dynamic from
Technosol may give important information about soil functioning and
Technosol evolution.According to this, SOM from three French old mine
Technosols, (an old tin mine, a lead and zinc, and a gold one which is
arsenic-rich), were studied and characterized using thermochemolysis
coupled with gas chromatography and mass spectrometry (GC-MS) with
tetramethyl ammonium hydroxide (TMAH) as reagent and FTIR. The
characterization and quantification of some specific biomacromolecules,
used as biomarkers, indicate the specific level of incorporation
relative to various subgroups. Global parameters of soils (pH, total
organic matter, cation exchange capacityaEuro broken vertical bar) were
also evaluated.Results on bulk samples show that lipids are the most
reactive group and therefore play the most important role in young soil
pedogenesis. All of the results show that the behavior of SOM of the
Technosol is similar to homolog non-anthropized soil and depends on
vegetation type.A slight inhibition of bacterial activity is observed
which underlines a protective effect of Technosols on SOM degradation
due to the low pH, the high clay content, and the presence of Al3+ and
metal(loid)s. In fine, lipid fraction of SOM may act as a well-done
fingerprint of pedogenesis processes in Technosols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;moisture-stress-indicators-in-giant-sequoia-groves-in-the-southern-sierra-nevada-of-california-usa&quot;&gt;Moisture Stress Indicators in Giant Sequoia Groves in the Southern Sierra Nevada of California, USA&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Ray, RL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;VADOSE ZONE JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, 15 (10):NIL_15-NIL_33; OCT 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giant sequoia [Sequoiadendron giganteum (Lindl.) J. Buchholz] trees and
their ecosystems are unique natural treasures in the Sierra Nevada,
California, where most groves are federally managed for biodiversity,
perpetuation of the species, and aesthetic, recreational, ecological,
and scientific values. Increasing temperatures during the next several
decades may create conditions unfavorable for these giant sequoias.
Therefore, it is necessary to develop effective management systems to
preserve the health of these giant sequoia groves. This study used a
topographic wetness index (TWI) as the indicator of soil moisture
conditions to evaluate the vulnerability of giant sequoia groves to soil
moisture stress and focused on evaluating TWI distributions among all 70
sequoia groves to assess their vulnerability to soil moisture stress.
The TWI values were derived using a 10-m digital elevation model and
compared with soil, geology, slope, aspect, and elevation at the sequoia
groves to understand the vulnerability of the groves to soil moisture
stress. The TWI values were also compared with snow cover persistence
derived from 12 yr of MODIS snow cover products. In addition, satellite
soil moisture products were used to compare the dry and wet periods
predicted by snow cover persistence. Results showed that the groves
located at higher elevation are less vulnerable unless the TWI across
the groves is low. For the large number of groves with elevations mainly
in the 1800-to 2100-m range, the TWI distributions can serve as a
first-order indicator of relative vulnerability. Further, this analysis
showed that areas with milder slopes and more converging area (higher
TWI), plus longer snow cover persistence, should be less susceptible to
low summer soil moisture than areas having steeper slopes, more
diverging topography (lower TWI), and earlier snowmelt. This analysis
can be used to highlight groves that are potentially more vulnerable,
particularly when considering TWI, snow cover persistence, and satellite
soil moisture together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;environmental-change-and-human-health-can-environmental-proxies-inform-the-biodiversity-hypothesis-for-protective-microbial-human-contact&quot;&gt;Environmental Change and Human Health: Can Environmental Proxies Inform the Biodiversity Hypothesis for Protective Microbial-Human Contact?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/bioscience/article/66/12/1023/2646819/Environmental-Change-and-Human-Health-Can&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt; to paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors:
Liddicoat, C; Waycott, M; Weinstein, P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:
&lt;em&gt;BIOSCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, 66 (12):1023-1034; DEC 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Microbiota from environmental sources overlap and interact with human
microbiota, contribute to human microbial diversity, and provide
beneficial immunomodulatory stimuli. Meanwhile, reduced diversity in
human microbiota and immune dysregulation have been associated with a
range of diseases. Emerging evidence suggests landscape-scale drivers of
microbial diversity may influence our health, but the area remains
understudied because of its multidisciplinary nature. Here, we attempt
to widen the view on this subject by offering an environmental
researcher’s viewpoint, proposing a unifying conceptual framework to
stimulate multidisciplinary interest. To focus research in this
challenging area, we propose greater emphasis on multiscale ecological
links and that landscape-scale proxies for potential underlying
microbial mechanisms be investigated to identify key environmental
attributes and health relationships worthy of subsequent detailed
examination. Wherever possible, ecological epidemiological studies
should account for the temporal nature of environmental microbiota
exposures, especially with respect to the early development of the human
commensal microbiota.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/01/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on January 09, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Soil Science Conference, Queenstown, New Zealand]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2016/12/queenstown" />
  <id>/2016/12/queenstown</id>
  <updated>2016-12-22T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2016-12-22T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;From 12-16 December 2016, I had the pleasure of attending the joint conference of the New Zealand Society of Soil Science and Soil Science Australia. The conference was held in one of the most iconic places of New Zealand: the scenic resort town of Queenstown in the South Island. The overarching theme of the conference was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nzsssconference.co.nz/&quot;&gt;‘Soil, a Balancing Act Down-under’&lt;/a&gt; to glance the torch light onto the challenges in managing soils to reach a careful balance between many, often competing, land-use, productivity and environmental aspirations. I report on some of my observations from this interesting conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general schedule of the conference was fieldtrips on day 1, followed by days 2, 3, 4, and half of 5 as normal conference proceedings consisting of keynotes, plenaries, and research presentations (both oral and posters). Some social functions were organised which included a BBQ at the end of day 1, a touch football competition (day 3), and conference dinner (day 4). The conference was situated at the Millennium Hotel, which is more-or-less central Queenstown. I arrived in New Zealand of the 11th December with a few colleagues, and departed for return to Sydney just after lunch on the 16th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conference-fieldtrip&quot;&gt;1. Conference fieldtrip&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First day of the conference was dedicated to a fieldtrip. There were two options for fieldtrips, and I went on the one that went through the Central Otago area. Most of my work colleagues were on this trip too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially the trip was a loop of the area to the east and north east of Queenstown. Pretty much after departing Queenstown and heading directly east we headed to the Crown Range Road Summit which is at 1119m elevation. The route to the summit was very steep and winding. Upon disembarking from the bus we were greeted with exceedingly chilly winds and the odd flake of snow. We were also greeted by tour leader Sam Carrick (Landcare Research) who introduced us to a freshly prepared Acidic Brown Soil - largely a silty soil with an abundance of Schist rocks of various size. This particular landscape is an example of New Zealand’s high country of which is mainly dedicated to pastoral farming. Tourism is also big in this type of landscape too. The combined pressures of farming and tourism makes management of these delicate landscapes a tricky task as they are both culturally and environmentally significant, yet also are a source of significant dollars in terms of the pastoral outputs and their tourism potential. Similar mindful approaches the land management are common elsewhere where competing and multipurpose land uses are in play. After spending around 20mins at this stop, most people were clamouring to get back onto the buses for the next item of the itinerary due to the near freezing temperature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/20161222queenstown/highcountry1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;high country figure&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 1. An example of New Zealand's high country. Complete with grazing sheep and snow capped mountains.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second stop was Mt Burke Station which is farmed by Tim Burdon with farm manager Grant Ruddenklau. Mt Burke Station covers approx. 10 000ha and is situated on the shores of Lake Wanaka. There are mixed land uses here with significant numbers of stock that include sheep, cattle (beef), and deer. Some cropping enterprises include Canola, Swedes, Turnips, and fodder beet. We were here to discuss in person some of the land management issues facing farming in high country pastoral stations. Mt Burke is typical of many high country stations in the lakes catchments. It has hundreds of streams flowing through the property and shallow stony soils that present challenges for water quality and nutrient management, and it also has the vast challenge of having an open lake frontage. Having this lake frontage (Lake Wanaka) leads to higher scrutiny from Government in how the land is managed, and how and to what extent nutrients are used and applied. In fact very stringent monitoring and reporting of nutrient use is the norm on this station (and elsewhere). Also having the lake frontage exposes the farm managers to greater scrutiny from the public who are naturally concerned and oftentimes vocal about the maintenance of a pristine environment. According to the farm managers, sometimes this scrutiny is mis-guided, leading to negative perceptions of agricultural land management in this delicate landscape. From what I could tell though, with government policy in place and stringent monitoring, coupled with a team of knowledgeable land managers, Mt Burke station is doing well and operating well. After having lunch on the shore of Lake Wanaka, Sam Carrick showed us a nice example of soils on this station, where we were introduced to a stunning Stoney Brown soil. There are so many knowledge gaps in understanding these soils, particularly how they respond to the intensification of agriculture. Part of this knowledge gap is trying to understand how nutrients are stored and flow through them, and measuring their water storage capacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/20161222queenstown/mtBurke1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mt Burke Station&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 2. Left image shows Sam Carrick and others talking about this very interesting Stony Brown Soil profile. The right image is a close-up of the same profile.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third stop before journeying back to Queenstown was to meet local viticulturist Roger Gibson to talk about horticulture in the central Otago environment. We were specifically located in the Cromwell area which is situated about 50kms due east of Queenstown. What really struck me about this area was how dry the environment was. In fact the area is classified as semi-arid where it receives less than 500mm of rainfall annually. The cool environment coupled with low rainfall, and pretty good soils makes this area quite a famous viticultural region. Roger Gibson manages the award winning Lowburn Ferry wine brand and gave us an excellent talk about the history of the wine industry in this region, and the associated management considerations for producing high quality wines. We were also treated to a delicious Otago Pinot Noir while listening to Roger and taking in the astounding surrounding landscape. We then got the opportunity to meet another great soil which reminded me of something I would see in Australia. This was an apparently weathered soil with a clay pan and a clear presence of pedogentic carbonate materials. The source of pedogenic carbonates is debated, but is probably due to the combination of mineral weathering and microbial action. Coupled with the semi-arid environment, leaching of carbonates would be minimal, leading to an accumulation and precipitation within the soil profile. Sam Carrick mentioned that from dating experiments upon these soils, it is estimated to be around 400 000 years old. Compared to Australian soils, this is relatively young, but by New Zealand standards these are quite old soils. I was fascinated by this stop because I did not expect to experience a semi-arid environment in this part of the world, and to come upon a soil that was so apparently weathered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/20161222queenstown/horticulture1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lowburn Ferry&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 3. Roger Gibson gave an excellent presentation about the wine industry in the semi-arid Central Otago region. The landscape we were situated in was simply breath-taking. The soil profile we view here displayed an apparently clayey sub soil and a pedogenic calcium carbonate horizon too.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summing up, the Otago fieldtrip was a memorable one. I was beguiled by the landscape and terrain we passed through from stop to stop. I was equally impressed by the variety of soils we experienced too. Sam Carrick’s knowledge of the environment and the issues faced with managing it was extensive and augmented the day very nicely. After gettting back into Queenstown in the early evening, everyone headed to the pre-conference BBQ where everyone got a chance to catch up and put away a tasty feed and a few quenching ales. The conference BBQ was also where the winners of the soil judging contest were announced. The gong was taken out by a travelling USA team. Second place was taken out by a team from Queensland, and the third place was taken out by our very own University of Sydney Team. Or thats how i interpretted the outcome as it seemed every team got an award somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/20161222queenstown/horticulture2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lowburn Ferry 2&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 4. Quite a gathering of Sydney Uni soil scientists attended the Central Otago fieldtrip.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;normal-conference-proceedings&quot;&gt;2. Normal conference proceedings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The format for the four days of conference proceedings were morning keynotes and plenaries to the whole delegation. This was followed by four parallel sessions. I attended a diversity of talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The afternoon of the first day I spent most of my time in the pedology, soil landscapes and mapping session. Assoc Prof. Stephen Cattle expertly chaired the first session of the topic, and I was greatly thrilled by diversity of talks. Talks ranged from traditional pedological discussions through to digital soil mapping and informatic presentations. For example from Richard Greene (ANU) about the characteristics of Aeolian accession on soils in the Yass Valley, NSW. Then we were introduced to some innovative digital soil mapping approaches to soil carbon (Sanjee Dwage) and soil moisture (Tom Bishop). Uta Stockmann and Pierre Roudier provided some interesting presentations about use infrared spectroscopy for estimation of soil properties. Pierre’s work on digital morphometric analysis of soil profile imagery was exceptional. I really think quality imagery of soil profiles could be considered an art form. Pierre’s work demonstrated some tools for visualisation and quantitative analysis of these images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Late in the afternoon I attended the session called Improved Decision Making. A colleague of mine Ed Jones was presenting in this session where he was elaborating on the design of a soil spectral inference system. In this session I was also fascinated to see the talk from the NSW Govt (Greg Chapman) regarding soil capability prediction throughout the state. I was encouraged to see some adoption of digital technologies in their process. Being in this session from go to end meant I was unable to attend to parallel session on soil carbon where there looked to be some really interesting talks. But at least I have the full handbook of abstracts of all talks presented at this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nzsssconference.co.nz/images/oral_abstracts.pdf&quot;&gt;conference&lt;/a&gt; to read up on later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The morning of second day I spent in the second session of the pedology, soil landscapes and mapping session. Colleague Philip Hughes gave a lively presentation about comparing taxonomic similarities between the Australian and USA soil classification systems. I think this type of analysis is critical if the soil science domain is to offer up to the general science community a universal classification system, rather than fragmented systems established by individual organisations and countries. My other colleague Stephen Cattle presented something of a pet topic for him on whether ‘parna’ - dust derived clay aggregations - existed. Using some micromorphological analyses, Stephen was able to demonstrate that silt-size aggregations of clay did exist in soils where Aeolian accession had occurred upon them. This talk was followed up by Carol Smith (Lincoln University) who gave us an excellent discussion of Aeolian derived soils in New Zealand. I was really fascinated by her use of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csiro.au/en/Research/MRF/Areas/Mineral-exploration-and-discovery/Rapid-resource-characterisation/QEMSCAN?ref=/CSIRO/Website/Research/MRF/Areas/Advanced-characterisation-facility/QEMSCAN&quot;&gt;QEMSCAN&lt;/a&gt; for discrimination of minerals within an albeit small sample. QEMSCAN employs a scanning electron microscope, four X-ray detectors and a software package to enables rapid discrimination of minerals, without reliance on visual judgments. This technology is something I should follow up on as it seems pretty useful. Other talks in this session ranged from digital soil mapping (Sharn Hainsworth, Jon Gray), to farm scale soil mapping - where Alan Palmer highlighted the inefficiencies of applying legacy soil survey mapping for farm scale applications. Marta Camps Arbestian gave a really nice presentation of soil geochemistry and its use in devising a new model of soil formation (need to read the abstract on this one).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A benefit of the parallel sessions being in such close proximity to each other, meant it was pretty easy to jump from session to session. This is what I did during the second afternoon where I jumped between the 3 sessions on offer: Laboratory and Rapid Testing (Galaxy 1), session 3 of pedology (Galaxy 2), and Balanced solutions farm systems and catchments (Galaxy 3). Again the breadth of presentations in the pedology session was remarkable. Bernard Walker (UTAS) presented some of his Honours research about assessing the likely provenance of E Horizons on some soils in Tasmania. For such a fresh young researcher, this was really quality research and more-or-less very thorough detective work. Colleague Stacey Paterson gave a nice presentation on soil variability analysis of soil texture at the continental scale (Australia) using a geostatistical and fractal approach. Then there were a couple of talks from QLD Govt, where I was encouraged by their application of digital approaches for soil mapping. Lauren O’Brien presented some excellent work using disaggregation methods, similar to the &lt;a href=&quot;/software/&quot;&gt;DSMART&lt;/a&gt; approach, for identifying subsoil constraints. USYD Alumni, Luke Finn also presented in digital soil erodibility mapping in the QLD Fitzroy basin. In Galaxy 3, Darren Kidd presented on a practical approach to quantifying soil security. As a concept, soil security works well for highlighting the importance of soil, and for communicating soil science to the non-soil science community. Trying to quantify the different dimensions of soil security through a digital soil mapping approach is pretty ambitious, but I think Darren communicated quite well the different things that were and could be considered. For example, how do we quantify the cultural value of soils? With some ingenuity and accessing what appear to be excellent GIS facilities within the Tasmanian Govt, they were able to link tourism activity to cultural value. I acknowledge that Darren’s work was a first step in the quantification thing, but at a least it got the cogs turning in how we can develop the concept further and deeper. The last two talks in Galaxy 1 were of interest to me. Les Janik (CSIRO) gave an excellent presentation on the comparative performance of different portable infrared sensors for predicting soil properties in the field. I was really encouraged to hear that the Spectral Evolution vis-NIR was one if not the best performing of the different instruments. Colleague Mario Fajardo pretty much floored the room with an excellent presentation on an App he created that measures soil aggregate stability. The amount of tech savviness and code underlying this App will probably never be appreciated, but this sort of technology gives a glimpse on where soil measurement approaches are headed in the coming years. For his efforts he was ultimately awarded the Bouma Award for best presentation of the conference. Ripper stuff Mario!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day three meant it was now time for me give my own presentation on work that I had been doing in the past year in terms of spatial downscaling for soil carbon auditing. But before this I attended the Keynote and Plenary session first up in the morning. Without commenting too much about the talk from Julian Cribb, I am always upset by people presenting doomsday predictions of the world future. Julian expertly does this, but I do not think it is entirely useful, and if anything, may cause undue alarm. Sure humans have done severe damage to the earth system, but I think there is a resilient and adaptive quality to these that are often not acknowledged or under appreciated. I acknowledge human behaviour needs to change in order to better manage environmental systems, but it all comes down to education and not frightening the bejesus out of people about predictions of where we are headed. That is my little rant over, but my mood lifted significantly with the following three Plenary talks. A nice heart-warming and inspiring presentation from Alison Collins (Landcare Research) talk about the importance of soil and keeping an eye on it for the future. I liked how Alison used imagery of her young family to highlight that how we manage soils now is of great importance for future generations. Francis Hoyle (UWA) gave us a challenging talk on the dynamic changes in soil carbon. Using research conducted by her group in West Australia, sequestering soil carbon is not a simple cut and dry approach. One needs to consider application rates of amendments in addition to the economic costs of application. Soil carbon sequestration seems possible with the right management practices, but they need to be nuanced and implemented over of a long period of time, are what I think was the ultimate message. Filling in for Sam Carrick, Alan Hewitt (Landcare Research) provided a presentation on the special soil wonders of the Otago basins. This talk augmented really well with what I experienced in the field during the Otago fieldtrip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My presentation was allocated to the second session of the Improved Decision making session. I was amongst some good company including Peter Wilson (CSIRO) talking about soil data standards of which are necessary for harmonising disparate soil data sets. Peter Dahlhaus added to this concept with work in Victoria using soil data visualisations and analysis for monitoring the condition of soils. Colleague and PhD student Ronald Muchelo highlighted to the audience in his presentation how urban expansion in Uganda is leading to substantial losses of viable agricultural soils. The encroachment of urban development upon agricultural land is very familiar, particularly in Sydney, but it seems to be on a whole different level in Uganda though. Ronald in his talk demonstrated some the analyses he used for quantifying soils of which were based on digital soil mapping approaches of which I found to be really encouraging to see it being used for operational purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With other prior commitments, I was unable to attend the rest of the Thursday conference proceedings. People whom I spoke with after though were really impressed with the panel discussion that occurred. Another notable conference functions that I have not detailed yet is the session dedicated to poster presentations. The poster session was on after lunch on the Wednesday, and provided an opportunity to walk about and look at all the posters of which there were many. Because of the arrangement of the venue, there were posters in all nooks and crannies about the place. This made getting to all posters a little difficult, but the experience was quite enjoyable and I was able to get round to most and have a few good discussions and catch-up moments with a number of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last day of the conference was scheduled as a half-dayer. I admired the people who had to get up and present as I am sure there would have been a few sore heads amongst them, due to the raucous night that was the conference dinner. Highlights were presentations from colleagues and PhD students Patrick Filippi and Liana Johnson. Patrick presented on monitoring soil change in cotton field of western NSW, while Liana gave a nice presentation about heavy metal contamination of soils in the Sydney Basin. After the research presentations were completed the formalities of the conference were over. Just before this however, the Norman Taylor Memorial Lecture was given by Louis Schipper. Norman Taylor has left a huge legacy upon soil science in New Zealand from what I have read, and I think Louis, more-or-less giving a rundown of the research that comes out of the group at the University of Waikato, gave an excellent taste of soil science research in New Zealand. I was fascinated to hear about their research on soil carbon and nitrogen dynamics, of which has inspired me to follow up more deeply on their excellent research in this field. With the lecture over, the official closing ceremony happened, which included some award giving and awkward thank you and well wishes from committee members of the New Zealand and Australian soil science societies. All in all, I got a lot out the formal part of the conference. It is unfortunate I was unable to catch all that was presented, but I walk away satisfied with what I had taken in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;social-functions&quot;&gt;3. Social functions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of social functions were dotted through the conference. As already mentioned there was the welcome BBQ on the Monday after the fieldtrips. On the Tuesday, I attended the Soil Science Australia AGM. Here we were introduced to the newly elected Federal Council. The new Council could best be described as youthful, and consists of John Bennett (President, USQ), Dan Brough (Vice President, QLD Govt), and Zoe Reed (Treasurer, ANU). The departure of several key members of the Federal Council, particularly of Executive officer Linda Bennison, leave some considerablly big shoes to fill for the future direction of the society. But the youthful team leading the society now will surely push it to new and unimagined places. I look forward to see where we are headed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably one of the highlights for the conference for me was an organised touch football competition that was held at the end of proceedings on the Wednesday. The concept of having a sporting context amongst colleagues and delegates is a stroke of brilliance. I think there were enough players to fill six teams. There was a USYD team (with a couple of drifters), plus a couple of QLD teams and other teams from NZ. There was even a crowd of onlookers taking in the spectacle. I don’t think any team was crowned a the ultimate victor, but it was just good all round fun and a chance to blow some steam off. I guess the pinnacle of the competition was a super match between Australia and New Zealand which abruptly ended when one of the Australian players from Queensland (sorry don’t know his name) dislocated his shoulder whilst scoring a try. This was obviously terrible news for the player injured, but as this was the only try scored in the match, Australia was the clear winner on the day. New Zealand will get the chance to atone in a rematch I guess at the next joint conference. It was much fun indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/20161222queenstown/touch1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;touch rugby&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 5. The Sydney Uni touch rugby team that took on the world in Queenstown. We did alright too.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference dinner was located at Skyline Restaurant which overlooks the town of Queenstown from several hundred metres up. The only way to get here is via a very steep gondola ride, where once to the top we were greeted which exceptional views and plenty of free beverages! There was plenty of good spirits on the night amongst the formalities of award giving and presentations. Our own Alex McBratney was awarded a Fellowship to Soil Science Australia. Other Australian award winners included Bob Gilkes (Honary Life Member) and Jock Churchman (JK Taylor Gold Medal in Soil Science). A couple of the really exceptional awards for the night was the announcement of the winners of the individual prizes in the soil judging contest. I think someone from the University of Wisconsin came in third, but our own USYD stars Bruce Tran and Rebecca McGirr came in second and first respectively. This would have been a massive achievement for them, and I was so happy for them too. All in all, the conference dinner night was super fun and enjoyable, although the body was paying for it the next morning a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/20161222queenstown/alex1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;alex award&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 6. Alex McBratney collected a number of awards during 2016. Here he is recieving his Fellowship Award from Soil Science Australia and giving an entertaining acceptance speech.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-points&quot;&gt;Final Points&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much thanks goes to the New Zealand Soil Science Society for putting on a fabulous conference. Although the weather was a bit fickle, and at times pretty unforgiving (especially in December), Queenstown and the surrounding area is a beautiful place of the world. I would love to come visit here again sometime.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2016/12/queenstown&quot;&gt;Soil Science Conference, Queenstown, New Zealand&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on December 22, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Website Launch]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2016/11/website-launch" />
  <id>/2016/11/website-launch</id>
  <updated>2016-11-17T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2016-11-17T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Brendan Malone</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;I have always had some interest or wonder into what and how websites are powered. Like where is all this content stored? And how is it all organised? Only recently these questions were more-or-less answered for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was when i undertook a short course on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecademy.com/learn&quot;&gt;codecademy&lt;/a&gt;. It was definitely worth my while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So these are just some pointers that i found entirely useful for helping me develop and deploy a website on to the internet. As you can see, this website you are using is the outcome of my learning about this to date. It is by no means a finished product either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 3 main steps to achieve these ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Generate a static site&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deploy the site to the Internet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give the website a custom domain name (optional step).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will just give a rather brief outline of these main steps but be aware that there are many little bumps and bungles to be encountered along the way as developing your own website will introduce you to problems specific to your use case. I have found though that a little intuition and iteration are the best means of finding the way through the issues that crop up. I have found that making a website is actually very fiddly and demands a lot of your time. I would not really describe myself as a computer literate either. More of a hack, but cobbling a few bits and pieces together of other peoples contributions has actually been the way i have floundered through to a result (a working website) that is mine and has my name all over it. It has my own personal brand, and that is what i wanted to achieve. I learned a lot in this process, so lets just get down to business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;creating-a-website&quot;&gt;1. Creating a Website&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll i have found is a really cool tool to quickly generate a website. Jekyll is a simple static site generator. Using Jekyll is a very common way of generating a “ready-to-publish static website” within seconds. You can learn more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post just demonstrates the process of using Jekyll to generate a static website quickly then focus on deploying it. You could use any sort of content you wish however and still follow the steps of deployment covered later on. Just make sure that your HTML is inside of a file called index.html. You can go ahead and create your own static site from scratch, but that is not for me. I am just going to do something simple, but bear in mind there is a vast array of &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllthemes.org/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Themes&lt;/a&gt; to tickle anyone’s fancy. The use of Github here is necessary though, as you can just select the theme of your choice, clone it onto your computer, then begin filling it with your own content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One catch is that Windows is not an officially supported platform for Jekyll. Consequently everything i do from here using Jekyll was development on Ubuntu 16.04. Before you install Jekyll, what you are going to need first is to install Ruby. More info on how to do this can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brightbox.com/docs/ruby/ubuntu/&quot;&gt;brightbox&lt;/a&gt;. There maybe a few other software to install as well, so after you install Ruby you can then check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/installation/&quot;&gt;Jekyll install instructions&lt;/a&gt;. Then in your terminal you can do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot;&gt;$ sudo gem install jekyll
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Jekyll now installed we use Jekyll’s new command and specify a directory name. The directory will contain all of your site’s default content that can be customized later. For example, to generate a website in a directory called my-own-site, we can type:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot;&gt;$ jekyll new my-own-site
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use Jekyll to view your site locally. On the web, a server hosts your site’s files and makes your website available for everyone to see. However, viewing a website locally means that you’re viewing the site on your own computer (hence the term “locally” or “local”). The site is not, however, available on the public Internet. Instead, your computer is acting as the server that hosts your site. You can view your site locally by using Jekyll’s serve command, like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot;&gt;$ jekyll serve
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This command starts a local server that will server the files to your computer. The serve command will also come in handy when you want to preview changes you make to your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website that Jekyll generates offers a standard directory structure, as well as components that help speed up development. It’s important to understand Jekyll’s default directory structure and contents of your site. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/structure/&quot;&gt;See here&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;deploy-website&quot;&gt;2. Deploy Website&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many different ways to deploy a website to the public Internet. One of them uses GitHub Pages to deploy your website. GitHub Pages is a service offered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. Specifically, GitHub Pages are public webpages that are hosted and published through GitHub. GitHub Pages offers extensive integration and support for Jekyll. By using both, we can benefit from:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easy setup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Troubleshooting your site&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updating and maintaining your site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously one caveat to successfully deploy your site, is that you will need a GitHub account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to publish your site using GitHub Pages, you’ll need to create a repository (repo) on GitHub. A GitHub repository is an online, central storage place where you can store files and all the versions of those files. We’ll use the repo create just before to store the contents of the basic website. A repo’s name must also follow GitHub Pages’ naming convention, otherwise the site will not publish at all. Specifically, the repo’s name must be in the following format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot;&gt;your-user-name.github.io
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the example above, you would replace your-user-name with your actual GitHub user name. Now we can upload the site that that was created (&lt;code&gt;new my-own-site&lt;/code&gt;) to GitHub. We’ll use Git to push (upload) the contents of your site’s directory to your new repo. To do so, we’ll first initialize a Git repository in the site’s directory. First, use the &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; command to navigate to the site’s directory. Once inside the &lt;code&gt;new my-own-site&lt;/code&gt; directory, initialize a Git repository with the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot;&gt;$ git init
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, Git needs to know what repo will store your site’s content. In this case, the repo will be the one you created on GitHub earlier. To specify the repo using Git, we’ll have to add the remote and label it as the origin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remote is the URL of the repo that will store your site’s contents. The origin is an alias for the remote. You can think of an alias as an abbreviation or a substitute name. This means that instead of having to always type the lengthy remote URL over and over again, you can simply refer to it as origin later on. In the terminal, you can add the remote with the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot;&gt;$ git remote add origin https://github.com/your-user-name/your-user-name.github.io.git
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Git also needs to know exactly which files should be pushed to your repo. In this case, we want to push all of your site’s content to the repo. This means we will do the following two things (in order):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add all of your site’s content to the Git staging area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot;&gt;$ git add .
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Save your changes using Git’s commit command and the following commit message:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot;&gt;$ git commit -m &quot;Save my work&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now use Git to help deploy the site. This time, we’ll use Git’s push command and push the contents of your site up to the repo using the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot;&gt;$ git push -u origin master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site will now be published on the public Internet. You can now navigate to your newly published website in your preferred browser. The URL for your GitHub Pages site is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot;&gt;your-user-name.github.io
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where your-user-name is your actual GitHub username.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;give-the-website-a-custom-domain-name&quot;&gt;2. Give the website a custom domain name&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now we have deployed the site and GitHub Pages has assigned it a default URL, or domain name. The next step is to purchase your own custom domain name and assign it to your GitHub Pages website. This will result in you being able to access your site using both your new domain name and your default GitHub Pages domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you choose a custom domain name, it’s important to first understand what domain names actually are. Domain names are human-friendly names that identify servers on the Internet. A global system known as the Domain Name System (DNS) is used for storing which domain names correspond to which servers. For example, Github’s’s domain name is &lt;code&gt;https://github.com&lt;/code&gt;. When you type the domain name into your browser, your computer asks the DNS to identify which servers should receive the request in order to load the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; This part of website deployment is optional. Nevertheless, you can follow through the steps required to purchase a custom domain name and assign it to your GitHub Pages site. From my own experience a custom domain name costs about $15 AUS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often, the most time consuming part of buying a domain name is actually deciding what you’d like it to be. Be aware that not all domain names are available; many have already been claimed by others. Here we are going to use Amazon Web Services (AWS) to purchase your custom domain. &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/&quot;&gt;AWS&lt;/a&gt; is an industry standard suite of web infrastructure services used frequently by developers. The specific service we’re going to use to purchase your domain name is called &lt;code&gt;Route 53&lt;/code&gt;. To begin the process you will need to establish an account with AWS if you do not have one already. Creating an AWS account is free - there are no required purchases. The only purchase that you’ll (optionally) make will be the purchase of your custom domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important Instructions&lt;/strong&gt;
After logging into your account, you’ll land on the AWS console. The console displays the many different services. Here we are going to focus on a service called “Route 53,” under the “Networking” category. Route 53 can be used to purchase domain names and create DNS records. Once in here, click on the “Get Started Now” button under the “Domain Registration” section. On the next page, locate the two buttons at the top of the page. Click on the button titled “Register Domain”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it’s time to select a domain name and make sure it’s available. Route 53 allows you to search the availability of a domain name you have in mind. It also offers many suffixes, like &lt;code&gt;.com&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.io&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.me&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;.soil&lt;/code&gt;. If the domain name you want is unavailable as a &lt;code&gt;.com&lt;/code&gt; for example, you can try using a different suffix. The suffixes of domain names are known as top-level domains (TLDs). Different TLDs cost different annual prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;.com&lt;/code&gt; domains are the most popular and are therefore generally unavailable (or expensive).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With your new domain name established,you might notice that it doesn’t work yet - you can’t visit it in your web browser. We have to connect it to your GitHub Pages website first. There are two steps required:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inform GitHub of the new domain name we’ll be using (the one you purchased)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set up DNS records in Route 53 that direct to GitHub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To perform these steps, open GitHub and access the repo you created earlier titled &lt;code&gt;your-user-name.github.io&lt;/code&gt;. Click the “New file” button. Name the new file &lt;code&gt;CNAME&lt;/code&gt;. Do not add a file name extension. In the file, on line 1, type the custom domain name you just purchased in the following format: &lt;code&gt;yourcustomdomain.com&lt;/code&gt;. You may have purchased a domain name with a TLD other than .com. In that case, make sure to use that TLD when creating the &lt;code&gt;CNAME&lt;/code&gt; file. Commit the new file. Under the title of the repo, click on “Settings.” Scroll down to the section titled “GitHub Pages” and confirm that there is a message similar to the following: Your site is published at &lt;code&gt;http://yourcustomdomain.com&lt;/code&gt;. Try navigating to your website in your browser using your new domain name. It still doesn’t work! Time to move onto the next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new &lt;code&gt;CNAME&lt;/code&gt; file in your repo informs GitHub that you’re assigning a new custom domain name to your GitHub Pages site. What we do now is let the rest of the Internet know that we want to associate the custom domain name with your GitHub Pages site. We can do this by creating DNS records, which are globally accessible records that map domain names to servers. The DNS records are created inside of a Hosted Zone in Route 53. A Hosted Zone is essentially a group of DNS records for a single domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important Instructions&lt;/strong&gt;
In your AWS account Access Route 53 again. On the left side of the page, click on the title that says “Hosted Zones.” Notice that you have a Hosted Zone for your new domain name. Click on it to open it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Domain names are associated with the correct DNS records by setting the domain name’s name servers. After a domain name is typed into a browser, the computer first retrieves the name servers that correspond to that domain name. The name servers are important because they’re responsible with providing the computer with other important information (in the form of DNS records) associated with the domain name. Setting your domain’s name servers is important. The DNS is a global system, which means that anyone can create DNS records. We must verify that the DNS records we create were actually created by the owner of the domain name (in this case, you). By doing this, the owner of a domain name ensures that only they have exclusive control over their domain’s DNS records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice that the Hosted Zone for your domain name already has an &lt;code&gt;NS (Name server)&lt;/code&gt; record. This record contains four values. These are the Hosted Zone’s unique name servers. Take note of these values and copy them down somewhere. On the left hand side, under “Domains,” click on “Registered domains.” Then, click on your domain name. On the right hand side of the page, locate the section titled “Name Servers.” Notice that these are the same name servers that your Hosted Zone’s &lt;code&gt;NS&lt;/code&gt; record contained. Route 53 did this for you automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that your domain name is associated with the correct name servers, it’s time to create some additional DNS records within the Hosted Zone. The records that we’ll create will be used by the name servers to help locate your site when a computer wants to load it. Specifically, the name servers will be responsible for providing that computer with important information stored in the records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several different types of DNS records. We’re going to start by creating an &lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt; record, which stands for Address record. An &lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt; record directs a domain name to an IP address. This record will associate our new custom domain name with Github’s servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important Instructions&lt;/strong&gt;
Inside of your Hosted Zone, click on the button at the top labeled “Create Record Set.” A form will appear to the right. Leave the “Name:” field blank. Set the “Type:” field to A - IPv4 address.
Leave the “TTL (Seconds)” value at the default of 300. In the “Value” text box, enter the following IP addresses (keep them on separate lines):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot;&gt;192.30.252.153
192.30.252.154
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These IP addresses belong to GitHub. We are specifying that when your custom domain name is requested, the DNS should direct the request to GitHub. Read more information about this &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/setting-up-an-apex-domain/#configuring-a-records-with-your-dns-provider&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Click the “Save Record Set” button at the bottom of the form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When setting up a website, it’s also conventional to also set up a &lt;code&gt;www&lt;/code&gt; subdomain. &lt;code&gt;www&lt;/code&gt; stands for &lt;code&gt;world wide web&lt;/code&gt;. Subdomains are part of a main (or root) domain. For example, &lt;code&gt;www.yourcustomdomain.com&lt;/code&gt; is a subdomain of the &lt;code&gt;yourcustomdomain.com&lt;/code&gt; root domain. We can set up a subdomain using a &lt;code&gt;CNAME&lt;/code&gt; record, which stands for Canonical Name. A &lt;code&gt;CNAME&lt;/code&gt; record specifies that a domain name will be used as an alias, or substitute, for the true (canonical) domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important Instructions&lt;/strong&gt;
Inside of your Hosted Zone, click on the button at the top labeled “Create Record Set”. A form will appear to the right. In the “Name:” field, enter only &lt;code&gt;www&lt;/code&gt;. Set the “Type: “ field to &lt;code&gt;CNAME - Canonical name&lt;/code&gt;. This step sets up the subdomain. In the &lt;code&gt;Value&lt;/code&gt; text box, enter the domain name that GitHub assigned to you earlier (the canonical domain name:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot;&gt;your-user-name.github.io
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click the “Save Record Set” button at the bottom of the form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;W have now created two DNS records: an &lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt; record for &lt;code&gt;yourcustomdomain.com&lt;/code&gt; and a &lt;code&gt;CNAME&lt;/code&gt; record for &lt;code&gt;www.yourcustomdomain.com&lt;/code&gt;. Let’s make sure they both work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important Instructions&lt;/strong&gt;
Try opening your website using your root domain in the web browser. You should see your new GitHub Pages site. Try opening your website using your &lt;code&gt;www&lt;/code&gt; subdomain in the web browser. You should see your new GitHub Pages site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Success! The website should now display in the browser when you navigate to your custom domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-points&quot;&gt;Final Points&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We have used Jekyll to create a static website, then used Github pages to host it on the internet. We then set up a custom domain so that the website can be widely seen on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is much to learn in terms of building content for your website. You should also look into the many Jekyll content templates that are available.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I find building Jekyll website content to be relatively easy as you only have to learn Markdown. Jekyll does the amazing job of converting it all in html. I have found though that even with this efficiency, building content can take an age.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt; command is super useful. You can make changes and quickly check the result by deploying the site locally.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2016/11/website-launch&quot;&gt;Website Launch&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brendan Malone at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brendan Malone&lt;/a&gt; on November 17, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>
