<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Smart Digital Agriculture</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2021-03-29T21:09:47+11:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/03/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/03/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-03-29T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-03-29T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-9&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rethinking restoration indicators and end-points for post-mining landscapes in light of novel ecosystems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting the message right on nature-based solutions to climate change&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assessment of the interpretability of data mining for the spatial modelling of water erosion using game theory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rethinking-restoration-indicators-and-end-points-for-post-mining-landscapes-in-light-of-novel-ecosystems&quot;&gt;Rethinking restoration indicators and end-points for post-mining landscapes in light of novel ecosystems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Degraded post-mining landscapes exhibit unique biotic and abiotic components and processes relative to predisturbance natural ecosystems. Yet the concept of pre-disturbance reference natural ecosystems and their associated soil quality indicators (SQIs) (e.g., pH, soil organic carbon) are prominently used for assessing restoration of post-mining landscapes. Limited reviews exist on the validity, limitations, opportunities and knowledge gaps associated with the application of the concept and SQIs on post-mining landscapes. Hence, evidence was examined to highlight constraints, opportunities and future research directions pertaining to the concept and SQIs. First, as novel, hybrid or designer ecosystems, severely degraded post-mining landscapes lack reference natural ecosystems. The framing of restoration is multi-dimensional, and dependent on spatial and temporal scales. Therefore, short-term data on SQIs often measured at point scale cannot adequately account for the multi-dimensionality and scales. Moreover, evidence linking SQIs to ecosystem functions, goods, values, services, and benefits on degraded post-mining landscapes remains weak. Potential redundancy exists among SQIs, because soil properties exhibit spatial and temporal correlation. The universality of SQIs remains unconfirmed, because data validating the measurement protocols and interpretation of SQIs across various biomes are scarce. A framework is presented proposing: (1) a shift from the concept of reference natural ecosystems to novel and designer ecosystems in restoration ecology, (2) the development of the next generation of hierarchical or ecosystem cascade indicators, and end-points addressing the multi-dimensionality and scale issues, and (3) a decision matrix for integrating novel, hybrid and designer ecosystems. The potential applications of novel tools such as drones, laser-based cameras, genomics, and big data analytics are highlighted. Such novel tools could unravel the complex linkages among biotic and abiotic components, and ecosystem function and services, which are currently difficult to investigate using conventional techniques. Finally, ten tentative hypotheses are presented on the restoration of degraded post-mining landscapes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-the-message-right-on-nature-based-solutions-to-climate-change&quot;&gt;Getting the message right on nature-based solutions to climate change&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nature-based solutions (NbS)-solutions to societal challenges that involve working with nature-have recently gained popularity as an integrated approach that can address climate change and biodiversity loss, while supporting sustainable development. Although well-designed NbS can deliver multiple benefits for people and nature, much of the recent limelight has been on tree planting for carbon sequestration. There are serious concerns that this is distracting from the need to rapidly phase out use of fossil fuels and protect existing intact ecosystems. There are also concerns that the expansion of forestry framed as a climate change mitigation solution is coming at the cost of carbon rich and biodiverse native ecosystems and local resource rights. Here, we discuss the promise and pitfalls of the NbS framing and its current political traction, and we present recommendations on how to get the message right. We urge policymakers, practitioners and researchers to consider the synergies and trade-offs associated with NbS and to follow four guiding principles to enable NbS to provide sustainable benefits to society: (1) NbS are not a substitute for the rapid phase out of fossil fuels; (2) NbS involve a wide range of ecosystems on land and in the sea, not just forests; (3) NbS are implemented with the full engagement and consent of Indigenous Peoples and local communities in a way that respects their cultural and ecological rights; and (4) NbS should be explicitly designed to provide measurable benefits for biodiversity. Only by following these guidelines will we design robust and resilient NbS that address the urgent challenges of climate change and biodiversity loss, sustaining nature and people together, now and into the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;assessment-of-the-interpretability-of-data-mining-for-the-spatial-modelling-of-water-erosion-using-game-theory&quot;&gt;Assessment of the interpretability of data mining for the spatial modelling of water erosion using game theory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This study undertook a comprehensive application of 15 data mining (DM) models, most of which have, thus far, not been commonly used in environmental sciences, to predict land susceptibility to water erosion hazard in the Kahorestan catchment, southern Iran. The DM models were BGLM, BGAM, Cforest, CITree, GAMS, LRSS, NCPQR, PLS, PLSGLM, QR, RLM, SGB, SVM, BCART and BTR. We identified 18 factors usually considered as key controls for water erosion, comprising 10 factors extracted from a digital elevation model (DEM), three indices extracted from Landsat 8 images, a sediment connectivity index (SCI) and three other intrinsic factors. Three indicators consisting of MAE, MBE, RMSE, and a Taylor diagram were applied to assess model performance and accuracy. Game theory was applied to assess the interpretability of the DM models for predicting water erosion hazard. Among the 15 predictive models, BGAM and PLS respectively returned the best and worst performance in predicting water erosion hazard in the study area. The most accurate model, BGAM predicted that 22%, 8.2%, 9.4% and 60.4% of the total area should be classified as low, moderate, high and very high susceptibility to soil erosion by water, respectively. Based on BGAM and game theory, the factors extracted from the DEM (e.g., DEM, TWI, Slope, TST, TRI, and SPI) were considered the most important ones controlling the predicted severity of soil erosion by water. We conclude that overall, game theory is a valuable technique for assessing the interpretability of predictive models because this theory through SHAP (Shapley additive explanations) and PFIM (permutation feature importance measure) addresses the important concerns regarding the interpretability of more complex DM models.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/03/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on March 29, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/03/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/03/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-03-28T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-03-28T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-8&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #8&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Global Surface Soil Moisture Drydown Patterns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Disentangling the Impact of Catchment Heterogeneity on Nitrate Export Dynamics From Event to Long-Term Time Scales&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mass-balance approach to quantify water distribution in soils based onX-ray computed tomography images&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Land system diversity, scaling laws and polygons map analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Statistical approaches for spatial sample survey: Persistent misconceptions and new&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimation of carbon stocks in boreal cropland soils - methodological considerations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introducing a mechanistic model in digital soil mapping to predict soil organic matter stocks in theCantabrianregion (Spain)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A log -barrier approach for airborne gamma-ray spectrometry inversion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The influence of rock fragments on field capacity water content in stony soils from hard sandstone alluvium&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil quality and grain yield: A win-win combination in clayey tropical oxisols&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;global-surface-soil-moisture-drydown-patterns&quot;&gt;Global Surface Soil Moisture Drydown Patterns&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding the global soil moisture (SM) dynamics and its governing controls beyond the Darcy Scale is critical for various hydrological, meteorological, agricultural, and environmental applications. In this study, we parameterize the pathways of global surface SM (theta(RS)) drydowns using seasonal observation from Soil Moisture Active Passive (SMAP) satellite (between 2015 and 2019) at 36 km resolution. We develop a new data-driven nonparametric approach to identify the canonical forms of theta(RS) drydown, followed by a nonlinear least squares parameterization of the seasonal drydown pathways at each SMAP footprint. The derived parameters provide the effective soil water retention parameters (SWRPeff), land-atmospheric coupling strength and soil hydrologic regimes for SMAP footprint. Depending on the footprint heterogeneity, climate, and season, the characteristics curves comprising different drydown phases are discovered at SMAP footprints. Drydown curves respond to the within-footprint changes in the meteorological drivers, land-surface characteristics, and the soil-vegetative and atmospheric dynamics. Drydown parameters display high interseasonal variability, especially in the grasslands, croplands, and savannah landscapes due to significant changes in the landscape characteristics and moisture patterns at the subgrid-scale. Soil texture exerts influence on the soil water retention and drydown parameters only when the footprint mean theta(RS) is low, specifically in arid and sparsely vegetated regions. The interseasonal variability of the SWRPeff is primarily driven by the landuse and climate of the SMAP footprint. A global understanding of the SM drydown features at SMAP footprint provides a significant step toward a scale-specific, effective soil hydrologic parameterization for various applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;disentangling-the-impact-of-catchment-heterogeneity-on-nitrate-export-dynamics-from-event-to-long-term-time-scales&quot;&gt;Disentangling the Impact of Catchment Heterogeneity on Nitrate Export Dynamics From Event to Long-Term Time Scales&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Defining effective measures to reduce nitrate pollution in heterogeneous mesoscale catchments remains challenging when based on concentration measurements at the outlet only. One reason for this is our limited understanding of the subcatchment contributions to nitrate export and their importance at different time scales. While upstream subcatchments often disproportionally contribute to runoff generation and in turn to nutrient export, agricultural areas (which are typically found in downstream lowlands) are known to be a major source of nitrate pollution. To examine the interplay of different subcatchments, we analyzed seasonal long-term trends and event dynamics of nitrate concentrations, loads, and the concentration-discharge relationship in three nested catchments within the Selke catchment (456 km(2)), Germany. The upstream subcatchments (40.4% of total catchment area, 34.5% of N input) had short transit times and dynamic concentration-discharge relationships with elevated nitrate concentrations during wet seasons and events. Consequently, the upstream subcatchments dominated nitrate export during high flow and disproportionally contributed to overall annual nitrate loads at the outlet (64.2%). The downstream subcatchment was characterized by higher N input, longer transit times, and relatively constant nitrate concentrations between seasons, dominating nitrate export during low-flow periods. Neglecting the disproportional role of upstream subcatchments for temporally elevated nitrate concentrations and net annual loads can lead to an overestimation of the role of agricultural lowlands. Nonetheless, constantly high concentrations from nitrate legacies pose a long-term threat to water quality in agricultural lowlands. This knowledge is crucial for an effective and site-specific water quality management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plain Language Summary To efficiently remove nitrate pollution, we need to understand how it is transported, mobilized, and stored within large and heterogeneous catchments. Previous studies have shown that upstream catchments often have a disproportional impact on nutrient export, while agriculture (a major nitrate source) is often located in downstream lowlands. To understand which parts of a catchment contribute most to nitrate export and when, we analyzed long-term (1983-2016) and high-frequency (2010-2016) data in the Selke catchment (Germany) at three locations. The mountainous upstream part dominated nitrate transport during winter, spring, and rain events. It had a surprisingly high contribution to annual nitrate loads. The agricultural downstream part of the catchment dominated nitrate export during summer and autumn, with relatively constant concentrations between seasons. Here, nitrogen inputs needed more than a decade to travel through the subsurface of the catchment, which causes a time lag between measures to reduce nitrate pollution and their measurable effect. The resulting storage of nitrate in the groundwater threatens drinking water quality for decades to come. While the role of agricultural lowlands for nitrate export can be overestimated if neglecting the disproportional role of upstream subcatchments, their impact poses a long-term threat to water quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mass-balance-approach-to-quantify-water-distribution-in-soils-based-onx-ray-computed-tomography-images&quot;&gt;Mass-balance approach to quantify water distribution in soils based onX-ray computed tomography images&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;X-ray computed tomography (CT) is commonly used in soil science to quantify distributions of pores, water and solids within soil samples. Particularly promising for liquid visualization is dual-energy scanning of samples with added dopant solutions. The approach uses solutions of heavy elements as a proxy for the soil water and utilizes the abrupt increase of the mass attenuation coefficient of heavy elements when crossing an X-ray absorption edge, detectable by dual-energy CT scanning. However, a key step in visualization of the added liquid is image segmentation. In partially saturated soils, the X-ray CT images consist of voxels with the presence of solid, liquid and gaseous phases in different ratios. These ratios are generally ignored by the traditional image segmentation methods, which separate image voxels into groups with either zero or complete saturation by either prevailing phase. The objective of this study was to develop and test a new physically based segmentation approach that accounts for partial saturation of image voxels by liquids. We combined a theoretical equation for detected photon intensity with the mass conservation equation to compute saturation of image voxels by dopant solution applied to the soil. This approach was tested on soil micro-columns with potassium iodide (KI) solutions. The proposed approach outperformed the traditional segmentation methods, particularly at low and intermediate water contents. Tests conducted forKIsolutions in the concentration ranges from 2 to 20% revealed deterioration of the method accuracy with decreasing dopant concentration in the soil. Based on the results of this study we recommend 10 wt% KI solution for quantifying spatial distribution of liquids in soils using dual-energy X-ray microtomography. Highlights
We developed a new approach to quantify soil water distribution based on X-ray CT. This approach accounts for partial saturation of image voxels by liquids. This approach outperforms the standard image segmentation methods. Its application is limited to using dual energy monochromatic X-ray beams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;land-system-diversity-scaling-laws-and-polygons-map-analysis&quot;&gt;Land system diversity, scaling laws and polygons map analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numerous lines of evidence have been presented in the literature that show the patterns of pedodiversity and biodiversity are very similar. One of the most corroborated patterns lies in the fits of the relationships between biodiversity and soil diversity to power laws according to the increase in study area. Several authors have analysed the presence of fractal and multifractal features in pedodiversity and biodiversity analyses. Similarly, it has also been found that valuable information can be extracted from the polygons of soil and vegetation maps, which also have surprising similarities. These approaches concern information on the spatial distribution of natural resources. However, other more artificial but interesting maps and their comparison have been neglected by such studies. Land systems maps and their georeferenced databases fall into this latter category, and they include most of the soil-forming factors. In this paper a georeferenced land system database and map were analysed and the results compared with those obtained in previous pedodiversity and biodiversity studies, primarily the spatial patterns of the polygons. The results showed that the analysed land system map units followed the same patterns that were previously found in pedodiversity and biodiversity studies; that is, the power law concerning richness-area relationships. The same patterns occur with the number of polygons. Some geographers claim there is a “law” that states that there are far more small things/objects than larger ones across several orders of magnitude in geographic space and thus this regularity conforms to scaling laws, independent of the resource involved. The results obtained corroborate this conjecture irrespective of whether natural resources or artificial cartographies were analysed. This paper represents a first test of land use maps; additional work in this area is needed. Highlights
Spatial patterns detected in natural and land system maps seem to be similar Composite GIS maps have the same spatial patterns as their base maps. Soil and land system units conform to long-tail or heavy tail distributions. Soil maps and land system maps conform to power laws, fingerprints of fractal structures There are more small polygons than large ones across several magnitude orders on choropleth maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;statistical-approaches-for-spatial-sample-survey-persistent-misconceptions-and-new&quot;&gt;Statistical approaches for spatial sample survey: Persistent misconceptions and new&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several misconceptions about the design-based approach for sampling and statistical inference, based on classical sampling theory, seem to be quite persistent. These misconceptions are the result of confusion about basic statistical concepts such as independence, expectation, and bias and variance of estimators or predictors. These concepts have a different meaning in the design-based and model-based approach, because they consider different sources of randomness. Also, a population mean is still often confused with a model mean, and a population variance with a model-variance, leading to invalid formulas for the variance of an estimator of the population mean. In this paper the fundamental differences between these two approaches are illustrated with simulations, so that hopefully more pedometricians get a better understanding of this subject. An overview is presented of how in the design-based approach we can make use of knowledge of the spatial structure of the study variable. In the second part, new developments in both the design-based and model-based approach are described that try to combine the strengths of the two approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;estimation-of-carbon-stocks-in-boreal-cropland-soils---methodological-considerations&quot;&gt;Estimation of carbon stocks in boreal cropland soils - methodological considerations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High expectations to harness agricultural soils as sinks for atmospheric carbon (C) necessitate methods for verifying changes in soil organic C (SOC) stocks and improving the accuracy of regional SOC stock estimates specific to various land-use and management types. In this study we used a sample set included in the Finnish national soil monitoring network (n = 125) to determine the SOC stock and its vertical distribution in Finnish agricultural mineral soils using fixed depth (FD) and equivalent soil mass (ESM) methods. Further, we explored the within-field variation in SOC stock and minimum sample size in the context of SOC sequestration. Boreal agricultural mineral soils were found to be rich in SOC. The average SOC stock ranged between 8.4 and 9.8 kg m(-2)in the top 30 cm depending on cropping system and soil type. Cultivation of perennial crops tended to enrich the C close to the soil surface in comparison to dominantly annual crops, which exhibited a less steep C gradient with depth. The commonly used van Bemmelen factor of 1.724 to convert results of loss on ignition to SOC was found to be appropriate for coarse-textured Finnish agricultural soils. However, the results showed that in clay-rich soils, it is critical to take into account the structural water bound in clay particles to avoid overestimation of the SOC content. The study also demonstrated that the minimum sample size required to detect the change of 0.1 kg C m(-2)at field level is typically several hundreds. Therefore empirical soil sampling is not at all cost-effective enough for verifying the changes in SOC stocks with regard to compensation of C sequestration for farmers. Thus, alternative verification methods, such as SOC modelling in combination with field-level data collected, for example, using remote sensing should be developed further. Highlights
Boreal agricultural mineral soils are rich in C Rotations where perennial crops dominated tended to enrich C in the soil surface Soil clay content should be taken into account when converting SOM to SOC The sample size required to verify SOC stock changes for C trading is extremely high&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;introducing-a-mechanistic-model-in-digital-soil-mapping-to-predict-soil-organic-matter-stocks-in-thecantabrianregion-spain&quot;&gt;Introducing a mechanistic model in digital soil mapping to predict soil organic matter stocks in theCantabrianregion (Spain)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital soil mapping (DSM) is an effective mapping technique that supports the increased need for quantitative soil data. In DSM, soil properties are correlated with environmental characteristics using statistical models such as regression. However, many of these relationships are explicitly described in mechanistic simulation models. Therefore, the mechanistic relationships can, in theory, replace the statistical relationships in DSM. This study aims to develop a mechanistic model to predict soil organic matter (SOM) stocks in Natura2000 areas of the Cantabria region (Spain). The mechanistic model is established in four steps: (a) identify major processes that influence SOM stocks, (b) review existing models describing the major processes and the respective environmental data that they require, (c) establish a database with the required input data, and (d) calibrate the model with field observations. The SOM stocks map resulting from the mechanistic model had a mean error (ME) of -2 t SOM ha(-1)and a root mean square error (RMSE) of 66 t SOM ha(-1). The Lin’s concordance correlation coefficient was 0.47 and the amount of variance explained (AVE) was 0.21. The results of the mechanistic model were compared to the results of a statistical model. It turned out that the correlation coefficient between the two SOM stock maps was 0.8. This study illustrated that mechanistic soil models can be used for DSM, which brings new opportunities. Mechanistic models for DSM should be considered for mapping soil characteristics that are difficult to predict by statistical models, and for extrapolation purposes. Highlights
Theoretically, mechanistic models can replace the statistical relationships in digital soil mapping. Mechanistic soil models were used to develop a mechanistic model for digital soil mapping that predicted SOM stocks. The applicability of the mechanistic approach needs to be explored for different soil properties and regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-log--barrier-approach-for-airborne-gamma-ray-spectrometry-inversion&quot;&gt;A log -barrier approach for airborne gamma-ray spectrometry inversion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The standard processing of airborne gamma-ray spectrometry (AGRS) data provides useful preliminary information to interpretation in several contexts, such as environmental studies, geological mapping, and analysis of mineral deposits. For optimal results, the acquisition conditions should be nearly constant, and the flight height should be uniform. However, abrupt changes in flight height (often originated from mountainous terrain) are common and lead to spurious variations and incorrect anomaly interpretation. Moreover, the commonly used corrections applied to radiometric data do not consider the effective sampling area of a survey, especially the overlap between successive fields of view. As a consequence, the concentrations estimates of potassium (K), uranium (eU), and thorium (eTh) are not sharp. A solution to deal with this problem is to compute the concentration from the AGRS data through an inversion algorithm. Inversion of AGRS data has shown to be an effective approach to suppress the significant overlap between successive fields of view. We introduce a logarithmic barrier approach for the radiometric inversion to avoid spurious negative values in the radioelement concentration models. We choose calibration ranges from Brazil and Canada to test the proposed methodology. We produced concentration models for K, eU and eTh and compared the standard approach model with the recovered model from both ranges. The predicted data from inversion of both calibration ranges are mostly consistent with the survey data, not over smoothing the data or fitting noise. The predicted data from inversion showed more consistency with the observed data than the one predicted from the standard procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-influence-of-rock-fragments-on-field-capacity-water-content-in-stony-soils-from-hard-sandstone-alluvium&quot;&gt;The influence of rock fragments on field capacity water content in stony soils from hard sandstone alluvium&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worldwide, rock fragments (RFs) are generally considered inert with respect to bulk soil hydraulic properties, such that all soil water retention properties predicted by national pedotransfer functions (such as S-map) are based on the volumetric fraction of the fine earth (&amp;lt;2 mm fraction) only. Research findings contradict those assumptions, but studies commonly focus on porous RFs, and rely on repacked cores and lab studies, leaving uncertainty as to how low porosity RFs characteristic of common strongly indurated lithologies affect soil in the field. We address this question by examining soil water storage in 52 pits excavated into stony soils on the Canterbury Plains, New Zealand, which are formed in sediment derived from a Mesozoic hard sandstone. The soils at each site were watered to saturation, and then after two days of drainage (a proxy for field capacity), a 30 x 30 cm pit was excavated in 10 cm increments to a depth of 60 cm. From each increment, soil samples were collected and analysed to determine the volumetric size distribution of RFs, the water content of the fine earth and the water content of the RFs themselves. Our results indicated that RFs could influence the fine earth bulk density, porosity, and soil chemistry. RFs could also retain water: 2-20 mm RFs (0.07 m(3) m(-3)) retained twice as much water as &amp;gt;20 mm RFs (0.03 m(3) m(-3)). The water retention of the hard sandstone was low compared to other lithologies, but the volumetric abundance of RFs in the stony soils we sampled meant that they accounted for similar to 10% of the water retained to a depth of 60 cm at field capacity. Our results demonstrate that similar to 13 mm of water retained by RFs at field capacity is not currently considered in water budgets and nutrient leaching predictions, which may be relevant to best practice land management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-quality-and-grain-yield-a-win-win-combination-in-clayey-tropical-oxisols&quot;&gt;Soil quality and grain yield: A win-win combination in clayey tropical oxisols&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relationships between a soil quality index (SQI(FERTBIO)) and soil functions with both relative cumulative grain yields (RCY) and soil organic carbon (SOC), were evaluated in a tropical clayey Cerrado Oxisol. Soil quality (SQ) was quantified integrating chemical (FERT) and biological (BIO) indicators in a weighted-additive soil quality index combining three soil functions and respective indicators: (F1) nutrient cycling (based on the activities of soil enzymes beta-glucosidase and arylsulfatase), (F2) nutrient storage (SOC and cation exchange capacity, CEC) and (F3) nutrient supply (Ca+2, Mg+2, K+, P, pH, H + Al; Al+3, sum of bases (SB) and base saturation (%BS)). The contribution of each indicator for the related soil function was scored using standardized scoring functions (SSF) that transform the indicator value on a scale between 0 and 1. Soil samples (0 to 10 cm depth) were collected in 2013 and 2015 from 21 treatments from three long-term field experiments, with different P fertilizer management strategies. P-fertilization resulted in higher cumulative crop yields that in turn were associated with better SQI(FERTBIO) and soil functions scores. Through linear regression analyses, critical limits (CLs) to interpret the individual scores of the SQI and of the soil functions, based on RCY and SOC were defined. The proposed SQI was positively associated with RCY (p &amp;lt; 0,001; R-2 = 0,95) and SOC (p &amp;lt; 0,001; R-2 = 0,88). Similar significant relationships were found between the three soil functions and RCY or SOC. Overall, the lower and upper limits of the interpretative classes for the SQI(FERTBIO) and soil functions scores (where the index scores are equivalent, respectively, to 40% and 80% of the optimal RCY or SOC) were 0.42 and 0.64. The combination of chemical and biological indicators in different soil functions and in the SQI(FERTBIO) proved to be a simple and useful strategy to assess SQ in tropical Oxisols, linking agronomic management practices to both SQ, yield benefits and SOC. These results will help extensionists, agronomists and soil scientists, when assisting farmers, in soil health assessments, by making easier to explain the importance of SQ for the economic performance of farms.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/03/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on March 28, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/03/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/03/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-03-14T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-03-14T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-7&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A TDR wireless device for volumetric water content sensing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ecotrons: Powerful and versatile ecosystem analysers for ecology, agronomy and environmental science&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Age and origin of the Cumberland (Inner Sydney) Basin of southeast Australia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uncertainty analysis of eleven multisource soil moisture products in the third pole environment based on the three-corned hat method&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A D-vine copula quantile regression approach for soil moisture retrieval from dual polarimetric SAR Sentinel-1 over vegetated terrains&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-tdr-wireless-device-for-volumetric-water-content-sensing&quot;&gt;A TDR wireless device for volumetric water content sensing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time Domain Reflectometry (TDR) is a widely used technique to estimate the soil volumetric water content (theta) and bulk electrical conductivity (sigma). This paper presents TDR-WiFi, a wireless, portable and low cost interface to ease sensing of theta and sigma by connecting TDR cable tester with a smartphone. TDR-WiFi consists of a microprocessor equipped with a WiFi microcontroller (M5Stack unit) and connected to the TDR device through an RS232-TTL adapter. The M5stack firmware is programmed in MicroPython language to act as a server between the user and the TDR device through a web page accessible from any smartphone web browser. TDR-WiFi is compatible with the Campbell TDR100 device and allows storing the TDR waveforms as well as estimating theta and sigma. A complementary web page for subsequent analysis of the TDR waveforms was developed and is publicly available at http://swi.csic.es/tdrwifi/. The system was satisfactorily demonstrated in laboratory and tested in the field. The field trial allowed water content measurements in a steep road slope. TDR-WiFi demonstrated to be operative in the field and it can be satisfactorily used in difficult access areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ecotrons-powerful-and-versatile-ecosystem-analysers-for-ecology-agronomy-and-environmental-science&quot;&gt;Ecotrons: Powerful and versatile ecosystem analysers for ecology, agronomy and environmental science&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ecosystems integrity and services are threatened by anthropogenic global changes. Mitigating and adapting to these changes require knowledge of ecosystem functioning in the expected novel environments, informed in large part through experimentation and modelling. This paper describes 13 advanced controlled environment facilities for experimental ecosystem studies, herein termed ecotrons, open to the international community. Ecotrons enable simulation of a wide range of natural environmental conditions in replicated and independent experimental units while measuring various ecosystem processes. This capacity to realistically control ecosystem environments is used to emulate a variety of climatic scenarios and soil conditions, in natural sunlight or through broad-spectrum lighting. The use of large ecosystem samples, intact or reconstructed, minimizes border effects and increases biological and physical complexity. Measurements of concentrations of greenhouse trace gases as well as their net exchange between the ecosystem and the atmosphere are performed in most ecotrons, often quasi continuously. The flow of matter is often tracked with the use of stable isotope tracers of carbon and other elements. Equipment is available for measurements of soil water status as well as root and canopy growth. The experiments ran so far emphasize the diversity of the hosted research. Half of them concern global changes, often with a manipulation of more than one driver. About a quarter deal with the impact of biodiversity loss on ecosystem functioning and one quarter with ecosystem or plant physiology. We discuss how the methodology for environmental simulation and process measurements, especially in soil, can be improved and stress the need to establish stronger links with modelling in future projects. These developments will enable further improvements in mechanistic understanding and predictive capacity of ecotron research which will play, in complementarity with field experimentation and monitoring, a crucial role in exploring the ecosystem consequences of environmental changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;age-and-origin-of-the-cumberland-inner-sydney-basin-of-southeast-australia&quot;&gt;Age and origin of the Cumberland (Inner Sydney) Basin of southeast Australia&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Cumberland Basin is a structural and topographic low within the sedimentary Sydney Basin of southeast Australia. To the west, the Blue Mountains Plateau was uplifted along the north-south Lapstone Structural Complex after around 90 Ma, with uplift largely completed by middle Miocene to Pliocene times. To the north, upwarping of the Hornsby Plateau preceded the major phase of movement along the Lapstone Structural Complex. To the south, the topography of the Cumberland Basin is closely related to the form of the Camden Syncline. This appears to have been active in the late Permian-Middle Triassic. The western limb of the syncline is truncated by the north-south Lapstone Structural Complex. The southern part of the Cumberland Basin must therefore have taken on its modern form prior to the movements that gave rise to its western margin. The eastern side of the Cumberland Basin forms a broad depression open to the sea. This may be a graben-like structure developed along the Lachlan Transverse Zone. The Botany Basin, which may have begun subsiding at least as far back as the Oligocene, lies within this feature, suggesting that this part of the Cumberland Basin may have already been in existence at this stage. Within the broader Cumberland Basin, the Penrith and Botany basins appear to have begun subsiding early in the Cenozoic, accumulating complex and interrupted records of alluvial sediments in the former and eolian, shallow marine and alluvial sediments in the latter. Over this period, the Penrith and Botany basins seem to have acted as the focus of drainage across the Cumberland Basin, explaining the enigmatic pattern of rivers across the region. The Cumberland Basin’s margins thus formed in different ways and at different times, with the margin-forming processes perhaps associated with the volcanicity and tectonic movements accompanying the uplift of Australia’s Eastern Highlands in the period 80-10 Ma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;uncertainty-analysis-of-eleven-multisource-soil-moisture-products-in-the-third-pole-environment-based-on-the-three-corned-hat-method&quot;&gt;Uncertainty analysis of eleven multisource soil moisture products in the third pole environment based on the three-corned hat method&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil moisture (SM) is a fundamental environmental variable for characterizing climate, land surface and atmosphere. In recent years, several SM products have been developed based on remote sensing (RS), land surface model (LSM) or land data assimilation system (LDAS). However, little knowledge is available in understanding spatial patterns of the uncertainty of different SM products and potential regional drivers over the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau (QTP), a complex environment for accurate SM estimation. This paper investigates the sensitivity of the SM uncertainties based on the three-cornered hat (TCH) method and a generalized additive model (GAM) in terms of underlying surface characteristics (sand fraction, soil organic matter, vegetation, land surface temperature, and topography) and near-ground meteorology (precipitation and air temperature) in the third pole environment over the 2015-2018 period. Eleven SM products are involved in this work, including Soil Moisture Active Passive (SMAP), Soil Moisture Ocean Salinity INRA-CESBIO (SMOS-IC), Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency (JAXA), Land Surface Parameter Model (LPRM), Climate Change Initiative - Active/Combined (CCI_A/CCI_C), Global Land Data Assimilation System (GLDAS), European Centre for Medium-Range Weather Forecasts Interim reanalysis (ERA-Interim), Global Land Evaporation Amsterdam Model product a/b (GLEAM_a/GLEAM_b), and Random Forest Soil Moisture (RFSM). Results show that most of the SM products perform well across QTP, while SMOS-IC is strongly affected by radio-frequency interference in this region, JAXA has a relatively higher noise level over QTP, and LPRM has larger relative uncertainties (RUs) in the southeast of QTP. Nonlinear regression analysis demonstrates that variations of RUs in SMOS-IC and JAXA are driven by topography, while LPRM’s are mainly controlled by vegetation. In addition, two groups of opposite (positive/negative) effects from topography and vegetation, topography and precipitation, and precipitation and land surface temperature affect the spatial variations of RUs in CCI_A, RFSM, and ERA-Interim, respectively. Meanwhile, more complex relationships are found between multiple surface factors and RUs of different products. In general, the underlying surface factors explain on average 39.41% and 28.34% of the variations in RS and LSM/LDAS SM RUs, respectively. Comparatively, the near-ground meteorology factors have a slightly larger effect on LSM/LDAS products than that on RS products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-d-vine-copula-quantile-regression-approach-for-soil-moisture-retrieval-from-dual-polarimetric-sar-sentinel-1-over-vegetated-terrains&quot;&gt;A D-vine copula quantile regression approach for soil moisture retrieval from dual polarimetric SAR Sentinel-1 over vegetated terrains&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil moisture retrieval from Synthetic Aperture Radar (SAR) over vegetated terrains requires an isolation of soil and canopy signals from observed backscatter (sigma degrees). This study develops a probabilistic soil moisture retrieval method from dual polarimetric C-band SAR Sentinel-1 (S-1) with uncertainty quantification at distinct vegetation covers (VCs). Both sigma(VV)degrees and sigma(VH)degrees were used to represent ground and volume scattering due to the high respective sensitivity to soil moisture and vegetation dynamics. A novel D-vine copula quantile regression (DVQR) was adopted to provide the soil moisture estimates based on modelling trivariate dependence of sigma(VV)degrees-sigma(VH)degrees -soil moisture anomalies (VV-VH-Mv), with a support from the innovative cosmic-ray soil moisture as ground-truth data. The feasibility of DVQR was underlined for: (1) multivariate nonlinear dependence structure modelling and (2) soil moisture retrieval with associated uncertainty. An inter-dependence analysis, which assesses the correlations among three major variables, indicated that the dependence between each pair of variables decreased as canopy density increases from herbs to forests, mainly due to the ci degrees attenuated by vegetation effect. The dependence structures simulated from the D-vine copula revealed highly nonlinear and asymmetric shapes with tail dependences occurred in most VCs, which can be well captured by different associated Archimedean copulas. Soil moisture anomaly (Mv) estimated using the DVQR and Multiple linear quantile regression (MLQR) were compared against ground-truth data for both in-sample and out-of-sample predictions. Superior performances of the DVQR in most VCs, with 10% and 16% improved in RMSE at grasslands and broadleaf forests, respectively, demonstrated the robustness of this method for S-1 soil moisture retrieval due to the highly nonlinear dependence structures captured by the D-vine models. Over VCs, better performances were obtained at low-canopy herbaceous regions (grasslands and croplands); whereas extremely dry conditions and complex structures in shrublands and dense forests resulted in inferior performances. A sensitivity analysis was then conducted to evaluate the change in My estimation accuracy given distinct VV and VH quantile levels. Result underlines that VV is the primary factor controlling the retrieval accuracy, but the increase in VH level also contributes to higher errors in soil moisture estimation, especially under wet conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/03/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on March 14, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/03/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/03/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-03-11T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-03-11T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-6&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Three different Fourier-transform mid-infrared sampling techniques to characterize bio-organic samples&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modeling of phosphorus loss from field to watershed: A review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Global Research Alliance N2O chamber methodology guidelines: Introduction, with health and safety considerations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drivers of regional soil water storage memory and persistence&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A profile shape correction to reduce the vertical sensitivity of cosmic-ray neutron sensing of soil moisture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimating coefficient of linear extensibility using Vis-NIR reflectance spectral data: Comparison of model validation approaches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;three-different-fourier-transform-mid-infrared-sampling-techniques-to-characterize-bio-organic-samples&quot;&gt;Three different Fourier-transform mid-infrared sampling techniques to characterize bio-organic samples&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent years, there has been a surge in the number of applications of Fourier-transform mid-infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy for the characterization of environmental samples and prediction of some of their properties whose measurement has traditionally involved time-consuming and costly methods. However, there are several different mid-infrared techniques available, and there is a gap in knowledge regarding the best-suited technique for recording informative spectra of different types of environmental samples. This study compared the three most widespread FTIR techniques using solid and liquid samples. A total of 11 environmental samples belonging to four categories were analyzed with attenuated total reflectance (ATR), photoacoustic (PAS), and diffuse reflectance (DR) FTIR spectroscopy. Overall, PAS-FTIR was the best technique, providing a greater amount of information, especially for opaque samples (i.e., organic waste, biochar, and soil), than ATR-FTIR and DR-FTIR spectroscopy. Attenuated total reflectance FTIR provided the best spectra for soft samples, such as plant materials, probably due to their ability to achieve good optical contact with the ATR crystal. Finally, DR-FTIR performed relatively well for most samples but was found to be more sensitive to moisture in the samples, resulting in noise in specific areas, and was less sensitive in bond vibrations related to Si.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;modeling-of-phosphorus-loss-from-field-to-watershed-a-review&quot;&gt;Modeling of phosphorus loss from field to watershed: A review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract
Phosphorus (P) losses from nonpoint sources into surface water resources through surface runoff and tile drainage play a significant role in eutrophication. Accordingly, the number of studies involving the modeling of agricultural P losses, the uncertainties of such models, and the best management practices (BMPs) supported by the modeling of hypothetical P loss reduction scenarios has increased significantly around the world. Many improvements have been made to these models: separate manure P pools, variable source areas allowing the determination of critical source areas of P loss, analyses of modeling uncertainties, and understanding of legacy P. However, several elements are still missing or have yet to be sufficiently addressed: the incorporation of preferential flow into models, the modification of P sorption-desorption processes considering recent research data (e.g., pedotransfer functions for labile, active, or stable P, along with P sorption coefficients), BMP parameterization, and scale-up issues, as well as stakeholder-scientist and experimentalist-modeler interactions. The accuracy of P loss modeling can be improved by (a) incorporating dynamic P sorption-desorption processes and new P subroutines for direct P loss from manure, fertilizer, and dung, (b) modeling preferential flow, connectivity between field and adjacent water bodies, and P in-stream processes, (c) including an assessment of model uncertainty, (d) integrating field and watershed models for BMP calibration and scaling field results up to larger areas, and (e) building a holistic interaction between stakeholders, experimentalists, and modelers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;global-research-alliance-n2o-chamber-methodology-guidelines-introduction-with-health-and-safety-considerations&quot;&gt;Global Research Alliance N2O chamber methodology guidelines: Introduction, with health and safety considerations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Non-steady-state (NSS) chamber techniques have been used for decades to measure nitrous oxide (N2O) fluxes from agricultural soils. These techniques are widely used because they are relatively inexpensive, easy to adopt, versatile, and adaptable to varying conditions. Much of our current understanding of the drivers of N2O emissions is based on studies using NSS chambers. These chamber techniques require decisions regarding multiplemethodological aspects (e.g., chamber materials and geometry, deployment, sample analysis, and data and statistical analysis), each of which may significantly affect the results. Variation in methodological details can lead to challenges in comparing results between studies and assessment of reliability and uncertainty. Therefore, the New Zealand Government, in support of the objectives of the Livestock Research Group of the Global Research Alliance on Agricultural Greenhouse Gases (GRA), funded two international projects to, first, develop standardized guidelines on the use of NSS chamber techniques and, second, refine them based on the most up to date knowledge and methods. This introductory paper summarizes a collection of papers that represent the revised guidelines. Each article summarizes existing knowledge and provides guidance and minimum requirements on chamber design, deployment, sample collection, storage and analysis, automated chambers, flux calculations, statistical analysis, emission factor estimation and data reporting, modeling, and “gap-filling” approaches. The minimum requirements are not meant to be highly prescriptive but instead provide researchers with clear direction on best practices and factors that need to be considered. Health and safety considerations of NSS chamber techniques are also provided with this introductory paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;drivers-of-regional-soil-water-storage-memory-and-persistence&quot;&gt;Drivers of regional soil water storage memory and persistence&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil water storage dynamics link landscape and climate processes with consequent impacts on hydrologic and biogeochemical cycles, and on ecosystem functions. We explore regional-scale, spatiotemporal dynamics of root-zone soil water storage using spatially explicit, long-term simulations from a land data assimilation system over an area of similar to 2 million km(2) in the U.S. Midwest. We synthesize the dataset to examine spatial patterns of hydroclimatic forcing and soil and vegetation properties to identify the key drivers of soil water storage across the region. To identify differences in temporal hydrologic variability between sites with different soil and vegetation characteristics, we focus on daily data from 10 locations, representative of three major land cover types in the region. We use the concepts of (a) soil water memory to evaluate differences in landscape buffering of rainfall and (b) persistence to evaluate the threshold-crossing properties of statistically defined “wet” and “dry” soil water conditions. Power spectral analyses of soil water storage reveal that regionally consistent patterns emerge in memory at multiple temporal scales. Threshold-crossing analyses reveal corresponding similarity in persistence between sites. The analyses show that stochastic rainfall is the key driver of landscape hydrologic dynamics, with rainfall frequency as the primary determinant of persistence across the region, whereas differences in land cover and soil properties across the region have second-order influence. The synthesis approach we present here is useful for ecological and agricultural risk assessments of climate change impacts, including increasing frequency of extreme events such as droughts and floods, but primarily points to the need for better understanding of future precipitation changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-profile-shape-correction-to-reduce-the-vertical-sensitivity-of-cosmic-ray-neutron-sensing-of-soil-moisture&quot;&gt;A profile shape correction to reduce the vertical sensitivity of cosmic-ray neutron sensing of soil moisture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent years, cosmic-ray neutron sensing (CRNS) has shown a large potential among proximal sensing techniques to monitor soil moisture noninvasively, with high frequency and a large support volume (radius up to 240 m and sensing depth up to 80 cm). This signal is, however, more sensitive to closer distances and shallower depths. Inherently, CRNS-derived soil moisture is a spatially weighted value, different from an average soil moisture as retrieved by a sensor network. In this study, we systematically test a new profile shape correction on CRNS-derived soil moisture, based on additional soil moisture profile measurements and vertical unweighting, which is especially relevant during pronounced wetting or drying fronts. The analyses are conducted with data collected at four contrasting field sites, each equipped with a CRNS probe and a distributed soil moisture sensor network. After applying the profile shape correction on CRNS-derived soil moisture, it is compared with the sensor network average. Results show that the influence of the vertical sensitivity of CRNS on integral soil moisture values is successfully reduced. One to three properly located profile measurements within the CRNS support volume improve the performance. For the four investigated field sites, the RMSE decreased 11-53% when only one profile location was considered. We therefore recommend to install along with a CRNS at least one soil moisture profile in a radial distance &amp;lt;100 m and a measurement depth down to 50 cm. Profile-shape-corrected, CRNS-derived soil moisture is an unweighted integral soil moisture over the support volume, which is easier to interpret and easier to use for further applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;estimating-coefficient-of-linear-extensibility-using-vis-nir-reflectance-spectral-data-comparison-of-model-validation-approaches&quot;&gt;Estimating coefficient of linear extensibility using Vis-NIR reflectance spectral data: Comparison of model validation approaches&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coefficient of linear extensibility (COLE) is used to classify soils according to their swell-shrink potential, and its estimation is crucial for engineering and agronomic applications. The aims of the study were (a) to develop a visible-near-infrared spectroscopy (Vis-NIRS, 400-2,500 nm) calibration model to estimate COLE, (b) to compare two model validation approaches (mixed data and country-wise), and (c) to test if a variable selection method improves the estimation accuracy of the calibration models. For this purpose, partial least square regression (PLSR) was used on the spectra of 53 soil samples from Slovakia and 24 samples from the United States. First, a calibration model based on 70% of the entire dataset (including samples from both locations) was developed and validated with the remaining 30% (mixed data approach). Second, a calibration model based on the Slovakian samples was validated with the U.S. samples (country-wise approach). Higher predictability for COLE with standardized root mean square error (SMRSE) of 0.099 was obtained for the mixed data approach than for the country-wise validation with SRMSE of 0.279. Furthermore, using interval PLSR (iPLSR) as a variable selection method did not improve the estimation accuracy of the mixed data approach (SRMSE of 0.099), and rather resulted in a twofold increase in SRMSE (0.560) for the country-wise validation approach. Overall, the good estimation of COLE from Vis-NIRS was attributed to the high correlation of COLE with clay content and spectrally active clay minerals.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/03/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on March 11, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/03/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/03/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-03-01T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-03-01T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-5&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prediction of available phosphorus in soil: Combined use for crop production and water quality protection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Predicting total petroleum hydrocarbons in field soils with Vis-NIR models developed on laboratory-constructed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Selecting soil properties for assessment of soil aggregation using principal component and clustering analyses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modified self-adaptive model for improving the prediction accuracy of soil organic matter by laser-induced breakdown spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prediction-of-available-phosphorus-in-soil-combined-use-for-crop-production-and-water-quality-protection&quot;&gt;Prediction of available phosphorus in soil: Combined use for crop production and water quality protection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Optimizing phosphorus (P) application to agricultural soils is fundamental to crop production and water quality protection. We sought to relate soil P tests and P sorption characteristics to both crop yield response to P application and environmentally critical soil P status. Barley (Hordeum vulgare L.) was grown in pot experiments with 45 soils of different P status. Half the pots were fertilized at 20 kg P ha(-1), and half received no P. Soils were extracted with ammonium lactate, sodium bicarbonate (Olsen P), dilute salt (0.0025 M CaCl2), and diffusive gradient in thin films. Soil adsorption coefficients were determined using the Freundlich isotherm equation, and the degree of P saturation was determined from both oxalate and ammonium lactate extracted Fe, Al, and P. All soil P analyses showed a nonlinear and significant relationship with yield response to P application, and all analyses manifested a threshold value above which no P response was observed. For the commonly used ammonium lactate test, inclusion of Al and Fe improved prediction of plant-available soil P. The threshold for yield response coincided with the environmentally critical values determined from the degree of P saturation. Results support the conclusion that soil P levels for which no P application is needed also have elevated risk of P loss to runoff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;predicting-total-petroleum-hydrocarbons-in-field-soils-with-vis-nir-models-developed-on-laboratory-constructed&quot;&gt;Predicting total petroleum hydrocarbons in field soils with Vis-NIR models developed on laboratory-constructed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accurate quantification of petroleum hydrocarbons (PHCs) is required for optimizing remedial efforts at oil spill sites. While evaluating total petroleum hydrocarbons (TPH) in soils is often conducted using costly and time-consuming laboratory methods, visible and near-infrared reflectance spectroscopy (Vis-NIR) has been proven to be a rapid and cost-effective field-based method for soil TPH quantification. This study investigated whether Vis-NIR models calibrated from laboratory-constructed PHC soil samples could be used to accurately estimate TPH concentration of field samples. To evaluate this, a laboratory sample set was constructed by mixing crude oil with uncontaminated soil samples, and two field sample sets (F1 and F2) were collected from three PHC-impacted sites. The Vis-NIR TPH models were calibrated with four different techniques (partial least squares regression, random forest, artificial neural network, and support vector regression), and two model improvement methods (spiking and spiking with extra weight) were compared. Results showed that laboratory-based Vis-NIR models could predict TPH in field sample set F1 with moderate accuracy (R-2 &amp;gt; .53) but failed to predict TPH in field sample set F2 (R-2 &amp;lt; .13). Both spiking and spiking with extra weight improved the prediction of TPH in both field sample sets (R-2 ranged from .63 to.88, respectively); the improvement was most pronounced for F2. This study suggests that Vis-NIR models developed from laboratory-constructed PHC soil samples, spiked by a small number of field sample analyses, can be used to estimate TPH concentrations more efficiently and cost effectively compared with generating site-specific calibrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;selecting-soil-properties-for-assessment-of-soil-aggregation-using-principal-component-and-clustering-analyses&quot;&gt;Selecting soil properties for assessment of soil aggregation using principal component and clustering analyses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aggregation is an important factor among physical soil parameters and affects soil quality. In this study, some soil physical (field capacity, wilting point and sand, silt and clay contents), chemical (pH, electrical conductivity, CaCO3, organic matter and exchangeable Na, Ca, Mg and K) and biological properties (CO2 from respiration and urease, dehydrogenase, beta-glucosidase, alkaline phosphatase and acid phosphatase activities) were examined. Some of these properties were eliminated by principal component and clustering analyses to create a minimum dataset. Correlations were evaluated between selected properties and the percentage aggregation of micro (&amp;lt;0.25 mm) and macro aggregates (0.25-4 mm). Sand, Mg, pH, organic matter, urease, dehydrogenase, alkaline phosphatase and beta-glucosidase properties were selected after principal component and clustering analyses. The highest correlation was between the percentage of micro aggregation and urease activity (0.545, P &amp;lt; 0.01). For macro aggregates, the highest correlation was with organic material (0.560, P &amp;lt; 0.01). A negative correlation was observed between macro aggregation percentage and sand content (-0.410, P &amp;lt; 0.01), with a similar relationship for micro aggregation and sand content (-0.450, P &amp;lt; 0.01), but there were positive relationships with other properties. The exchangeable magnesium content showed similar relationships for both aggregate sizes (0.430 and 0.440, P &amp;lt; 0.01). The correlations of aggregation with other enzymes and pH were nonsignificant (P &amp;gt; 0.05). In general, the highest correlation for micro aggregation was with enzyme activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;modified-self-adaptive-model-for-improving-the-prediction-accuracy-of-soil-organic-matter-by-laser-induced-breakdown-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Modified self-adaptive model for improving the prediction accuracy of soil organic matter by laser-induced breakdown spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil organic matter (SOM) significantly influences soil fertility, biology, and the global C cycle. Laser-induced breakdown spectroscopy (LIBS) is attractive, as it can measure SOM accurately and quickly with minimal sample preparation and effective cost. Our earlier self-adaptive (SA) model based on individual distances between LIBS soil spectra coupled with partial least squares (PLS) was favorable for SOM prediction. To optimize this model by including soil identification via the use of a hybrid distance between the spectra, two hybrid distance SA models to enhance SOM predictions from LIBS spectra in 250 Chinese topsoils were built and studied. The models used LIBS soil spectra and SOM content measured by the traditional potassium dichromate oxidation method for calibration. The performance of these models for the validation set was compared with the conventional no-identification PLS model and SA-PLS models. The modified models that used (a) a hybrid of Euclidean distance (ED) and angle cosine (SA(xc)-PLS), and (b) a hybrid of ED and the distance of response y (SA(xy)-PLS) improved SOM predictions , with a R-2 of 0.908, a RMSE of 5.65 g kg(-1), and a residual prediction deviation (RPD) of 2.91 in the validation set for SA(xc)-PLS; and a R-2 of 0.900, a RMSE of 5.49 g kg(-1), and a RPD of 2.99 in the validation set for SA(xy)-PLS. The improved performance mainly resulted from simultaneous consideration of diversity and correlation of the spectra. Therefore, modified SA models hold great potential for SOM prediction, especially for different soils.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/03/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on March 01, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/02/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/02/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-02-16T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-02-22T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-4&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prediction of available phosphorus in soil: Combined use for crop production and water quality protection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Life cycle assessment of wheat production and wheat-based crop rotations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quantifying organic carbon stocks using a stereological profile imaging method to account for rock fragments in stony soils&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How many sampling points are needed to estimate the mean nitrate-N content of agricultural fields? A geostatistical simulation approach with uncertain variograms&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Downscaling digital soil maps using electromagnetic induction and aerial imagery&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In-situ and triple-collocation based evaluations of eight global root zone soil moisture products&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conceptual Links between Landscape Diversity and Diet Diversity: A Roadmap for Transdisciplinary Research&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perspectives on validation in digital soil mapping of continuous attributes-A review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Objective functions from Bayesian optimization to locate additional drillholes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prediction-of-available-phosphorus-in-soil-combined-use-for-crop-production-and-water-quality-protection&quot;&gt;Prediction of available phosphorus in soil: Combined use for crop production and water quality protection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Optimizing phosphorus (P) application to agricultural soils is fundamental to crop production and water quality protection. We sought to relate soil P tests and P sorption characteristics to both crop yield response to P application and environmentally critical soil P status. Barley (Hordeum vulgare L.) was grown in pot experiments with 45 soils of different P status. Half the pots were fertilized at 20 kg P ha(-1), and half received no P. Soils were extracted with ammonium lactate, sodium bicarbonate (Olsen P), dilute salt (0.0025 M CaCl2), and diffusive gradient in thin films. Soil adsorption coefficients were determined using the Freundlich isotherm equation, and the degree of P saturation was determined from both oxalate and ammonium lactate extracted Fe, Al, and P. All soil P analyses showed a nonlinear and significant relationship with yield response to P application, and all analyses manifested a threshold value above which no P response was observed. For the commonly used ammonium lactate test, inclusion of Al and Fe improved prediction of plant-available soil P. The threshold for yield response coincided with the environmentally critical values determined from the degree of P saturation. Results support the conclusion that soil P levels for which no P application is needed also have elevated risk of P loss to runoff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;life-cycle-assessment-of-wheat-production-and-wheat-based-crop-rotations&quot;&gt;Life cycle assessment of wheat production and wheat-based crop rotations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
In the northern Great Plains (NGP), wheat is the primary grain commodity. There is a need for the NGP to have a detailed analysis of environmental impacts for wheat-based agricultural production systems to better understand regional agroecosystems. This article provides a cradle-to-field gate life cycle assessment (LCA) for NGP dryland wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) production. The environmental impacts for winter wheat production using crop rotation and agricultural intensification are quantified. Fourteen no-till crop rotations ranging in duration from 2 to 6 yr were evaluated and compared using data from a historical 13-yr replicated rotation study (&amp;gt;300 observations). Midpoint LCA categories chosen for this comparison are energy, agricultural land use, climate change potential, freshwater eutrophication, and freshwater ecotoxicity due to their direct links with agricultural management practices. The NGP farmers commonly use a fallow period every other year due to moisture limitations. This specific agricultural practice and allocations within rotations are critical considerations within agricultural LCAs. Two aspects of fallow considerations and a sensitivity analysis were also performed. The allocated midpoint impacts between crops in rotational studies averaged 0.31, 0.79, 0.62, and 0.63 kg CO2 eq. per unit of winter wheat when energy, economic, mass, and cereal unit allocations were used, respectively. Economic analysis of the studied experimental crop was performed; results demonstrated that crop insurance policies improved diversification economics by 20%. Agricultural diversification benefits and burdens were better represented by endpoint damage assessments than by midpoint impact analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quantifying-organic-carbon-stocks-using-a-stereological-profile-imaging-method-to-account-for-rock-fragments-in-stony-soils&quot;&gt;Quantifying organic carbon stocks using a stereological profile imaging method to account for rock fragments in stony soils&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accounting for soil organic carbon (SOC) in stony soils is critical for estimating global SOC stocks. However, accurate and cost-effective assessments of SOC stocks in stony soil profiles remain challenging due to the difficulties in accurately determining the rock fragment volume. The objective of this study was to develop a stereological profile imaging method for rock fragment volume fraction estimation and SOC stock assessment in stony soil profiles. Three soil profiles with different rock fragment lithologies, concentrations, and distributions were imaged and quantitatively sampled. The stereological profile imaging method reproduced consistent estimation of the 3-dimensional rock fragment number density distribution and volume fraction compared to the direct measurement. The SOC stocks of the three stony profiles estimated by visual estimation, profile imaging, and stereological profile imaging methods were also assessed and compared to direct measurement. The average difference in total SOC stock between direct measurement and visual estimation, profile imaging, and stereological profile imaging methods was 0.32, 0.17, and 0.09 kg m(-2), respectively. The total profile (0-100 cm) SOC stock for profile 2 differed among the visual estimation and profile imaging methods, but estimated SOC stock from the proposed method did not differ from direct measurement for the three profiles. Results also showed that the differences in SOC stock assessment between rock fragment estimation methods increased with rock fragment concentration. The proposed method was less affected by rock fragment concentration and was more stable compared to the visual and profile imaging methods. The stereological profile imaging method was demonstrated to be a reasonably accurate method for the quantification of rock fragment number density distribution, volume fraction, and SOC stock in stony soil profiles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-many-sampling-points-are-needed-to-estimate-the-mean-nitrate-n-content-of-agricultural-fields-a-geostatistical-simulation-approach-with-uncertain-variograms&quot;&gt;How many sampling points are needed to estimate the mean nitrate-N content of agricultural fields? A geostatistical simulation approach with uncertain variograms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowledge of how many sampling points are needed to estimate the mean content of soil nutrients in agricultural fields, given a precision requirement on the estimated mean, is limited. This paper describes a versatile geo-statistical simulation approach for predicting the variance of the mean nitrate-N (NO3-N) content within an agricultural field estimated by random sampling. In fall of 2016 sixteen agricultural fields were sampled on a square grid to model the spatial variation of NO3-N. On twelve out of sixteen fields NO3-N showed a lognormal distribution rather than a normal distribution. Variograms for (log-transformed) NO3-N are estimated using a Bayesian approach, resulting in 100 vectors with possible variogram parameters per field, obtained by MCMC sampling from the posterior distribution. Each of these variograms is used to simulate 100 maps of NO3-N, resulting in 100 x 100 maps of NO3-N per field. Each map is used to compute the variance of the estimated mean with stratified simple random sampling of 5,10, …, 50 points, with one point per compact geographical stratum. For each sample size (number of sampling points) the mean, median and P90 of the uncertainty distribution are computed. Based on the medians, the sample size required for a maximum expanded measurement uncertainty of 50% varies from &amp;lt; 5 to &amp;gt; 50. This large variation in required sample size shows the large variation among the sixteen fields in variance of NO3-N within a field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;downscaling-digital-soil-maps-using-electromagnetic-induction-and-aerial-imagery&quot;&gt;Downscaling digital soil maps using electromagnetic induction and aerial imagery&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coarse-resolution soil maps at regional to national extents are often inappropriate for mapping intra-field variability. At the same time, sensor data, such as electromagnetic induction measurements and aerial imagery, can be highly useful for mapping soil properties that correlate with electrical conductivity or soil color. However, maps based on these data nearly always require calibration with local samples, as multiple factors can affect the sensor measurements. In this study, we present a downscaling method, which combines coarse-resolution, large extent soil maps with sensor data in order to improve predictions of soil properties. The method modifies values from coarse-resolution soil maps to predict soil properties at a location, using relationships between soil properties and sensor data from other locations. We test this method for predicting clay and soil organic matter contents at five agricultural fields located in Denmark. We test the method for one field at a time, using soil samples from the four other fields to predict soil properties. The maps produced with the method are generally more accurate than the coarse-resolution soil maps, especially for soil organic matter. The method generally overestimates prediction uncertainties, a disadvantage, which will require improvements. Overall, the method is a simple, promising tool for giving a quantitative estimate of soil properties, when no local soil samples are available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-situ-and-triple-collocation-based-evaluations-of-eight-global-root-zone-soil-moisture-products&quot;&gt;In-situ and triple-collocation based evaluations of eight global root zone soil moisture products&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Root zone soil moisture (RZSM) is a vital variable for vegetation growth, drought monitoring and agricultural water management. Satellite remote sensing measures soil moisture at the surface layer, while RZSM is derived usually by model-based simulations. Here, we provide the first comprehensive evaluation of eight RZSM products at a global scale, including GLDAS NOAH, ERA-5, MERRA-2, NCEP R1, NCEP R2, JRA-55, SMAP level 4 and SMOS level 4 datasets. An in-situ validation based on the stations from the International Soil Moisture Network (ISMN) and a triple collocation (TC) evaluation are both conducted to assess the accuracy of these RZSM products. SMAP exhibits the median highest correlation and the median lowest RMSE with in-situ stations over North America. In the TC analysis, MERRA-2 shows the highest median correlation and the median lowest error standard deviation with the unknown truth, followed by GLDAS, SMAP, JRA-55 and ERA-5. A temporal pattern analysis indicates that SMOS has a dry bias relative to other datasets and NCEP R1 has larger seasonal variations relative to other datasets over Asia and North America. The TC analysis indicates that MERRA-2, SMAP, GLDAS, JRA-55, and ERA-5 have better performance relative to other datasets. SMAP is not as good as GLDAS, MERRA-2 and JRA-55 in RZSM estimation over forest areas. The possible factors influencing RZSM performance are discussed, including precipitation forcing, assimilated observations, radio frequency interference issue and validation methods. These results and conclusions may provide new insights for the improvement of model-based RZSM estimation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conceptual-links-between-landscape-diversity-and-diet-diversity-a-roadmap-for-transdisciplinary-research&quot;&gt;Conceptual Links between Landscape Diversity and Diet Diversity: A Roadmap for Transdisciplinary Research&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Malnutrition linked to poor quality diets affects at least 2 billion people. Forests, as well as agricultural systems linked to trees, are key sources of dietary diversity in rural settings. In the present article, we develop conceptual links between diet diversity and forested landscape mosaics within the rural tropics. First, we summarize the state of knowledge regarding diets obtained from forests, trees, and agroforests. We then hypothesize how disturbed secondary forests, edge habitats, forest access, and landscape diversity can function in bolstering dietary diversity. Taken together, these ideas help us build a framework illuminating four pathways (direct, agroecological, energy, and market pathways) connecting forested landscapes to diet diversity. Finally, we offer recommendations to fill remaining knowledge gaps related to diet and forest cover monitoring. We argue that better evaluation of the role of land cover complexity will help avoid overly simplistic views of food security and, instead, uncover nutritional synergies with forest conservation and restoration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;perspectives-on-validation-in-digital-soil-mapping-of-continuous-attributes-a-review&quot;&gt;Perspectives on validation in digital soil mapping of continuous attributes-A review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We performed a systematic mapping of validation methods used in digital soil mapping (DSM), in order to gain an overview of current practices and make recommendations for future publications on DSM studies. A systematic search and screening procedure, largely following the RepOrting standards for Systematic Evidence Syntheses (ROSES) protocol, was carried out. It yielded a database of 188 peer-reviewed DSM studies from the past two decades, all written in English and all presenting a raster map of a continuous soil property. Review of the full-texts showed that most publications (97%) included some type of map validation, while just over one-third (35%) estimated map uncertainty. Most commonly, a combination of multiple (existing) soil sampe datasets was used and the resulting maps were validated by single data-splitting or cross-validation. It was common for essential information to be lacking in method descriptions. This is unfortunate, as lack of information on sampling design (missing in 25% of 188 studies) and sample support (missing in 45% of 188 studies) makes it difficult to interpret what derived validation metrics represent, compromising their usefulness. Therefore, we present a list of method details that should be provided in DSM studies. We also provide a detailed summary of the 28 validation metrics used in published DSM studies, how to interpret the values obtained and whether the metrics can be compared between datasets or soil attributes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;objective-functions-from-bayesian-optimization-to-locate-additional-drillholes&quot;&gt;Objective functions from Bayesian optimization to locate additional drillholes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key available information to choose new locations for drilling are the estimated ore grade values and the corresponding uncertainties at the tentative locations. These pieces of information are combined to generate a single objective function. The mathematical form of the objective function should reflect the effect of these values and their relative importance. Traditional objective function use multiplication of these parameters by different powering values. In this study, we develop two novel objective functions from the Bayesian optimization: the probability of improvement (PI), and the expected improvement (EI). These two objective functions seek new drillholes while considering the effect of the used value and their relative importance. Therefore, they can provide a trade-off between exploration and exploitation. All the objective functions have adjustable parameters. These parameters are typically tuned using expert knowledge or heuristic rules. Here, a statistical method based on cross-validation is proposed to adjust the parameters of the traditional and novel objective functions. The performance of the novel objective functions is validated against other ones using a distance based ranking method, in a phosphate deposit. The obtained results demonstrate the robustness of the EI and PI, the newly introduced objective functions from the Bayesian optimization framework.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/02/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on February 22, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/02/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/02/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-02-16T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-02-16T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-3&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Glomalin - Truths, myths, and the future of this elusive soil glycoprotein&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How microbes can, and cannot, be used to assess soil health&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Analysis of the Informativity of Big Satellite Precision-Farming Data Processing for Correcting Large-Scale Soil Maps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Frontiers in Cultural Ecosystem Services: Toward Greater Equity and Justice in Ecosystem Services Research and Practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;glomalin---truths-myths-and-the-future-of-this-elusive-soil-glycoprotein&quot;&gt;Glomalin - Truths, myths, and the future of this elusive soil glycoprotein&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOIL BIOLOGY &amp;amp; BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term “Glomalin” was originally used to describe a hypothetical gene product of arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi (AMF) that was assumed to be a nearly ubiquitous, thermostable and highly recalcitrant glycoprotein, deposited in soils in large amounts, and deemed to indicate soil health and quality. It was defined operationally as the fraction of soil organic matter (SOM) extractable by a hot citrate buffer and assessed either by Bradford assay or by cross-reactivity with monoclonal antibody MAb32B11. Later, it was recognized that the extracts contained a variety of compounds, including some of non-AMF origin, cross-reactive with both Bradford assay and the monoclonal antibody. This led to re-describing the pertinent (and still only operationally defined) SOM as “glomalin-related soil proteins (GRSP)”, albeit without any substantial change in the underlying concepts. Consequently, a great deal of confusion in this area arose among researchers in soil, plant, and environmental sciences. Glomalin or GRSP (often used interchangeably) has previously been linked to various soil features, including stability of soil aggregates, size of soil C and N pools, sequestration of heavy metals, and alleviation of various plant stresses. GRSP concentrations in soil often, but not always, have been correlated with AMF biomass measured by alternative (mainly microscopic) approaches. GRSP formation, deposition, and/or decomposition in soils seem to be largely dependent on a multitude of interactions among plants, AMF, and other soil microorganisms, including prokaryotes. The chemical structure of GRSP extracted from soil remains unclear and generally complex. That is due to the unspecific mode of its extraction and purification, as well as the great variety of analytical approaches that have been used heretofore to assess it. Future research needs to elucidate the exact composition of this operationally defined SOM fraction, the controls over its production and accumulation in soils, and its exact role in soil ecology generally and soil food webs in particular. Furthermore, novel and independent tools should be established to more specifically (as compared to current glomalin assays) assess AMF biomass and functioning in mots and soil and its involvement in soil processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-microbes-can-and-cannot-be-used-to-assess-soil-health&quot;&gt;How microbes can, and cannot, be used to assess soil health&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOIL BIOLOGY &amp;amp; BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Healthy soils are critical to the health of ecosystems, economies, and human populations. Thus, it is widely acknowledged that soil health is important to quantify, both for assessment and as a tool to help guide management strategies. What is less clear is how soil health should actually be measured, especially considering that soil health is not exclusively a product of soil physical and chemical characteristics. Given their well-established importance to many aspects of soil health, microbes and microbial processes are often used as metrics of soil health with a range of different microbe-based metrics routinely used across the globe. Unfortunately, it is our opinion that many of these pre-existing microbial measurements are not easy to interpret and may not necessarily provide credible inferences about soil health status. Here we review the microbial indices used to assess or monitor soil health and discuss some of the broader issues associated with their use. We provide recommendations to more effectively guide and improve how microbial information could be used to yield relevant and actionable assessments of soil health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;analysis-of-the-informativity-of-big-satellite-precision-farming-data-processing-for-correcting-large-scale-soil-maps&quot;&gt;Analysis of the Informativity of Big Satellite Precision-Farming Data Processing for Correcting Large-Scale Soil Maps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EURASIAN SOIL SCIENCE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Large-scale soil maps produced by research institutes for land management (GIPROZEM) are the main source of soil information on arable land in Russia. These maps date back to the 1960s-1990s. During the time that has passed since the last round of soil surveys, the development of precision farming has greatly increased the requirements for the accuracy of the maps. At present, archival soil maps require correction (verification, updating, detailing, and unification). It is suggested that the maps of stable intrafield heterogeneity (SIFH) of soil fertility based on the analysis of big remote sensing data can find application in modern agriculture. Such maps are created within the framework of the general concept of big data analysis, including big geodata and big agricultural data as its components. Comparative analysis of archival soil maps and the SIFH map for the territory of southern Russia attests to the great potential of SIFH maps for soil mapping. Missing soil polygons have been detected, the location of existing soil polygons has been refined, new soil units not marked on archival soil maps have been identified, and a plan for additional soil surveys within the framework of the data-driven geography concept has been worked out. The accuracy of the soil map has been improved to be applicable to state-of-the-art farming systems, including precision farming. A new source of information on the spatial heterogeneity of the soil cover and its fertility has appeared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;frontiers-in-cultural-ecosystem-services-toward-greater-equity-and-justice-in-ecosystem-services-research-and-practice&quot;&gt;Frontiers in Cultural Ecosystem Services: Toward Greater Equity and Justice in Ecosystem Services Research and Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BIOSCIENCE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cultural ecosystem services (CES) are associated with diverse and profound values, such as spiritual fulfillment, cultural heritage, and identity-related phenomena. Early ecosystem services research often omitted these deep meanings, but they are increasingly explored in recent studies through a range of disciplinary and epistemological perspectives. In the present article, we distill emerging frontiers of CES research. These frontiers help to characterize varied sources of meaning that are central to the CES ethos. They represent both advances in and opportunities for CES research, especially as related to justice and equity. The frontiers are: broadening definitions and conceptualizations of CES; addressing collective aspects of CES and attending to process; acknowledging that CES are reciprocal, relational, and dynamic; embracing narrative; and better connecting CES to biophysical attributes. We focus on the implications of these frontiers for equity and justice and suggest future research that can help ecosystem services work better address both legacies and current manifestations of injustice.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/02/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on February 16, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/02/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/02/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-02-15T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-02-15T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-2&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gully prevention and control: Techniques, failures and effectiveness&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The potential of portable luminescence readers in geomorphological investigations: a review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Current trends in laser-induced breakdown spectroscopy: a tutorial review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A minimum data set of soil morphological properties for quantifying soil quality in coastal agroecosystems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Three-dimensional quantification of soil pore structure in wind-deposited loess under different vegetation types using industrial X-ray computed tomography&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gully-prevention-and-control-techniques-failures-and-effectiveness&quot;&gt;Gully prevention and control: Techniques, failures and effectiveness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EARTH SURFACE PROCESSES AND LANDFORMS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gully erosion is a major environmental problem, posing significant threats to sustainable development. However, insights on techniques to prevent and control gullying are scattered and incomplete, especially regarding failure rates and effectiveness. This review aims to address these issues and contribute to more successful gully prevention and control strategies by synthesizing the data from earlier studies. Preventing gully formation can be done through land use change, applying soil and water conservation techniques or by targeted measures in concentrated flow zones. The latter include measures that increase topsoil resistance and vegetation barriers. Vegetation barriers made of plant residues have the advantage of being immediately effective in protecting against erosion, but have a short life expectancy as compared to barriers made of living vegetation. Once deeply incised, the development of gullies may be controlled by diverting runoff away from the channel, but this comes at the risk of relocating the problem. Additional measures such as headcut filling, channel reshaping and headcut armouring can also be applied. To control gully channels, multiple studies report on the use of check dams and/or vegetation. Reasons for failures of these techniques depend on runoff and sediment characteristics and cross-sectional stability and micro-environment of the gully. In turn, these are controlled by external forcing factors that can be grouped into (i) geomorphology and topography, (ii) climate and (iii) the bio-physical environment. The impact of gully prevention and control techniques is addressed, especially regarding their effect on headcut retreat and network development, the trapping of sediment by check dams and reduction of catchment sediment yield. Overall, vegetation establishment in gully channels and catchments plays a key role in gully prevention and control. Once stabilized, gullies may turn into rehabilitated sites of lush vegetation or cropland, making the return on investment to prevent and control gullies high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-potential-of-portable-luminescence-readers-in-geomorphological-investigations-a-review&quot;&gt;The potential of portable luminescence readers in geomorphological investigations: a review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EARTH SURFACE PROCESSES AND LANDFORMS&lt;br /&gt;
The development of functional portable optically stimulated luminescence (OSL) readers over the last decade has provided practitioners with the capability to acquire luminescence signals from geological materials relatively rapidly, which allows for expedient preliminary chronostratigraphic insight when working with complex depositional systems of late Quaternary age. Typically, when using the portable OSL reader, infrared (IR) or blue post-IR OSL signals are acquired from bulk unprocessed materials, in contrast to regular luminescence dating, which is usually based on measurements on pure quartz or feldspar mineral separates, or on select silt-sized polymineralic portions. To demonstrate the utility of portable OSL measurements, this paper outlines the basic features of portable OSL readers and their constraints. Subsequently, case studies in which the instrument has been used to elucidate cryptostratigraphic variations in sedimentary sequences for geomorphological applications are reviewed. The studies can generally be grouped into three main categories. The first includes studies where the variation of portable OSL reader luminescence signal intensities with depth are plotted to generate profiles that contextualize sediment stratigraphy. In the second group, portable OSL reader luminescence signal intensities are used to interpret sediment processes that shed light on depositional histories. In the last category, luminescence signals from the portable OSL reader are calibrated to approximate numerical burial ages of depositional units. The paper concludes with a discussion of possible future directions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;current-trends-in-laser-induced-breakdown-spectroscopy-a-tutorial-review&quot;&gt;Current trends in laser-induced breakdown spectroscopy: a tutorial review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;APPLIED SPECTROSCOPY REVIEWS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this tutorial article is to provide a brief update on the advances available for laser-induced breakdown spectroscopy (LIBS), focusing broad experimental and instrumental possibilities. Due to the inherent versatility of LIBS, this technique can be elegantly applied to various applications. However, during the method development one should have prior knowledge about its analytical limitations in order to obtain reliable results. In the present review, we summarize key analytical variables required for proper sample treatment, analytical signal enhancement, data processing, qualitative and quantitative approaches as well as recent research and developments using LIBS. Remarkable analytical advances have recently been proposed for LIBS and raised its analytical performance to a level never reached before. Most prominent perhaps, have been the development of many nontraditional calibration approaches based on transition atomic energies (emission wavelengths), the use of a single standard for calibration, increase of the ablated sample mass (accumulated laser pulses), and even overcoming severe LIBS problems such as the matrix effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-minimum-data-set-of-soil-morphological-properties-for-quantifying-soil-quality-in-coastal-agroecosystems&quot;&gt;A minimum data set of soil morphological properties for quantifying soil quality in coastal agroecosystems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CATENA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil quality in coastal agroecosystems changes rapidly owing to coastal dynamics and land-use change. The potential of soil morphological properties as soil quality indicators is mostly unexplored. We present a minimum data set (MDS) of soil morphological properties to quantify the coastal soil quality. We compiled a dataset including 18 soil morphological properties from 468 soil profiles, representing five land-use types (plantation crops, sugarcane, grassland, rice, and cotton + pigeon pea) of the north-western coastal region of India. The categorical variables were transformed into numerical variables using the optimal scaling method, and categorical principal component analysis (CATPCA) was used to identify the MDS. The CATPCA produced five principal components explaining 60% of the variability. The MDS comprises pore abundance, structure size, drainage, pore size, and colour (value) with 32, 22, 21, 14, and 12% contribution to soil quality, respectively. The morphological soil quality index (MSQI) varied from 0.26 to 0.99 for surface soils, and from 0.11 to 0.94 for the subsurface soils. Among the land-use types, the rice-growing soils were low in their morphological quality due to structural degradation. Land-use types significantly influenced the MSQI in both surface and subsurface soils, and hence, we recommend the inclusion of subsurface soils for soil quality evaluation. The strong relationship of MSQI with saturated hydraulic conductivity (R-2 = 0.56) validated the suitability of the MDS for assessment of soil quality by the farmers, and non-experts in the coastal regions. Further, the higher variability explained by the soil morphology data indicates that the MDS identified in this study could be effectively used to evaluate soil quality in areas with limited data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;three-dimensional-quantification-of-soil-pore-structure-in-wind-deposited-loess-under-different-vegetation-types-using-industrial-x-ray-computed-tomography&quot;&gt;Three-dimensional quantification of soil pore structure in wind-deposited loess under different vegetation types using industrial X-ray computed tomography&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CATENA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quantifying the soil pore structure is critical for understanding plant growth and water/solute movements in the soil. However, most previous studies quantified the soil pore structure in a shallow layer by using low resolution medical computed tomography (CT), whereas few have quantified the soil pore structure in deep soil layers with high resolution CT. In this study, we quantified the soil pore structure of wind-deposited loess under different vegetation types (wheat, weeds, apple orchard, and Robinia pseudoacacia) at depths from 0 to 4.5 m by industrial CT. The results showed that the soil pore number and porosity tended to decreased with depth, but there were no significance differences below 2 m among all vegetation types. For different depths and vegetation types, the number of pores measuring 0-100 mu m was highest, followed by those measuring.
100-500 mu m, and lowest for those measuring &amp;gt; 1000 mu m. The contribution of pores measuring 100-500 mu m to the total pore volume was highest. The variations in the connectivity and surface area density were also focused mainly within the depth down to 2 m, and the variations were minor below 2 m. There were no significant differences in the bulk density and soil pore characteristics under different vegetation types, except for weeds. The results obtained in this study provide insights into the interactions between vegetation and soil water, as well as the hydrological processes for the wind-deposited loess.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/02/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on February 15, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2021/02/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2021/02/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-02-04T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2021-02-04T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2021-1&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2021 #1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil moisture–atmosphere feedbacks mitigate declining water availability in drylands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-moistureatmosphere-feedbacks-mitigate-declining-water-availability-in-drylands&quot;&gt;Soil moisture–atmosphere feedbacks mitigate declining water availability in drylands&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Global warming alters surface water availability (precipitation minus evapotranspiration, P–E) and hence freshwater resources. However, the influence of land–atmosphere feedbacks on future P–E changes and the underlying mechanisms remain unclear. Here we demonstrate that soil moisture (SM) strongly impacts future P–E changes, especially in drylands, by regulating evapotranspiration and atmospheric moisture inflow. Using modelling and empirical approaches, we find a consistent negative SM feedback on P–E, which may offset ~60% of the decline in dryland P–E otherwise expected in the absence of SM feedbacks. The negative feedback is not caused by atmospheric thermodynamic responses to declining SM; rather, reduced SM, in addition to limiting evapotranspiration, regulates atmospheric circulation and vertical ascent to enhance moisture transport into drylands. This SM effect is a large source of uncertainty in projected dryland P–E changes, underscoring the need to better constrain future SM changes and improve the representation of SM–atmosphere processes in models.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/02/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on February 04, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/12/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/12/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-23-02T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-12-23T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-21&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #21&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beyond ecosystem modeling: A roadmap to community cyberinfrastructure for ecological data‐model integration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monitoring of wheat crops using the backscattering coefficient and the interferometric coherence derived from Sentinel-1 in semi-arid areas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Synergistic use of SMAP and OCO-2 data in assessing the responses of ecosystem productivity to the 2018 U.S. drought&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;lidR: An R package for analysis of Airborne Laser Scanning (ALS) data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proximally sensed digital data library to predict topsoil clay across multiple sugarcane fields of Australia: Applicability of local and universal support vector machine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hypotheses, machine learning and soil mapping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Predicting soil properties in 3D: Should depth be a covariate?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paper chromatography: An inconsistent tool for assessing soil health&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UAV‐based training for fully fuzzy classification of Sentinel‐2 fluvial scenes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrating portable X-ray fluorescence (pXRF) measurement uncertainty for accurate soil contamination mapping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Bayesian approach toward the use of qualitative information to inform on-farm decision making: The example of soil compaction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Errors induced by spectral measurement positions and instrument noise in soil organic carbon prediction using vis-NIR on intact soil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combination of soil texture with Nix color sensor can improve soil organic carbon prediction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Numerical soil classification supports soil identification by citizen scientists using limited, simple soil observations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beyond x,y,z(t); Navigating New Landscapes of Science in the Science of Landscapes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From pools to flow: The PROMISE framework for new insights on soil carbon cycling in a changing world&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reference state and benchmark concepts for better biodiversity conservation in contemporary ecosystems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;COSORE: A community database for continuous soil respiration and other soil‐atmosphere greenhouse gas flux data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;beyond-ecosystem-modeling-a-roadmap-to-community-cyberinfrastructure-for-ecological-datamodel-integration&quot;&gt;Beyond ecosystem modeling: A roadmap to community cyberinfrastructure for ecological data‐model integration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an era of rapid global change, our ability to understand and predict Earth’s natural systems is lagging behind our ability to monitor and measure changes in the biosphere. Bottlenecks to informing models with observations have reduced our capacity to fully exploit the growing volume and variety of available data. Here, we take a critical look at the information infrastructure that connects ecosystem modeling and measurement efforts, and propose a roadmap to community cyberinfrastructure development that can reduce the divisions between empirical research and modeling and accelerate the pace of discovery. A new era of data‐model integration requires investment in accessible, scalable, and transparent tools that integrate the expertise of the whole community, including both modelers and empiricists. This roadmap focuses on five key opportunities for community tools: the underlying foundations of community cyberinfrastructure; data ingest; calibration of models to data; model‐data benchmarking; and data assimilation and ecological forecasting. This community‐driven approach is a key to meeting the pressing needs of science and society in the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;monitoring-of-wheat-crops-using-the-backscattering-coefficient-and-the-interferometric-coherence-derived-from-sentinel-1-in-semi-arid-areas&quot;&gt;Monitoring of wheat crops using the backscattering coefficient and the interferometric coherence derived from Sentinel-1 in semi-arid areas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radar data at C-band has shown great potential for the monitoring of soil and canopy hydric conditions of wheat crops. In this study, the C-band Sentinel-1 time series including the backscattering coefficients σ0 at VV and VH polarization, the polarization ratio (PR) and the interferometric coherence ρ are first analyzed with the support of experimental data gathered on three plots of irrigated winter wheat located in the Haouz plain in the center of Morocco covering five growing seasons. The results showed that ρ and PR are tightly related to the canopy development. ρ is also sensitive to soil preparation. By contrast, σ0 was found to be widely linked to changes in surface soil moisture (SSM) during the first growth stages when Leaf Area Index remains moderate (&amp;lt;1.5 m2/m2). In addition, drastic changes in the crop geometry associated to heading had a strong impact on the C-band σ0, in particular for VH polarization. The coupled water cloud and Oh models (WCM) were then calibrated and validated on the study sites. The comparison between the predicted and observed σ0 yielded a root mean square error (RMSE) values ranging from 1.50 dB to 2.02 dB for VV and between 1.74 dB to 2.52 dB for VH with significant differences occurring in the second part of the season after heading. Finally, new approaches based on the inversion of the WCM for SSM retrieval over wheat fields were proposed using Sentinel-1 radar data only. To this objective, the dry above-ground biomass (AGB) and the vegetation water content (VWC) were retrieved from the interferometric coherence and the PR. The relationships were then used as the vegetation descriptor in the WCM. The best retrieval results were obtained using the relationship between ρVV and the AGB (R and RMSE of 0.82, 0.05 m3/m3 respectively and no bias). The new retrieval approaches were then applied to a large database covering a rainfed field in Morocco and 18 plots of rainfed and irrigated wheat of the Kairouan plain (Tunisia) and compared to other classical techniques of SSM retrieval including simple linear relationships between SSM and σ0. The method based on the WCM and the ρVV-AGB relationships also provided with slightly better results than the others on the validation database (r = 0.75, RMSE = 0.06 m3/m3 and bias = 0.01 m3/m3 over the 18 plots of Tunisia) but the simple linear relationships performed also reasonably well (r = 0.62, RMSE = 0.07, bias = −0.01 in Tunisia for instance). This study opens perspectives for high resolution soil moisture mapping from Sentinel-1 data over south Mediterranean wheat crops and in fine, for irrigation scheduling and retrieval through the assimilation of these new products in an evapotranspiration model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;synergistic-use-of-smap-and-oco-2-data-in-assessing-the-responses-of-ecosystem-productivity-to-the-2018-us-drought&quot;&gt;Synergistic use of SMAP and OCO-2 data in assessing the responses of ecosystem productivity to the 2018 U.S. drought&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil moisture and gross primary productivity (GPP) estimates from the Soil Moisture Active Passive (SMAP) and solar-induced chlorophyll fluorescence (SIF) from the Orbiting Carbon Observatory-2 (OCO-2) provide new opportunities for understanding the relationship between soil moisture and terrestrial photosynthesis over large regions. Here we explored the potential of the synergistic use of SMAP and OCO-2 based data for monitoring the responses of ecosystem productivity to drought. We used complementary observational information on root-zone soil moisture and GPP (9 km) from SMAP and fine-resolution SIF (0.05°; GOSIF) derived from OCO-2 SIF soundings. We compared the spatial pattern and temporal evolution of anomalies of these variables over the conterminous U.S. during the 2018 drought, and examined to what extent they could characterize the drought-induced variations of flux tower GPP and crop yield data. Our results showed that SMAP GPP and GOSIF, both freely available online, could well capture the spatial extent and dynamics of the impacts of drought indicated by the U.S. Drought Monitor maps and the SMAP root-zone soil moisture deficit. Over the U.S. Southwest, monthly anomalies of soil moisture showed significant positive correlations with those of SMAP GPP (R2 = 0.44, p &amp;lt; 0.001) and GOSIF (R2 = 0.76, p &amp;lt; 0.001), demonstrating strong water availability constraints on plant productivity across dryland ecosystems. We further found that SMAP GPP and GOSIF captured the impact of drought on tower GPP and crop yield. Our results suggest that synergistic use of SMAP and OCO-2 data products can reveal the drought evolution and its impact on ecosystem productivity and carbon uptake at multiple spatial and temporal scales, and demonstrate the value of SMAP and OCO-2 for studying ecosystem function, carbon cycling, and climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lidr-an-r-package-for-analysis-of-airborne-laser-scanning-als-data&quot;&gt;lidR: An R package for analysis of Airborne Laser Scanning (ALS) data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airborne laser scanning (ALS) is a remote sensing technology known for its applicability in natural resources management. By quantifying the three-dimensional structure of vegetation and underlying terrain using laser technology, ALS has been used extensively for enhancing geospatial knowledge in the fields of forestry and ecology. Structural descriptions of vegetation provide a means of estimating a range of ecologically pertinent attributes, such as height, volume, and above-ground biomass. The efficient processing of large, often technically complex datasets requires dedicated algorithms and software. The continued promise of ALS as a tool for improving ecological understanding is often dependent on user-created tools, methods, and approaches. Due to the proliferation of ALS among academic, governmental, and private-sector communities, paired with requirements to address a growing demand for open and accessible data, the ALS community is recognising the importance of free and open-source software (FOSS) and the importance of user-defined workflows. Herein, we describe the philosophy behind the development of the lidR package. Implemented in the R environment with a C/C++ backend, lidR is free, open-source and cross-platform software created to enable simple and creative processing workflows for forestry and ecology communities using ALS data. We review current algorithms used by the research community, and in doing so raise awareness of current successes and challenges associated with parameterisation and common implementation approaches. Through a detailed description of the package, we address the key considerations and the design philosophy that enables users to implement user-defined tools. We also discuss algorithm choices that make the package representative of the ‘state-of-the-art’ and we highlight some internal limitations through examples of processing time discrepancies. We conclude that the development of applications like lidR are of fundamental importance for developing transparent, flexible and open ALS tools to ensure not only reproducible workflows, but also to offer researchers the creative space required for the progress and development of the discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;proximally-sensed-digital-data-library-to-predict-topsoil-clay-across-multiple-sugarcane-fields-of-australia-applicability-of-local-and-universal-support-vector-machine&quot;&gt;Proximally sensed digital data library to predict topsoil clay across multiple sugarcane fields of Australia: Applicability of local and universal support vector machine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowledge about topsoil (0–0.3 m) clay is required to maintain sugarcane profitability in Queensland, Australia. However, laboratory analysis to get this knowledge is tedious and time consuming. To add value to limited clay data, a digital soil map (DSM) can be created by using digital data and mathematical models. At the field level, site-specific linear regression (LR) models are often used along with gamma-ray (γ-ray) spectrometry and electromagnetic induction data (i.e. soil apparent electrical conductivity – ECa). But these LR might not perform well in site-independent calibrations across multiple sites. In this regard, support vector machine (SVM) might be useful. In this research, we first aimed to determine, using a stepwise SVM and calibration dataset, the optimal digital data (i.e. individual or combined) to develop local (for each individual site) and universal (for combined sites) SVM models. Using optimal digital data, our second aim was to predict clay for validation datasets by using local SVM in site-specific approach and universal SVM in site-independent, holdout and spiking approaches. Using these approaches, DSM of predicted clay and associated uncertainty were generated for a representative study site (i.e., Mossman). The third aim was to determine the suitable number of spiking samples and by varying the size of both spiking set and calibration model. Approaches were compared using prediction agreement (Lin’s concordance) and accuracy (ratio of performance to deviation – RPD). We concluded from stepwise SVM that combining digital data resulted in better accuracy (RPD = 2.17) than individual γ-ray (1.79) or ECa (1.49) data. In terms of independent validation, the results of Mossman reflected the general rank order of different approaches with site-specific (3.03) excellent, spiking (1.89) very good, site-independent (1.84) good and holdout (1.18) poor predictions. In case of DSM and uncertainty maps, under-predictions were problematic at field edges and where digital data changed as a function of soil type and or proximity to a prior stream channel. Considering the suitable number of spiking samples, size of spiking set showed linear relationship with improvement in predictions while that of calibration model showed no influence. These results suggest the usefulness of proximally sensed data and universal SVM to effectively predict clay across multiple sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hypotheses-machine-learning-and-soil-mapping&quot;&gt;Hypotheses, machine learning and soil mapping&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hypotheses are of major importance in scientific research. In current applications of machine learning algorithms for soil mapping the hypotheses being tested or developed are often ambiguous or undefined. Mapping soil properties or classes, however, does not tell much about the dynamics and processes that underly soil genesis and evolution. When the interest in the soil map is for applications in a context different than soil science, such as for policy making or baseline production of quantitative soil information, the interpretation should be made in light of this application. If otherwise, we recommend soil scientists to provide hypotheses to accompany their research. The hypothesis is formulated at the beginning of the research and, in some cases, motivates data collection. Here we argue that when applying data-driven techniques such as machine learning, developing hypotheses can be a useful end point of the research. The spatial pattern predicted by the machine learning model and the correlation found among the covariates are an opportunity to develop hypotheses which are likely to require additional analyses and datasets to be tested. Systematically providing scientific hypotheses in digital soil mapping studies will enable the soil science community to build on previous work, and to increase the credibility of data-driven algorithms as a means to accelerate discovery on soil processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;predicting-soil-properties-in-3d-should-depth-be-a-covariate&quot;&gt;Predicting soil properties in 3D: Should depth be a covariate?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil is a three-dimensional volume with property variability in all three dimensions. In Digital Soil Mapping (DSM), the variation of soil properties down a profile is usually harmonised by the use of the equal-area spline depth function approach. Soil observations at various depth intervals are harmonised to pre-determined depth intervals. To create maps of soil at the defined depth intervals, 2.5D model produces maps of individual depth intervals separately. Those maps can be reconstructed to produce a continuous depth function for each predicted location. More recently, several studies propose that soil property at any depth can be mapped using a model incorporating depth along with spatial covariates as predictor variables, creating a ‘3D’ model. The aim of this study is to evaluate the proposition that soil properties can be predicted at any depth. This study compares the 2.5D model and 3D model in two areas. The first test is on a 1500 km2 area in Edgeroi, New South Wales (NSW), Australia, mapping soil organic carbon (SOC, %), carbon storage (kg m−2), pH (H2O), clay content (%), and cation exchange capacity (CEC, mg/kg) based on depth-interval observations. The second study area in the Lower Hunter Valley has SOC observations at every 2 cm increment from a 210 km2 area. 2.5D and 3D models were tested in both study areas using four machine learning techniques: Cubist regression tree, Quantile Regression Forest (QRF), Artificial Neural Network (ANN), and 3D Generalised Additive Model (GAM). Results show that, in terms of R2 and RMSE, 2.5D and 3D models using different machine learning models produce comparable results on the validation of depth interval observations. The 3D tree-based models produce “stepped” prediction of properties with depth. Results on the Hunter Valley area with point observations show that the 3D model cannot replicate field point observations. 3D soil mapping on point depth observation has lower accuracy and larger uncertainty compared to the 2.5D model. For future DSM studies, 3D soil mapping with depth as a covariate requires caution with respect to the prediction method and the requirements of the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;paper-chromatography-an-inconsistent-tool-for-assessing-soil-health&quot;&gt;Paper chromatography: An inconsistent tool for assessing soil health&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although paper chromatography is being promoted as a cost-effective tool for rapid assessment of soil health, few studies have explored the quantitative relationship between chromatogram features and soil health variables, and no studies have investigated the association between chromatogram features and microbial diversity as determined using DNA sequences. We assessed 343 soil samples from varying land uses in southwestern Australia to investigate the relationship between total organic carbon, microbial activity and diversity, salinity and pH levels and 12 chromatogram features. Spearman’s correlations and variance partitioning were used to detect relationships. Although total organic carbon and microbial activity displayed the strongest correlations with chromatogram features, they were not associated with greater development of radial features and median zone radius as expected. This was in contrast to what has been previously reported, implying context dependent responses of chromatogram features to gradients in soil variables. Microbial community structure was found to explain changes in chromatogram features better than the measured soil variables. These results indicate that further studies are necessary before paper chromatography is embraced as a tool for soil health assessment, and raises questions regarding the use of chromatography by community groups as a tool to measure soil health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;uavbased-training-for-fully-fuzzy-classification-of-sentinel2-fluvial-scenes&quot;&gt;UAV‐based training for fully fuzzy classification of Sentinel‐2 fluvial scenes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An estimated 76% of global stream area is occupied by channels with widths above 30 m. Sentinel‐2 imagery with resolutions of 10 m could supply information about the composition of river corridors at national and global scales. Fuzzy classification models that infer sub‐pixel composition could further be used to compensate for small channel widths imaged at 10 m of spatial resolution. A major challenge to this approach is the acquisition of suitable training data useable in machine learning models that can predict land‐cover type information from image radiance values. In this contribution, we present a method which combines unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) and Sentinel‐2 imagery in order to develop a fuzzy classification approach capable of large‐scale investigations. Our approach uses hyperspatial UAV imagery in order to derive high‐resolution class information that can be used to train fuzzy classification models for Sentinel‐2 data where all bands are super‐resolved to a spatial resolution of 10 m. We use a multi‐temporal UAV dataset covering an area of 5.25 km2. Using a novel convolutional neural network (CNN) classifier, we predict sub‐pixel membership for Sentinel‐2 pixels in the fluvial corridor as divided into classes of water, vegetation and dry sediment. Our CNN model can predict fuzzy class memberships with median errors from −5% to +3% and mean absolute errors from 10% to 20%. We also show that our CNN fuzzy predictor can be used to predict crisp classes with accuracies from 95.5% to 99.9%. Finally, we use an example to show how a fuzzy CNN model trained with localized UAV data can be applied to longer channel reaches and detect new vegetation growth. We therefore argue that the novel use of UAVs as field validation tools for freely available satellite data can bridge the scale gap between local and regional fluvial studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;integrating-portable-x-ray-fluorescence-pxrf-measurement-uncertainty-for-accurate-soil-contamination-mapping&quot;&gt;Integrating portable X-ray fluorescence (pXRF) measurement uncertainty for accurate soil contamination mapping&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;significant reduction in the costs associated with contamination assessments can be achieved if traditional soil sampling for contaminated-site characterization is complemented by real-time sampling using proximal soil sensors. Real-time sampling using a portable X-ray fluorescence (pXRF) device is a cheap and fast sampling method to provide more data and reduce the time needed to map soil contamination. The main disadvantage of using pXRF is the degree of uncertainty of these in situ measurements due to the technology’s indirect nature, and its sensitivity to soil heterogeneity and soil moisture content. This study evaluates the potential of using both pXRF and traditional soil sampling measurements to accurately map soil contamination due to the presence of heavy metals. The approach proposed uses geostatistical sequential simulation with local probability distributions to characterize and integrate pXRF uncertainty at each sampling location. The resulting maps agree with the contamination map obtained using traditional laboratory data only, in terms of mapping accuracy and extent of contaminated areas. This study shows that with few collocated pXRF and laboratory analytical data it is possible to identify contaminated areas accurately, thus providing a cost-effective solution to work with pXRF data directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-bayesian-approach-toward-the-use-of-qualitative-information-to-inform-on-farm-decision-making-the-example-of-soil-compaction&quot;&gt;A Bayesian approach toward the use of qualitative information to inform on-farm decision making: The example of soil compaction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the development of predictive tools to aid decision making in agriculture increases, it must be acknowledged that the ability to incorporate management decisions as input data is limited. The data is either not recorded, or highly inadequate in terms of the volume, variety or relevance. Some circumstances are further hampered by the lack of benchmark data for comparison, and soil compaction is an example of this. The premise of this work was to take a probability based approach to decision making, utilising both qualitative and quantitative data to provide a probability distribution of risk against decisions made, in the context of grains production systems as an example of an agricultural enterprise. A Bayesian Belief Network (BBN) was constructed for soil compaction risk, as an exemplar. The BBN conditional probability tables for nodes were populated via a combination of biophysical model output (namely SoilFlex for soil stress distribution, and the APSIM package for soil-water and crop parameters) and expert opinion. Input nodes were parameterised with measured soil data, and the risk of soil compaction, given the soil stress at the wheel of a particular vehicle, was provided as the output. Potential effect on yield was subsequently calculated on the basis of percent change in soil bulk density, which was determined using literature based information (expert opinion). The tool broadly estimated yield impacts due to various agricultural traffic scenarios, providing means to highlight the financial consequences of failing to adopt controlled traffic farming management for a particular agricultural enterprise. Of significance, the BBN approach was determined useful for data limiting environments where empirical models struggle, thus providing a pragmatic and novel approach to on farm decision making incorporating management nuance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;errors-induced-by-spectral-measurement-positions-and-instrument-noise-in-soil-organic-carbon-prediction-using-vis-nir-on-intact-soil&quot;&gt;Errors induced by spectral measurement positions and instrument noise in soil organic carbon prediction using vis-NIR on intact soil&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil spectroscopy potentially would become a routine method for the measurement of soil properties in the field on soil cores. However, many factors could lead to errors in the measurement of spectra from intact soil cores. So far, errors induced by spectral measurement positions and instrument noise have rarely been quantified. The present study evaluated these errors based on 160 intact ring core samples collected from 20 profiles in a forest, southwest China. Each ring sample was scanned using a visible near-infrared (vis-NIR) spectrometer at nine evenly distributed positions at both ends of the ring to characterize within-sample variability. In addition, 10 scans were made at each position to characterize instrument error. A position spectrum was then calculated by averaging the 10 scans at each position, while a sample spectrum was calculated by averaging all 180 scans of each sample. The samples were then tested for soil organic carbon (SOC) content using the wet oxidation method. Based on the sample spectra and SOC content, a partial least squares regression (PLSR) model was calibrated. The modeling error was empirically calculated. Each scan, position spectrum, and sample spectrum was then fed into the calibrated PLSR model to predict SOC content, and the prediction results were evaluated for errors induced by instrument noise and different spectral measurement positions. Results showed that the error induced by different spectral measurement positions was about 75% of the modeling error, while the error induced by instrument noise was small and negligible. These three errors in terms of standard error of prediction (SEP) accounted for 18.6%, 23.8% and 1.46% of the average measured SOC content of the samples, respectively. Besides, the error due to different soil core sampling positions was also considerable. In terms of SEP, this error accounted for 12.5% of the average measured SOC content. These quantified error budgets would help to account for uncertainty in the measurement of soil properties using spectroscopy in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;combination-of-soil-texture-with-nix-color-sensor-can-improve-soil-organic-carbon-prediction&quot;&gt;Combination of soil texture with Nix color sensor can improve soil organic carbon prediction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The optimum ecosystem functioning is reliant on soil organic carbon (SOC) content which is traditionally measured in the laboratory via a cumbersome wet-chemistry method. This preliminary research tested whether a combination of Nix color sensor and portable X-ray fluorescence (PXRF) spectrometer data with soil texture data can improve soil SOC prediction accuracy relative to using them independently. A total of 371 samples representing diverse soil texture and SOC content were collected from three different ecoregions of eastern India: coastal saline zone, red and lateritic zone, and Gangetic alluvial zone. All dried, ground, and sieved samples were scanned via Nix and PXRF and random forest (RF) regression was used to predict soil SOC with different combinations of data. Soils were grouped into nine textural classes while soil SOC content exhibited substantial variability (0.08–2.26%). Comparing soil SOC with texture (sand + silt + clay), satisfactory prediction accuracy was observed (validation R2 = 0.70). Combining Nix extracted color parameters with texture substantially improved the model performance, producing the validation determination coefficient of 0.81. In contrast, PXRF-Rb, as a proxy of soil clay content was unable to achieve satisfactory prediction performance (R2 = 0.24), indicating the heterogeneity in soil mineralogical composition. The RF variable importance plot using Nix alone identified redness (a&lt;em&gt;) and yellowness to blueness (b&lt;/em&gt;) as influential predictors, manifesting the impact of red color from Fe and Al-oxides and their significant negative correlation with soil SOC (r = −0.62 and −0.57 for a* and b*, respectively). These color parameters were again identified by the RF variable importance plot of (Texture + Nix)-model, implying that the SOC prediction improvement may be linked with the Nix sensor’s capability of extracting useful information in the visible range. Summarily, a combination of Nix color variables and texture data was adept at predicting soil SOC in lieu of traditional laboratory analysis. The robustness of the (Texture + Nix)-based SOC prediction model can be augmented by incorporating more soil samples representing all 12 soil textural classes and variable SOC content, showing all possible soil colors in the pedogenic environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;numerical-soil-classification-supports-soil-identification-by-citizen-scientists-using-limited-simple-soil-observations&quot;&gt;Numerical soil classification supports soil identification by citizen scientists using limited, simple soil observations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accurately identifying the soil map unit component at a specific point‐location within a landscape is critical for implementing sustainable soil management. Recent developments in smartphone‐based technologies for characterizing soil profiles, coupled with improved numerical soil classification algorithms, have made it more accessible for non‐soil scientists to sample, characterize, and classify soil profiles. The main objective of this study was to evaluate an operational soil classification framework for identifying the soil component at a sampling‐location based on the numerical similarity of soil property values between the sampled soil profile and the soil components mapped in that area. To evaluate this soil identification framework, we used a subset of the U.S. National Cooperative Soil Survey Soil Characterization Database (NCSS–SCD) as our soil profile test dataset and the U.S. Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database as our reference dataset using profile data of soil components in the area surrounding each test profile. Numerical similarity was tested using soil property data representing different degrees of generalization, both in terms of generalizing depth‐wise variability (i.e., depth‐support) and generalizing across feature space (i.e., soil properties). Three soil property groups (i.e., Novice, Expert, Expert‐Plus) representing different levels of detail and three types of depth‐support (i.e., genetic horizon, depth intervals, and depth functions) were evaluated. Using a simple set of soil property inputs (i.e., Novice: soil texture class, rock fragment volume class, and soil color) resulted in nearly as high identification accuracy (46–53%) as that achieved with an Expert (48–57%) dataset that included more precise determinations (percent sand, silt, clay, and rock fragment volume), and virtually no further improvement with the addition of pH and organic matter in the Expert‐Plus dataset (53–60%). This study also showed minimal effect from the type of depth‐support used to represent depth‐wise variability. Furthermore, we evaluated several measures of soil functional similarity (i.e., ecological sites, land capability, taxonomic distance) which resulted in management relevant accuracies ranging from 65–89%. These findings support the utility of simple soil observations sampled at fixed depths for soil identification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;beyond-xyzt-navigating-new-landscapes-of-science-in-the-science-of-landscapes&quot;&gt;Beyond x,y,z(t); Navigating New Landscapes of Science in the Science of Landscapes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start of its centennial year, AGU’s surface process community revisited G. K. Gilbert’s legacy of landscape description and experimental models of surface processes, as well as his embrace of critique and pragmatism in the practice of landscape science. In the 100 years, since Gilbert and especially since the dawn of the 21st century, we have seen an intensified focus on the acquisition of more and more earth observation data and the numerical modeling of landscapes, alongside widespread use of deterministic and predictive practices to find solutions to the social, economic, and environmental challenges of today. What have we gained and lost in this pursuit? Here we lay out some of the challenges for the discipline in an increasingly data‐rich and complex world in which earth science is also being called to reorient itself towards more societally relevant roles. We ask the community to ponder the following: Is the discipline serving our scientific and societal goals, or is there a need for the science of landscapes to adopt new frameworks of thinking and to question the deterministic approaches that have dominated our discipline to date, in order to attend to the needs of living in the Anthropocene?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;from-pools-to-flow-the-promise-framework-for-new-insights-on-soil-carbon-cycling-in-a-changing-world&quot;&gt;From pools to flow: The PROMISE framework for new insights on soil carbon cycling in a changing world&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soils represent the largest terrestrial reservoir of organic carbon, and the balance between soil organic carbon (SOC) formation and loss will drive powerful carbon‐climate feedbacks over the coming century. To date, efforts to predict SOC dynamics have rested on pool‐based models, which assume classes of SOC with internally homogenous physicochemical properties. However, emerging evidence suggests that soil carbon turnover is not dominantly controlled by the chemistry of carbon inputs, but rather by restrictions on microbial access to organic matter in the spatially heterogeneous soil environment. The dynamic processes that control the physicochemical protection of carbon translate poorly to pool‐based SOC models; as a result, we are challenged to mechanistically predict how environmental change will impact movement of carbon between soils and the atmosphere. Here, we propose a novel conceptual framework to explore controls on belowground carbon cycling: Probabilistic Representation of Organic Matter Interactions within the Soil Environment (PROMISE). In contrast to traditional model frameworks, PROMISE does not attempt to define carbon pools united by common thermodynamic or functional attributes. Rather, the PROMISE concept considers how SOC cycling rates are governed by the stochastic processes that influence the proximity between microbial decomposers and organic matter, with emphasis on their physical location in the soil matrix. We illustrate the applications of this framework with a new biogeochemical simulation model that traces the fate of individual carbon atoms as they interact with their environment, undergoing biochemical transformations and moving through the soil pore space. We also discuss how the PROMISE framework reshapes dialogue around issues related to SOC management in a changing world. We intend the PROMISE framework to spur the development of new hypotheses, analytical tools, and model structures across disciplines that will illuminate mechanistic controls on the flow of carbon between plant, soil, and atmospheric pools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reference-state-and-benchmark-concepts-for-better-biodiversity-conservation-in-contemporary-ecosystems&quot;&gt;Reference state and benchmark concepts for better biodiversity conservation in contemporary ecosystems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Measuring the status and trends of biodiversity is critical for making informed decisions about the conservation, management or restoration of species, habitats and ecosystems. Defining the reference state against which status and change are measured is essential. Typically, reference states describe historical conditions, yet historical conditions are challenging to quantify, may be difficult to falsify, and may no longer be an attainable target in a contemporary ecosystem. We have constructed a conceptual framework to help inform thinking and discussion around the philosophical underpinnings of reference states and guide their application. We characterize currently recognized historical reference states and describe them as Pre‐Human, Indigenous Cultural, Pre‐Intensification and Hybrid‐Historical. We extend the conceptual framework to include contemporary reference states as an alternative theoretical perspective. The contemporary reference state framework is a major conceptual shift that focuses on current ecological patterns and identifies areas with higher biodiversity values relative to other locations within the same ecosystem, regardless of the disturbance history. We acknowledge that past processes play an essential role in driving contemporary patterns of diversity. The specific context for which we design the contemporary conceptual frame is underpinned by an overarching goal—to maximize biodiversity conservation and restoration outcomes in existing ecosystems. The contemporary reference state framework can account for the inherent differences in the diversity of biodiversity values (e.g. native species richness, habitat complexity) across spatial scales, communities and ecosystems. In contrast to historical reference states, contemporary references states are measurable and falsifiable. This ‘road map of reference states’ offers perspective needed to define and assess the status and trends in biodiversity and habitats. We demonstrate the contemporary reference state concept with an example from south‐eastern Australia. Our framework provides a tractable way for policy‐makers and practitioners to navigate biodiversity assessments to maximize conservation and restoration outcomes in contemporary ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cosore-a-community-database-for-continuous-soil-respiration-and-other-soilatmosphere-greenhouse-gas-flux-data&quot;&gt;COSORE: A community database for continuous soil respiration and other soil‐atmosphere greenhouse gas flux data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Globally, soils store two to three times as much carbon as currently resides in the atmosphere, and it is critical to understand how soil greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions and uptake will respond to ongoing climate change. In particular, the soil‐to‐atmosphere CO2 flux, commonly though imprecisely termed soil respiration (RS), is one of the largest carbon fluxes in the Earth system. An increasing number of high‐frequency RS measurements (typically, from an automated system with hourly sampling) have been made over the last two decades; an increasing number of methane measurements are being made with such systems as well. Such high frequency data are an invaluable resource for understanding GHG fluxes, but lack a central database or repository. Here we describe the lightweight, open‐source COSORE (COntinuous SOil REspiration) database and software, that focuses on automated, continuous and long‐term GHG flux datasets, and is intended to serve as a community resource for earth sciences, climate change syntheses and model evaluation. Contributed datasets are mapped to a single, consistent standard, with metadata on contributors, geographic location, measurement conditions and ancillary data. The design emphasizes the importance of reproducibility, scientific transparency and open access to data. While being oriented towards continuously measured RS, the database design accommodates other soil‐atmosphere measurements (e.g. ecosystem respiration, chamber‐measured net ecosystem exchange, methane fluxes) as well as experimental treatments (heterotrophic only, etc.). We give brief examples of the types of analyses possible using this new community resource and describe its accompanying R software package.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/12/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on December 23, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/12/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/12/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-12-02T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-12-02T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-20&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #20&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dynamics of soil penetration resistance in water-controlled environments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New pedotransfer functions for soil water retention curves that better account for bulk density effects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A combined data mining approach for on-line prediction of key soil quality indicators by Vis-NIR spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evaluating the applicability of soil moisture-based metrics for gauging the resiliency of rainfed agricultural systems in the midwestern United States&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Relationship between precipitation and 10Be and impacts on soil dynamics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vis-SWIR spectral prediction model for soil organic matter with different grouping strategies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Landscape-scale spatial variability of kaolinite-gibbsite ratio in tropical soils detected by diffuse reflectance spectroscopy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Problems of modern soil mapping and ways to solve them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dynamics-of-soil-penetration-resistance-in-water-controlled-environments&quot;&gt;Dynamics of soil penetration resistance in water-controlled environments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In water-controlled environments, because rainfall is one of the primary hydroclimatic forcings, its variability can affect the dynamics of soil water content and other related processes such as soil penetration resistance (PR), plant growth, and food production. The objective of this study was to simulate the relative soil water content (s) and PR year-round considering semi-arid rainfall conditions for different soil classes. An experiment was conducted to obtain relative soil water content (s) and PR data in sandy soil and this information was combined with a data set of four soils from a similar experiment conducted on different soil texture classes. The relative soil water content and PR were simulated at a daily timescale using a stochastic soil water balance model for the five soils. The parameters of the PR-s model can be estimated from the soil texture and bulk density. Under rainfed conditions, there is a short window for tillage (plowing and cultivation) of sandy soils compared with clay soils. During the majority of a typical hydrological year, the PR reaches high values (greater than 5.0MPa) imposing a moderate to high physical limitation for root growth in sandy soils. In the same soils, limiting PR is reached at s levels very close to the field capacity during the drying process. This indicates that an extra input of water through irrigation may be required during the establishment of crops with a well-developed root system in order to prevent impairments to root growth. The daily PR values modeled over the course of a hydrological year followed a beta distribution with shape parameters (α and β) which were strongly correlated with the frequency of rainfall events during the wet season (λwet). The modeling framework presented here for simulating relative soil water content and soil penetration resistance can be applied to agricultural systems in order to prevent physical limitations on crop growth and to plan tillage management schedules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-pedotransfer-functions-for-soil-water-retention-curves-that-better-account-for-bulk-density-effects&quot;&gt;New pedotransfer functions for soil water retention curves that better account for bulk density effects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pedotransfer functions (PTFs) describing soil water retention curves (WRCs) have been widely used in crop, soil, and land surface models. A limitation of the available PTFs is that they fail to account for shape changes in WRCs due to bulk density variations caused by soil tillage, compaction, and other processes. This study develops new PTFs that include bulk density effects on the WRC shape. A new framework is introduced to build the bulk density-associated PTFs based on a widely-used WRC dataset. The new PTFs were validated by comparing the performance with two common PTFs from the literature using two independent datasets. The results show that the newly developed PTFs provide reliable WRC estimates for the validation datasets, with mean RMSE values of 0.055 and 0.059 m3 m-3, respectively. The accuracy of the new PTFs is comparable or in some cases better than the common PTFs. While the literature PTFs investigated do not always properly describe bulk density effects on WRC changes, the new PTFs effectively account for such effects on the WRC shape, thus have the potential to be integrated into crop and soil management models to represent bulk density impacts on WRCs due to anthropogenic (e.g., plowing and compaction) and natural (e.g., wetting/drying) processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-combined-data-mining-approach-for-on-line-prediction-of-key-soil-quality-indicators-by-vis-nir-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;A combined data mining approach for on-line prediction of key soil quality indicators by Vis-NIR spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Successful modelling of visible and near-infrared (vis-NIR) spectra for on-line prediction of key soil quality indicators is crucial for accurate variable rate applications of farm input resources. The aim of this paper is to optimize modelling of on-line collected spectra for the prediction of soil pH, organic carbon (OC), extractable phosphorous (P) and potassium (K) by means of spiking, combined with clustering and/or extra-weighting. A mobile fiber-type vis-NIR spectrophotometer (CompactSpec from Tec5 Technology, Germany), with spectral range of 305−1700 nm was calibrated using 100 samples collected from five different fields, which were merged with 28 samples collected from a target field. The resulting dataset was subjected to spectral pretreatments followed by k-means clustering and 95 % confidence ellipsoid, resulting in three optimal datasets. Partial least squares regression (PLSR) analyses were carried out on the calibration set (75 % of samples) for four calibration strategies: (i) non-clustered and non-weighted (NCNW), (ii) clustered and non-weighted (CNW), (iii) non-clustered but extra-weighted (NCW), and (iv) clustered and extra-weighted (CW). Results showed that the quality of on-line predictions was the best after clustering combined with extra-weighting. Modelling based with CW significantly improved model prediction accuracy to be very good for pH (ratio of prediction deviation (RPD) = 2.32) and P (RPD = 2.05), and good for OC (RPD = 1.90) and K (RPD = 1.80), whereas results of NCNW (standard calibration approach) were the poorest to be fair for P (RPD = 1.74) and OC (RPD = 1.50), and poor for K (RPD = 1.1) and pH (RPD = 1.39). It can be concluded that optimal sample selection with k-mean clustering when combined with extra-weighting will result in accurate PLSR calibration models for on-line prediction of soil pH, P, OC and K using a multi-field diverse dataset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evaluating-the-applicability-of-soil-moisture-based-metrics-for-gauging-the-resiliency-of-rainfed-agricultural-systems-in-the-midwestern-united-states&quot;&gt;Evaluating the applicability of soil moisture-based metrics for gauging the resiliency of rainfed agricultural systems in the midwestern United States&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Measuring and improving resiliency is the key goal of climate risk management in rainfed agriculture. Currently, available metrics are generally used to qualitatively measure the resilience of agricultural systems at broader scales. Moreover, these metrics showed non-linear responses to climate variability, thus often fail to capture the temporal dynamics of resilience at field scales. Our objective for this study is to combine a few soil moisture-based metrics to gauge the resiliency of three promising rainfed agricultural treatments, namely the no-till, organic, and reduced input treatments against the conventional treatment. These treatments have been established at the Kellogg Biological Station Long-Term Ecological Research (KBS-LTER) experiment in a randomized complete block design with six blocks per treatment. All four of these treatments consisted of maize (Zea mays)-soybean (Glycine max)-winter wheat (Triticum aestivum) in rotation. Long-term (1993–2018) soil moisture data from this experiment was collected to compute the soil moisture metrics while the total crop biomass, crop yield, and soil organic carbon data were statistically analyzed to evaluate the robustness of the metrics to gauge the resiliency of these systems. Results have shown that, among the soil moisture metrics, the mean relative difference, the Spearman’s rank correlation coefficient, and soil water deficit index were suitable, while the index of temporal stability was not suitable to gauge the resiliency of different rainfed agricultural systems. The no-till treatment was identified as the most resilient treatment in terms of soil moisture retention, effectiveness for drought mitigation, and crop yields. Meanwhile, the reduced input treatment was the least resilient in terms of soil water conservation and drought recovery. The results of this study can be extended to other Midwest regions of the United States and similar climatological areas around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;relationship-between-precipitation-and-10be-and-impacts-on-soil-dynamics&quot;&gt;Relationship between precipitation and 10Be and impacts on soil dynamics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meteoric beryllium-10 (10Be) is commonly used as a proxy of landscape dynamics (erosion and sedimentation rates) and soil development. Soil represents the first-stage reservoir of meteoric 10Be, and variability in the concentration of the isotope in soils may be affected by soil properties and atmospheric deposition. Although many investigations have targeted this issue, there are still problems in estimating the atmospheric input of the isotope in different soil environments. Here, we used 10Be data measured in soils distributed across China to explore the potential influence of meteorological and pedological conditions on the isotope concentration and related applications. In addition, to determine the mechanisms controlling 10Be concentrations in topsoil on a regional scale, the soil samples were sub-divided into 18 different catchments according to fluvial systems. The results indicated that there were significant negative correlations between precipitation and the soil 10Be concentration in high-precipitation regions (&amp;gt;1200 mm·y−1) and significant positive correlations for soils in low precipitation regions (&amp;lt;1200 mm·y−1). The data also revealed that precipitation is the most important variable controlling the 10Be concentration in soils of China when compared with the effects of soil properties such as grain size, mineralogy, pH, and cation exchange capacity. Land use and soil erosion may have limited impacts on the distribution of 10Be in soils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vis-swir-spectral-prediction-model-for-soil-organic-matter-with-different-grouping-strategies&quot;&gt;Vis-SWIR spectral prediction model for soil organic matter with different grouping strategies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The effect of soil organic matter (SOM) on the spectral characteristics of soil differs among soil samples of different soil types with various mineral contents or mechanical compositions. SOM prediction models with visible and near-infrared and shortwave infrared (Vis-SWIR) spectral variables for grouping soil samples are more accurate than global modeling methods. However, the optimal grouping method must be explored. We measured the Vis-SWIR (400–2500 nm) spectral reflectance of 274 soil samples from the Songnen Plain and applied different grouping strategies, including traditional soil grouping, spectral clustering grouping and decision tree grouping considering both traditional grouping information and spectral information. The original reflectance, continuum removal, and first-derivative reflectance were analyzed with competitive adaptive reweighted sampling (CARS), and the results were used as inputs to establish a random forest model for SOM prediction. The following results were obtained: (1) the decision tree grouping method is the optimal grouping strategy for the SOM prediction model; (2) among different inputs, first-derivative reflectance is optimal; and (3) CARS is an effective way to reduce the number of inputs and improve the prediction accuracy of SOM. This study provides an effective soil grouping methodology for SOM estimation at the soil great group level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;landscape-scale-spatial-variability-of-kaolinite-gibbsite-ratio-in-tropical-soils-detected-by-diffuse-reflectance-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Landscape-scale spatial variability of kaolinite-gibbsite ratio in tropical soils detected by diffuse reflectance spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of diffuse reflectance spectroscopy (DRS) has gained prominence in the quantification of soil attributes due to its ease and practicality of obtaining data. This study aimed to evaluate the potential of different methodologies applied to spectral curves given by DRS to estimate kaolinite (Kt) and gibbsite (Gb), and their spatial variability characterization for the Western Plateau of São Paulo. The Western Plateau of São Paulo has 13 million hectares, 2 million of them covered by basalt and 11 million by sandstones. A total of 600 samples were collected at a depth of 0.0–0.20 m. Calibration curves were constructed with pure minerals for x-ray diffraction (XRD) and DRS techniques. The Kt/(Kt + Gb) ratio and the percentages of Kt and Gb were determined by XRD and using the following three methodologies applied to spectral curves: continuum removal technique (CR), direct ratio of the valley (DRV), and multivariate analysis by partial least squares regression (PLSR). The CR procedure had means similar to those observed by XRD, i.e., 0.90 and 0.92, respectively, while DRV overestimated the ratio, with a mean of 1.32. DRS allowed the estimation of the Kt/(Kt + Gb) ratio for the different geological and landscape compartments of the Western Plateau of São Paulo for the CR and DRV procedures. CR procedure allowed constructing models to be more efficient compared to those obtained by DRV and PLSR. The use of geostatistics to interpolate the data of the ratio Kt/(Kt + Gb) by DRS provided important information to define specific management zones accurately and more economically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;problems-of-modern-soil-mapping-and-ways-to-solve-them&quot;&gt;Problems of modern soil mapping and ways to solve them&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article analyzes the problems of modern soil mapping and offers a new, interdisciplinary approach to overcoming them. Among these problems, the most noticeable are the following: harmonization and thematic content of soil maps, multiscale soil mapping, and global soil map. It is shown that the main reasons of problems in modern soil mapping are the recognition of the priority of the practical purposes of soil mapping over the scientific ones, the lack of understanding of the relationship between soil mapping and the conceptual soil classification, the neglect or misuse of the systems approach and contemporary theories of classification, the lack of a universal soil classification system, and an orientation toward new technological advances. It is emphasized that hopes for a successful solution to the problems of soil mapping using the latest technologies, tools and methods are largely unjustified, since, first of all, a consistent theory of soil mapping is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theoretical foundations and technology for multiscale soil-landscape mapping in a GIS environment are described. Multiscale soil-landscape maps are defined as a system of interconnected maps of all scale ranges, which have a single classification basis and coordinated thematic content. They contain integrated information about soils and landscape systems, which are landscapes, considered from the point of view of the systems approach, and display soils mainly as derived landscape system elements. Another distinctive feature of multiscale soil-landscape maps is that they reflect the relationship between soil properties, on the one hand, and properties of the basic landscape system elements (parent rocks, air, water, and organisms), on the other. The advantages of multiscale soil-landscape mapping in comparison with traditional and digital are shown. From a practical point of view, multiscale soil-landscape maps are considered as the basis for making scientifically sound decisions on sustainable nature management at all levels - from global to local.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/12/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on December 02, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/11/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/11/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-11-15T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-11-15T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-19&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #19&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Operational Bayesian GLS Regression for Regional Hydrologic Analyses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Role of Fire in the Coevolution of Soils and Temperate Forests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Calibration Framework for High‐Resolution Hydrological Models Using a Multiresolution and Heterogeneous Strategy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bootstrap Aggregation and Cross‐Validation Methods to Reduce Overfitting in Reservoir Control Policy Search&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developing pedotransfer functions to harmonize extractable soil phosphorus content measured with different methods: A case study across the mainland of France&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Legacy data-based national-scale digital mapping of key soil properties in India&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimating Atterberg limits of soils from hygroscopic water content&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Characterization of the water retention curves of Everglades wetland soils&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Constant carbon pricing increases support for climate action compared to ramping up costs over time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;operational-bayesian-gls-regression-for-regional-hydrologic-analyses&quot;&gt;Operational Bayesian GLS Regression for Regional Hydrologic Analyses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dirceu S. Reis Jr Andrea G. Veilleux Jonathan R. Lamontagne Jery R. Stedinger Eduardo S. Martins&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;e2019WR026940 First Published:19 February 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key Points&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A comprehensive statistical framework for regional hydrologic regression is presented with spatially correlated flow data and varying record lengths
*Framework correctly attributes variability to sampling errors in computed statistic, variability explained by the model, and model error
*New diagnostics includes Bayesian plausibility value, pseudo adjusted R2, pseudo ANOVA, and Bayesian metrics for leverage and influence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-calibration-framework-for-highresolution-hydrological-models-using-a-multiresolution-and-heterogeneous-strategy&quot;&gt;A Calibration Framework for High‐Resolution Hydrological Models Using a Multiresolution and Heterogeneous Strategy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruochen Sun Felipe Hernández Xu Liang Huiling Yuan
e2019WR026541 First Published:12 June 2020
Key Points&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A novel framework is developed for automatic calibration of computationally demanding hydrological models with a large number of parameters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The framework alleviates equifinality, and calibrated parameters achieve more reasonable values that better correspond to physical reality&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The framework leads to faster improvement and smoother convergence to optimal objective values and is tested with 134 calibration parameters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-role-of-fire-in-the-coevolution-of-soils-and-temperate-forests&quot;&gt;The Role of Fire in the Coevolution of Soils and Temperate Forests&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assaf Inbar Petter Nyman Patrick N. J. Lane Gary J. Sheridan
e2019WR026005 First Published:11 July 2020
Key Points&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wildfire strongly influences forest hydrogeomorphology, yet its net effect on coevolution of soil‐vegetation systems is not yet constrained&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We used a new numerical model to test the hypothesis that fire is central to coevolution of forest‐soil systems in SE Australia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The hypothesis was supported, and the role of fire was found to increase with aridity due to higher fire frequency and less developed soils&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bootstrap-aggregation-and-crossvalidation-methods-to-reduce-overfitting-in-reservoir-control-policy-search&quot;&gt;Bootstrap Aggregation and Cross‐Validation Methods to Reduce Overfitting in Reservoir Control Policy Search&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zachary P. Brodeur Jonathan D. Herman Scott Steinschneider
e2020WR027184 First Published:08 July 2020
Key Points&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We apply machine learning techniques of bootstrap aggregation (bagging) and cross‐validation to improve reservoir control policy search&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Block bootstrapping of historic hydrology based on paleo‐inflows can efficiently generate calibration‐validation‐testing data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Policy selection according to validation performance on bootstrapped data leads to the greatest improvement in out‐of‐sample performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;developing-pedotransfer-functions-to-harmonize-extractable-soil-phosphorus-content-measured-with-different-methods-a-case-study-across-the-mainland-of-france&quot;&gt;Developing pedotransfer functions to harmonize extractable soil phosphorus content measured with different methods: A case study across the mainland of France&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geoderma&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phosphorus (P) is a nutrient essential to living organisms and ecosystems. Accurate information regarding extractable soil P is necessary for agricultural management and environmental quality. Direct measurements of extractable soil P at large scales are usually impeded by considerable time, labour, and economic resources required for implementation. To meet agronomic and environmental monitoring needs, multiple extraction methods have been developed worldwide to estimate the different components of soil P. In France, three extraction methods are used, namely the Dyer method for acidic soils, Joret-Hébert for calcareous soils, and Olsen for all soils. Therefore, it is difficult to compare data obtained nationwide for monitoring purposes. Consequently, it is of significant importance to develop pedotransfer functions (PTFs) to harmonise extractable soil P data obtained from different extraction methods with the assistance of other easily available predictors from soil information systems. In this study, we used an extensive dataset from the French soil-monitoring programme for the calibration and evaluation of PTFs. We implemented the partial least squares regression to relate extractable P measured by the Dyer or Joret-Hébert method to extractable P determined by the Olsen method considering 14 soil properties (total P2O5, pH, cation exchange capacity (CEC), CaCO3, soil texture (clay, silt and sand contents), total organic carbon, and exchangeable Fe, Al, CaO, Mn, MgO, and K2O). We constructed patrimonial models by selecting the most important predictors. According to the results of 10 iterations cross-validation, the average R2, root mean-square error (RMSE), and mean error (ME) of the PTF of calcareous soils were 0.66, 25.81, and −0.11 mg kg−1, whereas those of acidic soils were 0.70, 24.02, and −0.87 mg kg1, respectively. The Joret-Hébert P2O5, silt, pH, total P2O5, CEC, and K were the most important predictors for estimating Olsen P2O5 in calcareous soils, whereas Dyer P2O5, exchangeable Al, K, and pH were the most important predictors for estimating Olsen P2O5 in acidic soils. We observed that the explanatory power of the soil properties was more important in calcareous than in acidic soils. As expected, the proxies of Olsen P2O5, namely, Dyer P2O5 and Joret-Hébert P2O5, were the most important variables in modelling Olsen P2O5 variations. In addition, the relationship between Olsen P2O5 and Dyer P2O5 was much stronger than that between Olsen P2O5 and Joret-Hébert P2O5. The results confirmed the feasibility of estimating extractable P in soil by PTFs that were constructed using statistical methods, such as partial least squares regression. The addition of more predictors that are related to agricultural practices and topography attributes may improve the prediction accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;legacy-data-based-national-scale-digital-mapping-of-key-soil-properties-in-india&quot;&gt;Legacy data-based national-scale digital mapping of key soil properties in India&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Mapping soil resources at a national scale in large countries such as India is a challenge because of limited soil data available and efforts to collect them. Legacy soil information shows promise; but, there are still challenges that need to be addressed. In this study, we deliver the first digital maps of key soil properties down to 2 m depth across India using legacy data and quantified the relationships between mapped soil properties and bioclimatic and terrain attributes. A legacy database containing analytical data for 1,707 soil profiles with 7,337 soil horizons was collated from reports published by the National Bureau of Soil Survey and Land Use Planning and other Indian organizations. 3D regression kriging based on the random forest model was used to map sand and clay contents, pH and soil organic carbon (SOC) contents at depths as per the GlobalSoilMap specifications. Important covariates included mean monthly temperature and precipitation data from the World Climatic Centre and terrain attributes derived from the NASA’s Shuttle Radar Topography Mission (SRTM) digital elevation model. The uncertainty of the model was quantified as the coefficient of variation of the predicted soil properties by repeated random sampling of the profile dataset into calibration and validation samples at a ratio of 75:25. The performance statistics for the surface soil properties were superior to subsurface soils with the highest Lin’s concordance coefficient (LCC) recorded for soil pH. Estimated LCC values in validation datasets ranged from 0.81 to 0.84 for pH, 0.30 to 0.59 for SOC, 0.48 to 0.56 for clay content, and 0.34 to 0.44 for sand content. Elevation, topographic wetness index, high rainfall, and temperature were observed to be the major drivers for the variability of selected soil properties. Prepared digital soil maps across different agroecological regions showed that sandy soils dominated Western Plains while clayey soils were dominant in the central Deccan Plateau. Soils of the North-Eastern hills were acidic in nature while the Western Ghats and Coastal Plains showed high SOC accumulation. Although finer soil fractions are considered as major drivers of SOC stabilization, rainfall during June (onset of monsoon) was a major climatic driver for SOC in Indian soils. The national maps of soil properties may be linked to soil productivity and provisioning of ecosystem services to guide policy makers for creating region-specific soil management plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;estimating-atterberg-limits-of-soils-from-hygroscopic-water-content&quot;&gt;Estimating Atterberg limits of soils from hygroscopic water content&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
A number of environmental, agronomic and engineering applications require knowledge of the Atterberg limits (liquid limit, LL; plastic limit, PL) and the plasticity index, PI of soils. The tedious and costly nature of standard experimental methods, as well as challenges with measurement repeatability motivated the development of regressions as well as more sophisticated techniques to estimate the Atterberg limits from other properties such as clay content, cation exchange capacity (CEC), and soil specific surface area. The amount of water adsorbed to particle surfaces at relative humidity (RH) &amp;lt; 95% is intimately linked to these soil properties, which suggests that hygroscopic water content (wh) may be a better predictor of the Atterberg limits. The present study (i) proposes regression models that estimate the LL, PL, and PI from wh at different relative humidity values ranging from 10 to 90% and considering water sorption hysteresis, and (ii) compares the performance of the models to other models that comprise clay, silt and organic carbon contents and CEC. For model development, wh was measured by water adsorption and desorption for 168 soil samples that varied widely in terms of geographic origin, clay mineralogy, and soil organic carbon content. The LL and PL were determined with the drop cone penetrometer and rolling device, respectively. Regression models were developed for both sorption directions for nine RH values between 10 and 90%. For 44 independent soil samples, the models estimated LL, PL and PI accurately (e.g., for desorption wh measured at 90% RH, RMSE and r2 values were 6.43% &amp;amp; 0.89; 3.95% &amp;amp; 0.83 and 6.69% &amp;amp; 0.79, respectively). There was no clear effect of sorption direction on the estimation accuracy. The wh determined at higher RH tended to better estimate the Atterberg limits compared to that measured at lower RH. The wh models were superior in estimating LL and PL compared to models that were based on clay content and organic carbon or CEC. For the PI, the models based on CEC performed slightly better than the wh models. Thus, a single measure of wh can provide reliable estimates of the Atterberg limits and PI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;characterization-of-the-water-retention-curves-of-everglades-wetland-soils&quot;&gt;Characterization of the water retention curves of Everglades wetland soils&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Alterations to the natural hydrology of wetlands like the Everglades have increased the presence of unsaturated zones in typically inundated soil environments. Understanding soil moisture dynamics through numerical modeling requires a large dataset of soil hydraulic parameters (SHPs) due to the spatially variable nature of hydromorphic soils typically found in wetlands. Furthermore, the application of conventional parameterization models is challenging due to shrinkage with desaturation observed in these organic-rich soils. The objective of this work was to investigate water retention, shrinkage, and the effect of shrinkage on the SHPs of Everglades soils. This study used pressure plate extractors to determine the soil water retention curves (SWRCs) and corresponding shrinkage from triplicates for 53 sites across the Everglades. In addition, the organic content (OC), and fiber content (FC) were measured in the laboratory. An agglomerative clustering method applied to the retention and shrinkage data identified three distinct clusters: marl, mixed marl-peat and peat. Marl had higher volumetric water contents (VWCs) than marl-peat or peat particularly at higher pressures. The susceptibility of peat to shrinkage resulted in lower VWCs compared to the other two soils. When shrinkage was accounted for in the vGM model, a significantly higher  and lower  were observed. In addition, some deviations from typical SWRC behavior, attributed to the collapse of macro-pores, caused poor model fit. Northern marshes with predominantly fibric peat had steeper SWRCs due to the inverse relationship between FC and VWC at higher pressures. Further work is required to determine the influence of vegetation on the SWRC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;constant-carbon-pricing-increases-support-for-climate-action-compared-to-ramping-up-costs-over-time&quot;&gt;Constant carbon pricing increases support for climate action compared to ramping up costs over time&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael M. Bechtel, Kenneth F. Scheve &amp;amp; Elisabeth van Lieshout 
Nature Climate Change volume 10, pages1004–1009(2020)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
The introduction of policies that increase the price of carbon is central to limiting the adverse effects of global warming. Conventional wisdom holds that, of the possible cost paths, gradually raising costs relating to climate action will receive the most public support. Here, we explore mass support for dynamic cost paths in four major economies (France, Germany, the United Kingdom and the United States). We find that, for a given level of average costs, increasing cost paths receive little support whereas constant cost schedules are backed by majorities in all countries irrespective of whether those average costs are low or high. Experimental evidence indicates that constant cost paths significantly reduce opposition to climate action relative to increasing cost paths. Preferences for climate cost paths are related to the time horizons of individuals and their desire to smooth consumption over time.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on November 15, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/11/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/11/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-11-07T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-11-07T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-18&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #18&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Global Cropland Connectivity: A Risk Factor for Invasion and Saturation by Emerging Pathogens and Pests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Land use/land cover recognition in arid zone using A multi-dimensional multi-grained residual Forest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pedotransfer Function for the Brunswick Soil Hydraulic Property Model and Comparison to the van Genuchten‐Mualem Model&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil-based, field-specific fertilizer recommendations are a pipe-dream&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trade-offs in greenhouse gas emissions across a liming-induced gradient of soil pH: Role of microbial structure and functioning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;global-cropland-connectivity-a-risk-factor-for-invasion-and-saturation-by-emerging-pathogens-and-pests&quot;&gt;Global Cropland Connectivity: A Risk Factor for Invasion and Saturation by Emerging Pathogens and Pests&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yanru Xing,  John F Hernandez Nopsa,  Kelsey F Andersen,  Jorge L Andrade-Piedra, Fenton D Beed,  Guy Blomme,  Mónica Carvajal-Yepes,  Danny L Coyne,  Wilmer J Cuellar, Gregory A Forbes
BioScience, Volume 70, Issue 9, September 2020, Pages 744–758, https://doi.org/10.1093/biosci/biaa067
Published: 29 July 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
The geographic pattern of cropland is an important risk factor for invasion and saturation by crop-specific pathogens and arthropods. Understanding cropland networks supports smart pest sampling and mitigation strategies. We evaluate global networks of cropland connectivity for key vegetatively propagated crops (banana and plantain, cassava, potato, sweet potato, and yam) important for food security in the tropics. For each crop, potential movement between geographic location pairs was evaluated using a gravity model, with associated uncertainty quantification. The highly linked hub and bridge locations in cropland connectivity risk maps are likely priorities for surveillance and management, and for tracing intraregion movement of pathogens and pests. Important locations are identified beyond those locations that simply have high crop density. Cropland connectivity risk maps provide a new risk component for integration with other factors—such as climatic suitability, genetic resistance, and global trade routes—to inform pest risk assessment and mitigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;land-useland-cover-recognition-in-arid-zone-using-a-multi-dimensional-multi-grained-residual-forest&quot;&gt;Land use/land cover recognition in arid zone using A multi-dimensional multi-grained residual Forest&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Monitoring arid areas could effectively improve economic, ecological and humanity benefits. It is an effective monitoring approach to recognize the land cover or land use of arid areas through machine learning methods using satellite images. However, there is no public classified dataset for arid areas currently, and hence remote sensing image monitoring in desert areas is restricted. Existing classification methods are not able to fully utilize effective features of satellite images and multi-spectral optical parameters. In this paper, our contributions are as follows: Firstly, we presented a new satellite dataset named the ARID-5 for arid area land cover/land use (LULC) classification, the LULC in arid areas included desert, oasis, Gobi, and water system. Second, we proposed a machine learning algorithm named the multi-dimensional multi-grained residual forest algorithm for LULC recognition on arid areas. In this algorithm, the multi-dimensional multi-grained structure was able to effectively extract image features and spectral information. The residual forest structure mapped probability feature vectors to higher levels for prediction, which effectively improved the reflection of the forest structure on the sample. At the same time, the base estimator was transmitted in cascade layers, and thus the diversity and the accuracy were improved. Experimental results proved that the multi-dimensional multi-grained residual forest showed good classification abilities. Last, we also tested our algorithm on SAT-4 and SAT-6 datasets, which proved the generalization performance of our algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pedotransfer-function-for-the-brunswick-soil-hydraulic-property-model-and-comparison-to-the-van-genuchtenmualem-model&quot;&gt;Pedotransfer Function for the Brunswick Soil Hydraulic Property Model and Comparison to the van Genuchten‐Mualem Model&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tobias K. D. Weber  Michael Finkel  Maria da Conceição Gonçalves  Harry Vereecken  Efstathios Diamantopoulos
First published: 20 June 2020 https://doi.org/10.1029/2019WR026820&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Modeling soil hydraulic properties requires an effective representation of capillary and noncapillary storage and conductivity. This is made possible by using physically comprehensive yet flexible soil hydraulic property models. Such a model (Brunswick [BW] model) was introduced by Weber et al. (2019, https://doi.org/10.1029/2018WR024584), and it overcomes some core deficiencies present in the widely used van Genuchten‐Mualem (VGM) model. We first compared the performance of the BW model to that of the VGM model in its ability to describe water retention and hydraulic conductivity data on a set of measurements of 402 soil samples with textures covering the entire range of classes. Second, we developed a simple transfer function to predict BW parameters based on VGM parameters. Combined with our new function, any existing pedotransfer function for the prediction of the VGM parameters can be extended to predict BW model parameters. Based on information criteria, the smaller variance of the residuals, and a 40% reduction in mean absolute error in the hydraulic conductivity over all samples, the BW model clearly outperforms VGM. This is possible as the BW model explicitly accounts for hydraulic properties of dry soils. With the new pedotransfer function developed in this study, better descriptions of water retention and hydraulic conductivities are possible. We are convinced that this will strengthen the utility of the new model and enable improved field‐scale simulations, climate change impact assessments on water, energy and nutrient fluxes, as well as crop productivity in agroecosystems by soil‐crop and land‐surface modeling. The models and the pedotransfer function are included in an R package spsh (https://cran.r‐project.org/package=spsh).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;trade-offs-in-greenhouse-gas-emissions-across-a-liming-induced-gradient-of-soil-ph-role-of-microbial-structure-and-functioning&quot;&gt;Trade-offs in greenhouse gas emissions across a liming-induced gradient of soil pH: Role of microbial structure and functioning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highlights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two-year data from a field experiment initiated in 1942, with four liming rates.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Liming decreased N2O due to increased N2O reduction and by promoting plant growth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Liming increased ecosystem respiration with no effects on soil organic carbon.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lime application stimulated CH4 oxidation, but high rates decreased CH4 oxidation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liming is a common agricultural practice to improve crop yields by raising soil pH. Liming also modulates the production and consumption of greenhouse gases (GHGs) in soils, but the direction and strength of such effects are largely unknown. Since lime application is not a dichotomous variable (application or not), but rather can be dosed according to crop requirements, a critical research gap is whether liming effects on GHG emissions are linear or follow alternate relationships. Based on two-years of data from a long-term field-liming experiment (initiated in 1942), we show that the relationship between an established soil pH gradient (pH of 3.77, 4.92, 6.39, and 6.84 in 1 M KCl extracts) and the emission of GHGs deviates from linearity. Liming increased carbon dioxide (CO2) fluxes from ecosystem respiration, but there were no differences between limed treatments. The increased respiration was due to higher plant carbon (C) inputs and root respiration, enhanced decomposition activity (β-glucosidase) and increased abundance of specific microbial groups (e.g., cellulose-decomposing bacteria). Liming decreased nitrous oxide (N2O) emissions due to increased N2O reduction via denitrification and by promoting plant growth. Compared with native acidic soil, lime application stimulated methane (CH4) oxidation, but the highest liming rate was least stimulatory. This aligned with the soil CH4 oxidation potential, which was modified by liming-induced changes in soil microbial structure as indicated by phospholipid fatty acid analyses. There were no differences in soil organic C (SOC) content between liming levels, apparently because increased ecosystem respiration rates compensated for higher plant C inputs from limed plots. Overall, our results reveal a fundamental ecological trade-off: applying lime at a rate that maximizes crop yield with low N2O emissions may increase CO2 emissions (not compensated by higher SOC in a sandy soil) and decrease CH4 oxidation compared to liming applications below this level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-based-field-specific-fertilizer-recommendations-are-a-pipe-dream&quot;&gt;Soil-based, field-specific fertilizer recommendations are a pipe-dream&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author links open overlay panelA.G.T.SchutK.E.Giller
https://doi.org/10.1016/j.geoderma.2020.114680&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Laboratory ring-tests showed large coefficients of variation in soil analyses.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimates of soil N, P and K supply for a single field varied strongly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Field-specific recommendations based on a single soil sample were inaccurate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fertilizer with balanced N:P:K content strongly reduced errors in recommendations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Fertilizer recommendations are key for farmers: the investment is relatively large for smallholders and risky with unknown yield responses and variable fertilizer prices. Are agronomists able to provide useful site-specific fertilizer recommendations that reduce these uncertainties? We evaluated the influence of errors introduced due to soil sampling and chemical analysis procedures both within- and among laboratories on fertilizer recommendations. Using what we consider to be conservative estimates of the uncertainty in estimating soil supply of N, P and K in a single composite soil sample, the resulting 90% confidence interval of fertilizer recommendations ranged from 86 to 186, 0–58 and 38–114 kg N, P and K ha−1 respectively. The numerous laboratory services and digital applications providing field-specific recommendations appear to promise more accuracy than soil analysis can realistically deliver. We conclude that a field-specific fertilizer recommendation based on a single composite soil sample is indeed a pipe-dream.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on November 07, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/11/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/11/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-11-03T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-11-03T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-17&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #17&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mapping the effectiveness of nature‐based solutions for climate change adaptation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Diversity‐dependent soil acidification under nitrogen enrichment constrains biomass productivity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mapping-the-effectiveness-of-naturebased-solutions-for-climate-change-adaptation&quot;&gt;Mapping the effectiveness of nature‐based solutions for climate change adaptation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alexandre Chausson Beth Turner Dan Seddon Nicole Chabaneix Cécile A. J. Girardin Valerie Kapos Isabel Key Dilys Roe Alison Smith Stephen Woroniecki Nathalie Seddon
Pages: 6134-6155 First Published: 09 September 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We present the first global systematic map of the effectiveness of nature‐based solutions (NbS) for addressing the impacts of climate change and hydrometeorological hazards on people. We found that most studies on NbS interventions in natural or semi‐natural ecosystems reported reduced climate impacts and that, overall, more synergies than trade‐offs were reported between addressing climate impacts and broader ecological, social and climate change mitigation outcomes. However, to strengthen the evidence base and support the upscaling of NbS, future studies should compare the cost‐effectiveness of NbS with engineered alternatives and consider social and ecological outcomes. More NbS research is also needed in the Global South.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;diversitydependent-soil-acidification-under-nitrogen-enrichment-constrains-biomass-productivity&quot;&gt;Diversity‐dependent soil acidification under nitrogen enrichment constrains biomass productivity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kaitlin Kimmel George N. Furey Sarah E. Hobbie Forest Isbell David Tilman Peter B. Reich
Pages: 6594-6603 First Published: 01 September 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nitrogen enrichment is known to increase plant productivity, while also decreasing species richness and acidifying soils. We show that productivity could have been 14.5% greater on average in monocultures if not for nitrogen‐induced soil acidification and about 28.5% greater on average in 16 species communities if not for nitrogen‐induced species losses in a 20 year planted richness by nitrogen addition grassland plant experiment. Our results suggest that the positive effect of nutrient enrichment on productivity can diminish over time, especially because of soil acidification in low diversity communities and especially because of plant diversity loss in initially high diversity communities.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on November 03, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/10/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/10/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-10-19T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-10-19T00:00:00+11:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-16&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #16&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Molecular trade-offs in soil organic carbon composition at continental scale&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linear mixed effects models for non‐Gaussian continuous repeated measurement data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Circular regression trees and forests with an application to probabilistic wind direction forecasting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use of diffuse reflectance spectroscopy and Nix pro color sensor in combination for rapid prediction of soil organic carbon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A framework for modelling soil structure dynamics induced by biological activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;molecular-trade-offs-in-soil-organic-carbon-composition-at-continental-scale&quot;&gt;Molecular trade-offs in soil organic carbon composition at continental scale&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-020-0634-x&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The molecular composition of soil organic carbon remains contentious. Microbial-, plant- and fire-derived compounds may each contribute, but whether they vary predictably among ecosystems remains unclear. Here we present carbon functional groups and molecules from a diverse spectrum of North American surface mineral soils, collected primarily from the National Ecological Observatory Network and quantified by nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy and a molecular mixing model. We find that soils vary widely in relative contributions of carbohydrate, lipid, protein, lignin and char-like carbon, but each compound class has similar overall abundance. Ninety percent of the variance in carbon composition can be explained by three principal component axes representing a trade-off between lignin and protein, a trade-off between carbohydrate and char, and lipids. Reactive aluminium, crystalline iron oxides and pH plus overlying organic horizon thickness—predictors that are all related to climate—best explain variation along each respective axis. Together, our data point to continental-scale trade-offs in soil carbon molecular composition that are linked to environmental and geochemical variables known to predict carbon mass concentrations. Controversies regarding the genesis of soil carbon and its potential responses to global change can be partially reconciled by considering diverse ecosystem properties that drive complementary persistence mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;linear-mixed-effects-models-for-nongaussian-continuous-repeated-measurement-data&quot;&gt;Linear mixed effects models for non‐Gaussian continuous repeated measurement data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has an R package&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://rss.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/rssc.12405&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We consider the analysis of continuous repeated measurement outcomes that are collected longitudinally. A standard framework for analysing data of this kind is a linear Gaussian mixed effects model within which the outcome variable can be decomposed into fixed effects, time invariant and time‐varying random effects, and measurement noise. We develop methodology that, for the first time, allows any combination of these stochastic components to be non‐Gaussian, using multivariate normal variance–mean mixtures. To meet the computational challenges that are presented by large data sets, i.e. in the current context, data sets with many subjects and/or many repeated measurements per subject, we propose a novel implementation of maximum likelihood estimation using a computationally efficient subsampling‐based stochastic gradient algorithm. We obtain standard error estimates by inverting the observed Fisher information matrix and obtain the predictive distributions for the random effects in both filtering (conditioning on past and current data) and smoothing (conditioning on all data) contexts. To implement these procedures, we introduce an R package: ngme. We reanalyse two data sets, from cystic fibrosis and nephrology research, that were previously analysed by using Gaussian linear mixed effects models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;circular-regression-trees-and-forests-with-an-application-to-probabilistic-wind-direction-forecasting&quot;&gt;Circular regression trees and forests with an application to probabilistic wind direction forecasting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has an R package&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://rss.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/rssc.12437&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although circular data occur in a wide range of scientific fields, the methodology for distributional modelling and probabilistic forecasting of circular response variables is quite limited. Most of the existing methods are built on generalized linear and additive models, which are often challenging to optimize and interpret. Specifically, capturing abrupt changes or interactions is not straightforward but often relevant, e.g. for modelling wind directions subject to different wind regimes. Additionally, automatic covariate selection is desirable when many predictor variables are available, as is often the case in weather forecasting. To address these challenges we suggest a general distributional approach using regression trees and random forests to obtain probabilistic forecasts for circular responses. Using trees simplifies model estimation as covariates are used only for partitioning the data and subsequently just a simple von Mises distribution is fitted in the resulting subgroups. Circular regression trees are straightforward to interpret, can capture non‐linear effects and interactions, and automatically select covariates affecting location and/or scale in the von Mises distribution. Circular random forests regularize and smooth the effects from an ensemble of trees. The new methods are applied to probabilistic wind direction forecasting at two Austrian airports, considering other common approaches as a benchmark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-of-diffuse-reflectance-spectroscopy-and-nix-pro-color-sensor-in-combination-for-rapid-prediction-of-soil-organic-carbon&quot;&gt;Use of diffuse reflectance spectroscopy and Nix pro color sensor in combination for rapid prediction of soil organic carbon&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contemporary soil characterization is increasingly dependent upon proximal sensor data whereby high sample throughput and low-cost analysis are realized. Recent research studies have shown that combined sensor platforms generally offer greater predictive model stability and increased accuracy than the use of sensors in isolation. In this study, data from an inexpensive ($350 USD) Nix Pro color sensor, which measures the true color of an object by using red, blue, and green filters, was used with diffuse reflectance spectroscopy (DRS) (590–2490 nm) to predict soil organic carbon (OC) content in highly disturbed, landfill soils of India ex-situ. Generalized additive model (GAM) and partial least squares regression (PLSR) were applied to model DRS and Nix Pro data, respectively, both independently and by combining model predictions using a bilinear regression. Results showed that the combined model outperformed either sensor independently where the 30% external test set achieved a validation R2 of 0.95, residual prediction deviation (RPD) of 4.54, and the ratio of performance to interquartile range of 6.25 relative to laboratory-measured OC data. In contrary, the GAM-OC model using Nix Pro data alone and the PLSR-OC model using DRS data alone exhibited validation R2 values of 0.58 and 0.81, respectively. In sum, the addition of the inexpensive Nix Pro sensor substantively improved the prediction of soil OC relative to the use of DRS in isolation. Future studies should evaluate the effectiveness of such an approach on a wider variety of soil types (e.g., colors), its effectiveness in-situ under variable moisture conditions, and in possible combination with other proximal sensing platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-framework-for-modelling-soil-structure-dynamics-induced-by-biological-activity&quot;&gt;A framework for modelling soil structure dynamics induced by biological activity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil degradation is a worsening global phenomenon driven by socio‐economic pressures, poor land management practices and climate change. A deterioration of soil structure at timescales ranging from seconds to centuries is implicated in most forms of soil degradation including the depletion of nutrients and organic matter, erosion and compaction. New soil–crop models that could account for soil structure dynamics at decadal to centennial timescales would provide insights into the relative importance of the various underlying physical (e.g. tillage, traffic compaction, swell/shrink and freeze/thaw) and biological (e.g. plant root growth, soil microbial and faunal activity) mechanisms, their impacts on soil hydrological processes and plant growth, as well as the relevant timescales of soil degradation and recovery. However, the development of such a model remains a challenge due to the enormous complexity of the interactions in the soil–plant system. In this paper, we focus on the impacts of biological processes on soil structure dynamics, especially the growth of plant roots and the activity of soil fauna and microorganisms. We first define what we mean by soil structure and then review current understanding of how these biological agents impact soil structure. We then develop a new framework for modelling soil structure dynamics, which is designed to be compatible with soil–crop models that operate at the soil profile scale and for long temporal scales (i.e. decades, centuries). We illustrate the modelling concept with a case study on the role of root growth and earthworm bioturbation in restoring the structure of a severely compacted soil.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/10/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on October 19, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/08/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/08/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-08-16T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-08-16T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-15&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #15&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Characterising the biophysical, economic and social impacts of soil carbon sequestration as a greenhouse gas removal technology&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adapting smartphone app used in water testing, for soil nutrient analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From sensor data to Munsell color system: Machine learning algorithm applied to tropical soil color classification via Nix™ Pro sensor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Effects of water, organic matter, and iron forms in mid-IR spectra of soils: Assessments from laboratory to satellite-simulated data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quantifying-uncertainty-for-remote-spectroscopy-of-surface-composition&quot;&gt;Quantifying uncertainty for remote spectroscopy of surface composition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Characterising the biophysical, economic and social impacts of soil carbon sequestration as a greenhouse gas removal technology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To limit warming to well below 2°C, most scenario projections rely on greenhouse gas removal technologies (GGRTs); one such GGRT uses soil carbon sequestration (SCS) in agricultural land. In addition to their role in mitigating climate change, SCS practices play a role in delivering agroecosystem resilience, climate change adaptability and food security. Environmental heterogeneity and differences in agricultural practices challenge the practical implementation of SCS, and our analysis addresses the associated knowledge gap. Previous assessments have focused on global potentials, but there is a need among policymakers to operationalise SCS. Here, we assess a range of practices already proposed to deliver SCS, and distil these into a subset of specific measures. We provide a multidisciplinary summary of the barriers and potential incentives towards practical implementation of these measures. First, we identify specific practices with potential for both a positive impact on SCS at farm level and an uptake rate compatible with global impact. These focus on: (a) optimising crop primary productivity (e.g. nutrient optimisation, pH management, irrigation); (b) reducing soil disturbance and managing soil physical properties (e.g. improved rotations, minimum till); (c) minimising deliberate removal of C or lateral transport via erosion processes (e.g. support measures, bare fallow reduction); (d) addition of C produced outside the system (e.g. organic manure amendments, biochar addition); (e) provision of additional C inputs within the cropping system (e.g. agroforestry, cover cropping). We then consider economic and non‐cost barriers and incentives for land managers implementing these measures, along with the potential externalised impacts of implementation. This offers a framework and reference point for holistic assessment of the impacts of SCS. Finally, we summarise and discuss the ability of extant scientific approaches to quantify the technical potential and externalities of SCS measures, and the barriers and incentives to their implementation in global agricultural systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;adapting-smartphone-app-used-in-water-testing-for-soil-nutrient-analysis&quot;&gt;Adapting smartphone app used in water testing, for soil nutrient analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smartphone technology has now penetrated every aspect of modern life. At such high rates of access and utilization, there is today much potential for the development of smartphones as high-performing tools in a number of industries. Traditionally, smartphones have been used as e.g. point-of-care testing devices in developing countries; now a similar approach can be extended to agriculture. This paper assesses the viability of utilizing smartphones in soil analysis. An Android-based smartphone application, in conjunction with commercially available Quantofix® test strips, was employed to analyze 92 soil samples collected across Indonesia. The soils tested encompassed a wide range of different textures (with 13%, 60% and 25% of samples constituting sandy, loamy and clayey soils, respectively), soil organic matter contents (range: 0.8–19.7%) and nutrient concentrations (range for plant-available N: 0.1–137.4 mg kg−1 and P: 1.2 to 64.2 mg kg−1; on dry soil basis). The app utilizes the smartphone as a portable reflectometer, which relates the color of test strips to the concentration of particular nutrients present in the soil medium. Three mobile devices currently available on the market, representing low, mid- and high-end products, were used to test the application. The results obtained via the smartphone were compared against standard methods for determination of extractable nitrate-N and exchangeable phosphorus (Olsen-P) under laboratory conditions. The smartphone-mediated soil analysis was found to have a high degree of agreement with standard methods for nitrate-N determination (87% of samples with nitrate-N differed by less than 10 mg kg−1 from the standard method for the high-end smartphone) but not for phosphorus determination where chemical interferences to test strip colour development were noted. All three mobile devices were shown to be effective as portable reflectometers. However, color perception was found to differ amongst the devices, resulting in a consistent bias between the high-end phone and the remaining appliances. Whereas, it is essential to consider the inter-smartphone variability in readings and environmental factors such as temperature prior to the smartphone-mediated soil analysis, the smartphone-test strip combination might be employed as acceptable screening tool for soil nutrient concentration assessment to enhance crop outcomes, increasing yield, and preventing over-application of inputs, reducing consequent financial and environmental impact. Further enhancements can test the applicability of smartphone-mediated soil analysis in field conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;from-sensor-data-to-munsell-color-system-machine-learning-algorithm-applied-to-tropical-soil-color-classification-via-nix-pro-sensor&quot;&gt;From sensor data to Munsell color system: Machine learning algorithm applied to tropical soil color classification via Nix™ Pro sensor&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil color has historically drawn humans’ attention, although its definition is somewhat subjective. It is correlated with several soil attributes and it allows for inferences about several soil aspects. New proximal sensors, such as the Nix™ Pro color sensor, can determine soil color values, but its correlation with the widely used Munsell soil color chart (MSCC) has yet to be investigated. This work aimed to train machine learning models using the Random Forest (RF) algorithm to predict each notation of MSCC chips from data extracted by the Nix™ Pro sensor, test the model’s accuracy by evaluating whether it can identify MSCC chips using a brand-new and a dirty MSCC, and compare model predictions with soil color classifications made by the human eye. Additionally, MSCC data obtained via Nix™ was compared to Munsell renotation data to assess the color detection accuracy of the sensor. Prediction models were calibrated by scanning every MSCC chip (437 in total) in triplicate. All validation samples were excluded from model calibration. Accuracy of the predictions of MSCC notation reached overall accuracy and Kappa index values of 0.93 for the brand-new MSCC and of 0.70 for the dirty MSCC. Soil color classification by human eye had little agreement with the predicted MSCC notation, as expected due to the variable conditions affecting soil color conventional determination in the field. Color difference was calculated by the Euclidian distance (ΔE&lt;em&gt;ab) between three color stimuli in the CIELAB color space. The mean ΔE&lt;/em&gt;ab between Nix™-provided data and renotation data was 2.9, demonstrating high color detection accuracy. The Nix™ Pro color sensor allows for assessment of accurate color data. When applied together with machine learning algorithms, Nix™ Pro provides a reliable determination of soil color classification equivalent to MSCC in an easily reproducible, rapid, inexpensive and non-subjective way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;effects-of-water-organic-matter-and-iron-forms-in-mid-ir-spectra-of-soils-assessments-from-laboratory-to-satellite-simulated-data&quot;&gt;Effects of water, organic matter, and iron forms in mid-IR spectra of soils: Assessments from laboratory to satellite-simulated data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The soil mineralogical constitution directly influences its chemical, physical and hydraulic characteristics. Although very important, it is still rarely used for decision-making in agriculture, mainly due to the complexity and cost of standard analyzes. In this sense, the middle infrared spectroscopy (mid-IR, 4000 to 400 cm−1) has great potential to obtain soil mineralogical information quickly and accurately. Nevertheless, some soil constituents can severely influence the spectra and produce misinterpretations. In this research, we aim to detect changes in the mid-IR spectra caused by water, iron forms and organic matter (OM), and to relate soil attributes to laboratory spectra and remote sensing simulated spectral bands. The research area is located in São Paulo State, Brazil, where seventeen soil samples were collected. The reflectance intensities, shapes and absorption features of the mid-IR spectra before and after the removal of OM and iron forms and the addition of water were described. Soil attributes, such as kaolinite, gibbsite, 2:1 minerals among others were correlated with the mid-IR spectra and simulated ASTER spectral bands by Pearson’s analysis, to verify its potential on mineralogical evaluation. The description of mid-IR revealed that the removal of the OM from the soil samples decreased the reflectance intensities between 4000 and 2000 cm−1. Iron forms mainly influence the 3250 – 1200 cm−1 spectral range and mask the spectral features of other minerals as well. The addition of water masked several absorption features and decreased the reflectance intensities from 3700 to 2700 cm−1. High correlation coefficients were obtained between soil attributes and ASTER simulated spectral bands, which allowed the selection of potential spectral regions for future satellite sensors: 2760 – 2500 cm−1 (3600 – 4000 nm), 2150 – 1875 cm−1 (4600 – 5300 nm), and 840 – 740 cm−1 (11900 – 3500 nm).&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/08/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on August 16, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/08/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/08/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-08-06T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-08-06T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-14&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #14&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quantifying uncertainty for remote spectroscopy of surface composition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quantifying-uncertainty-for-remote-spectroscopy-of-surface-composition&quot;&gt;Quantifying uncertainty for remote spectroscopy of surface composition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remote Sensing of Environment
Volume 247, 15 September 2020, 111898&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Remote surface measurements by imaging spectrometers play an important role in planetary and Earth science. To make these measurements, investigators calibrate instrument data to absolute units, invert physical models to estimate atmospheric effects, and then determine surface properties from the spectral reflectance. This study quantifies the uncertainty in this process. Global missions demand predictive uncertainty models that can estimate future errors for varied environments and observing conditions. Here we validate uncertainty predictions with remote surface composition retrievals and in situ measurements in a field analogue of Earth and planetary exploration. We consider rover transects at Cuprite, Nevada, and remote observations by NASA’s Next-Generation Airborne Visible Infrared Imaging Spectrometer (AVIRIS-NG). We show that accounting for input uncertainties can benefit mineral detection methods such as constrained spectrum fitting. This suggests that operational uncertainty estimates could improve future NASA missions like the Earth Mineral dust source InvesTigation (EMIT) and the Lunar Trailblazer mission, as well as NASA’s Decadal Surface Biology and Geology (SBG) Investigation.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/08/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on August 06, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/07/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/07/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-07-30T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-07-30T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-13&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #13&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mapping soil profile depth, bulk density and carbon stock in Scotland using remote sensing and spatial covariates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new approach for studying vertical infiltration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increasing the organic carbon stocks in mineral soils sequesters large amounts of phosphorus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Global human influence maps reveal clear opportunities in conserving Earth’s remaining intact terrestrial ecosystems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Distinct controls over the temporal dynamics of soil carbon fractions after land use change&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil as an extended composite phenotype of the microbial metagenome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mapping-soil-profile-depth-bulk-density-and-carbon-stock-in-scotland-using-remote-sensing-and-spatial-covariates&quot;&gt;Mapping soil profile depth, bulk density and carbon stock in Scotland using remote sensing and spatial covariates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt Aitkenhead Malcolm Coull
EJSS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-new-approach-for-studying-vertical-infiltration&quot;&gt;A new approach for studying vertical infiltration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alexander Poulovassilis 0000-0003-1117-1158 and Ioannis Argyrokastritis 0000-0003-0519-2219
pp. 509-518&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The absorption of rain and irrigation water by soils, called the infiltration process, is of vital importance for plant growth. This process is controlled by the permeability properties of soils, and this paper presents new methods for determining these properties and new equations describing the infiltration process more precisely than in previous works. These contributions allow a better understanding of the infiltration process and more precise calculation of water infiltration rates under conditions imposed by both nature and irrigation practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;increasing-the-organic-carbon-stocks-in-mineral-soils-sequesters-large-amounts-of-phosphorus&quot;&gt;Increasing the organic carbon stocks in mineral soils sequesters large amounts of phosphorus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marie Spohn
Global CHange Biology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;global-human-influence-maps-reveal-clear-opportunities-in-conserving-earths-remaining-intact-terrestrial-ecosystems&quot;&gt;Global human influence maps reveal clear opportunities in conserving Earth’s remaining intact terrestrial ecosystems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason Riggio Jonathan E. M. Baillie Steven Brumby Erle Ellis Christina M. Kennedy James R. Oakleaf Alex Tait Therese Tepe David M. Theobald Oscar Venter James E. M. Watson Andrew P. Jacobson
Pages: 4344-4356 First Published: 05 June 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading up to the Convention on Biological Diversity Conference of the Parties 15, there is momentum around setting bold conservation targets. Yet it remains unclear how much of Earth’s land area remains without significant human influence. We compare four recent global maps of human influences (Anthromes, Global Human Modification, Human Footprint, and Low Impact Areas) and find that about half of Earth’s terrestrial surface has relatively low human influence. These findings offer opportunities for proactive conservation actions to retain the last intact ecosystems on the planet, although the relative abundance of ecosystem areas with low human influence varies widely by biome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;distinct-controls-over-the-temporal-dynamics-of-soil-carbon-fractions-after-land-use-change&quot;&gt;Distinct controls over the temporal dynamics of soil carbon fractions after land use change&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zhongkui Luo Raphael A. Viscarra Rossel Zhou Shi
Pages: 4614-4625 First Published: 13 May 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our understanding on the controls over soil organic carbon (SOC) composition, particularly its temporal dynamics, is quite limited, inhibiting reliable prediction of SOC dynamics. By assessing a comprehensive dataset including temporal measurements of three SOC fractions (i.e. particulate, mineral-associated and charred organic carbon) after land use change, we found that environmental factors present distinct effects on the dynamics of the three fractions, and these effects were time-dependent. To reduce uncertainties in SOC predictions in response to global change and land management, the distinct controls over the dynamics of SOC fractions should be properly considered in carbon models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-as-an-extended-composite-phenotype-of-the-microbial-metagenome&quot;&gt;Soil as an extended composite phenotype of the microbial metagenome&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew L. Neal, Aur?lie Bacq-Labreuil, Xiaoxian Zhang, Ian M. Clark, Kevin Coleman, Sacha J. Mooney, Karl Ritz &amp;amp; John W. Crawford&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/07/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on July 30, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/06/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/06/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-06-19T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-06-12T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-12&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #12&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil magnetic susceptibility and its relationship with naturally occurring processes and soil attributes in pedosphere, in a tropical environment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The challenge for the soil science community to contribute to the implementation of the UN Sustainable Development Goals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evaluating a low-cost portable NIR spectrometer for the prediction of soil organic and total carbon using different calibration models&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Dynamics of Soil Microbial Communities on Different Timescales: A Review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Debates: Does Information Theory Provide a New Paradigm for Earth Science? Sharper Predictions Using Occam’s Digital Razor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can Continental Models Convey Useful Seasonal Hydrologic Information at the Catchment Scale?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does Information Theory Provide a New Paradigm for Earth Science? Hypothesis Testing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Climate Adaptation as a Control Problem: Review and Perspectives on Dynamic Water Resources Planning Under Uncertainty&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Debates-Does Information Theory Provide a New Paradigm for Earth Science? Causality, Interaction, and Feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soil-magnetic-susceptibility-and-its-relationship-with-naturally-occurring-processes-and-soil-attributes-in-pedosphere-in-a-tropical-environment&quot;&gt;Soil magnetic susceptibility and its relationship with naturally occurring processes and soil attributes in pedosphere, in a tropical environment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: de Mello, Danilo Cesar; Dematte, Jose A. M.; Silvero, Nelida E. Q.; et al.
GEODERMA  Volume:  372   Pages:  14364-14364   Published:  AUG 1 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soil magnetic susceptibility (kappa) has potential to be used as a pedoenvironmental indicator from which mineralogy, pedogeochemical, pedogeomorphological and pedogenic processes can be inferred. It can be used in pedosphere studies, as an auxiliary information for appropriate and sustainable soil use and management. This research aimed to analyze how pedogenesis and geochemical processes affect the kappa and some of its attributes, as well as its potential use in discriminating soil great groups, following the digital soil mapping approach. The study area is located in Sao Paulo State - Brazil. Soil samples were collected for physical-chemical analysis from 79 locations (0-20 cm depth). At these sites, magnetic susceptibility was measured with a portable field instrument and analyzed in terms of geology, relief and soil class. The results showed that geology strongly affects kappa, mainly in diabase derived soils, followed by metamorphosed siltstone and siltstone. In fluvial sediments, the kappa exhibits different behaviors due to different sediments deposited by the Capivari River. In less evolved soils, such as Cambisols, lithology is a more important contributor to kappa than pedogenesis. In more evolved soils, pedogenesis increases kappa, whereas argilluviation/ferralitization reduces it. The kappa values did not decrease significantly or even increase downslope, due to the presence of diabase on the lower parts. Differences in kappa where observed between diabase bedrock located in different parts of the study area, indicating more of an influence by geomorphic processes rather than lithology. With respect to soil attributes, positive correlations between kappa and base saturation, cation exchange capacity, organic matter, and iron and clay content were found, whereas a negative correlation was found between kappa and sand content. The kappa correlates with changes in lithology and soil class demonstrating its application as a potential tool for the discrimination of soil great groups and digital soil mapping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-challenge-for-the-soil-science-community-to-contribute-to-the-implementation-of-the-un-sustainable-development-goals&quot;&gt;The challenge for the soil science community to contribute to the implementation of the UN Sustainable Development Goals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Bouma, Johan; Montanarella, Luca; Evanylo, Gregory
SOIL USE AND MANAGEMENT  Volume:  35   Issue:  4   Pages:  538-546   Published:  DEC 2019
Context Sensitive Links Full Text from Publisher  Close Abstract
Seventeen Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) were adopted by 193 Governments at the General Assembly of the United Nations in 2015 for achievement by 2030. These SDGs present a roadmap to a sustainable future and a challenge to the science community. To guide activities and check progress, targets and indicators have been and are still being defined. The soil science community has published documents that describe the primary importance of soil for SDGs addressing hunger, water quality, climate mitigation and biodiversity preservation, and secondary relevance of soil for addressing several other SDGs. Soil scientists only marginally participated in the SDG discussions and are currently only peripherally engaged in discussions on targets or indicators. Agreement on several soil-related indicators has still not been achieved. Involvement of soil scientists in SDG–based studies is desirable for both developing solutions and increasing the visibility of the soil profession. Inputs into policy decisions should be improved as SDG committee members are appointed by Governments. Possible contributions of soil science in defining indicators for the SDGs are explored in this paper. We advocate the pragmatic use of soil-water-atmosphere-plant simulation models and available soil surveys and soil databases where “representative” soil profiles for mapping units (genetically defined genoforms) are functionally expressed in terms of several phenoforms reflecting effects of different types of soil use and management that strongly affect functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evaluating-a-low-cost-portable-nir-spectrometer-for-the-prediction-of-soil-organic-and-total-carbon-using-different-calibration-models&quot;&gt;Evaluating a low-cost portable NIR spectrometer for the prediction of soil organic and total carbon using different calibration models&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Sharififar, Amin; Singh, Kanika; Jones, Edward; et al.
SOIL USE AND MANAGEMENT  Volume:  35   Issue:  4   Pages:  607-616   Published:  DEC 2019
Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
This study aims to assess the performance of a low-cost, micro-electromechanical system-based, near infrared spectrometer for soil organic carbon (OC) and total carbon (TC) estimation. TC was measured on 151 soil profiles up to the depth of 1 m in NSW, Australia, and from which a subset of 24 soil profiles were measured for OC. Two commercial spectrometers including the AgriSpec(TM) (ASD) and NeoSpectra(TM) (Neospectra) with spectral wavelength ranges of 350-2,500 and 1,300-2,500 nm, respectively, were used to scan the soil samples, according to the standard contact probe protocol. Savitzky-Golay smoothing filter and standard normal variate (SNV) transformation were performed on the spectral data for noise reduction and baseline correction. Three calibration models, including Cubist tree model, partial least squares regression (PLSR) and support vector machine (SVM), were assessed for the prediction of soil OC and TC using spectral data. A 10-fold cross-validation analysis was performed for evaluation of the models and devices accuracies. Results showed that Cubist model predicts OC and TC more accurately than PLSR and SVM. For OC prediction, Cubist showed R-2 = 0.89 (RMSE = 0.12%) and R-2 = 0.78 (RMSE = 0.16%) using ASD and NeoSpectra, respectively. For TC prediction, Cubist produced R-2 = 0.75 (RMSE = 0.45%) and R-2 = 0.70 (RMSE = 0.50%) using ASD and NeoSpectra, respectively. ASD performed better than NeoSpectra. However, the low-cost NeoSpectra predictions were comparable to the ASD. These finding can be helpful for more efficient future spectroscopic prediction of soil OC and TC with less costly devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-dynamics-of-soil-microbial-communities-on-different-timescales-a-review&quot;&gt;The Dynamics of Soil Microbial Communities on Different Timescales: A Review&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Chernov, T. I.; Zhelezova, A. D.
EURASIAN SOIL SCIENCE  Volume:  53   Issue:  5   Pages:  643-652   Published:  MAY 2020
Context Sensitive Links  Close Abstract
Soil microbial communities are subjected to significant changes over time. The most rapid changes caused by temperature and soil moisture alternations or the by the inflow of fresh organic matter occur during the several hours or days. They are mostly related to the soil microbial activity. Seasonal dynamics are caused by annual variations in temperature and precipitation that affect the microbial community directly or indirectly through the regulation of plant life. The microbial biomass and the taxonomic composition of soil microbial communities vary significantly throughout the year, which should be taken into account when sampling for a comparative analysis of different soils. The long-term dynamics of microbial communities during primary or secondary successions lead to an increase in the total microbial biomass and the fungi/bacteria ratio, as well as to changes in the taxonomic composition of microbial communities. The main factors of the long-term dynamics are the accumulation of soil organic matter, plant successions, and changes in pH. The diversity of microbial communities during long-term dynamics can vary in different ways and does not follow a single trend. The longest dynamics of soil microbial communities are associated with changes in bioclimatic conditions. Information about soil microbial communities of the past can be obtained by studying buried and permafrost soils. The study of future changes in soil microbial communities is possible in experiments with artificial changes in climatic parameters. Plants are a significant factor in the dynamics of soil microbial communities on all timescales; in short-term periods, the major role is played by the activity of plants; in the long-term trends, the changes in the vegetation abundance and diversity are the most important factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;debates-does-information-theory-provide-a-new-paradigm-for-earth-science-sharper-predictions-using-occams-digital-razor&quot;&gt;Debates: Does Information Theory Provide a New Paradigm for Earth Science? Sharper Predictions Using Occam’s Digital Razor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Weijs, Steven. V.; Ruddell, Benjamin. L.
WATER RESOURCES RESEARCH  Volume:  56   Issue:  2   Pages:  26471-26471   Published:  FEB 2020
Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract
Occam’s Razor is a bedrock principle of science philosophy, stating that the simplest hypothesis (or model) is preferred, at any given level of model predictive performance. A modern restatement often attributed to Einstein explains, “Everything should be made as simple as possible, but not simpler.” Using principles from (algorithmic) information theory, both model descriptive performance and model complexity can be quantified in bits. This quantification yields a Pareto-style trade-off between model complexity (length of the model program in bits) and model performance (information loss in bits, or the missing information, needed to describe the original observations). Model complexity and performance can be collapsed to one single measure of lossless model size, which, when minimized, leads to optimal model complexity versus loss trade-off for generalization and prediction. Our view puts both simple data-driven and complex physical-process-based models on a continuum, in the sense that both describe patterns in observed data in compressed form, with different degrees of generality, model complexity, and descriptive performance. Information theory-based assessment of compression performance with fair and meaningful accounting for model complexity will enable us to best compare and combine the strengths of physics knowledge and data-driven modeling for a given problem, given the availability of data. “Suppose we draw a set of points on paper in a totally random manner” …“I am saying it is possible to find a geometric line whose notation is constant and uniform, following a certain law, that will pass through all points, and in the sameorder they were drawn.” … “But if that law is strongly composed,the thing that conforms to it should be seen as irregular”Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz, 1686: Discours de metaphysique V, VI (from French)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;can-continental-models-convey-useful-seasonal-hydrologic-information-at-the-catchment-scale&quot;&gt;Can Continental Models Convey Useful Seasonal Hydrologic Information at the Catchment Scale?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Crochemore, L.; Ramos, M. -H.; Pechlivanidis, I. G.
WATER RESOURCES RESEARCH  Volume:  56   Issue:  2   Pages:  25700-25700   Published:  FEB 2020
Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract
The development and availability of climate forecasting systems have allowed the implementation of seasonal hydroclimatic services at the continental scale. User guidance and quality of the forecast information are key components to ensure user engagement and service uptake, yet forecast quality depends on the hydrologic model setup. Here, we address how seasonal forecasts from continental services can be used to address user needs at the catchment scale. We compare a continentally calibrated process-based model (E-HYPE) and a catchment-specific parsimonious model (GR6J) to forecast streamflow in a set of French catchments. Results show that despite expected high performance from the catchment setup against observed streamflow, the continental setup can, in some catchments, match or even outperform the catchment-specific setup for 3-month aggregations and threshold exceedance. Forecast systems can become comparable when looking at statistics relative to model climatology, such as anomalies, and adequate initial conditions are the main source of skill in both systems. We highlight the need for consistency in data used in modeling chains and in tailoring service outputs for use at the catchment scale. Finally, we show that the spread in internal model states varies largely between the two systems, reflecting the differences in their setups and calibration strategies, and highlighting that caution is needed before extracting hydrologic variables other than streamflow. We overall argue that continental hydroclimatic services show potential on addressing needs at the catchment scale, yet guidance is needed to extract, tailor and use the information provided.
Plain Language Summary Climatic variations can have a significant impact on a number of water-related sectors. Managing such variations through accurate predictions is thus crucial. Continental hydroclimate services have recently received attention to address various user needs. However, predictions for months ahead can be limited at catchment scale, highlighting the need for data tailoring. Here, we compare the predictions from two hydrologic setups at catchment scale. One setup (E-HYPE) is used in a European hydroclimate service, whereas the other (GR6J) is used for local water-related risk assessment. Our results show that predictions from the continental setup can be as accurate as the predictions from the local model when predicting streamflow averaged over several months and when looking at changes in streamflow rather than absolute values. A good estimation of the hydrologic states, such as soil moisture or lake levels, prior to the prediction is the most important factor in obtaining accurate streamflow predictions in both setups. However, the differences in the setups can result in different uncertainties for variables other than streamflow, like in the case of soil water content. We argue that useful information is provided by continental services, yet guidance for information extraction can result into tailored information for regional needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;does-information-theory-provide-a-new-paradigm-for-earth-science-hypothesis-testing&quot;&gt;Does Information Theory Provide a New Paradigm for Earth Science? Hypothesis Testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Nearing, Grey S.; Ruddell, Benjamin L.; Bennett, Andrew R.; et al.
WATER RESOURCES RESEARCH  Volume:  56   Issue:  2   Pages:  24918-24918   Published:  FEB 2020
Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract
Model evaluation and hypothesis testing are fundamental to any field of science. We propose here that by changing slightly the way we think and communicate about inference-from being fundamentally a problem of uncertainty quantification to being a problem of information quantification-allows us to avoid certain problems related to testing models as hypotheses. We propose that scientists are typically interested in assessing the information provided by models, not the truth value or likelihood of a model. Information theory allows us to formalize this perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;climate-adaptation-as-a-control-problem-review-and-perspectives-on-dynamic-water-resources-planning-under-uncertainty&quot;&gt;Climate Adaptation as a Control Problem: Review and Perspectives on Dynamic Water Resources Planning Under Uncertainty&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Herman, Jonathan D.; Quinn, Julianne D.; Steinschneider, Scott; et al.
WATER RESOURCES RESEARCH  Volume:  56   Issue:  2   Pages:  24389-24389   Published:  FEB 2020
Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract
Climate change introduces substantial uncertainty to water resources planning and raises the key question: when, or under what conditions, should adaptation occur? A number of recent studies aim to identify policies mapping future observations to actions-in other words, framing climate adaptation as an optimal control problem. This paper uses the control paradigm to review and classify recent dynamic planning studies according to their approaches to uncertainty characterization, policy structure, and solution methods. We propose a set of research gaps and opportunities in this area centered on the challenge of characterizing uncertainty, which prevents the unambiguous application of control methods to this problem. These include exogenous uncertainty in forcing, model structure, and parameters propagated through a chain of climate and hydrologic models; endogenous uncertainty in human-environmental system dynamics across multiple scales; and sampling uncertainty due to the finite length of historical observations and future projections. Recognizing these challenges, several opportunities exist to improve the use of control methods for climate adaptation, namely, how problem context and understanding of climate processes might assist with uncertainty quantification and experimental design, out-of-sample validation and robustness of optimized adaptation policies, and monitoring and data assimilation, including trend detection, Bayesian inference, and indicator variable selection. We conclude with a summary of recommendations for dynamic water resources planning under climate change through the lens of optimal control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;debates-does-information-theory-provide-a-new-paradigm-for-earth-science-causality-interaction-and-feedback&quot;&gt;Debates-Does Information Theory Provide a New Paradigm for Earth Science? Causality, Interaction, and Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Goodwell, Allison E.; Jiang, Peishi; Ruddell, Benjamin L.; et al.
WATER RESOURCES RESEARCH  Volume:  56   Issue:  2   Pages:  24940-24940   Published:  FEB 2020
Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract
The concept of causal interactions between components is an integral part of hydrology and Earth system sciences. Modelers, decision makers, scientists, and other water resources stakeholders all utilize some notion of cause-and-effect to understand processes, make decisions, and infer how systems react to change. However, there are different perspectives on the meaning of causality in complex systems and, further, different frameworks and methodologies with which to detect causal interactions. We propose here that information theory (IT) provides a compelling framework for the detection of causality and discuss approaches for several levels of analyses that capture interactions that range from pairwise to multivariate in nature. We illustrate these types of analyses with an example based on weather station time series variables, in which variables may interact pairwise or jointly and on short to long time scales. In general, many unsolved or even unanticipated questions in the hydrologic sciences could benefit from this perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/06/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on June 12, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal Paper Digests]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2020/06/journalDigest" />
  <id>/2020/06/journalDigest</id>
  <updated>2020-06-08T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2020-06-08T00:00:00+10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Smart Digital Agriculture</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>malone.brendan1001@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;journal-paper-digests-2020-11&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests 2020 #11&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bibliometric analysis of research on soil health from 1999 to 2018&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Climate drives global soil carbon sequestration and crop yield changes under conservation agriculture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marching in step: The importance of matching model complexity to data availability in terrestrial biosphere models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bibliometric-analysis-of-research-on-soil-health-from-1999-to-2018&quot;&gt;Bibliometric analysis of research on soil health from 1999 to 2018&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Liu, Yanan; Wu, Kening; Zhao, Rui&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JOURNAL OF SOILS AND SEDIMENTS Volume:  20 Issue:  3 Pages:  1513-1525 Published:  MAR 2020 Context Sensitive Links Close Abstract Purpose Soil health has been a major focus of research by international scholars because it is an important factor that supports human survival and development. However, few scholars have performed bibliometric analyses of research on soil health. This study investigated the current research status and development characteristics of soil health. Materials and methods We performed a bibliometric analysis of documents on soil health from 1999 to 2018 in the Web of Science Core Collection. The bibliometric analysis tools, CiteSpace and HistCite software, were applied. Results and discussion A total of 1629 documents on soil health in the Web of Science Core Collection were identified. From the research status of soil health, the number of publications will continue to increase. Most of the research institutions examining soil health are located in the USA, and there is little cooperation and communication among countries, neither do research institutions in this field. Each country has its own research labs while lab cooperation within individual countries is relatively close. Most documents on the research of soil health have been published in the journal Applied Soil Ecology. In addition, research directions are expanding from the basic study of soil production, soil health indicators, and soil pollution to the comprehensive study of soil ecosystem. Conclusions Bibliometric analysis tools, CiteSpace and HistCite software, provide a comprehensive approach for making predictions regarding trends in the field. This method was used in this study to identify the hotspots, frontiers, and future development of soil health to provide guidance for future research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;climate-drives-global-soil-carbon-sequestration-and-crop-yield-changes-under-conservation-agriculture&quot;&gt;Climate drives global soil carbon sequestration and crop yield changes under conservation agriculture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Sun, Wenjuan; Canadell, Josep G.; Yu, Lijun; et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY Volume:  26 Issue:  6 Pages:  3325-3335 Published:  JUN 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context Sensitive Links Close Abstract Conservation agriculture has been shown to have multiple benefits for soils, crop yield and the environment, and consequently, no-till, the central practice of conservation agriculture, has rapidly expanded. However, studies show that the potential for carbon (C) sequestration in no-till farming sometimes is not realized, let alone the ability to maintain or improve crop yield. Here we present a global analysis of no-till-induced changes of soil C and crop yield based on 260 and 1,970 paired studies; respectively. We show that, relative to local conventional tillage, arid regions can benefit the most from conservation agriculture by achieving a win-win outcome of enhanced C sequestration and increased crop yield. However, more humid regions are more likely to increase SOC only, while some colder regions have yield losses and soil C loss as likely as soil C gains. In addition to site-specific characteristics and management, a careful assessment of the regional climate is needed to determine the potential benefits of adopting conservation agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;marching-in-step-the-importance-of-matching-model-complexity-to-data-availability-in-terrestrial-biosphere-models&quot;&gt;Marching in step: The importance of matching model complexity to data availability in terrestrial biosphere models&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By: Feng, Xue GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY Volume:  26 Issue:  6 Pages:  3190-3192 Published:  JUN 2020 Context Sensitive Links Free Full Text from Publisher Close Abstract This is a Commentary on Paschalis et al. Building models to predict ecosystem responses to future rainfall changes requires closely matching model complexity to data availability. A new study by Paschalis et al. (Global Change Biology, 2020) examines opportunities to improve both data availability and model structure in 10 state-of-the-art terrestrial biosphere models.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/06/journalDigest&quot;&gt;Journal Paper Digests&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Smart Digital Agriculture at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Smart Digital Agriculture&lt;/a&gt; on June 08, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>
